Soul Anchors—Part Three

The gates of Hogwarts stand tall and strong, suffused with magic and strong enough to hold back a small army of sword-wielding goblins, wand-wielding wizards, or muggles wielding whatever happens to be in fashion this century. Hand-forged from goblin silver by the Smith family some two-hundred-odd years before the great betrayal, they alone are worthy of granting Hogwarts the title of ‘safest place in Magical Britain.’

The gaps between the bars are quite wide though.

In the weak dawn air of a December morning, a teenage female figure made her way down the path towards said gates. She was invisible to the casual glance, save for a faint outline in the air to mark her passage across the frost-covered lawn.

When she reached the gates, the figure whispered, “Plato!”

On the other side of the gates, Plato the house elf, wearing his Slytherin robes and crest popped into being. He looked around in puzzlement for a moment before the girl said, “Plato, it’s me.”

“Miss Icygrass.” The elf’s wide eyes focused on the spot where the invisible voice had come from. “Why is Miss calling Plato?”

“I need you to send an owl to Mister and Missus Granger. It’s urgent.”

“Right away, Miss. Where is the letter?”

“I haven’t written it yet. It needs to come from Slytherin himself.”

“Plato understands, Miss. What does the letter need to say?”

The future Lady Slytherin told him.

Plato bowed deeply and popped away.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

He didn’t pop far. Without the call of their masters to guide them, house elf apparition was quite similar to the wizard version—ie, short-range and magically taxing. Some fifty pops later, Plato arrived on Gairsay Island, right in front of Slytherin Manor, panting heavily. He made his way through the grand ballroom, up two flights of stairs, and into his master’s study. A large bookcase on the far wall was crammed with rolled up parchments.

“Master, indisposed,” the elf muttered to himself as he trailed a long, bony finger along the shelves. “Plato is not liking this, no, not one bit.” He found the parchment he was looking for among the collection and pulled it out. “No master is meaning no gold from sunken ship. No new gold is meaning no new house elves. No new house elves is meaning no mate for Plato. Plato is not liking to wait. Plato is wearing neat new robes like wizards now. Females be loving bad boys.”

He left the study and walked down the long corridor to the end of the hallway. There, he opened a set up large double windows, clambered up onto the sill, and called out, “Master’s owl! Master needs letter sent!”

The grounds of Slytherin Manor had been transformed since earlier in the term. Gone was the empty pasture, replaced with hardwearing bushes, trees, and other plants—all magical to a greater or lesser degree. From one of these trees, Macavity leapt and swooped up to the window.

“Good birdie,” Plato said, attaching the letter to his leg. “Go, swift like wind now. Is being very important.”

Macavity made a gesture that could be interpreted as a shrug, turned his back on the little human-like thing, spread his wings, and set off on the heroically long journey to the bottom of the hill.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In Granger Cottage, Clare Cooper was sitting at the kitchen table, groggily sipping from a cup of early morning tea when a tap from the window interrupted her. Minutes later, she’d taken the letter from Lord Slytherin’s owl, sent him on his way—probably back to Hedwig—and descended the secret stairs to the Granger’s underground workshop.

“Letter,” Clare declared to the room filled with machines and a couple of half-built giant broomsticks.

Emma looked up from where she’d been working. “Hedwig, Macavity?”

“Macavity. Here you go.” Clare then excused herself to get ready for school.

Emma sliced the letter open with a screwdriver and read.

“And what does our lord have to say?” Dan asked, appearing from behind one of the subs.

“He’s got to take care of some things,” Emma replied, turning back to the desk. “He’s being pretty vague, but he says he’ll be back in a couple of weeks.” She felt a presence behind her and strong arms wrap around her waist.

“Two weeks all to ourselves,” Dan murmured into her ear. “We can do a lot in two weeks.”

“We can’t go out in the broom-sub without him, or the girls, or Harry,” Emma commented idly.

“We could take the time to catch up on some of our other projects,” Dan replied. “Slytherin is a demanding master.”

“He’s not the only one,” Emma murmured back. A strong hand was trailing up her thigh. Her husband had never been skinny, but the discovery of magic had injected new motivation into his exercise.

“Is that what I am? A master?”

“Demanding, is what I meant.”

The hand stopped, just shy of her slowly building need. Emma groaned.

“Well then,” Dan said jovially. “I demand that you write Lord Smith a letter explaining that we now have some time to work some runes for him on his shield project.” He stepped back. “I’m sure he’ll be delighted.”

Emma turned and glared. “Having you role-play Lord Slytherin so much was a mistake.”

One frustratedly written letter later, Emma stomped up to the floo, threw in a pinch of floo powder and watched the green flames lick high in the fireplace. She chucked the letter in and said, “Hogsmeade Owl Office.”

She had just enough time to squeal in delight as strong hands grabbed her from behind, spun her around, and hauled her onto the kitchen table, before the letter was consumed and swirled away in a rush of green fire.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Letters, unlike people, didn’t need to remember to get out at the right grate. Emma’s envelope rocketed through the floo and after barely five minutes whooshed out of the fireplace of a large building, furnished with one large desk, a hundred wooden perches, and plastered in owl doings on every flat surface visible.

The wizard on duty cleaned his wide-brimmed hat again with the wand, plucked up the envelope, sliced it open, extracted the two knuts inside, pocketed them, and placed the other, still-sealed envelope, which had been inside the first, in a tray marked ‘OUT.’

A moment later, a small barn owl swooped down from one of the hundreds of perches and held out its leg expectantly.

One tied piece of string later, and it was off.

A half-hour later, Lord Smith looked up from his breakfast of bacon, ham, eggs, sausage, black pudding, cheese, and beer, before letting out a humongous belch and snatching a letter from a silver tray carried by a house elf.

“That was unrefined, dear,” said a well put-together lady on the far end of the huge table. Lady Smith was the kind of person who would perfect her make-up, potions, hair, skin charms, jewellery, and day clothes each and every day before even considering taking breakfast with her husband of seventy years.

“Yes, dear,” said Lord Smith. “Oh, look. Slytherin’s finally pulled his finger out of his arse.”

“Really, dear? Is this about those tiny runes you’ve been so excited about?”

“Yes, dear. Slytherin’s people finally have some time to kill. Hah! I bet that means Slytherin’s missing again.”

Lady Smith pursed her lips. “Oh dear.”

Twenty minutes later, three separate letters zoomed their way through the floo to three separate owl offices throughout the land. There, three different owls picked up those letters and whisked them to three different manor houses. Three different ladies wearing dressing gowns of three different colours—one red, one pink, one black—read those letters and sat down at three different writing desks. Three different letters then became five, which then became eight, then ten, then fifteen.

Morning became noon, which became afternoon, and finally evening.

Lord Jacob Greengrass stood in his office, the red stain of the sunset tinting his furniture and books, and read the owl that had just been delivered.

Lord Greengrass,

I have heard on the grapevine that Lord Slytherin won’t be with us for a few weeks. Since your previous reason for declining my invitation to the emergency meeting of the Mandrake Supply Council was lack of time due to political commitments, I wondered if this new development might have freed up some of your focus. If so, please let me know if you’d like to join us so I can make the necessary arrangements.

Yours with great respect,

Barallion Updike

Jacob took out his best thunderbird quill, put nib to parchment, and wrote.

Yes, I would.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The next morning, next to the main floo place of Malfoy Manor, Virgo inspected herself critically in the hallway mirror. Now that she was more than whole, she could easily see why the Malfoys had chosen her to be her diary’s body. Her face still contained a certain amount of baby fat, but it was clear that she’d soon develop into the kind of witch that powerful wizards fought duels over. Her robes were fine and rich—nothing like the cheap, mass-produced, orphan-appropriate clothes she’d worn when she’d first arrived at Hogwarts—nor like the more modern muggle clothes she’d recently worn, designed and made to keep out the biting Swedish winter. No, these robes made her look like a wickedly beautiful sorceress straight out of a high fantasy story.

They are robes appropriate for a noble witch of high-birth—a noble witch, like me.

Virgo chuckled nervously.

“What are you laughing at?” spat the mirror.

Virgo’s eyes narrowed.

Ten seconds later, Lady Malfoy burst in, wand out and alert. “What happened? I heard a crash—” She stopped when her eyes fell on the smashed glass laying around Virgo’s feet before travelling up to the candlestick held in her blood adopted daughter’s hand.

It took every ounce of control Virgo possessed not to look sheepish or guilty.

Lady Malfoy had insisted that she stay ‘home’ at least one more night before leaving back for school. That time had given Virgo much time to think and consider. The first major question had been, ‘was she still a Horcrux?’ That had been answered with a quick trip to the soul chasm, with a resounding, ‘yes, unfortunately.’ The second question had been, ‘what was she going to do now?’

That question, she was still considering.

After a final farewell and eager to get away from her new adopted mother’s fussing attention, she stepped into the floo and said, “Hogwarts!”. The rush of the floo warmed her as she rocketed up from Wiltshire to the highlands of Scotland. It was like the world’s coolest theme-park ride. And with her wand in hand, she felt like an actual superhero—or was that super villain? She was part Dark Lord, after all.

“Miss Malfoy!” Headmaster Lockhart beamed as she stepped into his office. “You’re a bit too late for breakfast, so you’d better skip along to your first class.’

Virgo did not skip as she made her way towards charms class, although the prospect of actually going to magic school almost made her want to—almost. Despite the harrowing experience of being a prisoner in her own mind, this was one of only two places she’d called home, the other being impossible to return to.

“Miss Malfoy,” chirped professor Flitwick from atop his pile of books when she tentatively poked her head into the classroom. “We’re currently practising the shrinking charm. Why don’t you sit next to Mister Creevey there?”

Colin Creevey’s eyes bugged as she sat down next to him, flicked her long hair, and flashed him a smile.

She watched in interest as Creevey tried to shrink down the goblet each of them had been given and failed miserably. Creevey then watched in awe as she flicked her wand, without even saying the incantation and yo-yoed her goblet from large to tiny and back again, several times in as many seconds.

He wasn’t the only one who’d caught that little display. A few of her fellow Gryffindors and many of the Ravenclaws they shared this class with were also staring at her.

“Excellent display, Miss Malfoy!” the professor exclaimed. “Take two points for Gryffindor. Why don’t you spend some time helping your classmates while I help Mister Cornfield here?”

“Happily, Professor.”

As Virgo started showing Creevey how to execute a proper ⅜ flick, her mind drifted to one already obvious, but now unavoidable fact. This was so easy! She was so much better than her peers even the teachers couldn’t help acknowledge it. She was almost twelve, but already better than even the oldest students in the school. There wasn’t anything she couldn’t do. If she wanted to, she could be the greatest sorceress the world had ever seen.

No, I AM the greatest sorceress the world has ever seen!

“Miss Malfoy!” Professor Flitwick called from across the room. “Please contain your enthusiasm in class! That is what charms club is for.”

Virgo, once again, tried not to look sheepish.

“Although, I must admit,” the professor continued in his usual light-hearted tone, “this is the first time one of my first-year students has produced a small army of river-dancing goblets. Take another two points.”

Virgo didn’t take lunch in the great hall. It wasn’t that she was scared, she just wasn’t … ready? She, that was it. She wasn’t ready. She wasn’t ready to talk to John Potter and Susan Bones in person for the sort-of first time.

In the Gryffindor girl’s first-year dorms, she whispered, “Dobby.”

Dobby the free house elf popped into being by her bed. “Miss is wanting Dobby?” His eyes looked worried. “Miss should not be calling Dobby in Hogwarts. It is not being safe.”

Feeling a bit guilty, Virgo quickly relayed her desire to the rare house elf she’d been introduced to the previous night.

Dobby wrung his ears. “Oh, Miss. Just this once, Miss. But you must only be calling on Dobby if it is life and death. That is what Lady Malfoy is saying.”

Dobby popped away and five minutes later Virgo had her lunch laid on in front of her. As she ate, her mind drifted back to the great things she could do. Before she’d performed that damn ritual with the diary, she’d had plans—so many plans—plans to travel the world, discover ancient magics and artefacts, and even forge her own. She’d wanted to climb to the top of Magical Britain and walk the road of immortality further than any had walked it before.

Dabbing the edges of her mouth with her handkerchief, she dismissed her now empty plates and made her way down to afternoon class—Defence.

That was where her plans for greatness hit a massive mental snag.

“What are you glaring at, Black?”

“Glaring, Creevy? I’m not glaring at anything. Certainly not at you.”

“John says you’re up to no good.”

“How dare you speak to Heiress Black like that, mudblood,” sneered one of the Carrow twins.

“Why, you! I know what that word means, you know. Hermione told me all about it!”

“Humph. Granger may be pretty, but her whole family are nothing but whores for Lord Slytherin.”

It wasn’t Black and the Carrow twins that were giving Virgo problems though, rather it was the girl sitting in a corner of the classroom, all by herself—the girl with fiery red hair and eyes that, in just a heartbeat, could go from relaxed to so intense they could pin a butterfly to a stone wall.

“Sit down, all of you!” Snape snapped as he swept into the classroom. “Creevey, five points from Gryffindor for your disrespect. Black, see me after class. Today we are going to study the lip-locker curse.”

Ginny Weasley caught her gaze and smiled.

Virgo felt a chill go down her spine. Actually, she wasn’t the best witch in the school, was she? Not if it really had been Weasley who was the one to ambush her not once, but twice, almost killing her each time. Virgo was as strong as she was because she was part Dark Lord. What terrible secrets did Weasley possess that allowed her her power?

After half an hour studying theory, Snape pulled up two students for practical, one of whom, was the current subject of Virgo’s worries. The girl’s movements were even more elegant than she remembered—not an ounce of energy was wasted, physical or magical—and the girl gave off the distinct impression of supreme amusement as her Gryffindor opponent, one of Virgo’s male classmates, tried his best to seal her lips, but failed time and time again.

“Yes, thank you, Miss Weasley,” Snape drawled. “Perhaps you feel in need of a greater challenge?” He turned. “Get off the stage, boy,” he snapped at the still-mute Gryffindor.

A murmur of surprise went through the students, Virgo among them. Snape was planning to duel Weasley himself? Sure, he’d been insinuating that he would eventually, but most had considered it an idle threat. Teachers did not, as a rule, duel students—and certainly not first-year students. Weasley herself looked shocked before the corners of her lips turned upwards.

These were not normal duels.

With the allowed spells limited to only one, it wasn’t really a test of combat, but rather a test of pure cast speed. Who could draw, aim, and cast the fastest.

In the first round, both Snape and Weasley were caught by surprise, each casting faster than Weasley had done against the Gryffindor boy. It ended in a draw, with both combatants mute.

“Again,” Snape snapped after unsealing their lips with a wave of his wand.

The second round went even faster. It was only Virgo’s magic sensing abilities that allowed her to follow it at all. Most of her classmates just gasped. Again, it was a draw.

“Again.”

Virgo suspected she was the only one who spotted the briefest look of worry that crossed the redhead’s face before both she and Snape sheathed their wands, ready to duel once again.

This time, Weasley lost.

While the whole of the classroom held its collective breath, Snape advanced on the now sheepish looking girl. “Miss Weasley,” Snape said in his silkiest voice. “Do you take me for a fool?”

“No, professor.”

“Do I perhaps look like someone who is easy to trick? Someone who might enjoy a good laugh?”

Weasley awkwardly shuffled her feet. “No, Professor.”

“Then let me make one thing quite clear. If you ever lose on purpose in my class ever again, I will have you in detention writing lines from now until year end. Have I made myself understood?”

Weasley blanched. “Yes, Professor.”

Thirty minutes and many duels later, Virgo left the defence classroom, face ashen, skin shivering, with only one thought going through her head.

Ginevra Weasley needs to die.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“There!”

In the middle of an empty classroom, Daphne, Hermione, and Alex aimed their wands at an empty patch of floor and let loose their magics. Their accumulated powers shot forward, hit nothing but stone, and rebounded in different directions.

Alexandra cursed.

“Focus!” Daphne shouted. “Position!”

The three witches jumped to stand back-to-back, forming a triangle with each side brandishing a promise of total magic destruction to any foolish enough to strike. Or at least, that was the intention.

“This is ridiculous,” Hermione whispered. “How are we supposed to—”

“Quiet,” Daphne hissed. “Listen.”

The classroom was deathly still. Alexandra shifted her weight in her boots, almost imperceptibly. Hermione and Daphne’s sensible flats stayed glued to the floor.

Then, out of nowhere, a flare of magic all but over-whelmed them. For those trained to sense the subtle flows of magic it was as if a sun had been lit in the deepest depths of an underground cave.

“It’s a trap!” Hermione shouted, but not quickly enough.

Alexandra had already pointed her wand in the direction of the flare and sent her chains whipping across the room. There was a blur in front of her, and the next thing the Black Heiress knew, a glowing red hand appeared from thin air, right in front of her face.

To those not familiar with group magical combat, it is often asked why stunners are so often used, when the enemy can just awaken their fallen comrades. The answer to this is simple. Stunning a wizard takes but a second, while getting your head back in the game when you’ve just been awoken from a magically induced slumber takes quite a few more than that, even for the well-trained.

Thus, as Alexandra Black slowly collapsed to the ground, neither Hermione nor Daphne counted on her to save their asses. Hermione did flick a quick enervate at Alex, and Daphne did spin around to shield Hermione while she did so, but they both knew that they were now well and truly up the proverbial creek, without the proverbial paddle.

And indeed, Alex’s eyes had barely even refocused when the same glowing red hand appeared again, this time at Daphne’s totally exposed back and fired another stunner.

In the time that it took Hermione to enervate the now falling Daphne, the floating hand was back again, this time at Hermione’s back. Another flash, and Hermione was gone as well.

Still groggy, Alexandra just about registered intent to stun forming in her general direction. As quickly as her foggy mind would allow, she formed the same intent on the tip of her wand and brought it up to swat the enemy magic away, but not, unfortunately, quickly enough.

Daphne, by contrast, barely even realised that she was waking up in the middle of a fight before another red stunner was fired at her, finishing off their team’s last hope.

This is why enervating team members only really works when the combatants in question can even hope to hold off the enemy for long enough to bring them back into the game.

A few meters away from the fallen girls, a shimmering cloak appeared in the air, whipped off by another young witch in a muggle tracksuit top, bottoms and trainers. “Damn Snape!” Ginny shouted. “I—Argh! I was so careful not to show my skill in public for so long! Damn him! I’m just so—! ARGH!”

After a few moments of this, Ginny remembered herself enough to fire off three enervates at her fallen comrades.

“Alex!” Hermione said angrily, the moment they’d both found themselves. “What were you thinking? It wasn’t even a spell! It was just raw magic! It was so obviously a trap!”

“Oh, like you were doing anything to help,” Alex snarked back. “You can’t even spell-swat.”

“You couldn’t spell-swat until a few months ago.”

“And you’re a whole year older than me. And top of the class.”

“That’s why I can’t spell-swat! If I had the time to train like you and Ginny, I’d have mastered it long before you did.”

“Are you saying you’re better than me!?”

“Girls,” Daphne said, firmly cutting across both of them. “Let’s not argue. What would Harry say if he saw us acting like this?”

Hermione and Alex looked thoughtful for a moment.

“That we need to get better at working together?” Alex asked.

“That each of us has unique strengths and is valuable in their own way,” Hermione suggested.

“Maybe,” Daphne conceded, before turning to Ginny.

Ginny still looked annoyed. “He’d tell you both to get back to work. I can’t believe how easy getting the drop on you three is.”

“But you have the cloak and won’t let me use my inferi,” Alex protested. “Why can’t we have a try with it?”

“You think that would make a difference?” Ginny smirked. “Take it if you want, but it’s not me that has to get better at fighting an overwhelming opponent.”

“Girls,” Daphne said again, drawing their attention back to her. “Ginny is right that we need to continue practicing as we have been, but we’ve been at this for over an hour now. Let’s take a break. In the mean time, Hermione has some interesting ideas for us, I believe. Hermione?”

“Oh! Right!” Hermione trotted over to her bag and returned with a large leather bound book. “I’ve been doing some research into animagi and how they can be used in combat. I’m sure Harry was going to talk to us about this eventually, but since he’s, you know”—her voice became strained—“not with us at the moment, I figured we should go ahead without him.” She collected herself and sat down on the charmed blanket that Daphne had laid down on the floor, the others following suit. “Oh, is that from the kitchens?” Hermione asked, as Daphne produced a wicker basket.

“It is. The elves here are still rather cautious around me. We don’t know if our lord can give them clothes and none of them want to be the first to find out either way.”

“Right. Oh, sandwiches? Thank you—just chicken for me. Why do they insist on cutting the crusts off? Don’t they know the crusts are the best part? Anyway, where was I? Oh, yes. Animagi in combat. I found this book written by an auror in the eighteenth century, Cecil Tempest, who did a lot of experimenting with his animagus form and some of what he says is quite fascinating. For example, the basic theory of aether flamelage that we learned in transfiguration seems to work with the animagus form, except for the transformation itself, which doesn’t seem to take hardly any magic at all.”

“That makes sense,” Ginny said with her mouth full of egg and cress sandwich, which caused Daphne to wrinkle her nose. “Some wizards hold their forms for years. My Mum used to tell me stories of wizards who turned into birds and just flew away and lived their whole lives like that.”

“Quite,” Hermione said. “But the most interesting part is that perhaps because the form doesn’t take much, if any, magic to hold or transform, an animagi’s magic continues to replenish while transformed.”

“Mfm!” Alex said, enthusiastically, keeping her mouth closed while munching on a bacon butty. She swallowed. “That is rather cool! That means that if we have a good form for combat, we can weave between forms and never run out of magic.”

“Yes,” Hermione agreed with a slight nod. “And some forms are better suited for combat than others. Bigger forms have more inherent magical resistance than smaller forms, while smaller forms are harder to hit. The ideal would be having a small form, but of a magical creature—preferably one that is already highly magically resistant.” She couldn’t help a slightly smug expression creeping onto her face. “Something like a miniature unicorn, to take a purely hypothetical example.”

“Hey, Grims are also magically resistant,” Alex quickly said.

“But are about the same weight-class as a normal wizard, which makes them much easier to hit.”

“Yeah, but can turn spectral! Which is awesome against wizards who rely on physical attacks.”

“Girls,” Daphne cut in. “Let’s not turn this into a wand measuring contest. Some of us, after all, won’t have forms suited for close combat at all.”

Hermione and Alex both looked abashed.

Ginny sniggered. “No, you’ll just be able to read over someone’s shoulder from over a mile away, up in the air, well out of range of any wand fire. I’d say that’s pretty useful. I just hope that I can learn to transform mid-sprint. That would be really awesome. It’s just a shame cheetahs aren’t inherently magically resistant.”

“No,” Hermione agreed, “You’ll just have to rely on your own inherent magical resistance. I just wished we knew what Harry and Luna’s forms are. Luna I get, but it’s not like Harry to keep secrets - even if he does like guessing games.”

Alex and Ginny both nodded.

“What else did you learn, Hermione?” Daphne asked.

“Well—” Hermione began, but before she could continue, Ginny cut her off.

“Hang on!” the tracksuit-wearing witch said. “You’re right, Hermione, it isn’t like Harry to keep secrets. He usually tells at least one of us, and, Daphne, I think that subject change was just a little too clean.”

Hermione and Alex raised their eyebrows and looked at Daphne.

Daphne looked annoyed for a second before she sighed. “Oh, alright. Yes, he gave me a clue on my birthday, but he did outright tell me later on.”

“Why didn’t he tell us?” Hermione asked, looking a little hurt.

Daphne shifted uncomfortably. “I think he’s having a bit of a wand measuring contest of his own—with Luna. He’s not telling all of us because he doesn’t want Luna to know until they meet in the ritual. You know what he’s like with her. Of all of us, Luna is the one that comes closest to actually challenging him.” She shrugged. “It’s a boy thing.”

Hermione folded her arms. “I’d have never told Luna if Harry had asked me not too.”

“Yes, but you know how perceptive Luna can be.”

Hermione’s shoulder’s sagged. “I suppose you’re right.”

“Wait!” Ginny jumped in. “So, you’re not going to tell us?! You can’t not tell us now that we know you know.”

“Ginny,” Hermione started in a scalding tone of voice, “If Harry doesn’t want us to know—”

“No,” Daphne cut her off. She sighed. “Ginny is right.”

“Wait, I am?”

“Yes. Besides, Luna is also out of it and we might have only a few weeks after they wake up before we do the ritual. Just promise you won’t tell Luna, even if she figures out that you know.”

They all promised.

“Okay.” Daphne brought out a book of her own and laid it down open in the middle of the quartet of witches. “Just remember that even I don’t know the details. I just know the general form.”

“General form?” Alex asked.

Daphne turned several pages, stopped, and pointed her finger. Ginny and Alex both gasped. Hermione’s eyes widened. The picture was of an abomination of a creature, like something out of a taxidermist’s worst nightmare. It had seven different heads, a body that looked formed from three different animals, five different tails, one of which had a head of its own, and legs that each ended in a different foot—claws, hoof, talons, and foot.

“Chimaera,” Hermione whispered. “A magical creature born of dark magic storms—fused from two or more different animals to create a new whole, greater and more terrible than the sum of its parts. Very interesting.”

“Interesting?!” Alex blurted out. “Harry has this as his animagus form and the best you can do is, ‘interesting‘?! Don’t you realise how insane this is?! Chimaera are five-x magical creatures! They’re some of the most dangerous and powerful magical creatures known to wizarding kind!” All the while the Black witch ranted, Ginny was emphatically nodding her head. “And don’t get me started on their intelligence!” Alex continued. “Chimaera are the only five-x magical creature that can understand the human tongue—they’re sentient! Some wizards and muggles in the past used to worship them as gods, despite the fact that they ate people! Only one wizard has ever single-handedly killed a chimaera—one insanely lucky wizard—and that was only a one-month old cub! With Harry like this, we’ll be unstoppable!”

“They’re not invincible,” Daphne said, quietly. “The one in the castle last year was killed by the Basilisk—and the ICW seems to deal with at least one rogue Chimaera every other decade.”

Alex paused for a moment. “Okay, they’re not invincible,” she conceded. “But I mean, what is? You remember what our lord constantly tells us during training. ‘In a fight between creativity and power, bet on the side that has both’. I’d love to see Voldemort or Dumbledore’s faces if Harry learns to weave this into his duelling style. So, what are his parts?”

“I told you already, I don’t know. He did make a joke once that he was both hot and cold blooded—or that his forms traditionally were, anyway.”

“Snakes,” Ginny said firmly. “If one of his parts isn’t a snake of some kind I’ll eat my hat.”

Hermione nodded. “I agree. Snakes do seem likely. Are there standard Chimaera forms? Maybe he’s one of those.”

“Some combinations and parts do tend to crop up more often than others,” Daphne said, turning one of the book’s pages. “Dragons, goats, and lions are common.”

Alex’s eyes widened. “Wait, dragons! So, Chimaera can have magical-creature parts. Okay, I’m calling it now. Harry will be every five-x magical creature mushed together.”

Hermione scoffed. “This isn’t a boy-who-lived adventure book, Alex.”

“I don’t read them!”

“I … never said you did?”

Ginny frowned. “And how would a lethifold fit into this ultimate five-x Chimaera?”

“Okay, forget it! It was just an idea.”

Hermione smirked and nudged Daphne in the side. “Maybe he’ll be a unicorn Chimaera with a snake tail. Then you wouldn’t need me, you could ride him.”

Daphne flushed red. “Can we get back to the topic at hand? We need to figure out how we’re going to use our animagus forms while working together against Harry.”

“Maybe I should ask my brothers,” Ginny thought out loud. “They’re really good at creative thinking.”

“They haven’t told you what they’re planning on doing for the ritual have they?” Daphne asked. “Or what forms they are?”

“Penguins,” Ginny said, now grinning widely. “Rock-hopper penguins. Fred said he’d go first. George will go with the next batch. They flipped a coin. As cool as it would be to chance a cerberus penguin, they are actually remarkably sensible when it comes down to the important things. They know the risks of rituals—especially untested ones.”

“I don’t think Harry would have actually let them stuff themselves into one pot,” Daphne said with a wry smile. “But then, that’s Harry, isn’t it? Let the other person choose to do what he wants them to.”

The four witches sat around the book on the floor fall silent for a moment.

“I really miss him,” Daphne said.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Hey, Malfoy. John Potter is looking for you,” said some random Ravenclaw as they passed in the corridor.

“So I’ve heard,” Virgo replied, with just a hint of annoyance. “Over and over again.”

At some point during the day, word had gotten to the boy-who-lived that the not-really-a-squib Malfoy had returned to the castle. Since then, she’d barely had a moment’s peace. It wasn’t that she was avoiding him …

Virgo sighed.

Okay, so it totally was that she was avoiding him.

It just felt so weird having been so close to this boy, while seeing him as nothing but a tool, while at the same time never having talked to him, but admiring him from afar, and having what she now knew was a teenage crush on him, possibly even more than that. None of this was helped by a small part of her screaming that she was a man, and that she didn’t bend over for anyone—in any sense of the phrase.

But the Hogwarts rumour mill was not a one-way street, to horribly mix a metaphor, and news about her wasn’t the only thing that had been plucked from the grape-vine, stamped on at said mill, and happily distributed around the local watering-hole for students and staff alike to get horribly drunk off of.

Harry Potter, the enigma, and Luna Lovegood, the whore, had both been taken ill to the hospital wing almost immediately after her own little accident, and rumour had it that they had been petrified.

That was extremely disturbing. Either because it meant that the two had somehow managed to invade her mindscape, or because the basilisk of Hogwarts proper was once again active, and possibly not even under her direction. Had the brief period of her not being a parselmouth reset the ‘first-come-first-serve’ rule? Had Lord Slytherin conquered the chamber while she’d been out of commission? Or even before then?

And not only that, but an even more troubling thought—had it been Harry Potter or Lovegood who had knocked on her soul just before the Basilisk had attacked her old selves while trapped in her own mind? That was another explanation for how they’d gotten petrified. After all, the magic of parseltongue had given her guardian more life-like qualities than any normal mental creature.

She’d been quite certain that Harry Potter was not a Horcrux, but now, once again, she wasn’t so sure. On the other hand, that wouldn’t explain how Luna had gotten petrified—since she obviously wasn’t a horcrux … probably … possibly? Or maybe Ginny Weasley was a horcrux! That could explain her skill—but only if it was Weasley who’d attacked her. But then what about Alexandra Black? She was also very advanced for her age. But, no.

Virgo shook herself.

Knowing what she knew about Voldemort, the horcruxes would never be able to work together. So either it was one of them, or it was none of them.

If Lord Slytherin was the Horcrux, then Luna Lovegood might be able to traverse the soul chasm, as his betrothed, but that didn’t explain Harry. Unless Harry Potter was secretly a witch who’d also been betrothed to Lord Slytherin—stranger things had happened.

Alternatively, none of them was a horcrux and there was some other explanation for their power. Or, even more annoyingly, their power could just be ‘because magic said so’. That was always a possibility.

Whatever the cause she needed to get on top of it. And, as much as her thoughts might panic at the idea, that did mean being close to John Potter. He was her best chance—at survival and at greatness.

“Virgo!”

A very familiar voice caused her to jump and spin around, guilt flashing all over her face.

“S-susan.”

Susan Bones practically tackle-hugged her. “You’re back! Why didn’t you say anything? Where have you been? John has been so worried! Are you okay? Who attacked you? Did you see his face? Her face? It wasn’t the same witch as before, was it?”

Virgo was both used to being hugged, and not used to being hugged, as seen by her hands, which froze, out in front of her, rigid, before finding their place, awkwardly, around the Bones Heiress’ back. “I’m fine, Susan. No, I didn’t see her face—and yes, it was the same person as before, I think.”

Susan leaned back. “Then why are you wandering around alone?! That’s very dangerous. We need to take care of you.”

Virgo grimaced. “I don’t need an escort everywhere now. I do still have the portkey.”

“And a fat lot of good that did you.”

Virgo glared. “It was just a mistake on my part. If I’d been more careful I’d have been able to use it. I won’t be caught out like that again.”

“Either way, you shouldn’t be here. Come with me. I’m taking you to John.” Susan grabbed Virgo’s arm and started to drag her.

“Susan, wait!”

“What?”

“I …” Virgo hesitated. What could she do? Say she didn’t want to see John because a part of her felt like she’d never met him before?

Susan’s gaze softened. “What is it, girl? Are you worried about John?”

“No!” Virgo paused. “Okay, maybe a bit.”

“Why?”

Virgo didn’t say anything. A whole host of excuses whipped through her head, but the number one that fought for attention was revealing her new animagus form to the Bones Heiress. That would surely be a good reason to be nervous about meeting John Potter again, but just as soon as the idea presented itself, she rejected it. Even if she had a good reason for having a snake animagus form—her dead blood mother being a Gaunt (something that she wasn’t ecstatic to reveal as it would brand her a bastard)—she hadn’t yet thought up a good excuse for how exactly she had realised that animagus form as a first year.

Then inspiration struck. Virgo bit her lip. “My Mother,” she started, voice dropping to a quaver. “She …”

Susan’s gaze softened again. “She what?”

“She said she wasn’t happy with me. She said that if I didn’t start acting more like a Malfoy, she’d make things very difficult for John.”

“Oh, Virgo.” Susan hugged her again. “You don’t need to worry about that. The Malfoys and Potters are always at each others’ throats. Surely you must know that. She can’t do anything to make John’s life more difficult without getting a bloody nose in turn. She wasn’t threatening you, was she?”

Virgo shook her head.

“Then that’s okay, then. C’mon, let’s go find John. He’ll be dying to know you’re okay.”

As they made their way towards the arena, and even if she was still anxious, Virgo couldn’t quite suppress a small smirk behind Susan’s back.

I am entirely too good at this.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Protego.”

In the middle of the Hogwarts duelling arena, John Potter was feeling extremely anxious.

“Stupefy.”

For the longest time, he’d been desperately trying to get the events of the timeline back on track, and had been miserably unsuccessful at every turn.

“Ventus divinum.”

The events of the other night, though, had rattled him.

“Locomotor wibbly.”

The basilisk was active again. But it wasn’t attacking muggleborns, as it should be, rather it had been his evil twin brother and the Lovegood Heiress who’d been the victims.

“Protego—stupefy—incarcerous.”

Not only that, but Virgo had been attacked too! Despite his promise to protect her. And he’d been helpless to stop them taking her away. Merlin only knew what she’d been through. She was avoiding him now. Did she hate him too, just like Ginny did? Did she think he was useless? Unheroic? Weak? A FRAUD?!

John’s hand, gripping his wand so tightly his knuckles were white, shook. “FULGUR STUPEFY!”

There was a loud crack of electricity, and in the middle of the duelling arena, a fourth year Hufflepuff hit the ground, hard.

“John!” Cedric Diggory stormed over. “Magical Merlin, are you trying to kill him?! Are you even paying attention?!”

John let out a deep breath. Another Hufflepuff was already by his downed opponent, casting basic healing spells over him. “Sorry,” he muttered. “I guess I should take a break.”

“You’re damn right you should take a break. And don’t get back in here until you can keep whatever drama you have in the castle out of the arena!”

“Cedric!” said a familiar voice behind him. “Don’t you think that’s a bit harsh?”

John turned to find Susan, leading an anxious-looking Virgo. It was an odd expression to see on her face, like an abashed dragon. To his great surprise, his heart skipped a beat.

Cedric grumbled something about the princess being found and left to coach some of the third years.

“Virgo,” John breathed. “You’re okay? Right?”

“Yes, I am.” She replied. “I’m sorry for not finding you sooner. I was being foolish.”

“Her mother threatened to hurt you, if she didn’t stop associating with us,” Susan supplied.

Anger flared in John’s gut. “Don’t listen to her, Virgo. I swear, I have nothing to fear from the likes of her. But still …” He looked at his wand in disgust.

“John,” Susan said. “What is it?”

“I can’t let things continue like this,” he said. “It’s too dangerous. We’ve been lucky up to now, but if things continue as they are …” he trailed off.

“John, what are you talking about?”

“I’m not strong enough.” His hands were shaking again. “I’m still not strong enough.”

Susan’s eyes popped. “What are you talking about? You’re one of the most powerful wizards I know! More powerful than even Dumbledore when he was your age. Only Harry compares, and you’re twins.”

“It’s not good enough. There are larger threats out there. Threats I thought I could control—direct—but I can’t.”

“What threats?” Virgo asked, eyes narrowed.

“Are you talking about Lord Slytherin?” Susan hazarded.

“No,” John said, firmly. “Well, Maybe a little. But no, not entirely.”

“Then, who?” Virgo asked.

John said nothing.

“Do your Mum and Dad know about these threats?” Susan asked. “Maybe we should tell them and let them—”

“—No!” John almost shouted, causing several Hufflepuffs waiting on the sidelines to turn and stare. “No,” he said, quieter. “No, I can’t tell them.”

“But you can tell us, can’t you?”

John said nothing again. For the longest time, he just stared at the duelling Hufflepuffs. Eventually he broke his silence. “I need to become stronger. More Powerful. Better at everything I do. I need to win. I can’t lose.”

“John,” Susan said, soothingly. “It doesn’t have to be all up to you, you know. Your Mum and Dad—”

“No.”

John was momentarily surprised that voice saying no wasn’t his own.

Virgo looked between the two of them, eyes cold and hard. “John is right, Susan. While others’ strength is useful, you must always be able to rely on your own power. If John believes he needs to be more powerful, to protect us from some secret danger, then that is something we should encourage. Weakness is never a virtue.”

Susan looked extremely uncertain. “But why can’t he tell us what the danger is?”

Virgo shrugged. “Magic is often shrouded in mystery. Sometimes not saying anything is best until you are fully certain of your path.” She turned to John. “Are you fully certain of your path?”

John shook his head. He couldn’t help but stare at the young witch sat in front of him.

“Then don’t tell us. Wait until you are ready. You can do that, can’t you?”

John found himself unconsciously nodding.

“But, Virgo, what if this secret danger is something to do with your attacker?” Susan protested.

Virgo shifted in her seat. “That’s not impossible, but, well—if I tell you something, will you promise not to get mad?”

John and Susan both nodded.

“I’ve been watching how she moves, and the way she attacks and everything, especially when she duelled Snape, and I think that the one who attacked me might be Ginny Weasley.”

“WHAT!?” John jumped up. “No! That’s impossible! Wait. What do you mean, when Ginny duelled Snape!?”

“Today, during defence class. Snape picked on her to duel, and she held her own against him. She’s a very skilled and powerful witch.”

John fell back on the wooden bench they’d made camp on and stared out across the duelling arena. Ginny trying to kill Virgo? That wasn’t possible. Why would Ginny try to kill Virgo? But, he already knew why. Harry was still convinced Virgo was the diary, wasn’t he? And he’d told Ginny about being from the future. So, could Ginny be trying to kill Virgo because of that? John shook his head. No, it wasn’t possible. If he knew anything about Ginny, it was that she wasn’t a killer. She didn’t have it in her. It just wasn’t part of her nature. But that didn’t actually rule out Harry in other ways.

He waved a dismissive hand. “It’s not Ginny. I know that. But thanks for your support, Virgo. I really appreciate it.” He grinned. “The Malfoys don’t happen to know any rituals that make you stronger, do they?” he added as a joke.

“John!” Susan gasped.

Opposite him, Virgo also stared at the duelling Hufflepuffs, deep in her own thoughts, so she barely processed John’s words when she replied, “Maybe a few.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

A few days past. The rumours surrounding Virgo, Harry, and Luna continued to swirl, but those about Virgo specifically died down as she returned to the day-to-day business of magical education. Harry and Luna’s state though, was cause for much more speculation. Petrification wasn’t a common ailment, and all the things that could cause it tended to be very scary.

All the books that might have anything to do with the subject had been checked out of the library, and a couple of the more unscrupulous students started selling fake anti-petrification charms at the school black(ish)-market.

Even quidditch wasn’t immune. With the Gryffindor—Slytherin match fast approaching, both Oliver Wood and Marcus Flint had been seen haggling over the gourde-looking necklaces with the air of holy pilgrims fighting over the last finger bone in the brightly coloured box.

That was when Fred and George Weasley decided to step in and shut that particular stall down.

There were far better ways of dealing with petrification.

Far away from anti-petrification amateur hour, in the capital city of the Italian peninsula, two wizards in emerald green robes sat around a round table, along-side two-dozen other wizards and witches, listening to a speaker summarise the global mandrake situation.

“And so, we hypothesise that the spread of mandrake-pox—a magical parasite, not unlike Brazilian Strangle Vine, may be an unintended consequence of the recent spike in growth of certain large-scale national ward magics.”

All two dozen figures around the table looked, as one magical, towards the two wizards in emerald green.

“I don’t know what you’re looking at us for,” said Lord Greengrass, blankly. “We do not control the Albion.”

“Quite,” added an amused Lord Lovegood. “And besides, this is only a hypothesis, am I correct? There could be any number of possible causes. I’d say solving the problem is more important than pointing fingers.”

An hour later, both lords left the meeting room in the bowels of the ICW and started the quick march back towards their hotel rooms.

“Can you believe it?” Jacob asked. “Any old excuse, eh?”

“People will hold a grudge until the end of time, my friend. Many still resent the role of Merlin’s greatest work throughout history.”

“Our contact didn’t look very happy to see us there, did he? Hopefully we will hear from him soon.”

They didn’t have to wait long. When they arrived back at their hotel rooms, Jacob found a hastily scrawled note pushed under the crack of his door. “Just an address and a name,” he said.

“Who?”

“Mister Grasso.”

“Where?” Xeno asked.

“Somewhere in Tuscany.”

“Full dragon-hide?”

Lord Jacob Greengrass smirked. “Oh, yes, my friend. I very much think so.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

On a Tuscan hillside, up a small, windy lane, stood a nondescript looking villa, which will now, nevertheless, be described. It was the kind of building to which the word ‘rustic’ could not be properly applied for fear of offending barnyards so tumbledown that horses could eat their fill from outside the building. Any foreign expat using the word ‘quaint’ upon seeing it, would soon be cursing the lack of phone line to call an insulation company, and any insulation company, upon seeing it, would suggest that this wasn’t so much a job for filling in with foam, but rather for building with it.

It was almost impossible that something so decrepit could still be standing by itself without the aid of magic, which of course, was the case.

“Is it just me,” Jacob said, looking at the building they’d just spied around the last corner, “or do all those holes look unnatural?”

“They look pretty natural to me,” Xeno quipped. “Moss growing around the stones—vines growing up the walls.”

“Yes, so why do none of the stones scattered around the holes have moss growing on them?”

They stared at the pile of stones littering the ground in a suspiciously explosion-shaped pattern before a wave of magic washed over them.

“Anti-apparition ward,” Xeno supplied in a cheerful voice, rather unnecessarily so, in Jacob’s opinion.

They both slipped their wands from their holsters.

Around another corner up the road, came four wizards in rather more flamboyish robes than the ones they wore. Not better quality, it should be noted, just louder. None of them were smiling.

“You two,” their apparent leader called. “You are not welcome here, English Wizengamot. Turn around and leave and there will be no violence.”

“Can’t do that, old boy” Xeno called back. “We have a meeting with mister Grasso.”

“Mister Grasso won’t be seeing nobody today.”

“Why’s that?”

“He’s sick.”

Jacob and Xeno exchanged glances.

“So,” Jacob started, “it doesn’t have anything to do with the fact that his house looks like one-hundred-year-old Swiss cheese?”

“You’re not the only one who needs mandrake, Wizengamot. Get ’em!”

All four wizards dashed forward, levelled their wands, and cast whatever hexes or curses they saw fit.

Meanwhile, Xeno slashed his wand in a wide arc, casting a powerful shield over both him and Jacob, while Lord Greengrass muttered under his breath, preparing an incantation of his own.

“Whenever you’re ready, old boy!” Xeno shouted over the hail of spellfire impacting on his shield.

Jacob pointed his wand. “Murus ignis!”

A wave of enchanted fire swept up the winding road, leaping high in the air and surrounding their attackers on all sides. Moments later, transfigured beasts formed from nearby rocks and leapt into the flames, adding snarls and roars to the cacophony of screams emanating from the tightly controlled firestorm.

“Not very good, are they?” Xeno commented. “I don’t know why I even bothered getting dressed.”

“Fire and forget spells have always been the purview of the lazy. Maybe this will teach them not to underestimate the right hand of Lord Slytherin.” He couldn’t keep the ironic drawl out of his voice as he said that last bit.

“I thought your daughter was his right hand.”

“At school, maybe. I don’t think the Wizengamot would appreciate a thirteen-year-old witch lecturing them.”

“You could always be his right foot.”

“Wouldn’t that make you his left foot? Wouldn’t Luna be his left hand?”

“You know, I always thought that feet got a raw deal. They do most of the honest hard work and then hands take all the glory, just because they were born with opposable thumbs.”

The screams coming from the fire-storm started to shift from expressions of terror and medium pain, to full-on skin-melting torture.

Jacob grimaced. “I guess I should do something about that.”

Thirty minutes later, the four wizarding thugs had provided all the information they knew about their unknown employer’s plans for Mister Grasso. It wasn’t much information, but it was enough to make inquiries. Fresh mandrake was currently in very short supply, and those who knew how to get it were in extremely high demand—high enough demand, apparently, to warrant full-on kidnap and extortion.

“I’d feel much happier about this if we had another foot to help,” Jacob said when they got back to their hotel room. “Things could get messy from here on.”

“Smith?” Xeno asked. “He’s pretty handy in a fight—I mean footy. Or Tempest? Of course, having Black would be favourite.”

“Sirius Black would make a useful third foot, but that’s up to Harry. He’s the man with the plan there.”

There was a pause.

Then, “If Alexandra is the bridge between Slytherin and Lord Black, wouldn’t that make her Slytherin’s third leg?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It was the weekend. And it was early morning.

In the Slytherin common room, Draco Malfoy watched Alexandra Black. She was casually slouched in his old chair, taking no heed to the convention that a witch of noble birth should present herself with the dignity and decorum proper to her station, watching an older Slytherin boy, who was standing in front of the two courts—Dark and Gray—complaining about the behaviour of some random Gryffindor girl. At least, Draco was watching the Black heiress, until the name ‘Malfoy’ was dropped. That focused his attention faster than the word ‘suitor’ would for a roomful of seventh-year witches.

“She’s been acting a lot more aggressively since coming back,” the boy said. “She appears to have developed quite a temper.”

“And when did this start?” asked Daphne Greengrass, presiding at the head of the Gray court, to the right of the still-empty Slytherin throne.

“Maybe on Wednesday? Isabel and I were discussing family matters with Rupert Holland from Ravenclaw outside the library when Malfoy turns up and just hexes the both of us out of nowhere.”

“No provocation?”

“None!” The boy paused for a second. “Well, we did have Rupert down on the floor, oozing quite badly, but it was a family matter. We told Malfoy so.”

Alexandra Black snorted. “Just like a Gryffindor to go around sticking their nose in other people’s business.”

Despite himself, Draco winced.

Greengrass smiled wryly. “It sounds to me, like a failing in education. But what can you expect from a house that mistakes a powerful witch for a squib? An uncouth and dangerous girl who plays hero by beating people up.”

“Hardly a hero!” the older boy butted in. “After she was done with us, she turned on Rupert! ‘Why are you weak!?’ she yelled at him. ‘I hate weak people.’ When she was finished, Rupert was worse off than I or Isabell.”

Interestingly, Greengrass didn’t look surprised. Instead she looked thoughtful. “And now our Miss Malfoy is aggressively prank-hexing every Slytherin she sees if she thinks she can get away with it,” she mused. “Hmm …”

Draco rhythmically rubbed his temples with the tips of his fingers. He dearly wished he could tell Black that Virgo was a spy. If you knew that, what was going on was so obvious. Virgo was establishing a position of respect and power within the Light. By publicly making an enemy of the Dark (and many of the Gray too), she signalled her willingness to fight the side she secretly served, as well as her separation from her family, rallying those who might be on the fence to her side.

Although the aggressive nature of the move was somewhat puzzling, Draco thought. Ever since he’d had first met his little sister, Virgo had given off an air of quiet menace—of coiled power ready to strike, held back only by her unwillingness to acknowledge, in those she dealt with, even the possible hint of a threat. Lashing out like the older boy was describing did indeed feel less Slytherin and more Gryffindor.

Alexandra had the right of that, at least.

Draco looked to where the Black and Greengrass heiresses were now arguing about what was to be done. Somehow, he had to guide this situation to Virgo’s best interests without appearing to do so. His future as Alexandra’s right hand depended on it. Now that he wasn’t obviously on top, there were plenty of others who’d love to take that position away from him. He then glanced to where the Carrow twins sat attentively on either side of Black—not on the couches, like normal people, but happily draped out on the floor, as though they were concubines in a sultan’s harem. Draco grimaced. If he could keep his status without swearing himself to Alexandra’s service for the rest of his school days, that would be a rather nice bonus.

He was jerked out of his musings by the name ‘Malfoy’ once again surfacing in the debate.

“I’m telling you, Greengrass, there’s no good reason not to let Malfoy take care of his little sister. This is obviously a family matter and that’s how we do things here.” Alexandra smirked. “Or is the Gray too Light to remember the importance of family?”

“Bold words coming from the daughter of a Light family,” Greengrass counted in an amused voice. “Especially one who is only heiress because there is no legitimate claimant.”

Black narrowed her eyes. “How I am heiress is no matter. What matters is that I am. Far more so than you, Greengrass, who is only heiress until your little sister resets her noble house ring. Why hasn’t she yet, by the way? Are Mummy and Daddy afraid she’s not up to the task?”

“Astoria will take up her responsibilities in all due course, but maybe you should keep your nose out of other people’s family matters.” Greengrass smirked. “That is, after all, how we do things here. Or are you too Light to remember the importance of family?”

Alexandra snarled before she froze and her face flashed triumphant. “Oh! So you do agree with me. Excellent! Malfoy”—she turned towards him.—“I need you to—”

“—Hold on!” Greengrass interrupted. “That is not what I meant.”

“Well, what would you do about our Virgo problem?”

“I would let the person best capable of dealing with it sort it out when he’s feeling better—Mister Potter.”

Alexandra rolled her eyes. “Of course the princess would want to hide like a little girl behind her betrothed’s personal attack gopher. For a moment, I thought you might show some balls and handle it yourself.”

“Mister Potter is the best wizard for the job. And don’t use that word. It is unbecoming of a lady.”

Alex sniffed. “I will use whatever words I like. And Potter’s not here. Heir Malfoy is. And I’m not going to listen to a stuck-up princess who fights like a girl.”

Black had made her opinion on Greengrass’s performance against Volf the previous year quite plain.

Greengrass glared. “And I will not deal with some uncouth bastard who forgets she’s a girl.”

BAM!

It all happened so quickly that Draco barely had time to react. Wands were drawn, spells cast, and students screamed and jumped away on both sides. Black had been the first off the mark, with Greengrass and Granger not far behind. Flint, Bole, Pucey, and Harper were next, followed by just about every other wizard and witch with the presence of mind to jump into the fray.

Being the first to pull her wand had made Black the first target, but, incredibly, most of the spells fired at her just didn’t seem to find a mark.

The short-burst exchange between Greengrass and Black, by contrast, was so smooth—so quick—and so on point—that if Draco didn’t know better, he’d have thought it choreographed.

By the time he’d gotten his own wand out and pointed at Granger (the most politically safe target, as far as he was concerned), Black had already hoisted Greengrass into the air by her wrists with her chains, leaving the leader of the Gray to dangle, writhing, helpless and wandless.

There was a sudden stillness as no spells were being cast and everyone had a wand pointed at everyone else and no one wanted to be the first to break that stillness.

“Okay! That’s enough, I think!” Black announced, her wand still trained on Greengrass. “I have two Ladies, a vassal, and two wands. Care to raise and go another round?”

Off to the side, Tracey Davis, who was also being held at wand point, muttered something about that not being how poker worked.

Greengrass glared daggers at Black. “When my lord finds out about this …”

Black scoffed. “Yes? What will Slytherin do? Swoop in to punish me for hexing his girlfriend? Can the princess not take care of herself? He duelled Volf because Volf was going to seriously injure you. I’m just going to have a little pranking fun.” She giggled, and for a brief moment, Draco couldn’t help but be reminded of the memories his father had shown him of his aunt Bellatrix. Alex brandished her wand again. “I got this one from Draco.”

Certain he must have misheard that last bit, Draco’s mind flashed to the only prank spell he’d recently shared with Alexandra—the one that turned a witch’s hair the same colour as their knickers. He gazed with a kind of horrified fascination as his cousin gleefully shouted the incantation and shot the spell towards the girl who most in their community had genuinely come to see as a kind of untouchable princess, right in front of a room full of people.

The spell hit, and Greengrass’s long, smooth, blond hair instantly turned pastel pink. A large white bow sprouted on the top.

“Huh,” Alex said. “Wasn’t expecting that. I’d have thought green and silver or something.”

For a moment, Draco thought Greengrass was actually going to cry, before he realised that the shaking and trembling he was seeing was not of shame and embarrassment, but of pure undistilled rage.

“WHAT IS GOING ON HERE?” Roared a voice.

Everyone turned to the portrait door to find Severus Snape, standing there, staring at all the many wands pointed at everyone, looking furious.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The weak winter morning gave way to an equally weak afternoon. Many chose to stay inside, but for the insane few, the cold was the perfect opportunity to train, all day, without anyone interrupting them.

On the Hogwarts quidditch pitch, a thin red and gold blur, starting high in the sky, tipped forward, and started a breakneck dive towards the perfectly manicured grass below. Spinning over and over as it went, as though circling an imaginary mirror image, it bottomed out a good several meters above the ground and soared back up into the sky.

It was deep, but not deep enough, and it was fast, but not fast enough.

“John!” bellowed a voice.

John Potter groaned.

“What are you playing at!?” Oliver wood shouted as he brought his broomstick level with his. “I don’t need my star seeker injuring himself barely a week before the big match!”

“You don’t understand,” John said. “I have to practice. I have to be better—better at everything.”

“You can be better at everything after you’ve helped us win the match! Was that a Wronski feint you were trying!?”

“So what if it was?”

“What in Merlin’s name do you think you’ll need that move for? Do you hate the Slytherin seeker that much?”

John glared at Wood. “This has nothing to do with Ginny. It’s just about being the best. And you don’t have to worry so. Ginny is good, but she’s not that good. Trust me, I know.”

“Do you now?” asked Fred, identifiable by the massive F on his sweater.

“I wasn’t even aware that our dear little sister knew how to fly at all,” George added, as they both dropped into the mid-air huddle. “Was right surprised when she turned up on their team. But that’s our Slytherin sister. Cunning little thing.”

“Probably out practising at the dead of night while everyone was asleep.”

“What can you tell us about her style?” Katie asked. It seemed everyone had decided to take a last break for the training session.

“Yeah,” Alicia added, while Angelina nodded emphatically on her broom. “Spill the beans.”

John quickly gathered his thoughts and memories from before he came back. “Ginny is an extremely team-focused seeker,” he said. “She’ll play cautiously whenever the enemy team is ahead, and look for the snitch only when there’s a chance to win. She prefers playing support while chasing and will always throw the quaffle with plenty of time left on the shocker. I’ve never known her to work with beaters to knobble enemy chasers, so we shouldn’t have to worry there, but she does like to misdirect her throws, which she is very good at.”

Wood grunted. “So, a defensive trickster. Easy enough to deal with. Just keep up the aggression and don’t fall into obvious traps. Now, get back to practice—and John, I don’t want to see any more insane moves, got it?”

Half an hour later, John emerged from the quidditch boys shower rooms to find Virgo. He found her reading intensely, hidden under the bleachers of one of the tall spectator towers. For some reason, she was wearing a large white bow in her hair.

“Ready to go?” He asked cheerfully.

Virgo practically jumped out of her skin. “Don’t do that!” She glared. “Yes, I’m ready.”

“Found anything yet?”

Virgo closed the library book she’d been reading. “There are hundreds of known rituals, but most of them are not worth it. Selecting a few choice ones will take time and patience, and getting hold of the requirements will be even more taxing.”

He flashed her a charming smile. “Any that will help me in quidditch?” He was almost sure that her cheeks reddened slightly.

“There’s one that increases your general balance, but it’s incredibly dangerous.”

“How dangerous?”

“One in five people who try it, die.”

“That sounds dangerous.”

They made their way up the grounds to the castle, up the many staircases towards Gryffindor Tower. His thoughts drifted back to Ginny, and to Virgo’s outrageous suggestion that she might be the one trying to murder her. But that wasn’t possible. Ginny didn’t have the diary. But with the basilisk possibly active, it was clear that someone must have it. The question was who?

“Virgo!”

Oh, John thought. Here comes likely suspect number one.

Draco Malfoy was coming up the corridor behind them, doing his best not to show just how much he’d been huffing to keep up with them.

“Brother?” Virgo said. John couldn’t help notice a slight lilt in her voice, as though she wasn’t quite sure how she should react to him.

“Potter,” Malfoy acknowledged him, finally catching them up. For some reason, the Malfoy heir then spent several seconds staring at the white bow in Virgo’s hair before turning back to him. “I need to have a private word with my sister here.”

John immediately crossed his arms. “Anything you need to say can be said in front of me.”

Malfoy cursed “Do you know how infuriating you can be?”

John smirked. “I pride myself on it. Now, what do you want?”

“Has it not occurred to you that this could be a family matter?”

“Is it?”

“Not as such …”

“Then get on with it.”

Malfoy cursed again.

Virgo was just looking between him and her brother with an unreadable expression on her face.

After cursing him out one last time, Malfoy turned to Virgo and in a voice that dripped formality said, “I have been sent on behalf of Hogwarts Slytherin house to request that you stop hexing us in the corridors. Your power has been acknowledged and the house as a whole recognises that you are not a squib. Will that satisfy you, sister?”

Virgo looked him up and down before smiling. “For now, dear brother.”

Malfoy looked like he’d swallowed a lemon, but did nod before turning to go.

John finished escorting Virgo back into the tower. “Hexing Slytherins?” he asked with a shit-eating grin.

Virgo flashed him a coy smile. “They were asking for it.”

“By the way, I think that bow looks very pretty on you.”

“Thank you.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

As Draco Malfoy headed back to the Slytherin Dungeons, another prominent member of the student Dark, in fact, one might say the predominantmember, was nervously making her way into the Slytherin second-year girl’s dormitory, careful not to be seen by anyone. Sitting by one of the large four-poster beds—the one covered in books so deep it was like a fortress—was a trunk. The first-year girl tiptoed over to the trunk, knocked a pattern on the lid, opened the lid, and climbed inside. At the far end of the expanded trunk, a lone female figure at a desk, with long blond hair, was stabbing away at a parchment. In front of the figure was a propped-open book titled Transfiguration Theory: The Lies and Lies.

“Um … Daphne?” said the newly arrived girl.

“Yes, Alexandra?” she said. The figure did not look around, but Alex could see the tension in her shoulders.

“You’re not … you’re not mad, right?”

“Mad?” Daphne put down her quill. To Alexandra’s ears, the sound it produced as it was rested on the desk was as loud as a trunk being dropped. “You mean mad for being exposed in front of all those boys without warning?” Daphne asked. “Mad about being sniggered at behind my back all day? Mad about every Dark witch in Slytherin, and even some from the other houses too, wearing white bows in their hair and blowing pastel pink bubbles from their wands whenever I walk past? Mad about all that?” She turned in her chair to face her visitor. “No. I’m not mad at all. Why would I be mad?”

Alex winced. “I know we said a simple pranking spell would do, but what you said about me forgetting I’m a girl, well, it kinda hurt. You know I wish we had more choice in our lives. I’m doing my best and I may have gotten a bit too into it. I’m sorry.”

Daphne sighed and turned around again, patting the seat next to her.

Alex sat down.

Daphne picked up her parchment and scanned it, as if looking for possible mistakes. “If I’d have had more warning,” she said. “I’d have worn plain white.”

“Sorry.”

“On the positive side, I doubt anyone will doubt our mutual antagonism now. The idea that you might secretly be a Gray spy would seem ludicrous.” Daphne picked up her quill again. “I’m sorry about pushing those buttons, Alex. I know they’re sore spots for you.”

Daphne scratched away a bit more.

“I’m a bit jealous of you, you know,” Alex said eventually.

“Jealous?”

“You’re just so accepting of everything—so calm and cool all the time. I wish I could be like that. You were betrothed before we even got to school, but you don’t let that phase you at all.”

Daphne cracked a small smile. “That’s only because of who I was betrothed to. And that was just luck … and kindness. It could so easily have been very different.” Daphne fell silent.

“He’ll be back soon,” Alex said softly.

“I know.”

—End of Chapter Fifty—

Chapter End Notes

A/N: I was originally intending for this chapter to be the last of the arc, but it was not to be. There will be a part four :P If you enjoy my work, please consider checking out my original projects. All support is appreciated. You can find the links through my website www.leadvone.com.

A/N: This chapter was drafted and made available early through the LeadVonE discord server, as will the next one. If you fancy discussing this chapter with like-minded people, or anything else DP&SW, feel free to head over there.

Also, as an experiment, I edited this chapter live on twitch, a few hours before publication, which I’m told people enjoyed a lot. My twitch handle, for anyone interested, is leadvone.

A special thank you to the following people for helping catch mistakes on #dpasw-editorial: aarabdht, ASK, Caelwyn, ChRiAn, Dragonbait, drakonpie250, feauxen, Fuuryuu, Grimjaw, JaydenStevenson, jgabriele, MageKing17, Magic Bird Dust, RaphtaliaBestGirl, Salty_sauce, sfu, Sumguy, Tendra, TrendyTreky, Turtle King of Fear,

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2019’s prices.

Soul Anchors—Part Four

“Welcome, witches and wizards! To the second quidditch match of the year! I’m your commentator—Lee Jordan—and this is Gryffindor vs Slytherin!”

A wave of cheers swept across the stands. Hundreds of students waved banners, flew flags, or showed off their charm skills with animated lions and snakes. Even the Hufflepuffs and Ravenclaws pledged their allegiance to one or other of the teams, at least for the event.

“History in the making, Hogwarts! Last year, Gryffindor fielded the youngest seeker in a century, our very own ‘Boy-Who-Lived’ and duelling phenom, John Potter—and this year, Slytherin will match them with their own first-year seeker! A fierce duellist in her own right and the first witch on the Slytherin quidditch team in twelve years—Ginny Weasley!”

The air carried a nip that fought against even the older year’s warming charms. The previous night hadn’t seen a cloud in the sky, leaving the grass crisp with frost and the breath of students foggy. The crowd was a roiling sea of thick, long robes and cloaks, with the occasional muggle winter jacket thrown in.

“And here come the Slytherin team!”

Another round of cheers sounded out.

In the Gryffindor vomitorium, John Potter held his Nimbus 2001 clenched in a fist.

They would start cheering him soon. They always did. They always did, and, until this year, he’d always loved it. He knew those cheers were supposed to be supportive, but given everything that had happened, the weight of their expectations now felt more of a rock than a balm. Twice, he’d publicly stepped up to the plate since coming back in time, and twice he’d failed—first at the last quidditch match, when he’d accidentally won the match for Slytherin by catching the snitch in his mouth—and then second at the duelling tournament when Harry had been ready to beat him, if Dumbledore hadn’t sprung his trap to send Harry to Azkaban in time to save him—a trap, which hadn’t even worked, despite putting him in hospital.

A tendril of guilt about that whole affair wormed its way into his head before he firmly crushed it. He couldn’t afford to be weak. There was too much riding on it. Virgo was right. He needed to be strong. He needed to be powerful. He needed to stop losing.

“And now, here comes the Gryffindor team! Wood, Spinet, Johnson, Bell, Weasley, Weasley, and Potter!”

The cheers rang in his ears as he walked onto the pitch. John Potter—the Boy Who Lived—the fake—the fraud—the chosen of Fate and Death—and now, the one who was always losing.

“Ready to lose, Potter?”

It took every ounce of self control not to wince at the words. Ginny Weasley, wearing green robes and a smirk, stood opposite him with arms folded while Flint and Wood looked like they were trying to break each other’s fingers.

“Lose, little sister?” Fred Weasley asked from beside him with a raised eyebrow.

“Isn’t it you who should be ready to lose?” George added.

“Don’t think we’ll go easy on you—”

“—Just because you’re our dear little sister.”

John took a deep breath. He narrowed his eyes. “I will not lose. I cannot lose.”

Ginny actually looked momentarily surprised by the force in his words before her smirk became a grin. “Good, Potter,” she said. “Then I won’t need to hold back.” And for just a second, John thought he saw a flash of his own Ginny buried deep in the Slytherin facade that stood before him now. That flash died a second later though, replaced again by the cold smirk, and his thoughts passed over the rumours he’d heard in the last week—that Ginny had duelled Snape in defence class, and that she hadn’t been found wanting, at least in a very limited duel. At first, he’d dismissed the claims out of hand—Ginny was never that good—but after Virgo had started pouring over all those possible rituals with him—rituals with terrible costs, but which might improve someone’s fighting prowess by a little, or a lot—doubt had stirred.

It could explain Ginny’s abilities, and, more importantly, it could explain Harry’s.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“There’s the signal!” the commentator shouted.

Game time. Ginny pushed off hard. The biting cold air whipped her hair, chilling her ears and fingers. Adrenaline, already coursing through her veins, kicked up a notch.

“The snitch is released!”

The briefest flash of gold zipped in front of her face before it did a round pass of Potter and vanished off across the grounds.

“The seekers line up for the quaffle!”

Madam hooch held up the round ball and glared at them both. “I want a nice clean game. No knobbling.”

Potter nodded, while Ginny merely grinned.

Hooch then threw the ball high in the air, she and Potter raced towards it, and moments later, John’s stomach connected with her shoulder. Potter let out an ‘Umph!’ as the air was forcibly expelled. Not looking back, she snatched the quaffle and was off in a flash.

“And the bludgers are released!”

She then had to immediately dodge one of the charmed canon balls zooming right past her, before Tamaron smashed it towards Wood. She laughed. Compared to what she was used to while training, that had been almost cute. Everything moved so slow. It was as though the rest of the world was made of treacle, and she was a red-hot knife, slicing through it like a flame-whip through ice.

Together, she, Draco, Flint, and Bole powered through a hastily constructed defensive formation, leaving her free to score the first ten points of the game.

“Weasley scores!”

The crowd went wild.

Her brothers gaped at her. Not surprising, really. If it felt easy, how must it look?

Draco high-fived her. “Not bad, Blood-traitor!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Slytherin Scores, again! 20—0!”

John shook himself in disbelief. Ginny moved like a lightning bolt. It was as if she simply went from point A to point B without passing through the air in between. That was silly, of course. She wasn’t actually doing that—but it sure felt like it.

“Potter goes for the intercept! Misses!”

His only reward was a smirk before she rolled under her broom and zoomed off again, dangling underneath her broom like an unsloth-like sloth, passing the quaffle to Malfoy just a gnat’s breath before the shock charm would have kicked in, allowing the pure-blood heir to easily punt it through the middle hoop.

“30—0!”

The groans from the Gryffindor side sounded like hot lead poured into John’s stomach.

He gritted his teeth. This Ginny was far too aggressive and far too good! It was like she wasn’t even the same person as before. Ginny had always been an acceptable quidditch player, but this was like playing against a young Victor Krum!

“John!” Wood bellowed. His captain pulled up beside him. “I thought you said she was a defensive player!”

“She’s changed!” John shouted back. They had to shout to hear each other over the crowd. “This isn’t anything like I expected!”

“Then we’ll have to make changes to our strategy! Katie! Angelina! Switch to Reginald’s Defence. Fred and George, switch priority from assist to disruption! We’ll play a cautious point exchange and then hope to win the seeker duel!”

John’s teammates all nodded and rushed up to their new positions, leaving him and Wood alone together. Wood looked him square the eye. “No pressure, John, but when the time comes, you absolutely must win this for us. They’re too good for us to win an extended quaffle fight, so get that snitch or die trying.”

John nodded.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Gryffindor scores! But Slytherin still leads 90—20! Are we seeing the birth of a legend here today?!”

Under the thick wood of the quidditch stands crouched a slight figure in expensive robes—crouched such that no one would see it unless they knew exactly what they were looking for and exactly where to look.

“Flint to Draco! Passes to Weasley! Bludger!”

The crowd gasped.

“Merlin! If she weren’t so good at dodging I’d think they were trying to kill their own sister!”

The figure shifted and a crack of light from the stadium outside shined on its face to reveal the young face of the new Virgo Malfoy. She was shaking.

“Slytherin score again! And Weasley breaks off to hunt the snitch! Wow, this is aggressive! Gryffindor have an opportunity to catch up now, but the gap is large!”

Virgo wrung her hands together. It had all been so easy when she was just thinking about it. But now that she was here, it was proving far more difficult than she’d imagined.

“Gryffindor score! 100—30! Weasley has seventy more points of freedom!”

She knew it was wrong. Killing. She knew it instinctively. But what choice did she have? It was life or death. Kill or be killed. She knew that instinctively, too. Anyone in her position who thought otherwise was a fool. John wasn’t going to help her—not like he was now. And she had no proof of a conspiracy. So she could only rely on herself. One thing she knew more than anything else, though—she did not want to die. Death. The idea terrified her—more than anything she’d ever considered. Death. Dying. Becoming nothing.

She was sure it was Ginny Weasley who was trying to kill her and had only become more sure as time went on. This was a perfect chance—a chance she might never get again.

“Gryffindor score! 100—40!”

Virgo clenched her fists and took a deep breath. It was now or never. She whispered, “Dobby.”

It took several seconds before the house-elf popped into being beside her. “Miss?” he asked in his high pitched voice.

“Shh!” Virgo urgently held a finger to her lips.

Dobby’s eyes widened. He grabbed his long ears and pulled them down around his face. “Miss?” he said again, this time in a whisper.

“Dobby,” Virgo began in a whisper of her own. “Tell me, is your magic strong enough to overcome the charms on the bludgers?”

Dobby nodded. “Most house-elfs could, Miss, but Dobby is not just being most house-elfs.”

“You could guide them to attack and kill a specific player?”

Dobby looked at Virgo with his bulbous eyes and nodded enthusiastically. “Oh yes, Miss. Dobby can attack and kill, Miss. Dobby is a free house-elf.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Gryffindor score! 100—50!”

There! Floating high in the sky, Ginny spotted a flash of gold, executed a ninety-degree barreled turn, and pelted down the pitch, feeling almost disappointed that it was going to be this easy.

“She’s seen it!” Lee shouted.

The crowd roared.

The snitch flittered from point to point in front of her, speeding up faster and faster as she approached closer and closer. She stretched out a hand.

“Is this it?!”

Then, out of nowhere, her senses screamed at her to move. Or rather, it would be more true to say that she moved first, and only afterwards did her brain receive the report from her senses telling it that they had decided to coordinate directly with her spinal column on the logic that it was better to ask for forgiveness rather than permission when the alternative was receiving a bone-shattering collision with a bludger moving several times the normal rate.

The snitch disappeared and the crowd let out a collective groan or relieved sigh depending on which side they were supporting.

Righting herself, Ginny cursed. That had been close. What on Earth had been up with that bludger?

“Ginny!” shouted a warning voice that she recognised as one of her twin brothers. She turned around, just in time to register the same bludger, still travelling at the same stupid speed heading straight for her, again.

She didn’t even think twice. She raced to gain height and started sweeping the sky—standard procedure for shaking bludgers, and so-called because it looked like the player was trying to clean the sky with their broom.

It didn’t work.

The bludger just circled and came barrelling for her again. Again she dodged, this time by only a finger. A small smile crept across her face.

“Tamaron! Hazlett!” Flint shouted. “Get that thing off her!”

“We’re trying!” Tamaron shouted back, giving the bludger a powerful swing with his bat, but which might as well have been a foam staff for all the effect it was having.

“Don’t bother!” Ginny called out, dodging again with a single spin on her broom as though it were a gymnast’s bar.

“You sure, Weasley?” Flint called back from below.

“Positive!” Ginny grinned and expanded her senses out as far as they could go. “Just keep us ahead as long as possible! I’ll deal with this!”

“Ginny!” Fred called out.

“You can’t be serious!” George added.

“Just play!” Then she spun around and raced up the pitch.

Her predicament had not gone unnoticed.

“I say!” Lee Jordan’s voice boomed across the stadium. “That bludger should not be doing that! Isn’t there some rule about that, Professor? No? Okay, Professor McGonagall informs me that apparently when bludgers go insane the game continues unless one side gives up. Is that really a rule? Really? Huh. You learn something new every day. And it doesn’t look like either side is going to give up—not even with the Weasley twins shouting at the Gryffindor captain—nope, Wood’s not having any of it.”

Ginny could feel the bludger’s magic swirling around inside it whenever it got close—powerful magic, demonic even—but it wasn’t actually that difficult to avoid now she’d got the hang of it. Sweep from side-to-side, feel the directional intent, then dodge at the last moment. She started scanning the pitch again for the snitch while another part of her mind started working on the likely suspects for this little stunt.

It was only because she was so familiar with the exact magic that was performed next that she was able to dodge by such a tiny margin that she actually lost several strands of long red hair. The bludger was behind her when she felt an almost lightning bolt crack of magic arc through the air and arrive in front of her. She’d already been banking left when the bludger appeared, out of thin air, at the position the magic had indicated, and zoomed right at her. For anyone watching it would have looked like the bludger had just teleported, accelerated from a dead still to almost half its ‘normal’ speed, and Ginny had nevertheless still dodged it.

Over three-hundred people were watching.

“Merlin!” Lee Jordan cursed.

That wasn’t the last time the bludger teleported.

An almost manic shit-eating grin was permanently plastered on Ginny’s face. She was starting to recognise this feeling. It was the feeling she got just before she’d taken on the diary. It was the feeling she got during the phoenix ash heist. It was the feeling of being able to pick out every individual muscle in her heart contracting in rhythm. It was the unnatural blueness of the sky and the greener than green vividness of the grass. She spotted a snowbeetle flying in mid-air, less than a foot from her face, and could make out every beat of its beautiful crystal wings—or at least, she could, for about half a second, before it got splattered by the speeding, teleporting canon ball.

She dodged that one by pointing her broomstick up and throwing herself around the shaft.

“Gryffindor score! 100—60!”

But she really did need to look out for the snitch.

Wait a minute!

Off in the distance, Ginny spotted a glint of gold. It took only a flick of her foot to point her broom in the right direction and urge it forward. The bludger disappeared behind her, but she didn’t feel any teleporting magic. Seconds later, she’d caught up with the snitch. She reached out her hand.

And again, her senses screamed at her that she’d already moved.

The snitch sped off and disappeared.

Ginny looked around sharply to locate the bludger, but couldn’t see it.

She frowned.

“Close one there!” shouted Lee Jordan. “Weasley almost had it!”

Her senses screamed at her again, but this time she’d been ready, consciously moving out of the way in time to avoid … nothing—nothing except the wind-rush of flying death zooming right past her face. Her eyes widened in realisation.

The bludger was now invisible.

But no worries. Her magic sensing gave her an advantage there. So long as she knew she couldn’t trust her eyes it wasn’t that big a problem. This was definitely getting difficult, but it wasn’t anything she couldn’t handle.

“Weasley!” Marcus Flint bellowed from somewhere above her. “We’ve lost the other Bludger!”

Well, shit.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Up in the top stands, holding the skirt of her robes in a white-knuckled death grip, Hermione stared at the darting shape high in the air. At times Ginny would dive. At other times she’d spin. And yet other times she’d fix her broomstick in place and frantically fling herself around the shaft, as though she were a muggle on a gymnast’s high bar or a dancer’s pole. The net effect was of a green and silver fly dodging two flailing invisible hands.

What was going on? Hermione thought. What magic could take over the bludgers like this? It would have to be strong—abnormally strong.

All around her, students were talking excitedly among each other—each of them asking the same question. It was obvious something bizarre was going on, and the quicker had cottoned on to the fact that both bludgers were now hidden and targeting the Slytherin seeker.

The only likely candidates, as far as Hermione could figure, would be a very powerful wizard like Dumbledore or Voldemort. But last year, even the Dark Lord had struggled to take control of John Potter’s broom in the middle of the match, and that was with eye contact. Whoever was behind this had made the bludgers invisible, completely removing that way to channel—and they were succeeding in overpowering two bludgers at the same time!

“Daphne,” Hermione began, uneasiness permeating her voice.

“Yes?” came the terse reply. Daphne was staring up at the spectacle with narrowed eyes.

“You don’t think it could be her?”

“If it is, then she must have some help.” Neither needed to say who the her in question was. “I think even our lord would have difficulty pulling this off alone. Where is she? Can you see her?”

It took Hermione several seconds to spot the new Malfoy. “There!” she declared. “In the Hufflepuff stands—next to Bones. She doesn’t look like she’s doing anything.”

Daphne frowned. “I hope it’s not Dumbledore.”

“I wish Harry were here!”

“Me too.”

“What are we going to do?”

“If the teachers aren’t going to intervene, then you should get down there. You’re training as a healer. It’s the perfect excuse.”

“Oh! Right! Of course!” Hermione jumped up and almost tripped over herself in her rush down the steps.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Slytherin are still leading, 110—80,” Lee Jordan’s voice boomed out across the stadium. “But the gap is closing rapidly! Is Slytherin about to lose their amazing first-century lead? And will Miss Weasley be able to keep dodging those things?! I mean—MERLIN! That one was close!”

Up in the top box, Lady Lily Potter’s fuming face was as red as her hair. “Headmaster, we must do something!”

Lockhart chuckled. “Now, now, Lily. Minerva seems quite happy to let play continue. If our dear transfiguration professor sees nothing wrong then who are we to contradict her?”

“In my experience, Headmaster,” came the silky voice of Severus Snape from beside her, “Professor McGonagall—level-headed woman though she may otherwise be—does have a tendency to lose her sense of perspective when it comes to quidditch.”

Lily shot her once-estranged childhood-friend a look of appreciation. Although she didn’t want to admit it, everything was starting to get a bit too much for her. The new job, the attacks on Virgo Malfoy, the business with Virgo’s brother in the forbidden forest, the terrible shock of finding Harry and Luna petrified in the hospital wing from another unknown attacker, and now this—she honestly didn’t know what she’d do without him.

Lockhart seemed to take Severus’ words a bit more seriously than her own, before he shrugged them off too. “Little Miss Weasley is doing fine! Look at her! Isn’t she amazing? Why, I dare say she comes close to my own skills when I were a lad. That was before I dropped my training to dedicate myself to fighting against the dark arts, naturally, but—Oh! Look! Here comes Minerva, right now.”

Lily looked around to see an irate Professor McGonagall climbing the stairs to the top box, three at a time. “Disillusionment charms!” she shrieked. “That’s not quidditch! We must find who’s doing it and stop them!”

“And you wouldn’t consider the possibility of just stopping the game, would you?” Snape drawled.

“Stop the game?” McGonagall looked as though Severus had asked her to close Hogwarts. “Don’t be silly—you don’t stop quidditch. But disillusionment charms are not quidditch, and we bloody well will stop that! Headmaster!”

Lockhart didn’t even skip a beat. “Of course, we must help! Miss Weasley is in danger!” He looked around the professors who had all turned at this proclamation. “Septima, Bathsheda, and Irma, would you go and search the student stands? Lily and Severus, I’m sure you can handle the storage rooms, and Filius, could you take on the changing rooms? Topsy!”

A house-elf popped in front of him. “Yes, Headmaster?”

“Be a good chap and find out who’s doing that, will you?” He pointed to the still frantically darting figure of Ginny Weasley.

“Yes, Headmaster, Sir!” The house-elf popped away.

“And alert the ghosts, too!” he called into empty air.

Lily was already halfway down the stairs before she turned back. “And don’t forget to check the wards, Headmaster!”

Lockhart grimaced, focused, and smiled brightly. “Nothing out of the ordinary! And now! It is time for the hero of the hour to save the fair maiden!”

Lily barely had time to consider exactly what Lockhart meant by that statement before he’d reached into his pocket, withdrawn a shrunken broomstick, expanded it, and mounted up.

“Don’ ye interfere with the game!” McGonagall shrieked as he zipped past and up into the air.

“Worry not!” Lockhart’s fading voice called back. “For I am Gilderoy Lockhart!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

At first, John couldn’t believe his luck. One of the bludgers had gone mental and focused only on Ginny. But then, as they’d closed the gap in points, his elation had given way to worry. Something wasn’t right here. Bludgers shouldn’t act like that, and now they’d gone invisible. Ginny was good—amazingly good—but even she’d start to tire soon. She was a girl after all.

“Ginny!” he called out.

“Sod off, Potter!”

“You can’t keep that up forever!”

“Watch me!”

“You need help!”

Ginny suddenly turned direction and John found her right next to him. “Okay, help me then.” She was smirking.

John had only a moment to process what she’d done before he felt a whoosh through his hair and he instinctively knew he’d been only a few inches away from having his skull caved in. He quickly backed off. “Ginny, what the hell! That was dangerous!”

Ginny looked at him like he was stupid, even as she flipped upside down on her broomstick to avoid another attack. “Of course it was dangerous.” Dive, dodge, spin. “That’s the point.”

“But this is insane!”

Ginny just laughed.

“Headmaster?!” shouted a female voice behind him.

John looked around to find a rather put-out Madam Hooch flagging down Gilderoy Lockhart. “What are you—?”

“Not to worry Rolanda,” Lockhart said in his ever-present jovial voice. I’ll keep an eye on Miss Weasley here. Don’t worry! I know the rules. I won’t interfere in the game. I just feel that we could use an extra layer of precaution here.” He winked at her. “And if things really get sticky, then I, Gilderoy Lockhart, will take out those pesky bludgers.” Hooch huffed, but did back off with an acknowledging wave of her whistle.

Lockhart then turned to him.

“Don’t you worry, John, my boy.” Lockhart gave him a wink too. “I’ll take care of Miss Weasley. You focus on the game.”

John nodded thankfully, and shot off back to the Gryffindor chaser formation. With the headmaster looking out for Ginny, he could focus on what was really important now … winning.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Back with Lockhart, there was a sudden pop, and the headmaster found himself straddled by a terrified-looking Hogwarts house-elf.

Lockhart looked down, rather bemused. “I say—” he began.

The elf didn’t let him get any further. “Free house-elf!” it shrieked.

Lockhart’s face went from jovial to puce-white, faster than a set of traffic lights, just moments before something heavy smashed into his side with the shape, weight, and speed of a cannonball, and Gilderoy Lockhart, Order of Merlin, Second Class, honorary member of the dark force defence league, three times winner of Witch Weekly’s most charming smile award, author of the best selling Boy-Who-Lived adventure series, and current Headmaster of Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry, slipped off his broomstick and fell to the ground.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Far off on the other side of the quidditch pitch, a bright blue light shot out of a wand-brandishing small figure in expensive Slytherin green robes, standing at the edge of the pitch. The blue light hit the falling figure of the headmaster, and slowly brought it to the ground.

“I think that’s Granger!” Susan shouted, squinting. “Yes, it’s Granger!”

Virgo felt ill. She’d been sure a free house-elf would have been able to take out Weasley without making too much of a scene, but Weasley was far better than she’d ever considered. Her magic sensing range was insane. She was reacting to the invisible bludgers as though they weren’t even charmed. And now, it seemed Dobby had even stopped caring if other people got in the way. Her hands started to tremble. Dobby wouldn’t target John, would he? Or get caught? Both would be horrible.

She kept her eyes on the action high in the sky, while occasionally glancing back to watch Hermione Granger casting basic first aid spells on the headmaster, including what looked like a bone-vanishing spell, if the way his arm went all rubbery was any tell. Nasty business. He’d be feeling that all night.

A gasp from the crowd wrenched her attention back skyward and her heart stopped. Weasley and John had started to dive.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“110—110!” The announcer shouted. “Will John Potter break off to look for the snitch? Yes! Yes, he is. We’re back to three-on-three for the quaffle, but now that their seekers are out of the picture, will the Slytherin team dominate as they did in the early game?”

The human fly that was Ginny Weasley cursed. She’d been hoping to spot the snitch by now, but these damn bludgers just weren’t giving her the chance. Merlin, it was fun though.

“Weasley!” Flint bellowed.

“I know!” Ginny shouted back, twisting her body so as to dodge both bludgers at once. “Find the snitch, win the match! On it!” Easier said than done though, she thought. Potter had total freedom to look while she played kiss-chase with two invisible flying bowling balls. Wait! An evil smirk spread across Ginny’s face as she remembered her last interaction with Harry’s brother.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

John Potter kept his eyes peeled as he scanned the pitch in the standard seeker pattern he’d perfected over two Hogwarts quidditch careers.

“Hi!” said an enthusiastic voice to his left.

John nearly jumped out of his skin. “Ginny?! What are you doing?”

“You looked lonely.”

“Lonely? Wha—” Something smashed across the tip of his broom, spinning him around and nearly bucking him right off. “GINNY!” he screamed.

“Well, it’s not fair that you get to look without worrying, and you do keep trying to get close to me.”

“Get away from me!”

Ginny grinned. “Na-uh!”

All thoughts of the snitch fled. As did he. It was amazing just how fast his Nimbus 2001 could go when he pushed it—not that it mattered much, since Ginny had the same model.

“Magical Merlin!” Lee Jordan shouted as the quaffle hoops passed in a blur. “Miss Weasley is sticking to Heir Potter like glue! She’s right behind him! I just wish we could see the bludgers!”

His only saving grace was that Ginny had to occasionally dodge a bludger, which gave him a moment to increase his lead. If only he had some way of seeing them.

“Flint goes for the hoop! Saved by Wood!”

Wait! The grass! And he could shake Ginny off at the same time!

John shot up into the air, rapidly gaining height, and then tipped over right at the apex. It was Wronski feint time!

Ginny pulled up beside him and pointed down. “Hey, look, the snitch.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

A gasp from the crowd wrenched Virgo’s attention back skyward and her heart stopped. Weasley and John had started to dive.

“They’ve seen something!” the commentator screamed as Weasley and John began their descent, not just in free fall, but actively accelerating towards the ground while corkscrewing around each other.

Shrieks filled Virgo’s ears and it took her a moment to realise that one of those voices was hers.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Go! Faster! Harder!

Ginny’s grin couldn’t have been wider as she pushed for everything she had, the world spinning around her, first the sky, then Potter, then the ground, then the stands, over and over.

Closer! Nearer!

The ground was like an emerald pumpkin pie being thrown at her by the will of a god.

Don’t let up! Not until the very—last—

“SHIIIITTT!” Potter yelled, a voice that started right behind her and then suddenly fell upwards.

Barely an inch from the ground, Ginny jerked up and felt blades of grass whip across her knuckles as she sped forward.

A glint of gold flashed across the pitch in front of her.

Heart beating, adrenaline pumping, that feeling of feeling ALIVE. Now! Speed! Fast! Win!

“The bludgers!” the commentator screamed.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Magical Merlin!” Alex shouted, wide-eyed, as the two invisible bludgers impacted right behind Ginny and started tearing twin furrows in the pitch as they ploughed unstoppably towards her, sending dirt and grass flying everywhere.

“The snitch!” Pansy shrieked. “She’s seen the snitch!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Ginny stretched out her hand. The snitch was hovering just out of reach, so close she could smell it, darting right—darting left. All she needed was a little more reach. Just a little more.

The snitch darted right in front of her hand.

For a moment, time seemed to stand still.

Her fingers closed over it, almost gently.

Her hand gripped it, the wings retracted into the ball.

She’d done it.

“SHE DID IT! 120—110! SLYTHERIN WIN!

The crowd erupted.

“HELL YEAH!” Ginny swooped up into the air, triumphant, holding the snitch above her head. “I WIN!” It was as if everything came together in that instant. All the training she’d done. All the hard work she’d put in. This was who she was. This feeling—Oh, how she loved it. John Potter could take his damsel in distress and shove it down his throat. She would do anything to be what she needed to be. Even hurt. Even kill. It was a them or us world, and she’d make sure it was always them!

Her senses screamed at her to move just a moment too late.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Lily lifted the curtain that blocked access to the last spare equipment room and gasped. Something bad was apparently happening outside, if the shrieks and groans of the crowd were any judge, but whatever was happening on the pitch had to pale to what was before her now.

Severus stepped in beside her, stiffened, and instantly had his wand out.

Four dead house elves lay strewn on the floor. They were very definitely dead. Live house elves tended to still have their heads and didn’t have their intestines dangling out around them. Needless to say, blood was everywhere.

“What … what could have done this?” Lily whispered.

“What is definitely the right question,” Severus said. “No student could have—not even the more … precocious ones. And I can’t imagine any of the professors doing it either. And all the ones who might have were upstairs.”

“What should we do?”

“Order the students back to their common rooms and inform the headmaster when he wakes up.” Severus seemed to think for a moment. “Topsy?”

There was no reply from the Hogwarts head elf.

“She’s not one of the dead,” Lily whispered. “Where is she?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Impedimenta!” shouted seven different voices, professors Flitwick, McGonagall, Sinistra, and Vector, along with madams Hooch, Pomphrey, and Pince.

The second bludger stopped dead in mid-air.

The first was already being wrestled back into its box by Hagrid.

Hermione was bent over Ginny—a Ginny who looked like she’d gone five rounds with a heavy-weight boxer, with compound fractures all down her right side—a Ginny who grinned up at her through half-lidded eyes and a bloody mouth missing three teeth, and said, “We won.”

Hermione harrumphed. “Yes, you won. Now hold still so I can fix this. You’re in even worse shape than Lockhart. Honestly, Ginny, what were you thinking?!”

Ginny spat out another tooth and scrunched her face up in pain, but did not answer.

Hermione’s face softened. “Relax, I’m going to give you a pain killer.”

A minute later, Ginny was feeling a lot better. She still had more wrecked bones than a novice necromancer, but at least the pain was gone. “Thanks, Hermione. I’m glad we have you.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Must we rush so?” Susan complained to a prefect as they were hustled out of the stadium.

“I’m sorry, Heiress Bones, but the teachers have made it clear that everyone must go immediately to their homerooms. No exceptions.”

Virgo was doing her best not to look like she was trying not to look like she was nervous. Her plan had not gone well. But at least she hadn’t been caught. Probably. Hopefully? Please, God—Merlin?—whoever!—please don’t let her have been caught.

“Maybe your brother would be able to tell us what happened later,” Susan whispered as they walked across the grass.

“My brother?”

“Yes. He seems quite close with Weasley. I don’t think I’ve ever seen him so chummy with a girl before. Not even Parkinson. I know you don’t get on with your family, but there can’t be any harm in asking, right? I can be there with you if you’re uncomfortable.”

Oh, right. Most of her classmates knew each other from before Hogwarts—even those from different factions. “He might be able to …” she started, sounding uncertain. My new brother knows Weasley,she thought. My new brother is friends with Weasley. Virgo firmed her jaw. “Okay, let’s talk to him—together.”

“Of course.”

They were almost at the doors when Virgo noticed something moving out of the corner of her eye. A second glance told her it was John. Oddly, he was skulking near the trees just shy of the forbidden forest. He didn’t appear to have anyone with him, but he did have his broomstick, slung over his shoulder like a muggle rifle. What was he up to? She nudged Susan, and, taking advantage of the momentary distraction while their prefect opened the doors, led her away to the shadow of one of the towers.

“What is he doing?” Susan asked, exasperated.

“I don’t know. Let’s wait and find out.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In the hospital wing, Lily looked down sadly at Harry’s stone-like form.

Severus and Professor Flitwick were standing like guards by the door.

“I’m going to wake the headmaster now,” Madam Pomfrey said from behind her.

Lily turned away from her son and towards the unconscious Lockhart. Miss Weasley was in the bed one further down.

“Now, what is the first thing we do on waking a patient?” Pomfrey asked the student healers. “Clearwater?”

“Assure them that we have everything under control and ensure a general state of calmness.”

“Exactly. Granger—if you would.”

Hermione Granger brandished her wand and cast an incantation over the headmaster.

The result was not what Lily expected. Lockhart bolted straight up in bed, wide-eyed and began taking a huge breath.

“Headmaster,” Hermione quickly began, “We-have-everything-under—”

“Free house-elf!”

The entire hospital wing went silent. Dead silent.

Lily felt the blood drain from her face.

“Headmaster, are you sure?” Severus snapped from behind her.

“Yes!”

Lily’s mind raced. “The wards!” she said urgently, jumping to the first answer she could think of. “Don’t they keep them out?”

“I don’t know!” Lockhart wailed. “They’re supposed to.”

“Dumbledore never liked strengthening the wards,” Severus muttered. “He hated blood-feud culture.”

“But they are there, right?” Lily said. “The wards? The headmaster just needs to activate them.”

“I don’t know how!”

“You should have learned!” Lily snapped. “You’re the only one who can.”

“No,” Severus said smoothly. “There is one other who can.”

“Who?” Lily asked. Her face wrinkled as realisation dawned. “Oh, Sev, not him.”

“While our headmaster is an accomplished wizard, it will still take him too long to learn. Lord Slytherin will know how to, and can hopefully get here sooner.”

“But we don’t know how to contact him.”

“Lord Greengrass is our best option. I will speak with his daughter. It is not unknown for lords to give their heirs emergency means of contact.”

“Excuse me,” Madam Pomfrey said, the student healers all staring at the exchange with wide eyes. “Not to butt in here, but what are we going to do, right now, about there being a free house-elf in the castle?”

The professors and headmaster all looked at one-another.

Three minutes later, a huge pulse of magic shot out from the castle, and every window, door, and gate slammed shut—a thousand kilometres away, in central London, a blaring red siren went off in the Department of Magical Law Enforcement—and twenty-three minutes after that, twelve fully-armed aurors stepped out of the Headmaster’s floo and marched in pairs to all four common rooms, the infirmary, and the kitchens, where Chief Auror Lord Sirius Black and his partner Kingsley Shacklebolt found over a hundred house elves, including Topsy, cowering in a corner by the ovens, behind a makeshift fort made from animated tables, chairs, and iron pots, ready to bite anything that got close. Nothing Sirius said would persuade them to leave the perceived safety of their fort, and eventually, the two aurors just set up station in front of it. Hopefully Lord Slytherin wouldn’t be too long coming.

Footsteps announced the arrival of another auror. “Sir!” The auror saluted. “Three students are unaccounted for—Miss Virgo Malfoy, Heiress Susan Bones, and Heir John Potter, Sir.”

Sirius cursed.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Some time later, and several thousand kilometres away, Lord Greengrass detached a parchment from a rather harried looking owl. Getting into Transylvania hadn’t been easy, and the hardest part of the journey was still ahead of them.

“We can take it a bit easier now,” Lord Smith said, propping his war-hammer against a wall with a grin and sitting down in a hotel chair, which creaked under him like an oak galley taking on new cannons. “The children aren’t going anywhere. And I could do with a rest. These old bones aren’t the same as they once were, you know.”

Jacob started to read the parchment.

“We will most likely have to fight once we get there, so rest could be a good idea,” Xeno commented. “I agree. There is no particular rush now that we know where we are going.”

Jacob finished reading and cursed. “Wrong,” he declared. “We are now very much in a rush.” He handed the parchment to Xeno, who took it, read, and whistled.

“I would agree with you, old boy. A rush, we are very much now in.”

“Give me that!” Smith took the parchment and read. He swore. “Okay, serious shit, but what does this have to do with us? Slytherin doesn’t need mandrake.”

Jacob and Xeno looked at each other.

Smith looked between them both. “Fucking hell!” he exclaimed. “Are you saying that our big stick is laying useless in some bed somewhere, totally stoned? Okay, yes, I agree, we’re in a rush.” He stood up and hefted his war-hammer. “Let’s go crack some skulls.” No sooner had the words left his mouth, then there was a knock at the door.

The three British lords exchanged glances.

Jacob was nearest, so he slipped his wand into his hand and gripped the door handle. “Yes?” he called out in the tone of voice which says, ‘this had better be important’.

“Ministry of Magic,” came the cultured sounding reply from the other side of the door. “The minister requests your presence.”

Jacob suppressed a groan. A quick look to his companions showed that both had their hands on their wands as well. They all shared a resigned nod. Jacob opened the door. Instead of the usual wizarding robes that might be expected from ministry officials, these gentlemen, and they most certainly were ‘gentlemen’, complete with quotation marks, were all dressed in black muggle suits—coattails—white tie—opera.

The lead ‘gentleman’ gave Jacob a quite literal pointed smile. His teeth gleamed. “So sorry to interrupt you, my lords, but the minister has some urgent business with you.”

“And do we have any urgent business with him?” Smith asked.

“You may very well find that to be the case.”

After another round of exchanged glances, the three lords allowed themselves to be escorted out of the hotel and, after several rounds of apparition, to a nearby castle on the top of the hill—nowhere near the size of Hogwarts, but very obviously built with one main aim in mind. To keep those who were on the outside, out.

“It’s so gratifying to deal with wizards who know how to apparate,” their lead ‘gentleman’ said as they walked under the portcullis and through several wards which felt almost as strong as Hogwarts’ own. “Makes matters so much easier.”

They were deposited in a waiting room with golden leaf plastered all over the ceiling. Large full-length mirrors, also inlaid with gold, surrounded them on every wall.

“That’s got to be a mental game,” Smith said. “Want us to always remember what we’re dealing with.”

“Perhaps,” Xeno said mildly. “It does make you wonder though. They’re always dressed to the nines—perfect hair—perfect skin. Must be hard to achieve that effect without being able to see yourself.”

On the other side of the room from the way they’d entered, a large double-door opened, and a lady—whose silhouette could easily be mistaken for an elegant candlestick—stepped out and gave them another very pointed smile. “The minister will see you now.”

She didn’t bother following them in. No guards, Jacob thought. No security, no nothing. Not that it was needed. The ‘gentleman’ on the other side of the large mahogany desk—noticeably older than the others—radiated quiet power in the same way that Harry could. The bronze plaque on the desk read:

First Transylvanian Minister of Magic, Count Dragos Dracula, Mugwump, Electorate, Eighty-six times Gobstones Champion

“My lords,” the aged vampire purred, sweeping up from his chair. “So good of you to drop in. It is rare we get a visit from the Albion.”

“We couldn’t stay away,” Smith said gruffly.

The count chuckled. “My servants can be a little forceful, it is true. They tend to interpret my suggestions as commands.” He gestured to four high-back leather chairs surrounding a low table to the side. “Please.”

There was a wooden box on the low table. They all sat. None of the three lords said anything. They instead waited for the minister to pour himself a measure of red liquid into a crystal glass. After taking a sip, the vampire opened with, “The mandrake supply crisis is terrible, is it not?”

Shit.

In the time it took for the minister to pause where most people would need to take a breath, the following thoughts sped through Jacob’s mind.

1. This is about why we’re here.

2. He knows why we’re here.

3. He knows that the mandrake supplier is here.

4. He ordered the kidnapping of the mandrake supplier.

5. We beat up and then tortured his agents.

6. He has mandrake in that box.

7. He wants to trade.

8. We might not be utterly fucked.

9. If we can’t give him what he wants, we could still be utterly fucked.

“And in times of crisis,” the count continued, “people are wont to do very silly things. Not me, of course, but friends. Friends who found themselves in desperate need. I’m sure you understand.”

10. He’s acting as an intermediary for someone else.

“So, what do you want for the mandrake?” Smith asked.

“Ahh, straight to the point.” The count leaned back. “What do you know of my land’s political situation?”

“Only what we’ve read in the papers, I’d wager” Xeno said. “You signed a new country into existence not long ago, and now rumour is that every wizard and witch in the new territory is being rounded up and bitten.”

Jacob winced. That was exactly the kind of horror situation wizards dreaded.

“Fullmoonia,” Smith grunted. “Stupid name for a country.”

The count swirled his crystal glass and looked at the ceiling. “The name was not my idea, I can assure you of that. And as much as it pains me to say it, the rumours are true. I’ll not pretend that life is perfect under my rule, but this ‘solution’ to my kind is barbaric.”

“Eliminate predation by making everyone a predator,” Xeno mused.

“We had an understanding,” the count said. “We do not take magical blood from any who do not choose it. And for those who do choose, the experience can be truly magical. The freedom in total surrender is like a drug—so I’m told. And you cannot eliminate predation by making everyone a predator—you just make the top predators that much harder to spot.”

“Doesn’t being top predator by merit rather than birth make it more meaningful?”

The count grinned, flashing his long canines. “Unfortunately, I must speak for all my people, not just myself.”

There was a pause.

“So, what do you need from us?” Jacob asked.

“There is a stronghold deep in Fullmoon territory, Castle Dragos. I built it long ago as a position to project power from, much like your Hogwarts has done before—I was not happy to lose it, believe me. Since then, it has become one of the best universities for ICW obliviators. When the Supreme Mugwump negotiated the peace accord, he insisted that Dragos be granted independent status from the Fullmoon Ministry. The ICW has a vested interest in making sure the university stays open and that both students and teachers need not fear werewolf attacks while conducting their studies. The unintended consequence is that when the accord was signed, many dozens of witches and wizards fled to Dragos for safety. Not long after, the Fullmoon ministry took control of the exit and entrance points, and now many people are trapped within the fortress.

“You need someone extracted,” Smith said.

The count nodded. “There is a VIP within the university—someone whom I have a vested interest in. Getting them out is a sensitive matter.”

Jacob stroked his chin. “Could be tricky if the Fullmoon is on guard.”

“Luckily, the minister of ‘Fullmoonia’ also has a vested interest in removing this individual from his new country.”

“Then why doesn’t he just let him go?”

“Unlike me, the minister of Fullmoonia is not an absolute ruler. He is a pack leader, and operates only with the approval of those he leads.”

Smith snorted. “So, he can’t look weak by letting anyone go—even when it’s the obviously sensible thing to do. Typical.”

“That is what happens when a bunch of dogs start a government.”

Jacob searched the powerful vampire’s face for any sign of a sneer, but couldn’t find one, amazingly. He found it difficult to imagine what it must be like to rule your lands for over half a millennia and then lose a good chunk of it to a race of magical creatures whose sole purpose for being was to deny you and your people the food that sustained your very existence.

Everyone knew werewolf blood was useless to vampires, but no one could have imagined it would eventually lead to this.

“Get my VIP out, and I will give you the mandrake you need.”

Jacob stared down at the box, then at his companions. “Fine,” he said—the first among equals. “We’ll move out as soon as we have our papers.”

“Please hurry.” And Jacob was once again reminded of the raw power radiating out from the being in front of him. “The matter may be more time sensitive than we could ever guess.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Compared to Transylvania, entering the newest magical nation of Fullmoonia had been a surprisingly quick affair. The badly-dressed Fullmoonia border guards, who, rather cutely, called themselves aurors, were rather impressed with having three Albion lords swing through their little checkpoint.

It did, however, necessitate another escorting to a rather nice looking cottage some twenty kilometres away from Castle Dragos, to meet the Fullmoonia minister of magic.

“Goliath Volf,” said the man, shaking each of their hands in a grip so hard Jacob was sure he could feel his finger bones grind together. “Welcome to my people’s great nation and the front line of the fight against oppression. I just want to make one thing quite clear. I know nothing about what you three are up to, understand?”

“Absolutely,” Xeno said, and then without missing a beat added, “Is there anything else you would like to not know?”

“Yes, as a matter of fact. I was hoping to not know if the rumours that you,” Goliath pointed to Smith, “can craft goblin silver are true.”

Lord Smith’s face darkened. “My house hasn’t been able to craft true silver for centuries.”

Goliath shrugged without apology. “Then how about the rumours that you”—he pointed at Xeno—“are a powerful necromancer able to speak with Death himself.”

Xeno gave the man a bemused look. “My great-uncle was a necromancer, but that’s as close as I get.”

“Fair enough. And you,”—he pointed at Jacob.

Jacob readied himself for whatever wild rumour might be floating around him.

“Is it true you are to be the father-in-law of Lord Slytherin?”

Jacob blinked. “Oh, yes, that is true.”

“I have heard many great things about your future son-in-law. Tell me, how does he feel about werewolves?”

“Umm … I don’t think he has a strong opinion either way.”

Goliath had a hungry look in his eyes. “But could he be made to see the justness of our cause? The unacceptability of how wizards and witches are treated in these lands? The need to join, fight, rise up!” Goliath’s voice was getting louder with each word. “And accept the curse!?”

Jacob glanced around to find that Smith and Xeno had subtly angled themselves in the direction of the door. He turned back. “I doubt he’d be willing to accept becoming a werewolf—and I mean no disrespect, but we do have many commitments back in Britain.”

Goliath deflated slightly. “But what about your Lord Genesis—the British vampire lord. Isn’t he a political enemy of yours?”

“Yes, a political enemy—not an existential one. No British family feels the need to ward their house against vampires.”

The man collapsed into a chair, suddenly looking very tired. “No, I suppose not. But we need all the help we can get. His words might be pretty, but the count’s fist is harder than steel, and his memory is older than the statute. ‘In a blood feud, truces last only as long as it takes for both sides to regrow all their limbs,’ from the count’s own book. No, this war is not over, and we need all the help we can get. You don’t happen to know Remus Lupin, do you?”

Dead silence filled the room. The werewolf might as well have said, ‘What’s wrong with familicide?’, or, ‘By the way, I’ve got a bomb rigged under the floor and it’s set to go off if anyone says the word cheese.’

After a very long pause, Jacob said, “One does not simply know a Lupin, even if you are acquainted, and even if the Lupin in question happens to share a minor life circumstance detail, such as being a werewolf.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Getting into Castle Dragos wasn’t difficult. Their cover story was that they were acting as convenient impartial messengers for the Fullmoon ministry, which was actually true. Goliath Volf sent word that they were to be shown all respect and courtesy, and that anyone giving them any difficulty would be literally torn apart. The hard part was getting away from their hosts, who were desperate for news from the outside world—teachers, students, and ICW officials alike. A solution to the blockade was being negotiated, but until it went through, even the usual residents were stranded.

Jacob eventually managed to slip off, while Xeno and Smith kept a pair of ICW diplomats busy with the British political situation.

Following the count’s instructions, Jacob quickly found his quarry, carefully hidden in a remote part of the castle, accessed only through secret passageways and passwords.

The woman was beautiful—young, with dark skin—far darker than one might expect for this part of the world. She had beads all down her hair, and her robes were exotic.

“It’s about time,” the woman said, after Jacob gave a pre-arranged code-phrase. “I was starting to think that vampire was just going to leave me here.”

“My lady,” Jacob replied. “The situation outside is delicate. The count made arrangements as soon as he could, I’m sure.”

The woman huffed, but perked up when he introduced himself. She peppered him with questions as he led her into the shrunk trunk he always carried on his person, many of them to do with Lord Slytherin, the Gray Lord, whom she appeared to have a special interest in. Mind you, that wasn’t at all unusual. Many of the women Jacob met had a special interest in Lord Slytherin, despite them knowing he was already betrothed, twice (or maybe because of?).

With his illicit cargo stored safely in his pocket, Jacob quickly met back up with his companions, said their goodbyes to their hosts, and easily made their way past the blockade. Soon they were back in Transylvania, where Jacob delivered the young woman into the care of the count.

“Thank you for your help,” the count said with a smile, handing over more than enough fresh mandrake to cure Harry and Luna. “And give my regards to Lord Slytherin. He seems to be a most interesting individual.”

It took over a whole day to get back to England. They had to take multiple portkeys spaced out over many hours, which was annoying, but did cut down on portkey sickness.

“I’m just frustrated we didn’t get the opportunity for a really good fight,” Smith grumbled, as they walked away from the landing point in King’s Cross Portkey Port, hefting his war hammer and giving it a consoling pat. “It’s been a long time since I’ve had reason to let the other woman in my life go nuts. Your scrap with those Italian boys looked like a grand ol’ time.”

Shaking his head in amusement, Jacob glanced down at the Daily Prophet as they walked past a news stand, and nearly bit off his own tongue.

There was a moving, smirking picture of the beautiful woman he’d just rescued not forty-eight hours ago, smirking specifically at him, along with the headline:

Gray Lord Tebola Evades ICW Investigators—Flees Eastern Europe Under Self-Transfiguration—African Union Refuses Comment

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Several days earlier, Susan and Virgo crept along one of Hogwarts’ outside walls.

The quidditch match had just finished and they’d spotted John up to something in the forest. They weren’t supposed to be out here—the prefects had ordered everyone inside—but bollocks to that, they both thought. If anyone asked, they could just say they were going to tell John about what they’d been told.

“What is he doing?” Susan asked, exasperated.

“I don’t know,” Virgo answered, eyes narrowed. “Let’s wait and find out.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Ginny!” Up in the hospital wing, Ginny let out an embarrassed smile as her mother hurried up to her bed, face red from running and worry. “Oh, dear, are you alright?” She caught sight of the mangled mess that was her shoulder and arm. “Oh, my goodness! Oh, I just knew this was a bad idea. Professor Snape told us all about what happened. Two rogue bludgers! What were the teachers thinking, letting the match continue? And then a lockdown! We had to come in through your father’s friends—never seen Amelia in such a state. Now, where is that broomstick?”

The smile vanished from Ginny’s face.

“I said before that quidditch is no sport for a young lady. I said—”

“Mum!”

“Molly,” came the calm voice of her father from the infirmary door. “You know we’ve talked about this.” He was flanked on each side by an auror, with their long robes and iron shields.

“But, Arthur—”

“—No buts.” He smiled. “From what I understand, Ginny proved herself to be especially talented today.” He walked up to the side of the bed and looked fondly down at her. “Our little girl may well pick up where Charlie left off.”

Ginny’s smile slowly came back. “Thanks, Dad.”

Molly Weasley looked like she was ready to continue arguing, but then deflated. “Is it too much to ask that at least one of our children doesn’t go into some hugely dangerous career?”

Ginny’s smile turned impish. “Percy won’t.”

Her mother ignored this. “And what about money? Quidditch doesn’t pay. She’ll be completely reliant on her husband. And who’s going to marry a girl who’s always running off to who knows where?”

“Mrs. Weasley?” said one of the aurors, joining them by the bed. “I hope I’m not intruding, but I dare say a quidditch star won’t be wanting for suitors. And can I remind you please not to ‘run off’ like you did before? The castle is not safe.”

Her mother bristled. “I mean good quality wizards of high standing, not some lazy, good-for-nothing pub-rat. And I am perfectly capable of taking care of myself, thank you very much.” She looked down at Ginny and her face softened. “I guess we’ll just have to sort something out when the time comes. You’re at least keeping up in your classes, aren’t you?”

“Yep.” Ginny nodded. “Fifth in my year.”

Molly frowned. “Only fifth?”

“Well, Luna’s above me—so is ‘Virgo Malfoy.’ ” She made sure to slot the quotation marks into place around the name the same way one puts handcuffs around a criminal. “Then there’s the Chesterfield twins—they’re very good too, so yeah, fifth.”

“Chesterfield? I don’t recognise that name.”

“They’re muggleborns.”

“Muggleborns? Really, Ginny, you should be able to do better than—” Molly cut herself off. “Not that there’s anything wrong with that, of course,” she amended hastily, before looking around and continuing in a lower voice. “But really, Ginny, I’m surprised you’re not doing at least as well as Luna.”

“Luna’s a genius, Mum.”

“Molly, dear, why don’t we find Madam Pomfrey? I’m sure Ginny here needs a rest. I’m sure she’ll be safe with these gentlemen here.”

“What? Oh, yes, I’ve got some questions for that woman.” And with that, her mother bustled off towards the back. A few minutes later, the aurors also stepped away, leaving her alone with her father.

Feeling tired, Ginny relaxed back into her pillow and turned her head towards the bed next to hers. There lay Harry, as still and as stoney as a statue.

“Lord Slytherin said your fates were intertwined,” her father said. Someone who didn’t know him might have taken it as an idle comment, but Ginny knew better.

“They are,” Ginny replied.

“Prophecy magic is one of the most dangerous forms of divination wizard-kind knows of,” he continued. “If the ICW could control it, I dare say they’d seal off all influence from her realm.”

Ginny didn’t say anything.

“I’m sorry I haven’t been there to help you with this before now. I can’t imagine what it must have been like to bear a burden like this for so long at your age.”

“I haven’t been alone.”

Arthur gave her a small smile. “No. I just wish it could have been us, your family.”

Ginny felt her stomach drop. “It still can be,” she said quietly.

“That’s what I intend.”

Ginny felt the weight in her stomach lessen. “Really?”

“Yes.” Her father’s face firmed. “From now on, you will have our full support. Your mother has been highly reluctant, which is understandable, but she sees the importance of what we’re doing, even if she believes you to be too young to discuss it with. This Winter Festival, I plan to talk with Lord Slytherin about the possibility of having our family publicly declare ourselves to be Gray.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Among the trees of the outmost reaches of the forbidden forest, John glared down at the book in his hands. It was one of the many that Virgo had smuggled to him over the last few weeks, all on the many rituals that young wizards and witches could undergo, if they were willing to pay the price.

He hated the Malfoys, and it galled him no end that they apparently had no qualms about giving their daughter such powerful knowledge, even despite their current animosity towards her. They didn’t coddle her. His own parents had never even entertained the idea of allowing him these kinds of books. The few times he’d asked, he’d been decisively shot down and they refused to hear anything more on the matter.

He turned the page from a ritual that gave the caster thicker skin, at the cost of the sense of touch, and quickly passed over another page, covered in delicate, spider-like script, set beside numerous diagrams of muggles spread-eagled on flag-stone floors, arms and legs bloody and mangled.

Obviously he could spot if something was a bad idea—if something was morally questionable. The notion that he couldn’t was stupid.

Faint through the thickness of the forest, a loud bell rang out.

Something was going on up in the castle, but John couldn’t have cared less.

He’d lost.

He flipped another page, cross-legged on the damp, dirty ground.

That was not acceptable. How was he supposed to defeat Voldemort if he wasn’t even better than his own classmates? Or even than Ginny, who was younger than him?!

He briefly considered telling Susan everything, just like Harry had with Ginny—all about being from the future, his brother, Voldemort, but quickly dismissed the idea. The thought of having to admit his failings was too painful. He’d tell her once he’d gotten things back under control … maybe.

Finally, his flipping fingers found the page he’d been looking for—a ritual to give him near perfect balance—and it didn’t even have that high a price. All he had to do was stand on one foot for the whole ritual, one-hundred feet above the ground, without putting his foot down.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“What’s he doing?” Susan whispered, sounding uneasy.

Virgo tried to angle her head more to see under the bush the two girls were hiding under. She wasn’t having much luck. Her neck was already so angled that owls would get neck pain just looking at her. “I can’t see very well,” she whispered back. “He’s just reading the book. I think he’s got his broom somewhere, but I can’t spot it.”

Susan’s breath was hot on her neck. “Hey, should we even be doing this? I mean, what if it’s Potter family business, or something personal?”

“Hush, you. We’re just keeping an eye on him. You know how boys can be.”

“I guess,” Susan conceded. “But what about the castle? It sounds like something important is happening.”

“I’m sure if it’s really important they’ll tell us later.” Besides, Virgo added in the privacy of her own mind, it’s probably to do with a certain homicidal house demon. She just hoped to hell that Dobby hadn’t been caught. That would be very bad.

“What about now?” Susan whispered. “Is he doing something? What’s he doing?”

Virgo snapped back to the here and now. “I think—” Through the bushes she could just make out the figure swinging his leg over something. “—It’s his broom!”

“What do we do?”

Too late, John Potter had already zipped up through a hole in the canopy, leaving Virgo lying dirty on the ground, feeling very silly, with Susan’s almost whole body weight pressed down on her, trying to get a better view.

She growled. “Get off, you lump!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It should have been midnight.

The sky should have been clear and black, save for a stray errant cloud, shining bright by a silvery moon.

It wasn’t.

It was still barely midday.

John alighted on the top of the astronomy tower and took a deep breath. It was by far the tallest tower in the whole castle, and so was perfect for this ritual. After he’d done this one, maybe he’d go through some of the others. There were all kinds. Rituals to increase reflexes, rituals to increase will power, even one ritual to fix his eyesight—heaven knows he’d have appreciated that one ages ago, even if it did require ripping the still-beating heart out of a pig.

John flipped the book back open to the page with the ritual and started his preparations.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“There!” Susan said excitedly, while still trying to keep her voice under control. “On top of the astronomy tower!”

Virgo squinted up and did indeed see a small figure right on the edge of the tower. “What the hell is he doing up there?”

Susan gasped. “He’s not going to jump is he?”

“He bloody well better not,” Virgo muttered. “No … it doesn’t look like that. … I think. …” Her eyes widened in shock. “No! He’s not going to—That idiot!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It was such a simple ritual, John mused. Chant the words of the ritual near a place of intense magical power while channelling your magic into the ground below your feet, and then stand on one foot for five minutes over a hundred feet above the ground. That was it. Well, Hogwarts was undoubtedly a place of intense magical power, and this tower was well over a hundred feet above the ground. And if he stood just so, in the event that he really did lose his balance, he could just put his foot back down and try again later.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Back downstairs, a distracted Susan allowed Virgo to use her Lamia form to hiss one of the locked doors open. She didn’t want Susan knowing about her animagus ability yet. They were now hurrying along one of the corridors towards the astronomy tower.

“What’s he doing?” Susan gasped out.

“Balance ritual,” Virgo spat over her shoulder. “The idiot thinks he’s outsmarted it. Second rule of ritual magic—”

“—Never try to outsmart the ritual.”

“—Never try to outsmart the ritual.”

The two voices perfectly synced into each other. Virgo looked briefly surprised at Susan whose eyes were now wide with alarm, but then, the Hufflepuff was an heiress, so if anyone as young as her would know, it would be her. “We have to stop him,” Susan squeaked.

“Yes.”

“We should tell someone.”

Virgo couldn’t allow that. She shook her head fiercely. “No! If we tell someone John will get in huge trouble.” And besides, she thought, she didn’t want to stop him doing rituals completely. She just needed to make sure he didn’t kill himself doing them.

Just then, Virgo rounded a corner, saw who was down the corridor with their backs to them, and just managed to clamp her hands around Susan’s mouth before the older girl let out a meep that would have given them away. Together they edged back around the corner before the two on-guard aurors, dressed and shielded with full-dragon hide and iron, saw them.

“That was Thicknesse and Blott,” Susan whispered. “Auntie says Thicknesse is a real piece of work. She’s always having to keep an eye on him.”

“Not the understanding sort then.”

“No.”

“Disillusionment charms, I think.”

“Yes.”

“HEY!” shouted a loud voice. “WHO GOES THERE?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The last words of the ritual fell from John’s mouth and he allowed himself a small smirk of satisfaction as he raised his leg into the air and grabbed it by one hand like a child playing hop-scotch. A faint circle of red light lit up around him, including the large drop to the ground, far below, but, more importantly, also including the crenellation he stood atop.

Then, suddenly, something felt wrong. He felt himself getting lighter.

“Wha—”

It was like someone had cast a levitation charm on him.

“What’s going—”

He started lifting up into the air.

“ooooOOOON!”

The ground fell away and, still clutching desperately at his leg, his whole body rose up into the air, higher and higher. Sweat started beading on his forehead. His heart started beating faster. And still the ground was falling away below him.

After a few more seconds, although it felt like a lifetime, the levitation stopped, and he felt his weight reassert itself, except he now stood one-legged on an invisible floor, well over a hundred feet above the tower, and the ritual had moved him, not just up, but also across. He was now right over the tower’s sharp spire tip.

What would happen now if he put his foot down?

Oh, Merlin. Oh, Merlin. Oh, Merlin.

His every sense became hyper-focused. The feel of the leather in his quidditch trousers pressing hard against the hand holding his foot up, rapidly moistening with sweat. The glare of the sun in his eyes. The vast distance of horizon spreading out far across the land. The lake. The forest. The village. And below him, far, far below him, the castle, and even further than that, the ground.

Breathe! John shouted in his mind. Don’t panic—just five minutes. He could do this. He was the best quidditch player in Hogwarts. Except, he wasn’t. Ginny was better. No! Focus! Don’t think about that. And don’t think too much about your leg. Just—don’t—think—about it.

His balancing leg twinged a warning of staying in one position too long.

An ominous breeze brushed across his hair.

John whimpered.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“They’ll catch us!” Susan wailed, only not really. A wail isn’t usually so quiet that an owl would have difficult catching it.

“No,” Virgo said urgently, leading her down another passageway at a dead run. “Trust me.”

“But this isn’t the way to the tower. Maybe we should just tell them? Then at least John will be okay.”

“Trust me!” Virgo pulled her into an alcove. “Just promise me something.” Her voice had become reluctant.

“What?”

“Promise me you won’t tell John about what I’m about to do.”

“What?”

“No time!” Virgo hissed. “Do you promise?”

Susan frowned. “Okay, yes, I promise.”

Virgo nodded and changed.

Susan stared, wide-eyed, as the first-year Gryffindor transformed before her eyes, her legs morphing together and stretching out behind her into a massive snake tail while the clothes on her upper body just sort of vanished into her skin, leaving her still-human body extremely underdressed, save for a set of scarlet scales covering her feminine chest from total exposure.

It was a lamia.

Virgo Malfoy was a lamia animagus!

Susan had little opportunity to gape though, because the mythical magical creature in front of her hissed at the wall of the alcove, a secret passageway opened up, and moments later, she’d been yanked inside by a tail far more powerful than any eleven-year-old girl should be.

The passageway closed behind them.

“Where are they?!” shouted the voice of one of the aurors.

“We’ve lost them,” said his partner, at a far more normal voice volume. “This place is a maze—never could get the hang of it, even by seventh year.”

Susan followed Virgo as the younger snake-girl continued to lead the way through the castle that she seemed to know amazingly well for a first year, her tail and body sweeping a path through the dust and grime of decades. A quick pulse to her mind brought her occlumency into sharp focus. She narrowed her eyes. “Virgo.”

“Mmm?” Virgo turned back to look at her. Her face was one of almost total innocence, tinged with perhaps a dash of apprehension.

“I will honour your request regarding heir Potter, but have no doubt that soon you and I are going to have a long chat about this.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It had to be five minutes soon. It had to be.

High up in the air, John was sweating bullets. He’d already almost lost his balance twice. His hands were shaking and not from the unrelenting cold wind blowing him about this way and that.

Suddenly, two figures barged out of the door leading to the astronomy classroom.

His heart leapt.

“Help!” he screamed.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Keep it quiet, fool!” Virgo shouted back. “Do you want to get caught?”

“I don’t give a FUCK about getting caught!” John screamed back. “Just get me down from here!”

“Easier said than done,” Virgo muttered. “Working on it!” she called back.

“His broom!” Susan said. She’d already snatched it up and was busy mounting it.

“Good thinking, but don’t get too close!” Virgo barked. “This ritual is highly volatile. Even small magics can interfere. And he hasn’t even taken his clothes off!”

“How close is too close?”

“Hover twenty feet below him.”

“I can’t catch him if he falls twenty feet!”

“You don’t have to catch him. You just have to slow him down. I’ll handle the rest.”

Susan nodded and shot up into the air. “No levitation spells!” Virgo called after her as an afterthought.

It took a few moments to prepare her part of the operation, and not a moment too soon.

“AHHHHH!” John screamed as the worst happened. Arms spinning like a catherine wheel, he spun on one leg, and, ever so slowly, toppled over. What happened next was decidedly not slow. He collided with Susan—“OOF”—hovering below with one arm outstretched, they dipped, but Susan didn’t dip far enough, quickly enough, and John’s tentative grip failed him.

“AHHHHHH!”

He fell, right into the massive cloth trampoline Virgo had conjured off to one side and rolled across the ritual space at just the last moment.

“Susan, get away!” Virgo shouted, grabbing John and hauling him as far away from the space as she could, using the smallest amount of magic she dared. She ended on top of him as they rolled to a rough and tumble stop. Behind them, the conjured material of the trampoline was busy ripping itself to shreds in the light of the failed ritual.

Virgo took a deep breath. Safe.

“John!” Susan alighted next to them and was on her knees in seconds. “Are you alright?”

John just stared at the still self-shredding material with wide-eyes.

“He’s fine,” Virgo muttered. She climbed off of him and glared. “But what the hell was that?” she spat.

John’s eyes travelled to her. “I …” But he didn’t seem able to finish the sentence.

“You, what?” Virgo continued. “Just couldn’t wait? You know I would have helped you if you’d asked for it.” She glanced at Susan. “We would have helped. I get that you need to get stronger—I get that, but we have time. We have seven whole years until we graduate—six. What’s the god damn rush?”

“John, what’s going on?” Susan pleaded, eyes wide and watery. “Please, won’t you tell us?”

John swallowed.

Virgo thought she was ready to hear anything. She was expecting him to spout teenage bravado about protecting her. She was expecting him to reveal that someone was blackmailing him for some petty reason. Or that his parents had trained him from childhood for his own protection against her other self’s death eaters.

What she wasn’t ready for, was for him to look them both in the eyes—eyes filled with apprehension and not a small amount of shame—and mutter, “I’m a time traveller.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Kill the spare,” said a high and terrible voice.

There was a flash of green light.

John Potter looked around in stupefied horror as Cedric Diggory fell to the ground beside him, dead. The sun chose that moment to fall below the tree-line, shrouding the graveyard in a foggy chill.

Dead. Cedric Diggory was dead.

“Bind him,” said the same voice.

The next thing John knew, he’d been restrained with ropes and tied to a gravestone.

The cowl of the man in front of him slipped from his face, and John let out a scowl. “You!”

Lord Lucius Malfoy gave him a sneer. “Me.”

“You won’t get away with this.”

“Oh, dear,” said the voice from the cauldron. “Did he really just say that? No matter. Start the ritual.”

John screamed in pain as blood was taken from his arm. He watched in horror as Malfoy cut off his own hand. And he gazed on uneasily as the first lord of the Dark used his still remaining hand to unscrew the lid off a jar and pour bone dust into the bubbling pot, along with the blood and flesh.

Voldemort rose from his metal womb, and more death eaters arrived. He addressed them.

“—But what’s most amusing of all!” Voldemort chuckled to the skull-masked crowd, halfway through his speech. “Is that my truest enemy isn’t even here! He rots in Azkaban! Isn’t that so, fake-boy-who-lived?”

The skull masks all laughed, and John felt the shame burning harder than the stab wound in his arm.

He was untied and handed back his wand.

“And now, fake-boy-who-lived, we duel.”

The patronus knight burst from John’s wand, strong, blindingly light, and instantly crushed with a careless flick of Voldemort’s wand.

“Crucio,” Voldemort said carelessly.

Pain screeched through him.

The skull masks all laughed again.

Fake. Fake. Fake.

“And now, fake-boy-who-lived, time to die. Don’t worry, I will keep your brother safe. He is, after all, very important to me, in a way you could never be.”

There was a bright flash of green light, and his world went dark.

He didn’t know how long he didn’t exist for.

“Good morning, Heir Potter.” A four-word sentence, male, in a voice of stone, empty caves, and deep gulps of fresh mountain air.

John opened his eyes and raised his head. The room was like an Anglo Saxon roundhouse—one of a great chief—fur everywhere, weapons lining the walls, wild looking dogs in a pile by the door. Two people sat in thrones before him—a man and a woman. The man looked vaguely swarthy, while the woman looked kind of like Lady Greengrass. The man held a scythe, while the woman was dressed in white lace and held a book.

He frowned. “Who are you two?” His eyes widened. “What happened to Voldemort?! Where are we? Are you with him?!”

The woman held up a hand. “Please, Heir Potter. We do not have much time. We are not associated with your Dark Lord. We are Fate and Death.”

“Fate and Death?”

“Yes,” said the man, “Because, you see, you, Heir Potter, are dead, although I suppose technically, that makes you no longer an heir as far as your Albion Magics are concerned.”

“Dead?” His eyes widened. The Avada Kedavra!

“Dead,” The woman confirmed. “But we are not done with you yet, Heir Potter. We are displeased that Voldemort still lives. Cheating Death—cheating me,in the manner he has—is not acceptable. So we wish for you to go back—back in time, fours years—and give it another shot.”

John blinked. “Back in time!? You can do that? Brilliant. But …” He hesitated. “What about my brother, he’s the real …”

Death smiled. “Yes, he is the subject of the prophecy, but we are giving you the chance, John, to fulfil the prophecy in his stead. Bringing your twin to us now would be troublesome. Our influence in the mortal plane is extremely limited. We can generally only operate through chosen ones and champions.”

John’s mouth slowly turned to a wide grin. “Really? I’ll be the chosen of Fate this time?”

“Yes.”

He hesitated again. “And, my heirship?”

“Once you are alive again, the Albion Magics should re-acknowledge you. Tracking them is difficult, and not even we fully understand them.”

“Oh, good.”

“Then, off with you.” The man carelessly waved his hand, and John felt himself blasted backwards through some kind of portal thing, and back into nothing—a nothing where everything was …

Quiet. Quiet and warm. And comfy. Quiet, warm, and comfy. John Potter’s eyes shot open. He sat bolt upright and looked around. He was home. The familiar red and gold of his bedroom in Potter manor felt odd now. Like seeing an old friend after a lifetime. He breathed, acutely aware of the lack of pain shooting through his body. He couldn’t feel the cruciatus. But, of course. It hadn’t happened yet. None of it had happened. The stone, the chamber, Pettigrew’s breakout, the tournament, Voldemort’s resurrection … his death—none of it.

He’d been given a second chance. Death and Fate had chosen him. His eyes gleamed.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Virgo eyed John Potter carefully.

Susan was gazing at him with wide eyes.

He finished the story and looked between the two of them.

Virgo’s voice had become soft. “It all makes so much sense now.”

“What?” John asked.

“Everything.” She hesitated. “Mostly.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Several days later, Harry opened his eyes. He was lying by the door to the soul chasm, a petrified Luna next to him. Moments later, she too was de-stoned.

“We’re back again,” Luna said softly.

“Seems like it.”

“I wonder how long we’ve been out.”

“Let’s find out.”

They made their way back to Harry’s mindscape, and Harry carefully woke up. A small crowd surrounded his bed in the hospital wing—his mother and father, John, and interestingly, Virgo, who was regarding him with an extremely calculating gaze.

He smiled thinly. “Good to see you are well again, Miss Malfoy.”

“You too, Mister Potter.”

For their part, Lily and James Potter played the role of concerned parents well, and Harry had to admit that, if he were so inclined, he’d quite appreciate the effort.

Lord and Lady Lovegood were there too, standing with Luna and conversing in hushed voices.

Apparently there were only a few days of school left. That left a ridiculously large amount to catch up on in an equally ridiculously small amount of time. The preparations for the winter festivals among other things. In a little under a week, well over a hundred wizards and witches would descend on Slytherin Manor, and he had to be ready for them.

Soon, his family left and his other family, his real family, arrived.

“Harry!” Hermione squealed. “I’m so glad you’re back.”

“Yes, she’s been very worried,” Daphne added.

Ginny smirked. “Don’t give him that—you’ve been the most worried of all of us.” To which Daphne blushed.

Harry smiled widely. “Can I assume our favourite dark witch is well? I don’t see her in any of these beds so I assume nothing too bad happened.”

“She’s still in the snake pit,” Daphne replied. “But it wasn’t her that you almost woke up next to as well as Luna.”

Harry gave her a quizzical look.

Daphne lowered her voice. “We’re not one-hundred per cent sure, but we think Virgo tried to murder Ginny.”

Harry’s eyes hardened. “Oh, she did, did she?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

And so the fall term came to an end. No one, it seemed, was staying at Hogwarts this year. Everyone was packing up in preparations for a packed holiday schedule.

Virgo found herself not looking forward to leaving, but then, the school had always been one of her only two real homes—Hogwarts and Stockholm, but Stockholm was a place she could never return too, no matter how much better a childhood it had provided than the orphanage.

She chatted with Susan for most of the trip back to London, simply enjoying being a pre-teen girl, before the reality of her current situation imposed itself on her again.

Lord Malfoy stood at the end of Platform 9¾, tall and imperious, next to his wife Narcissa—her mother.

Virgo’s face slid into an expressionless mask as Draco, her older brother, found his step alongside her.

“Father—Mother,” Draco said.

“Draco.” Lord Malfoy nodded to him, then to her. “Virgo.”

Virgo curtseyed, not so high as to indicate disrespect, but high enough to communicate a slight assertiveness, or, if one didn’t know her fake true identity, defiance. She was very aware of John’s eyes on her from the other side of the platform. She rose. “I hope I find you both well.”

“Quite well,” Narcissa hummed. “But we’ll leave the pleasantries for when we return to the manor. The house elves will have dinner waiting for us.”

Later that night, Virgo lay alone in bed, staring at the ceiling while the moonlight streamed in through the gap in the massive curtain windows.

John Potter was a time traveller, killed by her other self in the future and sent back to the past as a champion of death to destroy all of Voldemort’s horcruxes, which, worryingly, obviously had to include herself. On the other hand, Death hadn’t actually told him about the horcruxes, or anything that might help him in his task, which was a blessing while at the same time being rather odd.

Potentially, she could tell John all about it instead—she and Susan were now accessories to long-term time travel, a crime so serious that she didn’t even want to think about the consequences if anyone found out, and so a certain amount of trust could be relied on, but … no. She wasn’t willing to gamble her own life on a coin toss like that, not when there was another option.

Virgo rubbed her temples.

Death didn’t like horcruxes. She really wished she’d known that little tidbit of information before she’d created one, and probably the six others that came after her too. A near god-like being didn’t like horcruxes to such an extent that it was willing to expend not even Merlin knew how much magical power in sending a champion—and apparently his twin too—back in time to destroy them. She really didn’t like those odds.

But being destroyed didn’t have to be her fate. No, she could fulfil Death’s quest on her own terms. After all, it wasn’t her destruction Death sought, just her immortality through that particular method.

If she found all the horcruxes, destroyed each of them in turn, and used the reconstitution ritual to absorb each piece back into herself, she could keep her own identity as the prime Dark Lady, while giving Death no more reason to stalk her.

She shuddered.

And as for immortality … well, if the Flamels could get away with living for so long using a philosopher’s stone, then apparently that was a method that Death didn’t disapprove of … probably. She’d certainly considered alchemy as a path before, but had never been that interested when there was a much faster option available. She was the greatest witch that ever lived. If anyone could replicate Flamel’s feat, it would be her. But all this was moot until she’d solved her Horcrux problem.

Virgo closed her eyes.

When she opened them again, she was back in her mindscape.

There had been changes.

Hogwarts was now covered in a thick winter snow. Not thick like the marzipan on a wedding cake, like the snow she’d just left behind in Scotland, but thick like the winters of Sweden—so thick her eleven-year-old self could barely lift her leg up and over to take the next step forward. She melted a path to the front gate with her wand and dismissed the huge basilisk guardian with a hissed command in lamia form.

Tentatively, she opened the front gate.

The soul chasm beyond was everything she dreaded—an empty hole to nothing, hanging below a bridge as insubstantial as a human thought. She tried to reach out her magic senses across the space, trying to get a feel for which of the threads that now stretched taught from her chest might be the nearest to follow, but it was obviously a trick she’d need to work on.

In the end, she picked one that felt at least a little closer than the others, and started tiptoeing across.

She didn’t know how long the journey took. In the back of her mind, she imagined Narcissa trying to wake up her body, only to find it in the same comatose state she’d been in not that long ago, but no. It hadn’t been that long. Eventually, she saw her quarry off in the distance.

The sight puzzled her.

She hadn’t been sure what kind of mental representation another horcrux would have, but Azkaban Prison certainly wouldn’t have been her first guess.

Slowly, she edged her way towards it.

Less than thirty feet away, something gave a horrible creak sound.

She froze.

Then, like something out of a horror movie, the big doors to the prison swung open, revealing a tall, cloaked figure, in a green and black mask. Lord Slytherin.

“Hello, Miss Malfoy,” he said, sounding pleasant, before his tone dropped to something far sterner and all-together less pleasant. “I’ve been hearing that you’ve been a very bad girl.”

That was all the warning she got before ropes flew at her through the darkness. Panicked, she cut through them with her wand, only to catch a glancing blow from a tripping hex. She found her feet again, but that was all the opening her opponent needed to cast another incarcerous, this one successfully wrapping around her arm.

“No!” She was pulled along the thin bridge towards the prison door. In less than a few seconds she’d been dragged halfway. If she passed through them, that was probably the last anyone would ever see of her.

Virgo moaned. Her plans, her ambitions, her potential!

But, amazingly, with less than ten feet to go, she halted. Not because Lord Slytherin had ceased his pulling, but because something else wrapped around her other arm and stopped her dead. It was a chain—a black chain. Her arms pulled out on either side of her, yanking her up so her feet didn’t even touch the bridge.

“That’s enough of that,” a voice said.

Virgo looked around desperately. There, on another bridge angled off in another direction, was another man. He too was tall and masked, but his mask was a far more traditional one—traditional at least, if you were a follower of Lord Voldemort. It was a skull, and from his neck dangled an artefact that Virgo had only ever seen and read about in books from the Hogwarts Library. Slytherin’s Locket.

For a long moment, the three of them stood there, the two adult wizards and Virgo, stretched taut over an endless chasm by a rope and a chain between them.

Lord Slytherin inclined his head slightly. “RB.” It was not a statement of inquiry, more a declaration that a small puzzle, one that had nagged the mind for quite some time, had finally been solved.

The man in the skull mask inclined his own in acknowledgement. “LS.”

What happened next was over in seconds.

RB, whoever that was, shot something purple straight at Lord Slytherin, who countered by conjuring a solid concrete slab in front of him, which shattered into a thousand pieces on impact. Virgo was thrown directly backwards, both rope and chain loosening around her wrists, giving her just enough time to scrabble away down her bridge as the two adult wizards let loose the magics of hell on each other. The temperature of the soul chasm soared as she crawled back to safety, and when she finally got back to the gates of her own mindscape, it was to find much of the snow leading up to the castle already melted, such was the heat of the power struggle behind her.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Less than fifty kilometres away, from Wiltshire to Puddlemere, Harry sat bolt upright in bed, sweating and clutching at his head, which already had started to throb with a truly magnificent headache. They’d both retreated in the end—an end which had started quite soon after the fight had begun.

“Damn it,” he muttered.

Slipping to the side of the bed, he slipped on his slippers and padded down the stairs of the grand ballroom at Potter Manor, completely still in the dead of night, not caring a hoot if anyone caught him at such a late hour. He made his way over to the main entrance floo, threw in a pinch of powder, and flew on through to the only address this particular floo would allow him access to.

He stepped into the living room of the other house, tiptoed up through the many floors, and quietly knocked on a bedroom door.

“Alex?” he whispered into the dark room.

“Whaaa?” Alex looked around groggily.

“Alex, something just happened, and I think you have a right to know about it.”

—End of Chapter Fifty-One—

Chapter End Notes

—End of Chapter Fifty-one—

A/N: And so we come to the last chapter of the current arc. The second part of the year won’t be nearly as long as the first, I assure you, but I am going to plot it out first, so expect a bit of a break before we commence again. If you enjoy my work, please consider checking out my original projects. All support is appreciated. You can find the links through my website www.leadvone.com.

A/N: This chapter was drafted and made available early through the LeadVonE discord server, as will the next one. If you fancy discussing this chapter with like-minded people, or anything else DP&SW, feel free to head over there.
A special thank you to the following people for helping catch mistakes on #dpasw-editorial: APunchUponMalvaceae, ASK, ChRiAn, Drakonpie250, Dragonbait, DrSubnautica, FartyArtyPartyPooper, feauxen, Fuuryuu, HansC, JaydenStevenson, Leyrann, MageKing17, Magic Bird Dust, Oliver W.K. Salty_sauce, sfu, Shady, SunshineAmy, Tendra, Twist, and TrendyTreky.

A/N: Conversion rate is:
1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds
1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)
1 Knut to 10p (roughly)
All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2019’s prices.

Interlude — This is the House that Floating-Interest Built

Within the Slytherin girl’s second year dormitory, next to Hermione’s bed, inside Hermione’s trunk, five girls sat in a circle of chairs, pointedly not meeting each other’s gaze.

“I just want to make one thing absolutely clear,” Daphne said in a careful voice, having chosen the ceiling as her staring partner. “We are all responsible young witches—educated, and well-trained in the mind arts.”

“Yes, Daphne,” Luna, Hermione, Ginny, and Alexandra all responded.

“We are not irresponsible children with the self-control of a niffler.”

“No, Daphne,” the girls chorused.

“When we make decisions, they are measured. They are well thought out. They are calculated. We have all been taught about the importance of family finances and how to balance an account book.”

“Well, actually—Ow!” Alexandra shoved Ginny’s elbow back out from her ribs and scowled at the girl’s frantic eyebrow wiggling.

“So when a time-sensitive opportunity presents itself, we carefully weigh up the pros and cons,” Daphne continued, completely ignoring the interruption.

“Yes, to do anything less would be an insult to everything our lord has done for us,” Hermione nervously spoke up. “And for what it’s worth, I have got a list of all my pros right here—”

“Yes, thank you, Hermione, but we—”

A huge parchment unrolled itself from Hermione’s hands, hit her feet, and continued to unroll itself along the floor.

“—will only even consider these things if Harry’s meeting with Ragnok goes well.”

“Of course,” Hermione squeaked. “Obviously Harry has the final say.”

Daphne nodded. “He has much more experience than us.”

“I really hope he likes my Sssss idea,” Luna said with a smile, hissing the penultimate word.

“Luna, you are not going to ask Harry about your Sssss idea.”

Luna pouted. “Why not?”

“Because such extravagance is unbecoming of a lady of a noble house, because such things are highly inappropriate, and because … because. …” Daphne looked into Luna’s curious, friendly eyes and gave up. “I just want to make one thing absolutely clear.”

“Yes, Daphne?” the girls asked.

“We are all responsible young witches—educated, and well-trained in the mind arts, and we are not irresponsible children with the self-control of a niffler.”

“Yes, Daphne. No, Daphne.”

“And we are only going to trouble Harry with our extremely well thought out and entirely reasonable ideas, if, and only if, his meeting with Ragnok goes beyond and above expectations.”

“Yes, Daphne.”

There was a knocking on the trunk lid.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

On the outside, Harry carefully opened the lid of Hermione’s trunk, climbed in, and cancelled the disillusionment that had allowed him to sneak into the girls’ dormitories. They were all there. All eyes on him.

“Excellent news,” he said. “Ragnok has had our initial artefacts valued in the upper range of our estimates, for both the muggle and the wizarding worlds. He also believes that the legal problems we might experience from selling in the muggle world can be handled. Even better, he’s agreed to extend us additional credit based on your memories of the haul. All in all, everything went massively beyond and above expectations.”

He sat down in the remaining armchair.

As though on some prearranged signal, both Hermione and Daphne stood up with parade-like precision. He felt his chair move and looked around to find a grinning Ginny turning him towards the blackboard Hermione used to teach the muggleborns.

Hermione then stepped in front of said blackboard, and summoned a piece of chalk. “Right, um, Harry, we, err, have some ideas …”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Some time later and three hundred kilometres away, as the owl flies, on the sloping lawn outside Slytherin Manor, the gobliness Floating-Interest, daughter of Ragnok Boneslicer, and head goblin on the Slytherin Manor building project, read the letter that her father had just forwarded to her in utter disbelief.

“They want what by when?!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 20 days

This is the house that Floating-Interest built. It sits proud on the very most top point of Gairsay Island, in the Scottish Orkneys—a respectable manor in white granite and brick tile. The roof beams are oak—the first two floors, polished marble. The third floor was cedar, and the windows sparkled in the morning sun.

It was impressive. It screamed wealth.

One thing it was not, was outlandish. In much the same way that architects and designers have a tendency to go totally bonkers with their blueprints whenever science comes up with a new material that allows new possibilities, only to then dial back their enthusiasm several decades later, so magicals have had a tendency, throughout the centuries, to construct their homes and places of work, less with an eye to practicality, and more towards putting that prestigious Hogwarts education to really creative use. Hence, size ten-thousand boots, houses shaped like rooks, and banks purposefully designed to look like a Roman temple had melted.

This tendency was generally for the eccentrics only.

Most magical builders followed traditional muggle-style, grudgingly acknowledging that their physics-based approach, taking such petty things as loads and tension into consideration, did have its advantages in those rare cases where the magic might possibly fail—hence the granite, marble, and wood for Slytherin Manor, as opposed to say, ice, gingerbread, or pudding. It was this level of restraint and subtleness that Floating-Interest had been administering the construction project under. At least until the letter from her father had arrived.

Floating-Interest glared as she read the letter again.

To Floating-Interest,

Daughter,

Slytherin wishes to make some last minute additions. I wouldn’t normally agree (if they want changes, they should bloody well ask for them earlier), but Slytherin is a special case. Some of it will require ministry approval. Other bits will need family contracts. Everything must be complete before Gala Night. I will arrive three days before to inspect before handing it off to our client’s representative. Get it done. I’m confident you will.

Father,

—Ragnok Boneslicer

Floating-Interest then glared at the list of additions that she’d been given.

Behind her, half-a-dozen house-elves in lime-green pillow cases were hanging from ropes and using brushes to stain the wood, which framed the stone entranceway, while several other goblins were manoeuvering a large sofa in through a window. A lone wizard, down the hill, was tending to some newly planted shrubs.

“Junk-Bond!”

One of the goblins struggling with the sofa turned around and trotted over, leaving his fellows bent like compressed springs. “Miss?”

“We’re going to need to alter our plans. The big wizard in charge has had a sudden attack of money and wants more gong for his gold.”

Junk-Bond looked cautious. “What kind of changes?”

Floating-Interest showed him the list.

“Whoa. This here.”

“Yes.”

“And that there.”

“I know.”

“But, this is going to need family magic.”

“Yes.”

“And the deadline for completion is really soon.”

“I know. I need you to talk to our people in the human-liaison office. See if they can help us smooth the way. Slytherin’s name should help there too. Gold talks—at least, to humans it does.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 18 days

Slytherin Manor was bustling. What before had the air of a long project winding down, now was ladened with last-minute hustle, and occasional panic. Goblins, wizards, and house-elves ran from place to place, measuring, designing, assessing, and above all, arguing.

“It absolutely can not be done!” said an old wizard with a bald head and a long grey beard. “The number of charms, the way they intercross with each other, and you want it all done while working on other projects? Lunacy I say.”

“Lord Hawking,” Floating-Interest said in her best placating voice (her wizard skills were one of the main reasons she’d been given the project in the first place). “I know it looks difficult, and I can fully understand if you might be nervous about it—”

“Nervous? I’m not nervous, young woman—goblin—gobliness. I’m merely saying that the house of Hawking has never taken on such a large scale project on such short notice. Our space contraction charms are not last minute additions crammed in because someone wants a secret broom-cupboard.”

“No, of course not, lord wizard, and I assure you, there were extenuating circumstances that precluded your involvement before this. I’m sure Lord Slytherin will appreciate the difficulties and be very understanding.”

“Non-euclidian geometry isn’t a panacea,” Hawking warned with a wagging finger. “Without the proper foundations, it’ll all fall apart.”

“We designed the entire building assuming that your involvement would eventually be inevitable, lord wizard. The plans are right here.”

Still grumbling, Lord Hawking bent over to inspect them. “Well, at least you’ve got the walls good and thick,” he muttered. “You’d be amazed by the number of wizards who’ve asked us to build a cathedral between two bits of plasterboard. Exactly how understanding will Slytherin be, do you think?”

“Up to fifty per cent extra per square foot understanding, lord wizard.”

Lord Hawking settled down “Well, I suppose my grandson and his young wife do need some practice at these more hands-on kind of projects. Far too busy locked up in their attic lately, those two. I’ll send them down and be on hand as needed.”

“Thank you, Lord Hawking.”

Lord Hawking scrunched up his nose. “What’s this small room I’ll need to make room for here marked, Sssss?”

Floating-Interest didn’t miss a beat. “Lord wizard. That’s a Slytherin family secret.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 17 days

“So, you’ll be needing a dozen extra house-elves over the next few weeks.” Lord Parkinson strode briskly through the latest consignment of construction materials and furnishings, occasionally glaring at piles of chairs or floor tiles, paying no heed whatsoever to his interlocutor’s shorter gait. Floating-Interest was forced to jog to keep up. “The winter festival is a busy time of the year for my workers, goblin.”

“Yes, lord wizard.”

“Luckily for you, I have a few extra hands available.”

“Wonderful.” Floating-Interest paused to catch her breath.

Lord Parkinson turned to face her. “I’ll have them sent around immediately. Mimsy!”

One of the lime-green clothed house-elves popped into being in front of them.

“Go back home and fetch team six. When you’re done, I want another stock taking on the stuff we’re sending over here.”

Floating-Interest looked at him with concern. “Lord wizard?”

“I can’t help notice that we occasionally seem to lose track of things we send over. Wood and stone not used for anything on the plans—extra doors, furnishings, etc.”

Floating-Interest coughed nervously. Hawking’s grandson had arrived that morning and already got to work on some of the smaller secret rooms and passageways. “I can’t imagine that’s worth worrying about,” she said. “I take it nothing has been lost that has not been paid for?”

Lord Parkinson gave her a look. “No, but it is disconcerting. I am not used to things going missing in my business. I will have to bring this up with Slytherin himself when I finally get to meet him.” Lord Parkinson then turned his back on the furniture.

The moment he did so, Plato popped into being, grabbed one of the larger chairs, and popped back out.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 16 days

“Floating-Interest, Miss!” Junk-Bond screeched to a halt. “We’ve got everything we need for the rooftop project.”

“Excellent,” Floating-Interest snapped. “But can’t you see I’m a little busy now?”

“Oh, I don’t mind,” said Lord Lovegood with a genial smile. “You just continue.”

Floating-Interest gave the young goblin a glare that caused him to wither. “Start on phase one immediately, but don’t interrupt me again if I’m with the humans!”

“Yes, Miss,” Junk-Bond stammered before darting off again.

“Seems eager to please, that one,” Xenophilius said.

“Young males often are.” She sighed. “Unfortunately, eagerness is not the same thing as capability.” She shook herself. “Shall we?”

Lord Lovegood smiled and turned his back to the gobliness. In front of him rose one of the many staircases of Slytherin Manor, in this case, the left one from the third floor to the second. He rose his wand and waved a complicated pattern, whispering incantation and letting the magic flow out of him and into the very stonework. Behind him, Floating-Interest watched in appreciation of a job being well done. Several hours of incantation later, it was complete.

Lord Lovegood smiled at Floating-Interest, both of them now at the top of the stairs. “Would you like to do the honours?”

“What?! No, absolutely not. Junk-Bond!”

A few moments later … “Miss?”

“Would you just stand right there and twist that knob at the top of the bannister?”

“Like this, MiIIIIIIISssssssss?”

Floating-Interest and Lord Lovegood watched the goblin speed away down the now transformed slide. “Luna will be so happy.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 15 days

Mrs. Thorson knew, when she had been married to the nephew of a British lord, that she’d spend much of her time devising strange new magical artefacts as the product of her husband’s family magic, and that of her father, the Sorcerer of Cochem-Zell. In her ten years of acceptable marriage, however, she’d never been asked to devise something like this.

“It is a most interesting idea, Fräulein goblin.”

In front of her, on the lawn of Slytherin Manor, a small team of wizarding masons were sculpting a hollow snake from local stone, two feet tall and two-hundred feet long. Chalk marks had been placed at regular intervals for wooden sliding doors.

“A moving bookcase,” Mrs. Thorson mused. “One capable of bringing a specific book to the owner on a whim. It could follow them around like a dog. Or go to fetch books from the library if needed. Swallow and sort. And live coiled among the shelves when the mistress is not home. Mmm. Whoever conceived this must be a true bibliophile.”

Floating-Interest nodded. “I have never met the witch in question, but I have met her parents, and it wouldn’t surprise me at all.”

Mrs. Thornson frowned. “But even with my father and husband’s magics I will not be able to give it the final—how to say— … jolt.”

“Slytherin will take care of that. Parseltongue has powerful Serpenmorphic properties.”

“I am jealous. I could think of so many applications. Sometimes I truly curse Merlin for making the Albion.” She sat down. “I am hungry.”

A house-elf dressed in a crisp emerald green robe of silk popped into being in front of them, holding a silver tray. He gave her a formal bow. “Tea and biscuit, my lady?”

Mrs. Thorson raised an eyebrow and took a biscuit. “Thank you.”

The house-elf bowed again, then turned to Floating-Interest.

To Mrs. Thorson’s mild surprise, his voice shifted from the subservient tone she’d always associated with house-elves, to something altogether quite different—something more assertive—aggressive even. He smiled. “And Plato is needing an immediate update on the outside hill project. Master’s friends are worried it is not being ready for winter festivals.”

“Everything is on schedule,” Floating-Interest said shortly. “I will give you your update after our business here is complete.”

Plato smiled again, bowed to her, and popped away.

“I don’t think I’ve ever heard a house-elf speak that way before,” Mrs. Thorson said.

Floating-Interest pursed her lips. “That’s because you are human.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 13 days

The grand ballroom of Slytherin Manor was circular, spanning two whole floors, but Slytherin Manor itself was a rectangle. This created eight rather odd shaped rooms, each curved like a skateboarder’s ramp that had been turned up on its side. A few were earmarked for washrooms, another for cloaks, another for storage, but two of them, the second and third clockwise from the entrance on the second floor, had been put aside for the house-elves, one for living quarters, the other for kitchens, and were thus, a domain apart from wizardry.

“You, there! That toast is a shade too brown. Fix it.”

Aluminium countertops encircled the curved room like a spiky collar.

“No! Young Mistress Greengrass likes her egg yolks runny, but her whites hard. Do two separately and pour one into the other.”

Dozens of brand new magical appliances now lined those countertops, the combined literal firepower of which, when all activated at once, could turn the room from cool and sleek into a cramped and sweltering hellhole.

“If you isn’t getting it right this time, you will not be seeing toilet cleaning duty again for a month!”

Up against the one straight wall of the room, Plato hopped down from the chair he’d requisitioned from the incoming furniture pile and moved it a couple of inches to the left. It sat high up on one of the countertops and overlooked the room like a throne.

The rest of the room was completely empty of life.

“That is being perfect,” Plato said to himself. “Plato will be ready for other house-elves, but Plato will still be needing the traps, curses, and tripwires around Plato’s chair. Plato is Master’s head-elf here, and Plato will not give that up easily. Oh, no, Plato will not.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 11 days

“Firing up this bad boy!” shouted a voice.

All around the grand ballroom, spell-hunters and artificers were watching with calculating eyes. Some of them were looking over the balcony upstairs to get a different angle of view. A group of goblins, house-elves, and wizards, who weren’t anything to do with the project, but who knew an excuse for a break when they saw it, crowded by the front doors, and were kept back by one of the spell-hunters.

In the middle of the room, the man who had shouted the warning put his wand to the jewelled eye of a bronze snake—a snake inlaid into the very marble of the floor, coiling out for several meters on all sides.

He sent a pulse of magic into the jewel and spoke a default password.

The jewel sank away and what looked like a dozen liquid woods—liquid like liquid metals—flowed out of the hole. The different streams of wood rose up and swirled into the space over the man’s head. There were Oooos and Ahhhs from the watching crowd, mostly the house-elves, but a few wizards and witches too. Slowly, the wood started to form a globe, spinning majestically in the air, each different species forming a different feature—beech for the oceans, teak for the land, rosewood for the borders between the different sovereign territories of Earth.

“Well, I’d say that first part is a success,” the man said, wiping his brow.

There was a chorus of satisfied muttering around the room.

Floating-Interest stepped out of the crowd and walked forward to get a better look. Each territory had a little brass knob attached to it. She turned to the man. “May I?”

“By all means.”

Floating-Interest turned back to the globe, focused on Eastern Europe, caught sight of her target, and said, “Fullmoonia.”

The brass knob attached to Fullmoonia turned. There was a click, and a drawer in the shape of the newest magical nation on Earth sailed down into Floating-Interest’s hands. By the time it arrived, the drawer had changed shape into something more rectangular. There was a small collection of empty vials within.

“Mister Wizard?” Floating-Interest nodded at the vials.

The wizard took one, placed his wand to his temple, and drew out a long memory strand, which cascaded into the vial. He placed the vial in the drawer, leaving Floating-Interest to speak the return command, which lifted the box back out of her hands, changing shape as it went, and sliding back into the globe with a satisfying click sound.

“Set year 1991,” Floating-Interest called out.

The whole globe dissolved, turned into a swirling maelstrom of liquid wood, and reformed into an almost identical looking globe, except this time, Fullmoonia was absent, and the drawer of Transylvania, when inspected, was empty. Another command to set the globe to 1993 produced a Fullmoonia drawer also empty. It was only once they reset the globe back to 1992, that they were able to retrieve the man’s test memory.

There was a smattering of applause around the room.

“Incredible work,” the wizard said. “I must admit, I was skeptical when you called us all together—this has got to be the most impressive memory cabinet ever created—so many different family magics—and for travel-logging of all things—most people would just use a scrapbook—but whoever devised this clearly did their homework.” He turned to Floating-Interest. “I’d like to offer them a token of my greatest respect. Such wizards deserve recognition.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 10 days

“Greatest respect tastes pretty damn good,” Dan Granger declared, taking another sip of wine. “I could get used to this. A pity recognition isn’t part of our deal.” He and Emma were taking a precious moment to relax outside their cottage at the bottom of the hill, shielded from the bustle that had gripped the island over the last week. What had once been a bare Scottish island was now lush with magical foliage, but even that hadn’t blocked them off completely.

“Recognition would only endanger us,” Emma said. “Better we stay in the shadows.”

“Does make you wonder though.”

“What?”

“What other secret projects are going on in Slytherin’s name.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Albert Hawking, married with children, couldn’t hide his blush as he finished up yet another of the many secret spaces in Slytherin Manor—the Sssss room. “I don’t even know what half of these things are,” he muttered, glancing around the room. “I’m almost afraid to ask what goes on in Slytherin’s mind.”

Floating-Interest smirked. “I understand the idea was not his lordship’s, but rather Heiress Lovegood’s. The only input Slytherin had was to insist on an age line at all three secret passageway entrances.”

“Didn’t Slytherin’s second betrothed only just start Hogwarts?”

“Youth will always imitate maturity without truly understanding it.”

“In that case, I don’t want to know what maturity this girl is imitating.”

Floating-Interest shrugged. “It all seems reasonable to me.”

Albert Hawking knew better than to say something stupid like, ‘that’s because you’re a goblin,’ so he instead bit his tongue.

Floating-Interest gave him a sly look as though she could read his thoughts. “Power is everything in the goblin world,” she said. “Accounts are won and lost by the swing of an axe. Accounts make powerful warriors, and for the greatest warriors of all, the best breeders.” Floating-Interest shot Albert a toothy goblin grin. “That’s me, in case you were wondering.”

“Warrior or breeder?” someone said. To Albert’s horror, he realised it had been him.

Floating-Interest didn’t seem offended, however. If anything, she looked flattered. “Both, human. If I had my sword, I could cut you down before you could raise your wand.”

Albert didn’t doubt it. The light-green figure beside him may be half his height, and have hips and curves like some ancient fertility painting, but there was the promise of sinewy muscle, fast and powerful, under the thin layer of feminine fat. They’d left the secret room now and were in one of the bedrooms. He scratched the back of his neck, glad to be out of a room that he was sure his wife would flay him alive for having anything to do with the construction of. “I must say, you’re surprisingly candid for a goblin. I don’t think I’ve ever heard one of your kind speak so openly before.”

Floating-Interest gave him a kind look. “You’ve signed your memory-lock contract.”

Lord Hawking, Albert’s grandfather, walked into the room and pointed a wand at him.

Albert sighed. “Oh, right. I forgot, again.” He took off his noble house ring. “You know, I don’t think I’m ever going to get used to the way our family does business.”

“That’s by design,” Lord Hawking said. “Obliviate.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 8 days

The main land mass of Gairsay was divided into three areas. The large island, which comprised about sixty-five to seventy per cent of the total, the peninsula, which was connected to the large island by an isthmus, and the small island, sitting several hundred meters off from the rest. It was on the smaller island, looking up at the feverish work going on across the water, that Floating-Interest now stood. The way she stood was tense, and this was only partly due to overwork.

“I certainly think you were right to consult me,” said a nasally voice beside her.

The wizard she was currently sharing the company of wouldn’t have looked out of character as the villain of a Charles Dickens novel. Behind her, were two male goblins with their hands on their swords.

“I mean, what were you planning to do?” the wizard continued. “Just put up a few gates and stones and wait until the first pet dies? A good graveyard isn’t just something that happens! It needs planning, it needs care, it needs nurturing like a mother nurtures her child.” His voice dropped to a croon. “A graveyard is like a garden. It must be grown.”

The wizard’s name was Matilda, a licensed necromancer, freelancing for the Department of Ghosts and Spirits, and right now, Floating-Interest was silently cursing Slytherin for this particular project. The goblins’ feelings towards Death were complex, to say the very least. This was not at all helped by the top hat the man wore, atop from which, a large, very dead rat looked down with faintly glowing eyes.

“We need a theme!” Matilda clapped his hands together and rubbed them. “Oh, yes. This will be excellent. We need a theme and we need symbolism. The dead are not as literal-minded as the living. They need to be coaxed. How about—”

“—Snakes,” Floating-Interest said firmly.

“Snakes …” Matilda frowned, no longer rubbing his hands. “Not very necromantic, snakes … Demonic, yes. Plenty of good symbolism for good and evil and the choices of humanity. How about skulls instead? Always a classic, skulls. Or Beetles? Men have used beetles since the Egyptians. Got a good collection of wood knockers back home. I could—”

“Snakes!” Floating-Interest snapped.

“Snakes, right. Snakes. Ouroboros. The serpent biting its own tail. The symbol of eternity. Life and Death in the eternal dance. Yes!” Matilda’s voice went from sulking to enthusiastic in a few quick beats. “Yes, we can do that. We’ll start with a basic mausoleum to go with the yard. Oh! Why don’t we begin work on Slytherin’s own tomb? It’s never too early to consider eternity—”

“—I think just the basics to begin with.”

“Right, just the basics, right. Elegance. Panache. Every lord should have their own little patch of darkness.”

As the wizard rambled on, Floating-Interest rubbed at her temples. Too much stress. Too much work. Her muscles ached. The deadline was nearing, and there was still so much to be done.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 7 days

Plato gazed around the Sssss room with calculating eyes. While the true nature and ancestry of house-elves wasn’t known to the mass of wizardry, many of the more aware did know. Those wizards would not be surprised by the way Plato’s eyes now hungrily moved across the many artefacts that hung from the ceiling and walls.

The house-elf grinned.

“Plato wants one.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 6 days

Philip Scamander tapped his wand on the recently constructed greenhouse. “Not horrible, given the time,” he declared. “You’ll be able to grow a good selection of plants here. I really think you shouldn’t be in such a rush though.”

Floating-Interest shrugged. “Lord Slytherin wishes the island to be in viewing state for the Winter Festival. More importantly, is it fit for our other purpose?”

“Partly. You’ll certainly be able to keep a collection of small magical creatures. What did he have in mind specifically?”

“Magical insect breeding. Heiress Lovegood is quite the entomologist.”

Philip Scamander looked annoyed. “You should have called me in sooner. You need better warding. The floor is too thin. The air doesn’t have a self-regulating micro-climate.”

“Can you do anything?”

“Before the Winter Festival? I hope Slytherin doesn’t expect to have a full breeding program going on by then!”

“No, no,” Floating-Interest said in a placating voice. “He merely wishes it to be ready for Lovegood’s, ahem, inspection.”

“So, he’s showing off for his betrothed,” Scamander muttered. “Then we can have the big visible stuff finished and leave the tricky details for afterwards.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 5 days

“No, you damn demon!” Floating-Interest shouted. “You can’t have your own dungeon. What are you thinking? We’ve got barely any time left and you want to make another hidden room? What’s wrong with you?”

In front of her, the well-dressed Plato crossed his arms and smirked. “Plato is thinking the squib shouldn’t be calling the muggle empty.”

“Gah!” Floating-Interest rubbed her temples. “No, just no. I don’t have time for this!” Her voice rose in pitch until it was almost a screech.

Plato frowned. “Is pretty goblin girl taking care of herself? Overwork is not being good.”

“Shut up!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 4 days

Lord Parkinson sat down on a short grassy bench, looked around at his work, and found it to be good. It wasn’t every day one got to design and build a duelling arena. He’d have to show it to his daughter during Gala Night as an example of the kind of magic expected of a house as old and distinguished as theirs.

Next to him, a space of grassy hill flattened into more grassy bench, making space for one more bottom.

“Progress, lord wizard?” asked the female goblin in charge.

Lord Parkinson sighed. The gobliness had become more and more demanding over the last two weeks. “As you can see,” he said, “we are finished.” He gestured around him. “I always liked the Greek-style amphitheatre, but here we have that concept realised with magic. Will you not take a moment to fully appreciate great work?”

The gobliness sagged with visible relief, which he took as agreement. Not that he was going to stop either way. “Look,” he said, “at first the eye sees but a smooth grassy slope, carved directly into the hill. But with every body that enters, more and more slope becomes seating. The grass is my family’s own variety.” He pulled out a pair of scissors, placed them next to him, and smiled with satisfaction as the grass picked them up and started trimming itself. “And the wood for the bench-retaining-walls came all the way from magical India. When fully seated, the duelling wards have enough capacity to hold back a small horde and the arena itself has limited magical resonance, able to respond to the will of the Lord of the House, reforming itself as needed. Want a wetland duelling arena? A mountain-side? A beach? This duelling space will provide—so long as it’s natural. We can’t do towns or cities.”

The gobliness gave him a wane smile. “Practicing your sales patter, lord wizard?”

“Must your kind always be so crass? I merely wish people to fully understand what the house of Parkinson has been able to achieve here. This is not a large duelling arena—only around five-hundred seats—but have you ever seen one with such elegance before?”

The gobliness looked down the green hillside, down to the currently white circle of sand at the bottom, and out to the sea beyond. The water glittered icy blue in the weak winter sun. “No,” the goblin said, “I guess not.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Floating-Interest watched Lord Parkinson walk toward the floo and let out a yawn.

No! She lightly slapped herself. She didn’t have time for that. She needed to keep on. Next, she should head over to the security wards and check that the new parameters would function for Gala Night.

There was a pop sound behind her. Had the Parkinson house-elves finished work on the new hydrology system?

“Plato brings news for pretty goblin girl.”

Wrong elves.

She turned around. “News?”

The Slytherin head—and only—elf smiled at her. “Mistress Icygrass has authorised two-hundred galleons for discretionary house-elf interests.”

Floating-Interest’s heart fell.

“But since Plato knows pretty goblin girl is very busy, Plato has gone ahead and arranged everything for her. Pretty goblin girl only needs to sign and everything will be taken care of.”

Floating-Interest’s mouth hung open for only a fraction of a second before she took the parchment proffered her. Unfortunately, that fraction of a second was long enough for the house-elf to spot.

Mentally cursing, Floating-Interest read the parchment. She looked up in surprise. “Did you really arrange all this?”

Plato smirked. “What does pretty goblin girl think Plato is? Plato was trained in household management since he was old enough to walk.”

Floating-Interest felt a small weight lift off her. At least this wasn’t one more thing to deal with. “Fine,” she muttered. “You can have your ‘rest and relaxation’ room.” She withdrew a quill from the recesses of her dress and signed on the dotted line. “Just don’t take up any more resources than this.”

“Of course not,” Plato said, and popped away.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 3 days

Albert Hawking finished casting the last spell that would connect the secret tunnel that led from Granger Cottage to the library of Slytherin Manor. It had been a tricky job, requiring the passageway to navigate its way through a crack in the masonry no wider than a pencil, but once he was done, it was wide enough on the inside for two to walk abreast. He’d be lying if he said he wasn’t quite proud of it. “What are you going to do for a secret door?” he asked.

Floating-Interest yawned. She had shadows around her eyes. “We’ll probably use a tickling charm on a book, or a blood sacrifice, or something like that. Slytherin can be quite the traditionalist.”

“Is he? No one really seems to know where Slytherin stands on anything.”

“We goblins have a slightly better understanding of the man than most. We’ve worked with him the longest.”

“Really? I heard he originally came all the way from New Zealand—that he’s an adventurer, and that one day he found Slytherin’s treasure on a hidden Mediterranean island surrounded by perpetual fog—that he fought past legions of undead guards, and when he finally claimed Slytherin’s locket, the ghost of Salazar Slytherin spoke to him, found him worthy, and that is what allowed him to take up the mantle. Is that true?”

“No.”

“Oh.” Albert felt a pang of disappointment. “Then what about the story that he found a genie hidden in a bottle—that he wished for the power to restore honour to his family, who’d exiled him for running off with an Indian princess on the night before her wedding to the Maharaja.”

“No!” the goblin snapped.

Albert recoiled.

Floating-Interest grimaced. “My apologies, human. I am not quite feeling myself right now. Stress is not something goblins ever like to admit to. We hate being seen as weak. Not unless the one doing the seeing has earned our respect.”

Albert thought about this. “Then I’m honoured that you at least respect me enough to tell me so.” They were out in the empty main library now, evacuated of books due to ongoing work by outsiders.

Floating-Interest shot him a cranky look. “It will take more than doing a job you were hired for to get a goblin’s respect, human.”

The main door opened and Lord Hawking walked in. He pointed his wand at Albert.

Albert sighed. “Oh, right. I forgot, again.” He took off his noble house ring. “You know, I don’t think I’m ever going to get used to the way our family does business.”

“That’s by design,” Lord Hawking said. “Obliviate.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 2 days

Plato looked around what Floating-Interest was still euphemistically referring to the House-Elf Rest and Relaxation Room. He grinned. Seeing the wizard’s Sssss room had given him a basic foundation to work from, but he’d really innovated and expanded on the concept since then. Hidden between the kitchen and the house-elf sleeping quarters, Plato was now sure he had all the tools he needed to keep the other house-elves in line, and most importantly, keep him as the number one elf to serve the master and young mistresses.

The green, three-foot-tall door to the kitchens opened and Floating-Interest marched in.

“Well, are you happy now?” she asked. “Need anything else? A bejewelled iron maiden, perhaps? Infused with exotic scents and spices, maybe?”

Plato smiled. “No, Plato is quite happy. Pretty goblin girl’s team is very efficient. They followed Plato’s directions to the letter.”

The gobliness huffed.

“But Plato is thinking that pretty goblin girl does need to be relaxing more.”

“I don’t have time to relax! There’s still so much to do.” She made to sit down heavily on a wooden stool, misjudged the distance, and ended up crashing into the ground instead.

“Oh, dear!” Plato was at her side in an instant. “Plato is thinking pretty goblin girl really must be taking the evening off.”

Floating-Interest stilled, then shook her head. “I must be over seeing—I mean, I must oversee—”

“Why not be letting Plato take care of pretty goblin girl?”

Floating-Interest paused again before looking up at him, her eyes both weary and wary.

“Plato can be assuring pretty goblin girl that Plato’s kind knows how goblin girl wishes to be treated.”

“I have to manage the project,” she weakly protested.

“Pretty goblin girl be letting Plato handle everything. Plato has been here since the beginning. Plato is knowing everything that is needing to be done.”

“The ministry—”

“Arriving tomorrow at ten o’clock.”

“The magical theatre—”

“Setting up for rehearsal at two.”

Floating-Interest gave in. Plato could see it in her eyes.

“Okay, you damn demon,” she muttered, “but if you disappoint me, I swear I will cut you down.”

Plato smirked and gently reached for the rope.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 1 day

High in the sky, a wizard wearing heavy padding took a deep breath, looked around with a ‘why me,’ sort of expression, jumped off his broomstick, flailed wildly, fell a hundred feet, and landed in the water just off Gairsay Island with a loud smack.

Floating-Interest winced. She then subtly adjusted her full-length dress for the tenth time that morning.

“Well, that’s the high altitude drop test out of the way,” said the excited voice of Ludo Bagman. They were standing on the thin strip of lawn behind Slytherin Manor, looking out over the steep hill beyond and further out to sea. “Next up, the spectator emergency evacuation procedure. I say, are you sure Lord Slytherin won’t be around this afternoon? Only, I’ve got something important I wanted to discuss with him before Gala Night.”

“I’m sure,” Floating-Interest said with a relaxed smile. “Our client deeply wishes he could be here, but other matters called him away. Of course, you can always send him an owl if it’s important.”

Ludo Bagman looked decidedly less excited by that prospect, but perked right back up again the moment Clare Cooper arrived. “Oh! Miss Cooper, what a surprise. I’m glad to see you’re finding your own way in the world.”

The muggleborn’s greeting back to Bagman was far more neutral in tone.

The three then ascended a set of outdoor steps all the way to the roof of the manor where Clare stuck her wand into the eye-socket of a snake statue, and pulsed a set of spells into the stonework. All across the roof, a hundred stone snakes moved in choreographed sequence, lifting up five wooden benches for nearly five-dozen spectators to gaze out across the North Sea under a dome of invisible magic—protected from the elements—hidden from prying muggle eyes—all within shouting distance of a house-elf kitchen and whatever other luxuries Lord Slytherin could dream up.

Several minutes later, six levitating quidditch hoops shimmered into sight high above the water.

“Damn, I’d give a thousand galleons to know how you pulled that off,” Bagman muttered. “Quidditch over water. It could revolutionise the whole sport’s regulation. You’ve no idea how much effort we have to put into maintaining all our wards and illusions. Would have needed much more parchment-work if this whole thing was on land, let me tell you.”

By this point, the wizard from the high altitude drop test had joined them, looking rather put out and dripping water all over the wooden floor. He would have looked even more put out if he’d have known exactly what the spectator emergency evacuation procedure entailed.

His screech echoed through the air as Floating-Interest, Ludo Bagman, and Clare all watched his rapidly retreating form, which came to an abrupt stop with another loud, watery smack.

Floating-Interest winced, again.

“It’s just a shame there’s room for so few spectators,” Bagman continued. “I could easily imagine hosting a few exhibition matches here—for select fans, perhaps? I’ll certainly be lobbying for use of the duelling arena—work of pure art, that.”

From the ground on the other side of the manor came a series of loud and angry shouts, which turned out to be a team of goblins carrying an ever-iced chandelier getting in the way of a team of house-elves levitating a grand piano.

“I say, are you sure you’re going to be ready in time?” Ludo Bagman asked.

Floating-Interest smiled another easy smile. “I assure you, human, we have everything under complete control.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 0 days … and three hours

“Move, you slackers! My father will be here to inspect our work soon! Do you want to explain to the head of the Boneslicer clan why this place still looks like a dragon-shit pile?! Why isn’t that painting up yet?! What do you mean, ‘The wizard with the sticking charms went home?!’—Then go down to Granger Cottage and get Miss Cooper!—I don’t care if she doesn’t know the spell! Teach it to her!—Yes, in a few hours! Get on it!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 0 days … and two hours

“No, you idiots! Don’t put that there! The house-elves won’t be able to spell the floor polished if you pile up all this crap here. I don’t care if it’s only temporary! They’re going to start in twenty minutes, not your fantasy thirty! No, it’s not only ten minutes! They need the floor polished before they can roll out the carpet for the orchestral! No—I don’t—If you don’t move your shit right now, I swear to hell you will feel my blade!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 0 days … and one hour

“Move! Move! Faster! Faster! There’s plaster dust upstairs! You! Why is there rubbish still here?! It should be on the barge heading to the mainland! What do you mean, delayed?! That doesn’t matter! Get it moving now! Oh, dragon-crap, is father keyed into the floo? Junk-Bond! Is my father—He isn’t?! Plato!—Can you … Oh, thank hells. Wait, the barge! I need to go, but I want everything clean by the time I get back!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

T-minus 0 days … and thirty minutes

“What the hell is this?! There’s still cleaning to be done! Why is there string lying around?! From the carpets?! Do I need to order you to punish yourself, you incompetent house-elf?! Do you think I care that Lord Parkinson is your master?! While working here, I am your mistress, and if I tell you to jump, you say, ‘from where?’!”

The floo in the entrance way flared green.

Floating-Interest gasped. She whirled around. It couldn’t be her father, she thought wildly. It was too early. The head of the Boneslicer clan was never early. He was always right on time.

But it was him.

Out of the floo walked Ragnok Boneslicer, decked out in full chain mail and carrying his massive war axe. He looked around the small entrance room—a room which had a view to the grand ballroom—the grand ballroom in which the Earth-shaped memory library was currently hovering and turning above the wood-inlaid floor, and grinned. “I like the interesting ones.”

Floating-Interest slowly felt the knot in her chest uncoil. Her father nodded along as she guided him through the manor, asking pointed questions, but in general looking like he approved of the job she’d done.

“I find myself impressed, daughter,” he eventually declared, after she’d shown him the double layered warding system that would totally surround the island both at the water’s edge, and a hundred meters out to sea. “When I received the updated specs from Lord Slytherin, I didn’t immediately believe it could be done. But you proved it could be. You work hard. You work those around you hard. And you keep your dignity. I will have to see about moving you to one of our elite teams.”

“Thank you, Father.”

They started walking back up to the manor and Floating-Interest couldn’t help looking back on the time she’d spent here. Slytherin Manor was probably the most unique magical building she’d ever been asked to build. So full of secrets, even by magical standards. It was like being there when Hogwarts had first been completed. But soon her time here would be over. Just another project to add to her ever-growing resume. She’d miss it. But for those who were to live here, the stories were only just beginning.

They reached the doorway back to the main hall.

Floating-Interest looked back down the hill, and out across the water, and smiled.

“By the way, daughter, there are two rooms on your ‘unofficial’ plans that you haven’t shown me. I think I’d like to see them too.”

Floating-Interest’s smile froze. Crap.

Plato popped into being beside them. “Plato can show pretty goblin girl’s daddy if he likes.”

Crap!

Ragnok raised an eyebrow. “Plato? You are Slytherin’s head elf are you not? I’ve heard reports that you’ve been of great help to my daughter. I would be very interested to hear more about that.”

“Plato will happily tell pretty goblin girl’s daddy everything.”

CRAP!

Floating-Interest could only watch on, helpless, heart pounding, as her father and Plato turned and started walking towards the house-elf quarters. If the house-elf said even half of anything … let alone the totality of everything …

Then Plato turned his head behind her father’s back, looked her right in the eyes, shook his head, smirked, and winked.

He wasn’t really going to say anything.

That little shit!

Floating-Interest felt her knees go weak.

But, she was safe.

Chapter End Notes

—End of Chapter Fifty-two—

A/N: I hope you enjoyed the bonus chapter! Normally, I do these bonus chapters about half-way through the planning process for the next set of chapters, but for this one, I’m almost done with the prep work for what’s to come, so you can expect new updates on the discord much sooner, if that’s your thing.

A/N: I’ve also updated my Twitch streaming program and refocused specifically on writers and writing. I now stream three times a week on Mondays, Wednesdays, and Fridays, from 5:00 UTC to 8:00 UTC.

Mondays is dedicated to fan-fiction and Dodging Prison and Stealing Witches in particular (recordings, editing, readings, etc).

Wednesday’s stream is called Let’s Write a Story, and features live writing of a full-length work, with plenty of twitch chat input (We’re starting with one of my old fan-fics, ‘Harry Potter is the Boy-who-Lived, Child Hero for Hire).

And Friday’s stream is the Hardcore Writing Boot Camp, where I challenge myself to complete writing prompts against a timer (I also do writing critiques of submitted work). If writing is your thing you might like to check that out. Details are on the discord or in my Ao3 profile.

A/N: This chapter was drafted and made available early through the LeadVonE discord server, as will the next one. If you fancy discussing this chapter with like-minded people, or anything else DP&SW, feel free to head over there.

A special thank you to the following people for helping catch mistakes on #dpasw-editorial: ASK, Chuck, Dragonbait, drakonpie250, dutchy-jin, FartyArtyPartyPooper, Fuuryuu, Gloweye, Leyrann, MageKing17, Magic Bird Dust, SmartyPants, sfu, Tendra, and Violet_Ivy

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2019’s prices.

Movers and Shakers—Part 1

’Twas the night before Christmas, and all through the manor, wizards and witches a’gathered, to completely make a pig’s ear of muggle traditions.

Lily Potter’s eyes scanned her many guests again, secretly despairing at the number who continued to turn up to her yearly tribute to the most important western muggle holiday in flowing red robes, trimmed with white fur, and sporting either fake or transfigured long white beards. Even after ten years, they still didn’t quite understand. Some of the more traditional kept glancing nervously at the mistletoe hung up over doors, occasionally muttering about nargles.

It wasn’t all bad though.

The Weird Sisters were pitch-perfect playing, ‘Merry Christmas Everyone‘, brightly-coloured tinsel festooned the room like the world’s longest cat, and the house elves had long ago mastered muggle festive foods, which happily included mince pies, Christmas pudding, and mulled wine.

Lily took a small bite from her own mince pie and smiled. She’d have to remember to take some to the boys when she could shake these utter bores.

“And then what happened, Lady Potter?” asked Lord Updike—owner of a magical fish farm in the glens far up north. His temporary beard went down to his knees.

“Yes, do tell us,” gushed his wife, “Slytherin seems to be popping up more and more recently.” She gasped. “Do you think he’s going to make some ‘big move’ soon?” She’d styled her beard in curls.

Lily frowned. The incident had happened soon after Harry had been cured of petrification. The free house elf was still on the loose, and …

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The large stone corridors of Hogwarts had been bitingly cold, but the teacher’s lounge, at least, was always warm and cozy.

“But how could a house elf be on the loose?” Lily whispered.

Opposite her, Severus looked pensive. “It’s very rare, Lily. It is not enough to simply present an elf with clothes to free it, there is a whole ritual to go with it. And for an elf to be able to maintain its presence on the mortal plane would require an extremely strong purpose. The Department for the Regulation and Control of Magical Creatures will have a field day when they find out.”

“I’m going to have to check the wards around Potter Manor,” Lily said. “I know James says they’re better than the best gold can buy, but I’m not taking any chances. What if that elf is on someone’s orders? What if it’s one of our political enemies?” Her voice lowered further. “What if it’s Slytherin?”

Severus looked contemplative. “Not impossible, but I have my doubts. The bludgers were targeting Ginny Weasley, and I have my suspicions that she’s a student of the Gray.”

Lily nodded. She shared those suspicions too. Given how close the girl appeared to be to Harry, it was hard not to. “So, who?”

“I’d guess a rogue lord of either the Dark or the Light.”

Lily narrowed her eyes. “If I find out it was someone in the Light, I will whip them into line so hard no amount of dittany will help them.”

“And I will gladly help you. In the meantime, we can only wait for Slytherin to show up, and until then, the aurors will have to stay on full alert.”

“I just hope Harry won’t suffer long-term effects from the petrification.”

Severus snorted. “I dare say your son is resilient enough to cope. He has been through plenty in his life.” He gave her a meaningful look.

Lily looked uncomfortably off to the side.

“In any case,” he continued, “Dumbledore will want to know about these developments, so I suggest we arrange a meeting soon. He always had a soft spot for the house elves, and now four of them are dead.”

“None of this would have happened if Dumbledore were here,” Lily said. “I know Gilderoy means well, but he just doesn’t have as strong a handle on things as Dumbledore did. Was bullying as big of a problem before, or am I just misremembering? I’ve had seven students come to me in just the last month.”

Snape shrugged. “It was and it wasn’t. Bullying was more of an in-house thing before. Now it’s becoming increasingly inter-house. Dumbledore was always dead set against that.”

“And what about all the contraband?” Lily continued. “I swear, the number of banned items I’ve had to confiscate from students recently has gone up five-fold. Where are they getting it all?”

“I don’t know.”

Just then, Lily heard multiple footsteps coming down the hallway outside. She and Severus stood up from their chairs, just as the door opened, and the masked figure of Lord Slytherin swept in, followed quickly by Headmaster Lockhart, Sirius Black, Kingsley Shacklebolt, and Richard Vablatsky, head of the Department for the Regulation and Control of Magical Creatures.

“When I find that demon, I’ll have its head!” Vablatsky roared. “Oh, Lady Potter.” His voice calmed. “What a surprise.”

Lily’s gaze didn’t shift from the masked man in front of her, who gave her a polite nod of acknowledgement before turning back to the group. “This will do well,” he said, and gracefully sat down in the plushest of the room’s many chairs. “Finding the correct wards for demonic incursions will take time. I suspect many other wards will be tied into it, but once I have found it, it will simply be a matter of reweaving the correct enchantments.”

Just then, the door opened again, and, of all people, Minister Fudge barged in. “Wait!” He stood in the door opening, huffing and puffing. “I know what you’re planning, and you can’t!”

Everyone stared at him.

“I beg your pardon?” Sirius said.

The minister got his breath back. “Umm … what I mean is that, Lord Slytherin, as much as I respect your ancestral rights to Hogwarts, the age of magical fortresses is over. We live in the time of the ministries now, and the world is much better for it, I think we can all agree on that. The wards of Hogwarts are as strong as they could possibly need to be, and there is no need to strengthen them, or bring any of the old wards back into use, or—”

“—Minister, there is a free house elf on the loose.”

Vablatski’s words caused the blood to drain out of Fudge’s face. It was like his entire body did a one-eighty shift from bluster to shock. “A … a free house elf?”

“Yes, Minister.”

“But I thought … Ah—I—I—Um …”

His spluttering was interrupted by Slytherin. “Minister, I understand your concerns, but I think we can all agree that the safety of the students should come first. Perhaps we can agree to a limited time period of, as you’d put it, ‘Magical Fortress Hogwarts’? Say, three months? That should give the ministry enough time to track down the culprit?”

Minister Fudge straightened. “Three months? Three months. Yes, That’s acceptable. But after that it all comes back down, agreed?”

“Of course, minister.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Back in Potter Manor, the Weird Sisters had just finished Merry Xmas Everybody and had moved onto Mistletoe and Wine.

… ”We didn’t find the house elf when the old wards came back up, but at least we knew it had left.” Lily finished giving a much-edited version of events to her small circle of guests. Several others had joined them during the telling. It was the fourth telling of that particular story tonight.

Lord Updike shook his head. “Did the Minister really think Slytherin was trying to seize control of Hogwarts to use as his own private fortress?”

“I don’t agree with Hogwarts having its wards strengthened like in the old days,” said one Heiress Bolingbroke, adult daughter of another of the Light’s oldest supporters. “But still, a free house elf. Who would be so insane as to try to keep a free house elf?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

On the other side of the Potter Ballroom, Sirius Black cursed James for leaving him all alone with the sharks.

“I’m so sorry to hear about the problems you’ve been having with your daughter, my child,” said a particularly ancient wizard, whose name Sirius knew he should know.

“It’s no problem,” Sirius said tersely. “She’s free to follow her own path. Just like I was.”

“Do you really believe that? Or have you just lost control of her?” asked a witch who had the kind of distinctive face that was only achieved with several large overdoses of beautification potion.

“Not at all. Alex is an independent girl and I’m very proud of her.”

“You mustn’t blame yourself. It was probably her mother’s blood.”

Sirius gritted his teeth. “I assure you, Madam—”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Oh, oh! Mister Hale, what a pleasure to see you here. Can I present to you, my daughter?” Arthur Weasley beamed with his hand on Ginny’s shoulder.

Mister Hale, manager of Bobmin Moor Quidditch Stadium, had been looking around the ballroom with the kind of smug self-satisfaction oft-worn by those who were hitting well above their own social class. The moment he saw Ginny, though, that smug look vanished and his eyes widened in genuine excitement. “I say! Is this young Ginevra? Arthur, you rogue! You must know she’s been the talk of Puddlemere for weeks.”

“I did have a suspicion.”

“You must find time to bring her to Bodmin! Oh, I’m sorry.” He turned to Ginny. “Mister Hale, Miss Weasley, at your service. I’m not going to beat about the bush—you keep flying like that and I’m going to have to talk Ludo into getting you an age exemption for league play.”

A corner of Ginny’s lips quirked upwards.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Well, well, well. Look what the cat dragged in.”

Xenophilius Lovegood turned around with a mince pie in each hand and another in his mouth to find himself looking at a wizard in his mid-twenties with a smirk on his face and a glint in his eye. He swallowed and smiled widely. “Terrance, my old friend! How are you these days? Haven’t seen you since—”

“Since you left the Light to run off with that masked, unknown lord.”

“Ah, well, you know how it is.”

“I really don’t. I’m surprised you have the balls to show your face around here.”

“You’d be surprised what I’ve had the balls to do recently.”

“Oh?”

Xeno put a friendly arm around Terrance, leaned in, and whispered. “Can’t talk about it, though. Very hush hush.”

Terrance rolled his eyes. “So why are you and the rest of the Grubbies here?” He nodded towards where Lords Greengrass, Smith, Davies, Slughorn, and Tempest were investigating the massive charmed Christmas tree in the middle of the ballroom.

“Grubbies?” Xeno barked a laugh. “I’ll have to remember that one. You must have heard that Lord Potter wants to twist our arms about the Muggle Protection Act. It not passing before end of session was a blessing and a curse. On the one hand, it gives us more time to hash out details, but on the other, the longer we prattle on the less likely anything is going to actually pass.”

“Mmmm … I can see how that might be problematic. So is Slytherin himself going to grace us with his presence? I’m sure he was invited.”

Xeno rubbed the back of his neck. “Ah, yes, about that …”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Augusta, did you see where Susan ran off to? Sunny and Pandora haven’t seen her for years. I want to make sure they don’t miss her.”

Augusta Longbottom gave the Head of the DMLE a soft smile. “I believe I saw her leaving with John Potter, Amelia.”

“Oh, then it’ll probably be the second playroom. I know John had Virgo Malfoy stashed up there.”

Augusta’s smile vanished, something which Amelia Bones immediately caught. She gave her friend an accusing look. “Miss Malfoy is under a lot of pressure from her parents, you know.” She put extra emphasis on the word pressure, as if to communicate all sorts of contextual undercurrents—undercurrents possibly involving rope, bricks, and a good strong sack. “It can’t be easy for a muggle-raised girl to be expected to fit into such a traditional Dark family so suddenly. It’s a very encouraging step that they allowed her to attend at all. The least we can do is offer our full support.”

Augusta sighed. “Yes, I suppose, you are right. It’s just so difficult to think of the Malfoys as anything other than trouble.”

“Trust me. I know exactly what you mean.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Hey, look. Isn’t that Slytherin’s muggleborn girl?”

“The one who fought the troll?”

“The one who caught Dumbledore’s stunner.”

“I’ve heard Lord Slytherin put her through all kinds of dark rituals. Dozens! How else would you explain how one of her kind could do so well at Hogwarts?”

“Now, I take exception to that.”

“Well, how do you explain it?”

“…”

“That’s what I thought.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Should you even be with me?” Hermione asked. “Won’t it be troublesome if word of our talking like this gets back to Draco and the others?”

“Oh, relax,” Alex said, bringing a dollop of whipped cream to her tongue, tasting it, and pulling a disgusted face. “I’ve got a plan for if that happens. And I’ve got to talk to someone. It’s mostly all Light and Gray here. Who else would I talk to? You want me to stick by my dad the whole time? That would look even weirder.”

Hermione sighed. “I suppose so.”

“Besides, I’ve dressed for it.”

Hermione had to admit that this was true. Alexandra Black looked like a teenager’s idea of what a dark lady looked like, at least at the base layer. i.e, black lace, ruffled skirts, corsetry, high heels, puffed sleeves, and a traditional witches hat, but with the not unimportant addition of a see-through black veil. It was just a shame, Hermione thought, that the first-year didn’t yet have the figure to properly pull off the look. In the sea of red and white Father Christmas knock-offs filling the hall, what Alexandra Black actually looked like was a rather short lump of coal.

“You’ll still need to find something to do while we’re upstairs,” Hermione said. “There’s no way you’d be able to explain that away if John Potter found you with us up there.”

“I’m sure I’ll find something. I just wish I could say the same about winter snacks that aren’t sweet.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Hi, Neville.”

“Oh, hi Ron. Managed to shake your parents?”

Ron grinned. “No need. Dad’s with Ginny and Mum’s on the hunt for Slytherin. She’s been looking for a chance to interrogate him for years, you know.”

“You think he’ll turn up here?”

“How am I supposed to know?”

Neville shrugged. “You’re closer friends with John than I am. And he’s always going on about Lord Slytherin this and Lord Slytherin that. Figured if anyone knew anything it’d be him.”

“Nah, he’s been with Susan and Virgo more recently. Heir business, you know.”

Neville let out a long-suffering sigh. “Unfortunately, I do.”

Ron elbowed him good-naturedly in the ribs. “Cheer up! You’re at a party. Never seen some of this stuff before. What are these little ones called?”

“That’s a mince pie, Ron.”

“It’s good!”

“This is your first time at the Potter Christmas Party, isn’t it?”

“Sure is. What’s the massive tree in the middle for? Some special ritual?”

“It’s where muggles put their winter festival gifts.”

Ron swallowed his last piece of mince pie. “Odd, but to each their own. You haven’t seen Smith or Boot, have you?”

“The Smiths had to cancel. The Boots weren’t invited this year,” Neville rattled with the ease of the over-prepared.

“Oh.” Ron’s eyes, tracking around the ballroom as though looking for them anyway, fell on one small group, and narrowed. The fact that the group happened to contain a boy their own age with roguishly messy black hair, green eyes, and a scar on his forehead, probably played a large role in this.

Neville followed his gaze. “You never liked John’s brother, did you?”

“He’s a slimy snake.”

“So John keeps saying.”

Ron looked annoyed. “No, it’s not that. There are Slytherins like Malfoy and Granger, and all the others, and they’re one thing. But that one … ugh, he makes me shiver.”

“Why?”

“Have you ever seen him smile?”

“He smiles all the time.”

“That’s the point! He smiles even when he has no reason to. When someone tells a joke, he just smiles while everyone else laughs. If someone buggers up a spell in class, he just smiles before showing them how it’s done properly.”

“It’s very helpful.”

“It’s creepy is what it is. It’s like he’s found one emotion that works, so he just sticks to it all the time.”

Neville carefully inspected the younger Potter as best he was able to from as far away as he was. It wasn’t easy as there were at least three or four grown-ups jockeying around him at that moment. Potter could certainly cut a striking figure when he wanted to. The way he stood made him appear several inches taller. His robes looked custom-tailored—not unusual for children of their status, but the way he wore them was somehow more regal. Lord Potter stood close by, watching with the air of an amateur lion tamer bringing their new charge in front of a live audience for the very first time.

Harry Potter was smiling. He was smiling like the whole world was a joke and only he knew the punchline.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Lord James Potter was not a man easy to worry. He’d signed up with the DMLE straight out of Hogwarts, got into the auror training academy not long after (a very fancy name for a few large empty rooms in the Ministry basement), served a brief stint in the war against the Dark Lord, and then retired to enter to the world of politics, where a wizard had to at all times keep his wits about him, lest they end up broke, disgraced, and in a magically-binding contract betrothing their as-yet unborn great-great-granddaughter to the great-great-grandson of their worst political enemy.

Under most circumstances, Lord James Potter was not an easy man to worry, but when it came to his sons, both Harry and John, he nevertheless found himself worrying on a fairly regular basis.

“Oh, bravo!”

“Good show!”

“My, my, so talented.”

The crowd of lords and ladies clapped as Harry wandlessly conjured an exquisite glass replica of the Statue of Wizardly Brotherhood, and handed it to one of the younger witches, who giggled. She was in her mid-twenties.

James smiled tightly. He was very aware that the impressive display was not the result of Harry Potter, raised spare of the house of Potter, but rather Harry Potter, raised cat’s paw of the House of Slytherin. Wizarding lords did not normally include provisions in marriage contracts for children of their house to be raised by their daughter’s new families for exactly this reason. No one wanted a potential heir raised by someone else’s house.

This was compounded by a shocking revelation that had taken place just before they’d ushered in the first of their guests that evening.

Both Harry and John had been standing side by side by the huge doors, both dressed immaculately, and both being fussed over by Lily.

“And make sure you keep your hat angled correctly, John. You tend to let it slip. Now, let’s see, Harry … hat—good, robes—good, you’re using correct hair potions, I see—good.” She frowned. “Where’s your ring? You really should keep it visible during formal events.”

James knew something was wrong the moment Harry’s expression changed to one of mild confusion. “Ring?”

“Yes, ring, you know, your house ring.” Lily turned to look at him with wide eyes. “James, you did show him didn’t you?”

James blanched. “I … I kind of assumed Slytherin had already shown him.”

The resulting bollocking hadn’t been pleasant, and at the end of it all, they hadn’t had time to show Harry how to summon his Potter Noble House Ring. That had to be put off until they found a free moment. Knowing that Harry had been walking around for years without mental protection was actually horrifying. On top of that, the prophecy they’d seen from the Department of Mysteries said that they were now supposed to control Harry to stop the fall of magic. The fact that someone else may well have been doing so instead was not a good feeling.

“How’s he handling it?” asked a voice. It was Lily, holding two small plates of finger food.

“Good,” he replied. “He’s a natural.”

Lily sighed. “Makes you wonder, doesn’t it? About what might have been.”

“It does. But, we mustn’t allow that to blind us to our responsibilities now.”

“All of them.”

“Yes, all of them.”

Just then, on the other side of the room, the floo by which guests arrived flared green and a tall bearded wizard stepped out. The wizard cleaned his robes with a careless wave of his hand and looked around the hall with a kind smile.

Standing just to one side of the floo, the Master of Ceremonies caught the new arrival’s eye, nodded respectfully, cleared his throat and called out across the hall, “Lords and Ladies, Wizards and Witches, Order of Merlin, First Class, Chief Warlock of the Wizengamot, and Supreme Mugwump of the International Confederation of Wizards, Albus Percival Wulfric Brian Dumbledore!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Headmaster Lockhart frowned as the attention of the group he’d been regaling with astonishing tales of derring-do shifted to the new arrival.

Arriving early had clearly been a mistake.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“James! Lily.” Dumbledore smiled and turned towards the hosting couple as they drew near. He’d somehow already found a glass of eggnog with a stick of cinnamon in it. “I must thank you greatly for the invitation. I must admit, I was wondering if I would be receiving one this year.”

Lily gave the ex-headmaster what could only be described as a look. “I won’t pretend I didn’t seriously consider not sending it—”

Dumbledore’s face became solemn.

“—But seeing as how no permanent damage seems to have been done, I believe we should look instead to the future.”

“I can only apologise again, Lily.”

“And I have not yet accepted that apology. Your handling of my son will be a permanent stain on your character, Albus.”

The entranceway was far from empty. More than a few knowing glances were exchanged between watchful eyes attached to listening ears.

“Enough,” James said. “This is a celebration of the good in the world. Albus, won’t you follow me? I’d like to show you the enchantments we’ve added to the tree this year.”

“I’d be delighted.”

As they moved into hall proper, the many groups thinned, providing some semblance of privacy—with the right spells, of course.

Dumbledore smiled. “Congratulations, by the way, on winning the Animagus Hunt this year,”

James smiled back wryly. The Greengrass Winter Festival was one of the highlights of his year. It was one of the few opportunities for animagi to really let loose in Britain. This year’s had been particularly fun. He’d narrowly avoided being tagged by Slytherin’s girls by jumping a massive ditch that their horse couldn’t follow him over. “Thank you,” he said. “It was certainly easier without Slytherin himself on my tail.”

“So it is true?” Dumbledore asked. “Lord Slytherin was not at the Greengrass Winter Festival this year?”

“No. Or if he was, I certainly didn’t see him.”

“Curious. One would imagine that he’d be keen to be seen, given his own upcoming gala night.”

James shrugged. “From what I’ve heard, he wasn’t at the Malfoy Yule Ball either.”

“And also not here.”

James frowned. “No.”

“Are you going to go to his gala night?”

James sighed. “I’m not sure. We really should. It’s important for the Muggle Protection Act, but … I don’t know. Might look weak. He hasn’t done us the courtesy of showing up. In previous years I’d understand, but this year?”

“I would encourage you to go anyway. If Lord Slytherin wishes to act childish that is no reason to imitate him.”

James thought for a moment before replying, “Yes, you’re right of course. Thank you.”

“I see Lily is still angry at me.”

“She and I both, Albus. Harry isn’t too chuffed with you either, you can imagine.”

Albus sighed. “No, I imagine not. I was hoping to have the opportunity to talk with him about it, in fact.”

“That shouldn’t be difficult.” James scanned the ballroom, looking for his youngest son. He’d almost certainly be in the centre of some group of adults, charming them with his ridiculous magical talents. But no matter where he looked, he couldn’t find him.

The moment Albus Dumbledore had shown up, Harry had vanished.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Upstairs, well away from the general bustle of the party, Harry closed the door he’d just stepped through, further muffling the sounds from downstairs.

“Finished showing off, have you?”

Harry turned to find his brother not far up the corridor. He smiled. “Nothing you haven’t also done, brother. I heard you were quite enthusiastic to display your special talents last year. And it’s all for the good of House Potter. Have to display our best face.”

“As if you give a toss about the house of Potter.”

Harry made his way past John and turned back. “I care enough to learn. I hope you haven’t forgotten our agreement after the polyjuice incident.”

John scowled. “Yeah, yeah, I’ll show you where the family magic is. Tomorrow?”

“Tonight would be better. Don’t want Mother and Father interrupting us, after all.”

“Slimy Slytherin.”

“Through and through.” He watched John walk away. It wasn’t surprising that they’d chosen the playrooms furthest apart from each other to host their little hideouts from the main party.

As Harry turned back and made his way on his path, he caught snatches of conversation and goings-on through open doors. In one room, a small group of post-Hogwarts wizards were rather loudly discussing politics. In another, an older wizard was mentoring a younger on the finer points of metallic alchemy. And yet another held a mismatched couple who obviously thought their privacy charms were stronger than they actually were, given their rather enthusiastic state of undress. Most of the rooms he passed through, were either empty or containing children or Hogwarts students too bored to spend more than an hour or two downstairs.

The room he was making his way towards would be one of the empty ones—empty save for a magical, space-expanded, multi-compartment, shrinkable trunk.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Daphne stared at the blackboard that hung from one wall of the trunk, chalk in hand. The board was covered in the names of wizards and organisations with arrows linking them and circles surrounding groups of them. Many of those circles overlapped each other, sometimes several times.

Six of those names had been written in all-caps and underlined with coloured chalk.

The Dark

The Gray

The Light

The Ministry

The Judiciary

Gringotts

Around the corners, several names were completely separate from the main mess of lines and circles in the middle. The Flamels, the Arwen, the Lupins.

In the very top-right corner, the letters, “RAB” were circled alongside a massive question mark.

“Okay,” Daphne muttered, “this is the current political situation as best I can make it. Lord Black could potentially come to our side, if we played our cards right. The Weasleys don’t have a seat, but their father is a skilled influencer. My father has his spies in the ministry, while we’re doing our best to infiltrate the Dark. Ragnok is firmly on our side, but there are other goblin clans who don’t like us, and we don’t have even a single set of eyes on the judge’s bench. Having one would be amazing, but those positions only come up once in a blue moon.”

Daphne turned around.

“What do you think, Luna? Have I missed anyone important? Anyone who could potentially be a threat?”

Luna Lovegood, the only other witch in the trunk, inspected the blackboard with unblinking eyes. She then quietly stood up, drifted over to the board, took the chalk from Daphne’s unresisting fingers, and on an otherwise empty bit of the board, in large capital letters, wrote, “The Muggles.” She then underlined it twice in the fashion of the six other major power players and sat back down.

Daphne stared at the new letters. “Oh,” she said. “I guess I should have remembered to add them.”

A knock on the trunk’s roof caused the two girls to turn sharply. Chances were it was Harry or one of the others, but no point in taking stupid risks. The blackboard flipped in on itself, showing a completely blank face. Daphne crossed the room, and after a series of knocks and counter knocks, opened the trunk’s lid from the inside.

“Harry!”

Harry smiled warmly and hugged her before following her down the steps and doing the same for Luna.

Then his face turned serious. “We have a situation. My parents have discovered that I’m not wearing the Potter family ring. If I’m forced to summon it, the Albion Family Magics will check and update my status as a son of the house of Potter.”

Daphne frowned, flipped her blackboard over again and stared at it, again.

Under the name Harry Potter were written the words, Heir Potter(?). They wouldn’t know for certain until they tried, obviously. No one truly knew how the Albion Family Magics worked. And this was a very unusual situation. But Harry did technically have a soul age older than John’s. And since Fate and Death’s intervention, soul age was what was supposed to determine things like this.

“So, what’s the plan?” she asked.

Harry shrugged. “Avoid and distract. If I can hold it off until we leave for Hogwarts again, that’s another four months of not having to deal with it, or at least, having to deal with Lord Potter. But I doubt they’ll be that irresponsible. Ironically.”

“They couldn’t force you to summon it, could they?”

“No, but I have to weigh the pros of being seen to be deliberately disobedient versus the cons of having them see Slytherin as a directly malevolent force.”

“You think they would attribute your being the Potter Heir as Slytherin’s doing?”

Harry tapped various names on the blackboard. “There would only be a few ways you could potentially pull off something like this, outside of the actual truth, and all of them require powerful friends.”

“Could we not just let it all play out?” Luna asked. “Seeing John’s face if it was true would be funny.”

Harry smirked. “Maybe after Slytherin Gala Night. I’m sure John’s got enough on his plate right now with the teenage dark lord he’s romancing.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Virgo could be very cute, when she wasn’t being very scary. These were John Potter’s thoughts as he watched in mild awe as Virgo described all the different rituals the three of them could go through, either individually, or as a group, while using a teddy bear taken from one of the shelves to show how some of them could royally fuck you up.

Virgo, him, and Susan were sitting on the floor in a circle in the middle of the darkened room. Susan still wasn’t showing any signs of being comfortable with the idea of using rituals, unsupervised, at their age, but as he’d pointed out to her, “If we can’t even beat kids our age, how are we supposed to beat Voldemort?” That had shut her up.

Virgo put the teddy bear back together again with a flick of her wand after a rather vicious demonstration, letting the stuffing and fur knit itself back together. “Of course, the downside of most of these rituals is that their results can be extreme, or simply extremely visible. Sure, you can turn yourself into a giant with massive magical resistance at the cost of most of your wits, but good luck getting the rest of the wizarding world to accept you. The trick is to identify the right ritual that works specifically for your situation. One where the downsides are negligible and the upsides are many.”

“The downsides just seem so many,” Susan said. “I don’t want to go bald, or suffer from rickets, or give up my firstborn child to the fair folk. Why can’t there be one that gives a huge power upgrade and only costs something like, I dunno, bad morning breath?”

Virgo smirked. “I don’t know the why, but if there was such a ritual that people knew about, everyone would use it, the power balance would equal itself out, and all you’d have to show for it would be a culture where bad breath was a sign of status.”

Susan grimaced.

“So, are there any we can do?” John asked.

Virgo tapped her chin. “You had the right idea with the balance one back at the quidditch match. We could certainly do that. We just have to make sure to do it properly. And I have a few that I managed to acquire from the Malfoy Library. They need a Malfoy to perform, but can have other participants in them as well.” Virgo turned back to Susan. “What about you? Do you have anything you can share with us from the Bones Library?”

“I—um …” Susan began. “That is to say, yes, probably, but if Auntie caught me sneaking around that part of the library, I don’t even want to begin to imagine the trouble I’d be in. I do know of some of our family rituals, like there’s one that lets you see in extreme detail. Auntie uses it when investigating crime scenes, but it causes extreme nearsightedness in one eye.”

“Is that why she wears a monocle?”

Susan nodded. “And what about the Potter Library?”

John groaned. “Don’t remind me about the Potter Library. I have to show Harry how to get in soon.”

“Couldn’t you remove or hide some of the better stuff beforehand?” Virgo asked. “Just for while he’s there. Then you could put it back again afterwards.”

John grinned. “Brilliant. Why haven’t I gotten you a declaration of intention gift, yet?”

He was expecting Virgo to either ignore him and deflect (unlikely), or curse him (more likely). These would fit the mental picture he had built up of Virgo Malfoy. But what he hadn’t expected was for her to catch Susan’s eye, put her head to one side, lock eyes with him, and say calmly, “I don’t know, Potter, why haven’t you?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Back in the Gray Playroom, Hermione had finally turned up. “But I don’t understand,” she said, “who is this Regulus Black? I don’t remember that name from any of the family history books. And why is he so important?”

Harry rubbed his temples. “Regulus Black was … is the younger brother of Sirius Black. He fought alongside Voldemort in the last war—a death eater—and became a prison guard for one of his soul pieces, a task it appears he failed at. He disappeared after taking on the task, and was never seen again, in either timeline, which is worrying to say the least. Why now? What changed?”

Hermione had a hand over her mouth in shock. “But if Lord Black’s brother is alive …”

“Yes, Alex’s position as heiress is threatened. As a witch, if Sirius died, the lordship would first pass to Regulus before Alex. If he then had children, they would come before her.”

“And how did Alexandra take that?” Daphne asked.

“Amazingly well, actually. She still has her heiress ring, so she still has options. Getting betrothed would secure her position, for one.”

Daphne smirked. “I take it she has a candidate in mind?”

“Oddly enough, she does. In her characteristically headstrong way. She was very blasé about it. Although getting Lord Black to sign the parchment-work will certainly be a challenge. That man despises betrothals. I suspect it would be easier getting your parents to sign such a thing, Hermione.”

Hermione blushed bright red.

“That would be wonderful,” Luna said, clapping enthusiastically. “Then you’d only need Ginny to complete the set.”

“I still think Black isn’t worthy of being with you like that,” Hermione muttered, still bright red. “Tracey would deserve it more.”

Daphne frowned. “It isn’t for you to pick who our lord is in negotiations with.”

“I know, I know. It’s just, she can be really immature at times.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Headmaster Lockhart looked out over the crowd of noble and important wizards and witches at the Potter Christmas Party and preened. Yes, Dumbledore was attracting a lot of the attention that should be going to him, but by all accounts the party was going very well.

His only other qualm was that Lord Slytherin hadn’t shown yet, but no matter. He had an invitation to the Slytherin Gala Night and the man just had to be there.

“Excuse me,” said a girl’s voice from his right and down.

“Yes—?” He turned around, looked down, and almost took his eye out on the pointy black hat.

The young witch tilted her head back, eyes wide as he cursed with a hand over his eye. “Oh, don’t you worry about that,” he chortled while his eye streamed. “It happens. Miss Black, correct?”

“Heiress Black,” the girl corrected with bite. Then she hesitated. “Um, actually I was wondering if …”

Lockhart realised the girl was holding one of his Boy-Who-Lived adventure books to her chest—holding it as tightly as a druggie might hold mandrake leaf.

“Aha! A fan!” Lockhart beamed. “Want me to sign, no doubt?”

Miss Black looked immensely relieved and nodded quickly.

“Well, let’s have that here. Ahh! The Boy-Who-Lived and The Mystery of Yeti Town-Hill—quite possibly my favourite of the series.”

Miss Black’s eyes lit up. “Oh, yes! The way the Boy-Who-Lived actually got help from the Black Witch of the North and was able to break up the cabal.”

Lockhart made the last flourish with his peacock-feather quill and snapped the book shut. “Yes, that was pretty clever, if I do say so myself, which I do.” He leaned forward and gave the girl a conspiratorial wink. “To be honest, that was about as morally ambiguous as I could get away with for a children’s book. The publisher was extremely nervous about that one, I don’t mind telling you.”

“Really?” The girl was hanging on his every word. “I don’t suppose I could ask you a few questions about the story, could I?”

Lockhart beamed. “Of course. Questions are always welcome.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“No questions?” Hermione asked. The blackboard was full of scribbles about the progress of various projects.

Harry, Luna, and Daphne all shook their heads.

“Good. Next!” Hermione flicked her wand, transfigured the chalk into a long pointy stick, snatched it out of the air, and smacked it into the blackboard with a loud fwap sound. “The full itinerary of our findings from the sunken ship and the Icelandic dragon cave. In total we have identified twenty-three enchantments, five charms, seven curses, and two rune patterns that are sufficiently different from those currently used to probably not trip patent charms. Mum and Dad are going through the records to identify who these enchantments might hold the most value for. We’ve also found some incomplete magics that could potentially be really powerful.”

Harry leaned forward in his chair. “Go on.”

“The first is a ritual. It took quite a bit of translating from Sanskrit, but it seems to be the second half of a two-part ritual to make someone a metamorphmagus.”

Three pairs of eyes widened slightly.

“Too bad it’s only the second half,” Daphne mused.

“The next is an incomplete variation of the space expansion charm that seems to work only on boats, which I might be able to get working with enough arithmancy crunching.”

Harry nodded. “Valuable. Hold off on that until you’ve started formal arithmancy studies.”

Hermione looked dismayed. “But, Harry!”

“No buts. Spell discovery is dangerous if you haven’t already mapped out the territory.”

Daphne tapped her chin. “Would the broomsub count as a boat?”

“That’s what I was thinking,” Hermione grumbled.

“Hermione, you are not ready. You will be soon. I will make sure you are. Trust me.”

“I understand, Harry.”

“Did we find anything else?”

“Plenty of references to the Albion Family Magics—”

Daphne’s eyes lit up.

“—But no written records of the missing rituals or anything.”

Daphne let out a disappointed sigh.

“And of course, plenty of muggle gold artefacts. I’ve been reading all the law books from the Hogwarts Library, and we should be able to get away with switching in a non-magical boat for the magical one to satisfy the ISS requirements.”

“It will have to be a very good replica,” Luna said. “Muggles are good at spotting fakes.”

“And will only get better in the future,” Harry added.

Hermione nodded. “And finally,”—she tapped the blackboard—“we have a box.”

Daphne raised an eyebrow. “Just a box?”

“It’s locked.”

“And Alohomora doesn’t open it?”

“No. It’s a magical password lock. There are snakes carved around the lock.”

The girls all looked towards Harry.

“Parseltongue password. Got it. I’ll pop down during the Slytherin Gala and we’ll sort it out then.”

“Speaking of the Slytherin Gala,” Daphne said, her voice turning uneasy. “Are we sure you’ll be able to attend?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Dumbledore sighed. “I, unfortunately, will not be able to attend the Slytherin Gala.”

Opposite him, Bill Weasley blinked. “Why not?” They were alone in a corner of the grand ballroom.

“Because I have not been invited,” Dumbledore continued. “Even the Malfoys invite me to their Yule Ball. But Slytherin? No. I can’t imagine why, but that man seems to hold some great personal enmity towards me. He has been using every opportunity he can to make things harder, and, old man that I am, I haven’t been entirely immune from his efforts.”

Bill Weasley gaped. “But, you’re the Light Lord—the defeater of Grindelwald. Surely, even Slytherin”—his voice picked up a note of great disdain as he spoke the name—“wouldn’t be so impolite as to refuse you.”

Dumbledore smiled. “Alas, it is not so. But it does mean that I will need some eyes and ears there …”

“Well, of course, I’ll help.”

“Wonderful! There are a few matters in particular I’d like you to keep an eye on.” He lowered his voice, more for effect than any actual fear of being overheard. “The first being our young friend Harry Potter.”

Bill Weasley’s face darkened. “What about Harry Potter?” he all but growled.

Dumbledore raised a surprised eyebrow. “Just anything of interest. Anything unusual. Anything of questionable morality. But I must say, I wasn’t expecting to see such enmity in you towards a boy of only twelve.”

“Did you forget that Harry Potter has been acting under orders from Lord Slytherin to steal Ginny away from us since she was seven?”

Dumbledore chuckled. “Mister Weasley, that cannot have been—” He stopped. It could have been, couldn’t it? He’d completely forgotten that the Weasleys had an unknown benefactor who’d been teaching their youngest daughter occlumency. It was one of the small details you just lost track of in the general flood of day-to-day politics, and he’d completely dismissed that benefactor being Harry Potter at the time. But looking back, knowing what he now knew about Harry’s capabilities—about Lord Slytherin’s—it was perfectly possible. He sighed. “I remember John coming to me with these concerns last year. I wish I had not dismissed them then. It seems I too must learn to trust more.”

Bill Weasley nodded slowly. “I will keep an eye on Harry Potter. What else did you want me to look out for?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“I’m hoping it won’t be too much of a problem,” Harry said. “In the worst case, you girls will have to take turns being Harry Potter while I play Lord Slytherin. Although the Slytherin Gala Night will be the perfect opportunity to lay the foundations for the big reveal. I’ll need to be Harry Potter then.”

“Who will play Lord Slytherin?” Hermione asked.

“There is a not-insignificant chance that this deception will be spotted. We simply cannot account for all the different situations that could transpire at such a large social event. Therefore, the one who will be Lord Slytherin will be the one who will suffer the fewest consequences, and insult the fewest people, if they are caught.” Harry turned to Daphne. “In other words, Daphne, it will be you.”

Daphne took a deep, steadying breath.

Luna pouted. “Awww. I wanted to know what it is like to be a man down there. Hermione, what is it like to be a—”

“—Anyway!” Hermione loudly interrupted. “We’ve got lots to do! The animagus ritual, raising the sunken ship, preparing for the reveal, and talking to Mum and Dad, and we need to firmly establish our political platform, and all sorts of things! So we absolutely don’t have time to talk about Harry’s—about things like that.”

There was a silence.

“Indeed,” Harry said simply, although he looked more than a little amused. “Luna, I’m sorry this one won’t be on you. I’m sure you’ll get an opportunity soon.”

“I can’t wait!”

“I think I could,” Hermione muttered. “I don’t want to know what Luna would be like with one-hundred times the testosterone.”

“One-hundred times the fun!”

“Hermione,” Harry interrupted. “Why don’t you give us an update on the muggleborn project? It is very important that we’re as far ahead as possible with that. Some of our future plans could heavily rely on them.”

Hermione perked up. “Oh, right!” She cleared her throat. “All the muggleborns in our year are doing very well with the new system of occlumency training and should soon be ready to—”

There was a knocking on the trunk lid.

Three of the occupants froze for a fraction of a second, enough time for the fourth to flick his wand and hide every shred of evidence of what they’d been discussing.

“Enter!” Harry called out.

The trunk lid opened, and John Potter stuck his head inside. “Magical Merlin, look at all this stuff! Whose trunk is this!?”

Hermione glanced at Harry for confirmation before replying. “It is mine, Heir Potter.”

“Yours, Hermione?! How?! You’re not rich.”

“I may not be rich, but my lord is. Was there something you wanted?”

Harry stood up. “I dare say my brother wished to discuss some family matters with me, is that not so, brother?”

“Yeah,” John said, still distracted by the trunk’s furnishings. “Yeah, that’s right.”

Before the two left, Luna tugged on the sleeve of Harry’s robes and leant in to whisper. “About our strategic direction, my lord. I will soon have something for you to read about that.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Lily Potter looked around the ballroom again, frowning. The party had reached that time of night where the formalities and dignities of wizarding aristocracy were sufficiently washed away by alcohol, and a group of quite literal drunken lords had formed a conga line, making their way around the room to the Christmas music’s beat, waving their wands and firing off miniature firework charms.

In a corner, Albus Dumbledore was deep in what looked like argumentative conversation with Arthur Weasley. In another, Madam Bones was tearing a strip off the heir to House Glen for getting a little too handsy with his very embarrassed betrothed, while over by the food, Alexandra was monopolising the headmaster’s attention the way only a fan could.

But the biggest exhibition had to be Ginny Weasley, whom someone had somehow found a broomstick for, and who was currently making full use of the ballroom’s high roof to show off her frighteningly good aerial acrobatics, much to her mother’s obvious dismay, and the crowd’s cheering delight.

There were, however, two people she had a special interest in who were very obviously missing. “This is ridiculous,” Lily said to her husband. “Harry should be here. Won’t you go find him, dear? I’m going to go make sure Virgo is okay.”

James nodded slowly.

“And make sure you get him to summon his ring before he comes back,” she added before sweeping off.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Virgo watched John leave the room with his younger brother.

“Ahh,” Harry said. “Miss Malfoy, what a surprise to see you here.” He quirked an eye at John. “I understood this was to be a family matter?”

“Lay off it,” John growled. “She’s just with us ‘til we get to the library. Mum asked me to keep an eye on her, you know.”

Virgo felt Harry’s eyes bore into her. The oppression felt disturbingly familiar.

“A task I’m sure you’ve been carrying out with your usual impressiveness,” Harry said dryly.

The two boys walked ahead, leaving her to trail behind. There was something about the younger Potter that Virgo had difficulty putting her finger on. She hadn’t felt like this before, but now something had changed … something about Potter scared her.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Gilderoy Lockhart was sweating.

“And when the Boy-Who-Lived confronted the Eternal Lich of Darkness, why didn’t he use the magic water he found in the muggle church? Vivian still had the vials in her belt and she was only on the other side of the room.”

“That’s because …” Lockhart’s mind raced. “That’s because the glass was special magic glass! That only broke when used against inferi. Yes, that’s why the Boy-Who-Lived was able to use it in book sixteen.”

Alexandra frowned. “But what about when they were in the Boy-Who-Lived’s secret lab and Maldeve dropped a vial and it broke on the floor. The floor isn’t an inferius.”

“Ah, yes, but you see, the floor isn’t alive.”

“Neither are inferi.”

“But inferi are magical. That’s what makes the difference. The glass breaks only against inferi, and things that aren’t alive but that also aren’t magical, and the lich still has his soul, even if it’s not in his body, you see, which means he’s still partly alive, see?”

There was a pause.

“Okay,” Alex said slowly.

Lockhart mentally breathed a sigh of relief.

“So what about when the Boy-Who-Lived had to sneak into that library? How did he get those books out when that’s not how family magic works?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

John never took his eyes off his Slytherin younger twin as they made their way through the Potter library. They’d left Virgo at the door. She might now be one of his closest confidants, but there were limits, even if she now knew both he and Harry were long-distance time travellers.

Not that Harry knew that, of course.

The bastard had told Ginny, at the least. It was only just that he do the same. It had taken quite a few evenings, but he’d told his girls everything. Everything that had happened in the past, in the future, all the way up to his death in the graveyard—Virgo had insisted on it—everything except for his not being the boy-who-lived. No need to go that far.

Susan hadn’t been thrilled to be an accessory, as she called it, but had agreed the end goal of stopping Voldemort’s conquering Magical Britain, and possibly the world, to be worth it.

Obviously, he’d left out the bit where he and Dumbledore had conspired to send Harry to Azkaban last year. He suspected Virgo would approve (that girl was scary ruthless sometimes), but he had no wish to have Susan on his case, or even worse, telling her aunt.

Given the mission, he didn’t think she would, but he couldn’t risk it.

When they were sufficiently deep into the library, Harry turned and gave him a single raised eyebrow. “Well?”

“Yeah, yeah, it’s here.” John led his brother to a bookcase that looked no different from any other. The thirteenth book in was a large, leather-bound volume on the use of ceramics in the creation of magical artefacts.

“A pottery book for the Potters,” Harry drawled. “How droll.”

John scowled. “You just take your house ring and press it into the seal on the spine.”

They stood in silence for a moment.

“Well?” Harry eventually said.

“Well, what?”

“Well, are you going to do it?”

John scowled again, flashed the ring that marked him as heir to the Ancient and Noble House of Potter and pressed it into the seal.

The bookshelf split in two, creaking under the weight of the books, forming a doorway into a hidden room.

“Very traditional,” Harry commented before strolling in.

John smirked. It wouldn’t do him any good. He’d taken Virgo’s advice and hidden many of the more useful spell books and rituals around the rest of the library before going to fetch him. Harry may have slithered his way past his plans before, but not this time. This was a victory he’d savour.

“Ahh,” Harry said, halfway through one of the books John knew he couldn’t hide. “The patronus knight. An avatar of light, fuelled by righteousness and capable of actually hurting a dementor, rather than just fending it off. I’ll enjoy mastering this one.”

John scowled again to keep up the show. It wasn’t a difficult show to keep up.

“And what is this? Oooo, the family’s Sleekeazy’s Hair Potion and Scalp Treatment recipe. Hard to imagine such an impressive business empire being built on something so innocuous.”

Harry wasn’t even properly reading now, just flipping through the books, eyes barely resting on pages before moving on. Merlin knew why. It wasn’t as if pensieves worked on memories collected in here.

John scowled yet again, this time quite genuinely. “Are you done yet? What are you even doing anyway?”

“Yes,” said an adult voice behind them, causing John to spin and Harry to turn.

Lord James Potter stood there with his arms folded. “That’s something I’d like to know, too.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“And not only that,” Alex continued, “There was that time in book seven when—”

“—Look,” Lockhart interrupted, no longer his usual airy self. “If you disagree with some things in how the books were written, why don’t you write your own interpretation of how it went?”

Alex blinked. “Could I?”

“Sure, sure.” Lockhart looked around quickly. “If it’s good enough, maybe I’ll even publish it, oh! Look, is that Lady Knight? Gotta run—Lady Knight! How excellent to see you.”

He swept off, leaving a thoughtful Alexandra Black staring off into the middle distance.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Lord Potter stood with his arms folded, looking down at the two boys. “Well?”

In Harry’s mind, a dozen trains of thought were busy clacking away along well-used neural train-tracks.

There were many possible reasons they were being confronted like this. Most probable among them being that Lord Potter was displeased about him, Harry, having access to the family magic, given his association with Slytherin, which was exactly why he hadn’t broached the subject with him before, apart from general lack of trust.

Another possible reason was neither of them was supposed to know about the family magics. Many noble families didn’t share them with their children until their thirteenth birthdays.

And yet another reason could be that there were dangerous books in here, and Lord Potter was angry at his heir messing around in here without adult supervision.

Harry had words ready for all three, and more.

His brother was the unknown variable. He didn’t know what discussions John had had with Lord Potter before this. Presumably there had been a talk about family magic, since John had used the patronus knight during last year’s duelling tournament, but he didn’t know what the circumstances were. Had John bullshitted his way out of knowing the family magics when he was too young? Had Lord Potter showed him the family magics early? When even was early for the Potters? He didn’t know.

Therefore, possibly against his better judgement, the smartest thing to do in this situation would be to let his brother take the lead, if only until he put his foot in it so far that muggle businesses would consider dumping him in the ocean and using him as an oil drill.

“It’s okay, Dad, I was just showing Harry the library.”

Harry raised an eyebrow. Interesting. Going for the, ‘everything is fine, why are you making a fuss,’ angle. Not a terrible opening line, all things considered. Also suggested they’d already talked about this.

“It most certainly is not okay,” Lord Potter said, frowning. “Harry does not wear a noble house ring. How can he be expected to keep the secrets of house Potter without it?”

John’s head twisted around to stare at Harry with comically wide eyes. “Is that why you’re evil? You’re being mind-controlled?”

“John!” Lord Potter snapped.

Harry rolled his eyes. Deep sea oil drilling operations commenced. Also, Lord Potter’s reason for being angry didn’t line up to logic. If John was okay to already know the magics, he should be too. Lord Potter had only known he didn’t wear a ring for a handful of hours, so that couldn’t be the primary reason he hadn’t been shown them already. But if his association with Lord Slytherin was the reason, why would Lord Potter set himself up for obvious failure of his objective? Summon ring, get family magic. Not something Harry wanted to do, but from James Potter’s point of view, he should want to.

Harry watched the now back and forth argument between James and John, feeling more like an outsider than ever before. What was most surreal, though, was that if you listened to their actual words, the two were actually in agreement. Harry should summon his ring, and then he could have limited access to the family magic, but the two were shouting anyway.

Harry looked around the alcove and realised that many of the holes in the shelves were book-sized, and suspiciously free of dust, given the rest of the room. Ahh.

“You just don’t understand what’s at stake!” John shouted.

“Enough!” James said loudly back. “Do we need to have another talk with your mother?”

John quietened.

Lord Potter nodded and turned to him. “Harry, you need to summon your house ring now. It’s important.” His father then started talking him through how to summon a noble house ring, which was actually the simplest thing in the world. It was so simple, in fact, that when he’d first come back in time, he’d done it so easily that it hadn’t even needed thought.

You just had to want and accept your position in the house. Not a magically binding contract. No obligations. At least, no magical obligations that weren’t already there.

Harry looked down at the finger that often proclaimed him as Lord Slytherin. What should he do now? He could just envision all the different versions of how this might go, given that the distraction tactics he’d used before seemed to have run out.

He could refuse, but that would make him look unreasonable and rebellious. That might not be a terrible thing, but it could cramp his style for a bit.

Best case for the short term, he summoned the ring, and nothing changed. In this version of the universe, he was a spare of the house of Potter, not the heir.

On the other hand, if he went ahead and summoned the ring, and he did become the heir, that could be good for the long term, but bad for the short term. The explanations his parents could come up with for how him being the heir was possible weren’t great.

On the other, other hand, becoming the heir would open up interesting possibilities not available before. No dead ends, so long as John kept his mouth shut about their long-term time travel—just different paths.

“Ready?” James asked with a hand on his shoulder.

Harry rubbed his ring finger.

He was going to roll the dice. Time to see if Fate was still on his side or not. Time to see exactly what version of the universe they were in. He willed his Potter noble house ring to his finger, and looked.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“It is very hard for me with the Malfoys,” Virgo said softly into her teacup. “My new father is very demanding.” Opposite her, in the upstairs drawing room, Lily Potter looked sympathetic and worried. “I’d feel much safer with a family like yours,” Virgo continued. She pretended to hesitate, then said, “John is very kind.”

“Have you considered reaching back out to your muggle foster parents?” Lily asked.

Conflicting emotions warred within Virgo. On the one hand, she felt a huge spike of hurt right in her heart as she remembered the mum and dad she’d lost back home. But on the other hand, she was a witch. If she’d stayed in Stockholm, that part of her would never have had the opportunity for greatness. Durmstrang didn’t take muggleborn students. Besides …

She shook her head. “Their memories of me were completely wiped when I returned to the wizarding world.”

Lily put a hand to her mouth in horror. “Monsters. Oh, I’m so sorry.”

“It’s okay,” Virgo put on a brave smile. “I’m doing my best. And I’m just happy father let me come here tonight. Potter Manor feels much more like a home than Malfoy Manor. I just wish I could spend more time here.”

“But you’re doing well at Hogwarts, aren’t you? Apart from the troubles with the attacks. You look confident in class, and your potions are some of the best I’ve ever seen from a first-year.”

Virgo nodded demurely. “Magic comes naturally to me. I think I have a talent. I’ve even been able to help John a bit with homework sometimes.” She snapped her head up. “Not that he’s copying or anything, we just—”

“—Virgo,” Lily smiled, leaned over and put a comforting hand on hers. “It’s fine. And being able to help John is nothing to be ashamed of. Both my sons are geniuses. That reflects very well on you.” Lady Potter’s eyes travelled downwards and focused on something. Her eyes narrowed. “That golden chain … I recognise what that is.”

Virgo hesitated, for real this time. She hadn’t been planning to show Lady Potter that, but perhaps … Yes! Perhaps this was the way. Slowly, she reached for the chain and drew out the pendant portkey that John had given her. Her ticket to safety wherever she might be in or out of Hogwarts.

Lily sighed. “Oh, John.”

“He won’t get in trouble, will he?”

Lily looked conflicted, then shook her head. “I can’t fault his reasoning. You probably do need it more than him. But the heir of House Potter giving such a valuable artefact to a Malfoy … well …”

“He said it would be okay if it was a declaration of intention gift.”

“And you know what one of them is?”

Virgo nodded and another conflict flared inside her, one repeated many times over the past few weeks. Part of her shouted out that this was wrong—that she shouldn’t ever risk putting herself under anyone’s influence, not even someone as powerful as John. That was the dark lord in her speaking.

The other part wanted her to charge on ahead and get the prince for herself—all for herself. He’d love and care for her, shower her with magic gifts like a princess, and be utterly, helplessly devoted to her. That was the little girl raised on Disney movies talking.

The result of this conflict was always the same. She would be Lady Potter—the power behind the throne, the cunning behind the brute, Narcissa Malfoy’s metaphorical dagger in the dark, to John’s strong and mighty staff.

… She hadn’t meant to think that last bit.

Virgo nodded. “Yes, I know.”

“And you’re okay with that? Does your father know? He might take this as an invitation.”

“He doesn’t know, yet. But I’d be okay with that.” She plunged ahead. This was it. Time to go in for the kill. “If it was John, if House Potter could protect me—”

A noise interrupted her.

A loud noise, coming from up the corridor towards the library. Annoying!

Then the noise became clearer. Two people arguing with each other, quite loudly at that, and … that was John, wasn’t it? And the other was Lord Potter?

“What the—” Lily said, standing up and looking alarmed, just as the doors banged open and the two Potter men stormed in, still shouting.

“I told you he’s evil! I told you!”

“John, that’s enough! We’re going to sort this out.”

“James! John! What on Earth—”

“Mum, Harry stole my heirship!”

Lily’s mouth dropped open, as did Virgo’s.

“Sweetie, that’s not possible—” Lily began.

“He has the ring! When he called his, mine vanished! I’ve just got a normal noble house ring now. See?”

Virgo saw, and her mind whirled with possibilities, the first being that since it sounded like Harry went back in time further than John, according to the events he’d described, then maybe the family magics recognised him as older. But there was a problem with that theory. If her memories from Tom served her correctly, the Albion magics were based on date of birth.

So that probably wasn’t it?

The second, third, and fourth possibilities were all immediately rejected as impossible, but the fifth—the fifth made her stop dead. Oh Merlin, if that was the answer, then … holy hell. But how to tell John without dooming herself?

The Potters were still shouting, and even Lily had joined in.

“Silence!” Lord Potter roared.

John and Lily immediately shut up. Virgo sat attentive.

Lord Potter took a few moments to get his breath back before speaking again. “John, take Virgo back to your room and don’t speak a word about this to anyone. I declare this to be a Potter family secret. Virgo, if you truly wish to show yourself to be a friend of our house, you’ll also not speak of this to anyone. Go now. Your mother and I have to discuss matters.”

They left, Virgo leading the way. Her stride was determined.

Halfway through the manor, John spoke up.

“Virgo?” He sounded uncertain. “Where are we going? This isn’t the way back to the playroom.”

“Library,” Virgo said. “I need to check something. Always check. Never assume.”

“Always check what?” John asked, but she didn’t bother elaborating.

They walked into the library and Virgo immediately started going through the shelves, looking for something very specific.

“Virgo, there are family books laying out here, remember?”

“Then you’ll just have to take them off the shelves and hide them somewhere better won’t you? Hardly matters now, does it?”

John shrugged and walked off.

The logic had started with an idle thought—a small strand that she’d started pulling at, only to find that the strand might be attached to a string, which might be attached to a rope, which if pulled might pull over a whole building’s worth of trouble.

The thought was this. Harry Potter might be a horcrux. This was a possibility she’d constantly come back to again and again. Had spent months pondering. At times the evidence pointed away, but then the evidence pointed towards.

Given that this was a recurring possibility, she’d be a fool not to consider that Harry’s heirship might have something to do with it.

“I’m done,” John announced, arriving back at a jog. “Is that the book on the Albion Family Magics?”

“The latest version.” Virgo flipped through the tome. Her eyes narrowed. “John, go find Susan and meet me back in the playroom. This is very important.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Hey, Ginny,” Harry walked into his group’s hideaway, currently containing Daphne, Hermione, Luna, and Ginny, with a big smirk on his face. “How would you like to one day be Lady Potter?”

Ginny’s face turned to horror. “Absolutely not! How could you even suggest—”

Harry stopped in the middle of the group and flashed his brand spanking new heir ring.

“—Something so logical and reasonable,” she continued without missing a beat. “Screw that pauper brother of yours. Nothing but a proper ladyship is good enough for Magical Britain’s newest quidditch phenom, Princess Ginevra Molly Weasley.”

“So it really happened,” Daphne whispered. “This is going to complicate things.”

“Indeed. Lord Potter was not pleased at all. I dare say getting to my own gala night will now require a more adventurous journey than just taking the floo.”

He drew up a chair and sat directly opposite Ginny. His face dropped the smirk. “Ginny, you know I’ve had a few vague talks with your father about a possible betrothal. With your permission, I’d like to pursue that possibility a bit more aggressively. Is that something you’d like?”

Ginny’s cocky grin also dropped, replaced with nervous shyness. She was silent for a moment while a blush started to form on her cheeks. Eventually she said, “Yes, Harry. I’d like that.”

“Okay then. I’m glad, because it’s something I want too.”

Ginny smiled shyly.

The moment was broken by the three girls behind them clapping, all with smiles on their faces. And just like that, a hint of Ginny’s cockiness returned with a small smirk of her own.

“But Harry,” Hermione began. “How are you going to get Lord Potter to agree? You yourself said he’s not exactly pleased with you.”

“No idea. It’s mostly Slytherin he’s not pleased with actually, but you are still correct. I’ve no idea how I’m going to wrangle this.” Harry stood back up. “But I’m damn well going to make it happen.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Virgo stared down at the book like it was some strange and fascinating creature.

Her instincts had been right.

Damn Tom Riddle. Damn Julia Olsen. She’d been this close to arrogantly thinking she knew best when she really knew nothing. She’d been this close to believing that the dark lord in her had to know better.

The logic chain had started simply. Harry Potter might be a horcrux. Maybe that played a part in his being the Potter Heir. How could it play a part? Maybe Harry was like her—a merged horcrux—a merged horcrux like Lord Slytherin.

“Hey, Virgo!” It was John. “I found Susan. She was downstairs. She’s heading over to the playroom now. What’s all this about?”

“I’ll tell you when I get there. Go on ahead. I need a few moments alone to sort my thoughts.”

John left.

Virgo took a deep steadying breath. If Harry Potter was a merged horcrux, his soul age would be older, just like hers. She wasn’t sure exactly how the soul merge between Julia and Tom went, but she wouldn’t be surprised if she was now only a year younger than John’s actual soul age.

But that wouldn’t mean anything. Not if the Albion Family Magics determined age by date of birth.

They didn’t. Her hands gripped the book harder.

They used to. By Merlin, they used to! But that had changed in a historical event known as The Great Accounting. A change that made soul age the primary determinant of age by the Albion Family Magics. A change that became active in the year 1988—just like Lord Slytherin.

Virgo bit her lip.

But if soul age was what determined age now, why couldn’t her original idea be correct? Why couldn’t Harry be the heir simply because he’d travelled back in time further than John? That was a perfectly rational explanation. But if that was the case, it begged another question. Why would Harry have travelled back in time further than John?

‘Death smiled. “Yes, he [Harry] is the subject of the prophecy, but we are giving you the chance, John, to fulfil the prophecy in his stead. Bringing your twin to us now would be troublesome. Our influence in the mortal plane is extremely limited. We can generally only operate through chosen ones and champions.’

Annoyingly, John had later told her he didn’t know the exact contents of the prophecy, only that Harry had been originally fated to eventually ‘vanquish’ the dark lord, but in the process become an even worse power himself—annoying and terrifying. But it was Death’s next words that were most relevant at the moment. ‘Bringing your twin to us now would be troublesome.’

Bringing him nowwould be troublesome. But Harry had also travelled back in time. How?

What if they’d brought him later?

Fate and Death hadn’t even told John about Voldemort’s horcruxes. They’d told him basically nothing! What chance did she honestly think John had of taking Voldemort as he was right now? Probably none.

Suppose John had travelled back in time and failed.

Fate and Death then use another chosen one or champion to arrange to have Harry brought to them. That could explain why they sent him back in time further. They decided he needed more time to succeed. So they send him back to 1988, three years before John’s arrival … the same time that Lord Slytherin comes right out of nowhere … the same time that the Albion Family Magics changed how age was calculated to soul age rather than date of birth—a change that would allow an eight-year-old to take on a lordship if they had a soul old enough.

Virgo’s mind was barrelling on ahead now, desperately looking for any cracks in her reasoning.

There was a whole extra timeline to work with! A timeline in which anything could have happened. The possible scenarios were endless.

How could Harry Potter be Lord Slytherin? Easily.

Suppose …

Virgo glanced towards one of the many books on Potter history that filled the bookshelves.

Suppose Harry had been sent to Azkaban, like he had been in John’s original timeline.

Slowly, driven mad by dementors and by the injustice of being sent to Azkaban for a crime he didn’t commit (because if anyone killed Ginny Weasley with the basilisk, it would have damn well been her!), Harry becomes bitter and resentful. He harbours thoughts of revenge.

And then, one day, John goes up against Voldemort and Voldemort wins.

Virgo shut the book she was holding with a snap.

Then, once Voldemort wins, he frees Harry from Azkaban and offers to blood adopt him as his own son! And Harry, bitter and resentful, accepts. He acquires Riddle blood, rejects the common blood of the Evans family, becomes half Potter, half Riddle, and becomes eligible for the lordship of Lord Slytherin by having a full soul, just like she, Virgo, was able to become an animagus for the same reason!

Of course, Voldemort would need a good reason to blood adopt someone, and there weren’t many of them, but there was one good one she could think of … if they were a horcrux prison.

So, Harry becomes the Dark Prince—Voldemort’s most terrible enforcer. But at some point, for some reason, Harry’s soul merges with the horcrux, which Voldemort would never be able to accept, and so Harry becomes Voldemort’s enemy.

Fate and Death then have him brought to them and send him back in time to merge all the horcruxes into himself, effectively neutralising them (which would also almost certainly kill her, if he got to her before she got to him.)

And voila, Harry Potter is Lord Slytherin.

And now, Heir Potter too (which was a problem that could easily be fixed with his death).

Of course, this was just one possible chain of events, but the overall picture was likely similar. Harry was the blood adopted heir and merged horcrux of Lord Voldemort.

Virgo let out a sigh.

There was, however, a problem with all this.

Given what she knew of John Potter so far, he wasn’t likely to accept any hypothetical chain of events that included his failure to succeed in his mission. While she appreciated him a lot now, that didn’t mean she was blind to his weaknesses. That meant she’d have to leave that bit out, but that created a massive hole in the logic that needed to be filled.

Besides, there was absolutely no way she was going to straight-up tell John that her death was a possible avenue to destroy Voldemort. No fucking way.

But every problem contained an opportunity, and this one coincided well with the promised discussion she’d recently had with Susan after rescuing John from the tower ritual.

The best way to plug this hole? Tell the truth. Tell the truth and lie, lie, lie.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“John, what’s all this about?” Susan asked.

“No idea. Virgo just came across all mysterious. Like Hermione when she’s figured something out.”

“I can’t believe your brother could steal the heirship from you.”

John clenched his fists. “If I ever get my hands on him …”

Just then the door to the playroom opened, and Virgo walked in, holding a small pile of books, and looking very nervous. “Susan?” She made her way to where the two of them were sitting. “You remember that conversation we had about telling John certain things? I found something out, but I need to tell him about that first.”

“Oh, good.” Susan smiled. “I’m glad I don’t have to pester you about it.”

“What’s the mystery then?” John asked. “What have you figured out? What do you need to tell me?”

Virgo sat down. “You remember you told us about the last timeline? About how Ginny was being enchanted by a magic diary made by the dark lord?”

John felt an uneasy feeling coil in his stomach. “Yes?”

“When Lord and Lady Malfoy brought me back from the muggle world, they did the same thing to me.”

The feeling turned to lead. John’s eyes went wide.

Susan gasped. “Wait, what is this? This isn’t what we talked about.”

“I know. Just trust me, I’m getting to it.”

But John’s mind was already whirling. “But the map! It always says you’re Virgo Malfoy. The last time around it would say Tom Riddle when Ginny got enchanted.”

“The map doesn’t say Tom Riddle for me because I am not being enchanted. Over the summer, my parents used a dark ritual on me to try and speed up the enchantment process—the life-draining process. It failed. And instead, I got all the memories and skills from the enchanted diary. That’s the real reason my parents are so unhappy with me. It has nothing to do with my sorting into Gryffindor. I killed the diary.”

John’s mouth fell open. “You have the memories of the diary? Of Tom Riddle?”

Virgo nodded.

“Tom Riddle who became Voldemort?” Susan whispered.

Virgo nodded.

“Is that the real reason for your …” she trailed off, giving John a side-ways glance.

“Getting to that, yes.”

“Wait, why didn’t you tell us before?” John said. He was having difficulties keeping the hurt out of his voice. She’d been dealing with something this important all year and hadn’t told him?

“Because I was scared, John. Imagine it. You don’t remember anything about being magical, and then suddenly you get pulled from your home, and given to two people like the Malfoys. They give you this diary, and it seems like it’s your new best friend. The only person in the world who understands you. Then it turns out he’s an evil dark lord who wants to suck out your life energy. And then, when that fails, you learn all his secrets. All the ways he was going to protect himself in the future. Imagine what would happen to me if anyone learned I had that knowledge.” Her voice got softer. “What if they already did?”

Susan put a hand over her mouth in horror. “Is that why people have been trying to kill you?”

“I don’t know. I suspect so.”

“So what were the ways?” John leaned in eagerly. “All the ways he protected himself, I mean.”

“His most important one was a ritual that tears off a piece of your soul and puts it into an object for safekeeping. The object then tethers you to this world, stopping your soul from passing through the veil, to the world of Death.”

“Like a lich?” Susan asked.

“Yes, except you keep a portion of your soul inside yourself, so you do not become undead.”

John’s heart was racing now. This was it. This was what he needed. This was the lucky break that would turn all his fortunes around!

“These objects are called horcruxes.”

Horcruxes … even the word sounded evil.

“Most of the horcruxes Tom Riddle planned to make were to be inside objects, but he also entertained the idea of using living creatures as horcruxes, making a kind of living prison. One of the big problems with horcruxes is that the soul piece inside the object used has a will and consciousness of its own. A soul piece with the temperament of Tom Riddle or Lord Voldemort would try every trick it could imagine to break free. He theorised that using a living creature could potentially solve that problem since the will of the container could act as a kind of impenetrable wall between the horcrux and the outside world. But it would come with downsides too. Tom Riddle certainly wasn’t planning on creating any living horcruxes for a long time.”

John glanced to his side and saw that, like him, Susan was hanging on Virgo’s every word.

“Do you know where any of these horcruxes are?” She whispered.

Virgo looked uncertain. “Yes, and no. I believe I know where one of them was. And what one of them now is.”

Virgo changed. Her legs moulded together, robes disappeared into her body and a massive snake’s tail with brilliant red scales swept around the room, coming to rest in a circle around John and Susan. It was only Susan’s apparent blasé acceptance of this that stopped him letting out a small scream. He did, however, point a shaky finger at her. “L-L-Lamia!”

“Lamia animagusss, actually,” Virgo said in a hissy voice, covering her now larger chest with her hands, despite the scales already there. “Thank you, Sssusan.” She took a t-shirt from the other girl and pulled it over her head.

“You’re a horcrux?” John said, weakly.

Virgo shook her head. “No. The diary wasss a horcrux. When the Malfoysss performed the dark ritual to ssspeed up my enchantment, I instead merged with it, cutting it off from the other soul pieces, and destroying its function as a horcrux. But I was left with thisss.” She gestured down at her body.

John just stared. The girl he’d been starting to have a crush on had turned into a massive magical snake witch in front of the other hand, he’d gotten quite an eyeful before she’d put that t-shirt on. There was no such thing as an immature animagus, after all. And they’d been quite impressive.

Thankfully she couldn’t read his thoughts, and simply continued with the explanation. “Merging with the sssoul fragment held within the diary also had the effect of increasing my sssoul age—sssomething that I’m fairly sure only I know about. Thisss simply isn’t magic that has ever been done before. I am now actually probably closer to your age, John, than Sssusan here isss.”

That was interesting. Susan would also develop larger boobs quite soon in the future, too. Together they could eventually be the bustiest pair in the castle. No, wait! He mentally shook himself. He shouldn’t be getting distracted like this. “The second horcrux.” he said. “What is it?”

Virgo took a deep breath. “It’sss Harry.”

Susan gasped.

John stared. Then his eyes widened. “You think that’s how he’s older than me?”

“Yesss. I think that when Voldemort attacked you as a baby, he was planning to use your death to make your brother a horcrux. Except it was his own partial death that ended up being used instead. I believe he’d have split his sssoul to the absolute limit at that point, so even his own demise could have triggered the final part of the ritual. Then sssometime in-between the time when you first called your heir ring and now, Harry merged closer with his sssoul fragment, but not close enough to sssever the connection.”

“What makes you think he hasn’t severed the connection?” Susan asked.

“Because of thisss,” she held the Albion Family Magics tome up. “In 1988 the family magicsss changed to recognise sssoul age as the only legitimate measure. And it was at exactly this time that Lord Ssslytherin became active.”

“So you think that Lord Slytherin was behind the horcrux merger with Harry?”

Virgo was silent for a moment before she said, very slowly and deliberately. “No, John. I think that the horcrux gave Harry rights to the Ssslytherin line that Voldemort was never able to claim. And that his new sssoul age allowed Harry to do so. I think that Harry is Lord Ssslytherin.”

It was like a wall of silence hit him with all the force of a tidal wave. He just could not process what had just been said. He couldn’t have heard that correctly could he? Virgo thought that Harry was … that Harry was …

“… it actually makes an odd kind of sense—” was as far as Susan got before—

“—THAT BASTARD!” John leapt to his feet, causing his chair to crash to the ground behind him. “That evil! That Slytherin! That Slytherin!” Suddenly all the little hints Harry had dropped over the years leapt up and smacked him in the face all at once. The wordplay used in casual conversation. The looks. The smirks. “All this time! Time! It must have been the trip back in time! It must have done some weird magic thing. C’mon! Let’s go tell Mum and Dad! They can—”

“—Wait!” Virgo snapped.

John froze halfway to the door.

“We can’t just go running off and telling anyone about this without a plan. There are too many things that could blow up in our facesss. We have information that we should not have—illegal information. And Harry isn’t committing any crime that we ourselves wouldn’t also be guilty of if we revealed what we know.”

“Couldn’t we reveal it anonymously?” Susan asked. “You know, sort of point people in the right direction?”

“We can, but we need to be cunning about it.”

“We have to do something!” John shouted.

“And we will. I have a plan.”

“A plan?”

“Yesss, a plan.” Virgo grinned and John suddenly realised that while he’d seen many scary things in his life, including Lord Voldemort in a graveyard, having a lamia grinning at you from only a few feet away was a special kind of scary.

“Lord Ssslytherin is a Hogwarts ssstudent. This is the battlefield we will fight on,” Virgo said. “We will gather the Light children throughout the castle and train them to work together, just like Harry is doing with the mugglebornsss. We will conduct all the rituals we can safely get away with to further increase our powersss. We will plant ssspies all throughout the castle, bring the paintings to our side, and persuade the ghosts to play our game. And when we are ready, when the correct opportunity presents itself, we will show the world who and what Lord Ssslytherin really is at the worst possible time. And completely destroy the Gray.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

[Some minutes previously]

Lord Potter closed the doors to the sitting room as Virgo and John left. He turned to his lady wife who was looking extremely agitated.

“Harry couldn’t have done this by himself,” Lily said.

“I agree.” Lord Potter walked over and poured himself a drink of firewhisky. “And not only that, but I have finally figured something out.”

“What?”

“I have figured out who Lord Slytherin is.”

Lily’s eyes narrowed. “Who?”

James downed the whisky in one go and began to pour himself another. “Think about it, Lils. Who is someone that no one would suspect returning, after all this time? Who has a large grudge against the Light? Who would have the power to do something like this? Terrible powers that no one truly knows the depths of?”

Lily gasped. “You don’t mean …”

“Yes.” James nodded grimly. “Lord Slytherin is Remus Lupin.”

—End of Chapter Fifty-Three—

Chapter End Notes

A/N: Whew! Things are going to start moving quite quickly from here on out. The second half of the year isn’t going to be nearly as long as the first, so hang on tight.

Also, I apologise for the late posting of this chapter. If you haven’t been following on discord, I’ve been dealing with some family medical issues, which cut about three weeks out of my writing schedule. That combined with the new longer editing process means that this chapter took quite a bit longer than expected. The plus side is that while we were editing this chapter, I continued drafting the next one, and we’re actually about two-thirds of the way through that one, so there shouldn’t be as long a wait for that one.

One of those original projects—Trial by Conquest—a fantasy 4X LitRPG—will soon start to be released for free on Royalroad, Wattpad, and other similar websites, so keep your eyes open if that’s your cup of tea. Head over to www.leadvone.com to stay updated.

A/N: This chapter was drafted and made available early through the LeadVonE discord server, as will the next one. If you fancy discussing this chapter with like-minded people, or anything else DP&SW, feel free to head over there.

A special thank you to the following people for helping catch mistakes on #dpasw-editorial: ASK, Blake Belladonna, ChRiAn, Dragonbait, dutchy-jin, emergancy, feauxen, Fuuryuu, Gloweye, Hyperius, JaydenStevenson, Leyrann, Lunatico, Magic Bird Dust, Malin, Salisaad, Salty_sauce, sfu, Super Big Mac, Tendra, Rafilar, Ravana, and Vin5!

A/N: Twitch streams have been restructured to focus on editing and recording first, and other topics as fill-in in between those two major focuses.

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2019’s prices.

Movers and Shakers—Part 2

Christmas Day, for those who celebrated it, came and went—presents under the tree and goodwill to all wizards in the air, provided of course, that they were the right kind of wizard. And the morning after, the daylight broke in the front shop of the Diagon Alley Owl Office, where a very special delivery was being prepared.

“Blimey,” said Stan Shunpike staring at all the packages being frantically packed. “What’s ‘is lordship wanting all those masks for? Ain’t he got enough?”

The room was full of half-open boxes, all containing hand-quilled letters along with a green and black mask wrapped in packing paper.

“Duh,” said his sister, carrying yet another box full of fake Lord Slytherin masks from around the back. “They’re for the posh party tonight. Dem lords always gotta do it like this, don’t they. Ma-ska-raid and all that.”

“But if they’re all wearing masks, how’d they then know who the real Lord Slytherin is?”

Rodger from up the street clapped Stan on the back. “That’s the point, innit? It’s like, all cunning and stuff. Slytherin. All part of some master plan, no doubt.” He tapped the side of his nose conspiratorially. “Now, come here and give us a hand, yeah? You fancy yourself a charms master.”

“Fancies himself more like it!” called his sister. “Fancies himself more than a Malfoy, that one.”

“No more than you!” Stan called back, sitting down and drawing his wand. “And I’ll have these all done in a less than a jiffy. You’ll see.”

Over two hundred packages were charmed shut and wrapped. Over two hundred owls swooped down. All throughout the day, deliveries arrived at the front doors of the possibly good and questionably great.

At Malfoy Manor, Lord Malfoy opened his box and stared inside. “Seriously?”

In the kitchen of the Burrow, Molly Weasley opened one box after another, shaking her head in exasperation. “Arthur! Your Lord Slytherin is up to his games again!”

At Grimmauld Place, a very uncertain Lord Black walked into his daughter’s room, only to find her enthusiastically posing in front of a mirror, wearing a long evening dress, and an exact half-copy of the mask that he now also carried.

All across the country, the packages were met with reactions ranging from excitement to incredulity, to suspicion, but mostly they were met with bemusement.

And finally, at Potter Manor, a house elf handed four packages to Lord Potter, who opened them and immediately gave one of the four back. “Harry is not to leave the manor tonight, understand? Harry is grounded.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

A few hours later, Harry watched from behind the upstairs banisters as the other Potters made their final preparations to leave.

“And remember, be on your best behaviour, John,” James Potter said. “There’s a lot riding on tonight. The Light needs the Gray’s support if we want to advance our interests in the Wizengamot. If you do anything to endanger that, I will be very displeased.”

“Yes, Dad,” John said from behind his Lord Slytherin mask. He had not looked pleased at all when he’d learned that he’d be expected to wear it for most, if not all, of the evening.

“And, Harry,” Lord Potter called up to where Harry looked down on them. “I don’t want to hear about you giving the house elves trouble.”

“Of course not, Father.”

“Good.” James Potter donned his Lord Slytherin mask, and Lily Potter did the same. The three then stepped into the roaring green floo, one after the other, and shouted, “Slytherin Manor!”

The first place Harry ransacked was the library, looking all over for the missing family magic books John had hidden. He succeeded in finding two before a clock told him he was running out of time. His second march took him to the storeroom where he’d found the invisibility cloak, all those years ago. He’d been half-hoping that the Potter family might possess other useful treasures—maybe even the stone or the wand of Death—but alas, it was not to be.

Another clock chimed that he was already slightly late for his next appointment and so he jogged through the manor, down the stairs, out the back door, and down to the very edge of the wards.

“Master Harry is not to be leaving the manor,” said a voice from behind him.

Harry turned around. One of the Potter house elves stood with her arms folded, tapping her foot. Harry’s back was almost scraping the ward’s edge, it was so close.

“Not planning to, my friend. Not planning to.” He put his hands behind his back, one palm open, and felt a glass vial drop into it. An invisible hand gently squeezed his before retreating.

“Then why is you being here?” asked the elf.

“Just going for a walk. It’s a beautiful winter’s evening.” Unseen, he slipped the vial into the pocket of his robes.

“It’s dark out.”

“Exactly. That’s the point.” He sighed. “But perhaps you are right. Perhaps it is rather cold out, too.” He gestured back to the manor and the elf escorted him all the way back. Twenty minutes later, all the elves were laying unconscious, drugged out of their skulls by the powerful sleeping potion Harry had slipped into their drinks. He finished the ruse by replacing the half-empty glasses with new ones, spiked with Ogden’s finest taken from Lord Potter’s drinks cabinet.

Plausible deniability taken care of, he opened a downstairs window, and slowly floated up and into the night.

Harry was anything but grounded.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Sitting at his office desk, Lord Jacob Greengrass really wished he couldn’t hear the argument that was going on just outside his door.

“But where’s Daph?” Astoria asked for what felt like the hundredth time. “Is she with Harry? Huh? Huh? She is, isn’t she?”

“Astoria,” snapped his wife. “Mask!”

“What, this?” There was a giggle.

“No, not that mask. Your metaphorical mask. Your Slytherin mask.”

“This is my—”

“—You know exactly what I mean.”

“But using occlumency so much is just so boring, and I’ll be at it all night! What are we waiting for anyway?”

At that moment, Jacob felt through the wards exactly what they were waiting for, arriving via the floo.

A couple of minutes later, Harry stood before him.

Jacob cleared his throat. “I wish to say that I do not approve of what we are about to do.”

“You understand this is the safest way,” Harry replied.

“I do, but that doesn’t make it any less inappropriate. If we are found out it will cause a scandal.”

“Then we shall have to ensure that we are not found out.”

Jacob didn’t really have a reply for that so he just tossed over a small vial of mud-coloured potion and watched as his future son-in-law turned into his first-born daughter.

“Daphne!” said his wife, materialising through the office door as if pulled by a summoning charm. She had a huge shit-eating grin on her face. “I see that nasty boy has been having far too great an influence on you. Look at those clothes! Just follow me and we’ll get you ready for the gala, just as I’m sure your betrothed would love to see you.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

“Lord Slytherin!” gushed the wife of a random minor lord. “That is you, isn’t it? Yes, it is—so hard to tell with all these masks. Can I just congratulate you on such a magnificent home? My husband has been most impressed and I’m sure if my children were here, they would be too.”

“Thank you,” said Daphne graciously, having to clamp down on her occlumency to stop herself snapping at the boring cow.

After a few minutes of polite conversation, she managed to beg off to attend to other guests. Everything about this felt wrong. Not the playing host for a huge number of magical lords and ladies—she’d been practically bred for that. No, it was the being a wizard thing that was the sticking point. She wasn’t a wizard and while Ginevra and Luna might relish the opportunity to play dress-up, as it were, she would be quite happy to spend the rest of her premarital life avoiding the embarrassment of being reminded exactly what Harry was going to be lugging around beneath his robes when he was older. That worked until she had to use the bathroom, which would probably be soon. The first guests had arrived three hours ago and she’d been going non-stop since then.

Greeting the Potters had been particularly difficult. The testosterone flowing through her blood demanded she smash Lord Potter’s nose into the brilliantly polished floor. Thankfully, she’d resisted the temptation, but it was a close-run thing, especially when the leading lord of the Light had made comments about Harry and how they would have to have a talk about him soon.

The rest of the guests milled around the entranceway, or else had wandered off to find their seats in the sea of round tables that had been laid out in the ballroom. The house elves had been working hard all afternoon and soon all that effort would bear fruit. Just as her lord planned.

The floo flared green and Daphne had to steel herself as her father, Lord Greengrass, stepped out, followed quickly by her mother, her sister Astoria, and herself. And despite herself, she couldn’t help letting out a cough. Firstly, did she really look that small? And secondly, wow—Harry could pull off pureblood princess as easily as he could all-powerful lord. It was kind of annoying, actually.

“Lord Greengrass,” she said, opening her arms and embracing her father in an incredibly manly hug. “I hope I find you well.”

“Quite well, Lord Slytherin,” her father replied. She noticed with a quirk of her lips that he wasn’t handling the awkwardness quite as well as Harry was. “As is my family.” He gestured behind him.

“I’m happy.” Daphne turned to the other three, two of whom giggled, one of whom didn’t, and it was that one who gave her a perfect demure curtsey. “My lord,” Harry said, dipping low in a dress that she recognised as one of the ones her mother had been trying to get her to wear for years.

“Daphne,” Daphne said, smiling. “You look absolutely enchanting tonight.”

“Thank you, my lord. You look amazingly handsome, too.”

“Okay, that’s enough of that,” her father cut in. “Lord Slytherin, I believe you have some words you need to exchange with Daphne? Astoria, will you go and keep an eye on her?”

“Of course!” Astoria chirped.

The three of them were soon ensconced in the drawing-room just off the main ballroom.

The moment the door was locked, Astoria burst into laughter. “I can’t believe you really went through with it! Daph, you have the best betrothed ever! I’m so jealous.”

Harry removed his mask and smiled with Daphne’s face. “I trust you are ready to play your part, Astoria?”

“Of course.”

Daphne removed her own mask and tossed Harry his Lord Slytherin wand. “Lady Charmer took ill soon after arriving—she’s been flooed to St. Mungo’s—Heir Shafiq has been stunned for trying to force his way through a locked door, and Lord Thynn is complaining that his plus one couldn’t be one of his mistresses.”

“That all?”

“Not by a long shot.”

“You stunned someone, Daph?” Astoria looked up at her, wide-eyed.

“He had it coming.”

“But isn’t Shafiq on our side?”

“Yes. His grandfather is extremely embarrassed.”

“I’ll bet he is.” Harry took the small potion she proffered him and held it up. “Ready?”

Daphne nodded. Together, they drank the vials in one gulp.

Then, as Harry’s skin began to bubble, he flicked his wand and switched their clothes.

Daphne felt the wizarding robes she’d been wearing switched with the far more familiar and comforting embrace of a dress, even if it was one of the more complex ones.

“Oh, thank Merlin.”

Harry, now male and much taller, put his mask back in place. “Don’t get too comfortable. This will be far from the last switch tonight.”

“And now it’s my turn!” Astoria was practically jumping up and down.

Lord Slytherin turned to her. “Astoria. Mask.”

Astoria’s face instantly blanked.

“Well done.”

The girl let a crack of happiness peek through before turning back once more into full-on ice princess.

One more round of polyjuice potions, and another switching spell later, and Daphne and Astoria had also completely switched places.

“And now, the final finishing touch,” Harry said. “Astoria, banish and recall your noble house ring.”

Astoria nodded, closed her eyes and focused. Seconds later, Daphne felt her heiress ring vanish from her finger, where it reappeared on her little sister’s.

It was now official. Her betrothal to Harry had always precluded her from taking on the role of Lady Greengrass. But the family had always suggested that they keep her in the role of heiress anyway, until Astoria arrived at Hogwarts, just because she was so good at it. This was just moving the schedule up a few months. “Astoria,” she practically begged. “Please don’t do anything unseemly. This is my reputation I’m trusting you with.”

“Hey, don’t worry, Sis. I got this.” Astoria placed a hand on her chest. “I would have you know that I am most pleased with how this soiree is progressing, my lord, and hope you would indulge my proclivities later on for a pleasant stroll by the water.”

“I don’t speak like that!”

“You totally do.”

“Girls,” Lord Slytherin interrupted them. “It is time for Astoria Greengrass to fall ill.” He pulled out his shrunk trunk from the pocket of his robes. “Hop in, Daphne.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

The table was covered with a white linen table cloth, and laid for ten. Around it, three families sat, exchanging conversation while waiting for both performance and food. The first family were the Malfoys. Draco sat on his father’s left-hand side, while his mother sat on his father’s right. He was quite pleased with the holidays so far. The attention he’d garnered as the up-and-coming Dark wizard who’d summoned a basilisk in the forbidden forest felt good in a way that being praised for being Heir Malfoy alone never quite had. He hadn’t realised the difference until now. The basilisk-summoning episode was his—not his family’s. Even if it had been a fluke—even if almost the entire Wizangamot had voted to ban his further experimentation with it—it was still his.

The second family sitting around this particular table were the Parkinsons. Draco’s mother and Pansy’s were avidly discussing his and Pansy’s respective Hogwarts achievements in the way that competitive mothers are wont to. Draco caught Pansy’s eye and gave her a faux bow.

Pansy smiled back. The witches wore only half-masks so he could see some of her cheeks. She was blushing.

Being the witch whom Draco had primarily summoned the basilisk to protect had changed things between their families. There were still many noble houses interested in marrying their daughters into the Malfoy sphere of influence, but the Parkinsons had definitely moved up the queue, as it were.

With two acknowledged Dark families making up most of the table, the final family would have been seen as the odd one out by those who didn’t keep up to date with the politics of the day. Unfortunately, it seemed that one of those people who didn’t keep up with the politics of the day was the very head of that exact family.

“I can’t tell you how good it is to see the Ancient and Noble House of Black rediscovering the old ways and traditions,” said Lord Parkinson.

“Indeed,” added Lord Parkinson’s younger brother, Robert. “I remember when I were a lad. Me and Saumual here once snuck into Knockturn Alley and tried to hire a troll to live under that little bridge over the creek.”

“Errr …” said Lord Sirius Black.

“Of course it didn’t work. But our Grandmother liked to lead us around with all those fairy-tale rituals. Said later it kept us out of real trouble. I bet Alexandra here gets up to that kind of trouble all the time.”

“Ummm …”

“Anyway, it’s been fascinating to watch her play the Snake Pit. Scary too, at times. Don’t you think so, Sam?”

“Sure has. I’m rather jealous, to be honest. In my day, I was one of the only heirs attending, so my leadership was a fait accompli. But even then, I doubt I’d have been able to fight off that many challengers all at once.” Lord Parkinson raised his mask and winked at Alex. “She’s a fearsome one, no doubt. I’m glad the Dark’s future leadership is looking strong. It’s just a shame she’s a witch.” He laughed and refixed his mask. “If she weren’t, I’d be pushing you hard for Pansy’s consortship contract.”

“Ahh … yes, um. …”

Draco carefully watched Alexandra as the exchange continued. His public leader was sat on Lord Black’s left, radiating calmness and looking just a little smug. He shivered. Despite everything, he still couldn’t quite shake that feeling of anxiety sometimes around her. Casting his mind back to the beginning of the year, he couldn’t believe he’d so boldly suggested on the train that one day Black might be one of his consorts. The witch was an untameable mess of contrasts.

On the one hand, she sometimes appeared amazingly naive about aspects of pureblood culture. Like when she’d first played wizard’s poker with him and the other Slytherins. It quickly became apparent that she was an amateur who knew only the rules and none of the subtleties.

But then on the other hand, she was cunning, ruthless, and a magical combat prodigy powerful enough to take on a good chunk of upper years all by herself—much like the Potter twins of the Light and the Gray. That, more than anything else, was the driving force behind Draco’s decision to ally himself behind her—to act as her guiding hand through a world she appeared only partly ready to command.

He just wished—oh, how he wished so badly—that he could guide her in regards to the other potentially dangerous witch sitting at their table.

“It’s all not really that big a deal,” Alex said airily. “Any true Slytherin would understand.”

Lord Black shifted uneasily.

“It’s just unfortunate that the world is not all Slytherin,” she continued. “Isn’t that right, Virgo?”

Despite himself, Draco felt a cold sweat break out on his brow as, sitting next to him, his little sister, Alex’s classmate, the Malfoy’s spy in the Light, fixed Alex with a glare that he could feel even through her mask. She opened her mouth to retort.

Whatever that retort might have been though, was cut short as the lights around the ballroom suddenly dimmed.

All around them, over 150 wizards and witches from the very top of wizarding society quietened at their own tables. Another fifty sat on the surrounding upstairs balcony at much smaller tables, looking down on the proceedings in groups of two and three.

In front of them all, sat a raised stage, onto which a robed figure strode, wearing that distinctive Lord Slytherin mask. Draco had no doubt that this was the real Lord Slytherin.

The man stopped in the centre of the stage. “Lords and Ladies—” he began. Every pair of eyes in the room was on him. “—wizards and witches. Welcome to my new home and to Slytherin Gala Night. I invite you to enjoy my house’s food and hospitality, as well as the first performance by the Floo Theatre Company of Sebastian Rosier’s classic, The Many Champions of Death, with Death played by Humphrey Piper, directed by Madam Victoria Bolton.”

Draco frowned. Piper? He didn’t recognise that name.

“After dinner, the room will be cleared for dancing, while drinks will continue to be served in the sitting and dining rooms. And finally, at midnight, my gift to Magical Britain—an old ritual of renown, long thought lost, as so many have been, now found again with the revival of my house. I invite you all to be present as, for the first time in over five hundred years, we perform the Stella Benedictio.”

Draco heard a small chorus of gasps ring out around the room, quickly followed by excited whispers. Whatever the Stella Benedictio was, it was apparently noteworthy.

“But that is for later,” Slytherin continued. “For now, I leave you in the very capable hands of Madam Bolton. Thank you.”

Applause filled the room as Slytherin walked off stage, only pausing to collect Granger, who’d been watching at the sidelines, before leading her through a back door. Draco smiled. At least she didn’t have a spot out here.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Those who have been backstage at most any theatre production, from the primary school Christmas nativity play, to the most complicated Broadway extravaganza, will easily speak of the barely controlled chaos required to ensure that the show really does go on. Adding magic to the mix does not make things easier. It merely allows the chaos to take on several more degrees of magnitude, and for the final effect to be so much more spectacular. Thus it was, that as the performers hurried off stage in between scenes, they were met by a small auror force of potioneers, charms masters, and transfiguration experts.

Clothes were switched, altered, and sometimes even fully changed with a flick of a wand. Props, sets, and whole backdrops materialised from space-shrunk trunks and compartments. Actors desperately checked the labels on vials before chugging down more disguise magic than an undercover field unspeakable, before being hustled back into position for their next part, completely different from their last, not just in character, but in height, voice, sex, face, and sometimes even species.

On stage, the settings and backdrops swirled around the stage like water free from gravity, barely staying one form long enough for an actor to pluck a flower from a pot, or a wand from a mantlepiece, before it was off again, becoming the seat under another actor’s rear just as he confidently sat down, seemingly without a care in the world.

And in the centre of it all stood Death, the only unmoving part, orchestrating the surrounding events like a grand puppet master, sending out his champions to the mortal world again and again to ensure the natural order of things. Three hundred-years-old, it was a very traditionally Dark piece of performance art—a Dark magical play, led in the titular role, this time, by a muggleborn.

And as yet another would-be champion of Death came before the terrible higher power, Alexandra Black caught Draco’s eye, smirked, and mouthed the words, ‘you will serve me,’ in time with Death’s own.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Outside of Slytherin Manor, away from Death’s soliloquy, down at the bottom of the hill, Dan Granger sat down with Emma on their comfy living-room sofa, while their daughter and Lord Slytherin sat in the two armchairs opposite.

“Anyway, Slytherin,” Dan said, “It’s good to see you again. The whole island has been crazy the last few weeks.”

“Yes,” Emma added. “I’ll be glad when this is all over. It’s so difficult to concentrate on the work with men and goblins thundering about all the time.”

Slytherin adjusted his mask. “The projects are going well, then?” he asked.

“About as well as since our last owl to you.”

“Ah, that is most satisfying then. And indeed, you are not the only one looking forward to seeing the end of all this, although I’m not talking about the party, but rather my bringing you, finally, into the pact, as it were, about my true identity, for better or worse, although obviously I hope it is for better.”

“You are sure you want to do this?” Dan asked. “We do not mind being kept in the dark. We know the risks.”

Slytherin nodded. “Yes, I am sure. So long as you both are willing.”

“We are,” Emma said. “So, how are we going to do this? Are you just going to whip off that mask and make jazz hands?”

“No, I was planning something more theatrical than that.”

Dan smirked. “More theatrical than jazz hands? So we get our own private magical play while the lords on the hill get theirs. Nice.”

Lord Slytherin held up a finger and caught Hermione’s eye.

Hermione nodded.

“Now, what you have to understand about masks,” Slytherin began as Hermione started fishing in a bag, “is that often there are multiple layers of mask underneath, and I am going to show you who I really am, but you need to understand that it is not the full story, and that I won’t be able to tell you that full story now.”

Dan nodded and saw that Emma did too.

Hermione pulled out two different potions from the bag and gracefully handed them to Slytherin—one mud-coloured, one milky-blue.

“Do you know what these are?” Slytherin asked.

“The brown one is polyjuice, isn’t it?” Emma asked. “I don’t know about the blue one though.”

Slytherin nodded. “Indeed, you are correct. And the milky-blue one is ageing potion antidote.” Slytherin then reached up and plucked a hair from his own head and let it fall into the polyjuice. “Ready?” he asked.

Dan held his breath.

Taking that for his acceptance, Slytherin quickly drank first one, then the other.

In front of Dan’s eyes, Slytherin began to change. He shrunk—not just a little, but a lot! His hair changed colour, grew longer. His robes shrank to fit his new height. And there was a subtle undefinable difference that he couldn’t quite put his finger on. At least, until a slim hand came up and took the mask off.

“Hermione!” Emma gasped.

Hermione smiled a nervous smile. “Hi, Mum. Hi, Dad.”

Dan’s brain stalled for a moment. “But …” He turned his head to where the other ‘Hermione’ had been sitting. He sighed. “Was that really necessary, Lord Slytherin?”

“It was,” the fake-Hermione said.

Only now did Dan see all the Slytherin-like ways this fake-Hermione moved. All the little gestures, the tone of voice.

“Often, the best way to truly appreciate the beauty of a grand deception is by revealing it piece by piece,” Slytherin continued. “Like a maiden letting her clothes fall piece by piece for her husband’s appreciation on her wedding night.”

Dan grimaced. “I’m not sure if I like you saying things like that while wearing my daughter’s form.”

“Then I’m sure this will make you feel at least slightly better.” Slytherin reached into the bag again, withdrew another mud-coloured potion, plucked a hair from his own head, let it fall into the potion, and drank.

Soon, the form of Hermione was replaced by another familiar one.

“Daphne!” Emma gasped. “That was amazing. I truly thought you were Slytherin. Your acting skills!”

Daphne Greengrass smiled slightly.

“Hey,” Hermione cut in. “Don’t I get any credit for my acting skills?”

“Yes, sweetie, of course you do.”

Dan stared at the two girls sitting opposite him. What were they saying? That they were both Slytherin? That Slytherin wasn’t real? That he was made up? “Noooo,” he said slowly. “That can’t be right. We’ve spent years reading the books about the magical world. Lords have to be male. It’s hard-coded into the Albion Family Magics—as are seats on the Wizengamot.”

“You’re right, Dad,” Hermione said. “Neither of us are Lord Slytherin. We just act on his behalf sometimes when he can’t for various reasons.”

“Slytherin trusts you with that?” Emma said, wide-eyed. “And I know you’re his fiancée, Daphne dear, but even so. From what I’ve read such delegation is unheard of in the Wizarding World.”

“Our lord trusts us more than anyone else,” Daphne said.

Something clicked in Dan’s mind. He looked towards his daughter. “Hermione, you know who Lord Slytherin is.”

Hermione nodded.

Dan fell back into the sofa. “Wow.”

Emma leaned forward. “The fact you have kept that secret for—how long—?”

“Over four years.”

“—Over four years, is incredible.”

“Yes,” said a deep voice from the front doorway. The mask in Hermione’s hands leapt from her fingers and flew around the corner, towards the voice. A few seconds later, Lord Slytherin entered the room. “I’m very proud of them. They are the best.”

“I’m glad you think so,” Dan said.

“Especially Luna,” Slytherin continued. “That girl is so amazingly talented and wonderful it’s a miracle they don’t just hand over the whole of Magical Britain to her right now.”

“Errr …” Hermione said.

“In fact,” the man continued. “I’ve decided that Luna’s birthday should be made a national holiday, and everyone will have all the pudding they could want. Unless that means less pudding for Luna, of course, in which case, someone will just have to give up their portion for her, because otherwise it wouldn’t be fair.”

Daphne put a hand over her face.

“And of course we’ll need a statue of her in front of Slytherin Manor. An adult nude maybe, with real robes added on after, like on the ancient Greek statues. I think Luna would really like that. And maybe versions for Alex and Hermione, and Daph—”

“Luna!” Daphne almost shouted.

‘Lord Slytherin,’ paused while counting off on ‘his’ fingers. “Oh, poo,” he said.

A few minutes later, a rather put-out-looking Luna Lovegood sat on the armrest of Hermione’s armchair.

Dan gave them all an amused look. “So, can we expect any more of your friends to be playing Lord Slytherin?”

“Just one more,” said the now-familiar deep voice again. Lord Slytherin stood in the doorway, again.

Emma smiled warmly. “Hello, Harry.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Ginny Weasley grinned as, up on stage, an unknown champion of Death clashed with the king of Gringotts in an epic battle deep in the heart of the bank. Rumour had it that this particular champion had been a Smith, although if that was the case, the Smith family wasn’t saying.

Ginny clapped along with everyone else as the music swelled for the scene’s climax.

Most of the tables sat nine or ten, and hosted two to three families.

Her table was the only large table that hosted only one.

Obviously her father had to be invited. And her mother too, that was a given. Next came Bill. As the current future head of house, not inviting him—when she herself had been invited—would have been socially unacceptable. Then there were the twins, and since their dealings with Slytherin weren’t public knowledge, that meant that Charlie, Percy, and Ron also needed invites.

Once all was said and done, they were the only family in attendance with a table all to themselves, and certainly the only one with more than two children present. In fact, the Weasley children made up a little less than half of all children in attendance.

This had not gone unnoticed, despite the masks. Most had taken it as a sign that the Gray were currently putting pressure on the Dark by leaning closer towards the Light.

While the performers swirled off the stage in a sea of magical mist, Ginny snatched a glance towards the table next to theirs.

For once, the expression on John Potter’s face was incredibly difficult to read. He was deep in hushed conversation with Susan Bones, using the music to muffle his whispering, and didn’t seem to be paying any attention at all to the performance. As the performers leapt back onto the stage to a great crash of cymbals, all theatrically brandishing wands at each other, John Potter glanced up and caught her watching him. For a moment, his expression was absolutely blank. And then, he smirked.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Back down in Granger cottage, the masked Lord Slytherin in the door tilted his head slightly to one side. “What makes you think I’m Harry Potter, Emma?”

Emma Granger smiled mischievously. “It would be only fitting.” She was quite enjoying this guessing game. “We’ve had Hermione and Daphne, and now Luna. Harry is the only one of Hermione’s friends I know left who’s also close to our Lord Slytherin.”

“It would fit the pattern, certainly,” the Lord Slytherin said. “But maybe you are wrong. Maybe I truly am Lord Slytherin. Maybe Harry is hiding behind a bookshelf. Or maybe Slytherin is.”

Luna giggled.

Dan Granger rolled his eyes. “Is he hiding behind a bookshelf?”

“Which one?” the Lord Slytherin asked. “Harry? Slytherin?”

“Either.”

“No.”

Emma Granger pointed a triumphant finger. “So you are definitely one or the other. Actually, I’ve changed my mind. You are the true Lord Slytherin. It’s your gravitas. That feeling of quiet power. I don’t believe that can be faked.”

“I agree. It would be very hard. But it could be. The proof, Dan, Emma, is actually very simple. If one wanted to identify a British lord, how would one do it?”

“His ring,” replied both Dan and Emma in unison.

“Well?” Slytherin pulled off a white glove.

Both Grangers looked down at the Lord Slytherin’s fingers.

There, on his index digit, lay the ring they’d seen many times before.

“Lord Slytherin.” Dan grinned. “So, this really is you. Not Harry. Unless you’ve somehow managed to fake your own ring.”

“That would be difficult,” Lord Slytherin said. “And now I believe it is time for the real reveal.” He nodded towards the girls. “Daphne, if you would.”

The Greengrass heiress passed their lord two vials, one of polyjuice and another—to both Grangers’ confusion—of ageing potion antidote. Lord Slytherin then quickly mixed the polyjuice with a hair from his head, and then drank both potions in quick succession.

To Emma’s shock, and clearly to her husband’s as well, the man started to change, just like the girls had. He shrunk. His hair changed.

The boy removed the mask and gazed at them levelly.

“Harry!” Emma gasped. “But … what? How?”

“Is it that much of a surprise?” Harry asked. “You’ve seen how good our acting skills are. Is it so surprising that together,”—he gestured to the girls—“we could pull something like this off?”

“Yes,” said Dan definitely. “You are too young. That ageing potion proves it.”

“And yet I have the ring.”

Emma frowned. “May I see it closer?”

“Of course, Emma.” He reached out a hand and allowed her to inspect it carefully in her hands, examining it from every angle.

Emma bit her lip. “It looks real.”

“It is real.”

Dan stood up. “I know how to settle this.” He left the room.

Emma let go of Harry’s hand and sat back down. “Listen, Harry. I’m not saying you couldn’t be Lord Slytherin, but you must see how outrageous it sounds. When Lord Slytherin approached us, you were only eight.”

“And I’m only twelve now. But we live in a world of magic. Strange things can happen.”

“Nothing we’ve read could explain this.”

Harry smiled a wry smile. “Oh, dear. Has familiarity already bled all the mystery and wonder out of the magical world? I know you know that the books available to you in Flourish and Blotts are the safe, sanitised ones, approved by the Light for the consumption of those deemed incapable of handling inconvenient truths.”

The girls all mirrored similar wry smiles.

Emma felt distinctly wrong-footed. That certainly sounded like Lord Slytherin. But coming from Harry—that charming boy who’d stolen her daughter’s heart, long before even Hermione knew it—it just sounded odd.

“Here we go,” Dan said, returning with a half-rotted box under one arm. He put the box down on the low table between them. “Now, err … Harry. I’m not saying you couldn’t be Lord Slytherin, but you must see how outrageous it sounds.”

The girls all traded amused looks.

“If it is true, then I certainly understand why you’ve kept it secret all this time. And I—or rather, we’d—be very interested in hearing all the details.”

Harry nodded. “As I said, some details I can’t reveal tonight.”

“Technically, I said that,” said Hermione.

Daphne shook her head. “When you take the role of our lord, your words are not your own.”

“Unless you’re pretending to be Harry, pretending to be Hermione, talking to someone who you know thinks you’re pretending to be—”

“—Yes, Luna,” Daphne cut in. “I think we get the idea. My lord?”

Harry stared down at the box in front of him.

Emma edged closer in her seat. She couldn’t quite believe this was going to work.

Harry opened his mouth … and hissed.

There was a small click.

Emma let out a small sigh. “You really are Lord Slytherin.”

“I am.”

Dan slumped back in his chair. “I suppose it’s better than Hermione being him. We need to talk about many things.”

“Certainly.”

Suddenly, there was a small whoosh of visible magic, and the box-lid flipped itself open.

Everyone in the room, save Harry, but including Emma, gasped.

Inside the box, there was a fist-sized ghost-like gemstone, pouring mist out of the box like a magical fog machine.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Up in the manor, the intermission had started.

Xenophilius Lovegood stood in a small group of young Light nobles, regaling them with his expertise of esoteric myths and legends. One of which was quite topical, given the subject of the performance.

“And so, the three brothers stood triumphant, just like their ancestors at Wessex. After falling to their deception, Death cursed them and all their lines, ‘May conflict rip you apart and Fate herself stalk your heels.’

“But for all the mighty power’s rage, he had agreed to a bargain, and so to each brother, he handed over an object of great power.

“To the first brother, Death gave up his own wand—elder and thestral tail hair—known today simply as the Elder Wand, the Wand of Death, or the Death Stick. This mighty weapon made its wielder near-unbeatable in battle, no matter their skill or power. But with this mighty power came a great curse. The wand would call out to those who sought that power—whispering unheard challenges to the greedy and the insecure. Antioch died gurgling blood from a slit throat while he slept. Since then, all known wielders of the Elder Wand have always needed to keep an eye open for treachery, from the paranoid dread vampire Allred to Light Lord Dimwiddy.

“To the second brother, Death gave the Resurrection Stone, a simple round pebble from the banks of the Black Sea, but infused, like all the artefacts, with an aspect of Death’s power. While the wand contained Death’s magical might, the stone contained his knowledge of what souls resided within his vast realm. With the stone in his possession, Cadmus was able to confirm that his beloved fiancée had not run away from home, as their uncle had always maintained, but had indeed died while under the same uncle’s care. After murdering the man responsible for his love’s Death, Cadmus hanged himself, and the stone was lost to history, never to be seen again.

“And finally, to the third brother, Death granted a cloak of water and magic—the aspect of Death’s separation from the mortal realm. When Ignotus asked Death what his gift did, he was given the answer that it, ‘hides the wearer from the gaze of all, no matter how powerful they might be, including himself.’ And indeed it did. Under the cloak, Ignotus lived for hundreds of years, before finally embracing Death as a brother. Some versions of the legend say he never truly died—that he still lives among us, even now, hidden by the cloak.”

“Could that be true?” asked a sceptical heir.

Xeno’s lips quirked. “Unlikely. The cloak has been glimpsed at various points throughout history, although which sightings are legitimate is always hotly debated. Together, the hallows represent some of the most sought-after artefacts in the Wizarding World, even if the story isn’t as fashionable these days as it used to be.”

“Well, yes,” said the sceptical heir. “Chasing after one legendary artefact is difficult enough. But three at the same time? I know if I were a treasure hunter, I wouldn’t be chasing after a collection that hugely powerful wizards haven’t found for over a thousand years. Surely there would be more accessible prizes out there.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Down in the cottage, Harry was bent over the ghost-like gem, inspecting it from every angle. “Fascinating,” he said. “There’s so much more magic seeping from this one.”

“So, what do you think?” Daphne asked. “Lost relics from ancient civilisations? Some kind of key, perhaps?”

“Maybe it’s a phylactery,” Hermione suggested, excitedly. “That would explain how a non-organic object emanates magic like this. I remember you telling me about the one you and Daphne saw in Gringotts, but I didn’t imagine it to be like this.”

Harry tapped his chin in thought. “Remember that there are other objects that can emanate magic despite not being alive—ward stones, enchanted objects, etc. And yes, I’m aware that it can’t be a ward stone or enchanted,” Harry quickly added as Hermione took a deep breath. “I’m merely pointing out that the precedent exists.”

“Or else it is alive,” Daphne suggested.

The three second-year Hogwarts students were busily crowded around the gem, Luna having already left to rejoin her parents up at the manor.

Across the room, Dan Granger watched the rapid-fire exchange between them with a pensive look on his face.

“Amazing, isn’t it?” Emma said quietly, standing next to him.

“Amazing is one way of putting it. I know we’ve known Harry for over four years now, and Daphne for not much less than that, but it’s still incredible, in the very literal sense of the word.”

“Harry suggests there is deeper magic at work here.”

“That’s the only thing stopping me from declaring it all a con orchestrated by Lord Greengrass.” Dan sighed. “Look at them. They’re so in sync—Hermione, Harry, Daphne, even Luna. If we were still in the muggle world, I’d call this a recipe for heartbreak, but …”

“We’re not in the muggle world anymore.”

Dan snorted. “No. We’re vassals of a twelve-year-old boy, who controls a major political party in a sixteenth-century-style aristocratic government, who is already engaged to two girls, and whom our only daughter is besotted with. You know she’s going to ask us to sign a betrothal contract at some point. What do you think of that?”

Emma pursed her lips. “When I was thirteen I had a huge crush on David Bowie. I read every magazine article. I begged Mum and Dad to take me to see him every chance that came up. I stole a poster from one of those concerts and stuck it up on my bedroom wall. All my friends were jealous of that poster. I was obsessed, really. If you’d asked me back then if I’d like to be his girlfriend, I would have said yes in an instant.”

Emma sighed. “But looking back, I realise that even back then, it wouldn’t have been the truth. Our worlds were just too different. And I was not ready for a real relationship with anyone, not even my rock-star idol.”

Dan grunted.

“But if I learned that he was actually a boy my age,” Emma continued. “A boy masquerading as an adult, successfully, with all of an adult’s maturity and power—a boy just like the boys in school—but who was secretly going around doing world tours and stuff like that, and that he now trusted me with that secret—that he needed me to help him maintain that secret. That would have changed everything. That would have been hard to resist.”

Emma looked back towards Dan and caught his eye.

Dan shrugged. “Working with Lord Slytherin has always been like riding a tiger—like joining a mafia crime family. We host an ex-prostitute as a debt slave, even if doing so does save her from Azkaban. We go to auctions where sapient beings are sold off to the highest bidder. We hobnob with other families who personally fund government departments in exchange for favours and influence. And we’re currently building weapons which our lord is actively flogging to anyone with the gold to pay for them.”

“Harry is Hermione’s magical guardian and has right of first refusal on any betrothal contract we might sign,” said Emma.

“Harry is an abnormally powerful wizard in a polygamy-accepting society, already has two wives picked out, and clearly likes Hermione a lot,” said Dan.

“Hermione is head-over-heels for him, even if she doesn’t quite realise it,” said Emma.

“Hermione is best friends with both of the other girls betrothed to Harry,” said Dan.

They held each others gaze.

Dan sighed. “I’ll talk to our lord.”

Emma nodded. “Then I’ll talk to Hermione. We should try to give it as much time as possible—read up on betrothal magic. Who knows, maybe things will change in a few years.”

“That sounds best. In the meantime, we should focus on making ourselves as valuable as possible to our patron.” Dan lowered his voice even further and hissed, “After all, if Harry is doing all this at twelve, I can’t begin to imagine what the future will hold.”

Emma smirked. “Have a bit of a David Bowie thing going on yourself?”

Dan smiled back wryly. “That’s rich coming from you given the Lord Slytherin mask we have in the bed … side … drawer. …” He trailed off awkwardly.

An uncomfortable silence descended.

“Head-canon, Lord Slytherin is always an adult?” Emma suggested.

“Deal.”

“Mum, Dad.” Hermione swept over. “Harry has a plan.”

“Oh, that’s wonderful, sweetie,” Emma started in an indulgent voice, before snapping herself out of it. “Errr … I mean, yes, Harry?”

Harry smiled as he wandered over. “We already have an agreement with the goblins regarding these artefacts, and given how critical Gringotts is to so many of our plans, I’m loath to put such a useful friendship in jeopardy, even if the chance of being found out is small. Having said that, there’s nothing in the agreement that says how quickly I have to hand them over, so I’d like to ask you both to throw every muggle trick you know at it—to find out as much as you can before then.”

Dan nodded. “How long do we have?”

Harry passed a polyjuice vial to Daphne. “I think about a month is how long we can get away with.” He pulled out a few vials of his own and started drinking.

“Fine,” said Dan. “We’ll get on it just as soon as we finish up the final upgrades on the latest broomsub prototype. The final bidding process for MaCUSA is only a few weeks away. Really, we’re starting to get to the point where help would be useful, but I appreciate how difficult that would be.”

“Indeed.” Harry, now Lord Slytherin, re-attached his mask to his face. Daphne climbed into a trunk, which Hermione then shrunk and pocketed.

“Be good, you three!” Emma called after them as they walked up the garden path. She paused. “With respect, of course!”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

The performance of The Many Champions of Death ended with the title character giving a poetic soliloquy on the nature of magic, life, and place of wizards within it, while his final champion was dragged, kicking and screaming, into the deepest depths of the never-ever, more commonly referred to as hell.

It was a stirring performance, to be sure.

As the curtain fell, the audience all rose up for a standing ovation. The actors came back out and bowed three times before the clapping eventually died down. Dessert followed, the guests already having been served dinner during the production. Chocolate cake, sorbet, cream, and fruits—Alexandra Black tried to look like someone disdaining something they actually liked, rather than someone disdaining something because it tasted like mushy cardboard.

On the other side of the room, Lyndsea Morweena, founder and chief editor of Witch Weekly, couldn’t believe her luck. At the start of the second half, Lord Slytherin had returned to the hall and sat down at her table, escorting an elegant young witch she recognised as Clare Cooper—Slytherin’s reformed prostitute. It was a ballsy move to make for the founding night of what was presumably intended to become a respectable date on the social calendar, but it was also exactly the kind of daring roguishness that fired the imagination, sold newspapers, and as such, she wasn’t complaining.

“Tell me, my lord” she began, after an appropriate amount of small talk. “Was the decision to cast Humphrey Piper as the lead role politically motivated? Do you feel that muggleborns should be given roles normally held by purebloods?”

“Not really,” Slytherin replied in his deep baritone. “I had very little input on that. The Floo Theatre Company simply asked if I would grant them directorial control over the production if they hosted in my new home.”

“You didn’t know Mister Piper was a muggleborn?”

“Yes, I did.”

“So you did implicitly give your approval for a muggleborn to take the lead role?”

Slytherin took a small bit of cake and dabbed his mask lips with a napkin. “I made it clear that I expected the best. I also confirmed when they asked that I wasn’t concerned what background ‘the best’ came from, so long as they were, in fact, the best.”

“A meritocratic stance then?”

“That has long been my policy.”

She leaned in slightly closer. “But aren’t you worried that maybe the Floo Theatre Company chose Mister Piper over more qualified candidates to make a political statement of their own? That they are taking advantage of your hands-off management style to further an extreme pro-muggleborn ideology?”

“I have found no evidence that any such thing is taking place.”

Suddenly, the lights dimmed slightly.

Lord Slytherin placed his fork down on his plate with a small clink sound. “That’s our signal to congregate outside while the house elves prepare the hall for dancing. I hope you’ll join me again later, Lyndsea. This talk has been stimulating. I would like to continue it.”

“Oh, of course, my lord.”

Lyndsea Morweena really couldn’t believe her luck. She was the first journalist in the world to get the chance to pick Lord Slytherin’s brain.

Several tables away, Lord Xenophilius Lovegood watched with a carefully controlled smirk.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

“Quickly!” Plato snapped from the middle of the kitchens, standing on top of one of the granite tabletops while a small army of house elves in pillowcases frantically popped in and out carrying chairs, tables, cutlery, table cloths, flowers, dirty plates, and everything else required for a large formal dinner. “Master needs the hall cleaned soon. Plato will not be seeing him opening those doors to all the Lords and Ladies, just to find you lot still carrying stuff!”

Another dozen or so house elves were busy scrubbing dirty plates and packing up leftovers to be put under stasis charms. More still were popping in to refill empty glasses from a massive selection of ornate-looking bottles.

They’d been seconded from noble houses from all across the country. Greengrass, Lovegood, Smith, Ogden, Moke, Davis, and even Slughorn house elves were represented.

Plato looked around with a satisfied expression. This felt right. Having this many other elves under his command. It felt good. It was just a shame house elf auctions came up so rarely. To get a team anything like this for his master, he’d have to be patient.

A last house elf popped in carrying a silver candlestick—a young female with cute floppy ears.

“Is that last?” Plato barked.

The female nodded furiously.

“Excellent.” Plato stood up and popped away himself. Time to let master know.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Harry nodded back at his head house elf who’d just popped in and given him a subtle nod.

He stood as Lord Slytherin in front of the large double doors, facing the large crowd of milling wizards and witches. “And now,” he called out, instantly silencing the hum of conversation. “I wish you all the best for the last dance of the year.” He swept his arms and the doors swung back open.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Draco shivered. It was December and they were on a Scottish Island. Basic warming charms could only go so far.

He wouldn’t normally choose to be out in temperatures like this, but this was different. He had been summoned. He had been summoned, and he couldn’t help the feeling that whatever was about to happen was going to be important.

So, while his parents were waiting for the dancing to start, he’d slipped out the front doors to look out over the inky blackness of the North Sea. The pathways around the island were lit by magic, creating a spider’s web of light, spreading out from the centre—the manor steps where he now stood—and shining lights on the major landmarks—the greenhouses, the woods, the terraced gardens, the dock, way over on the left side. It was dramatic, magical, and more impressive than any of the other manors he’d seen before.

“What do you think?” asked a voice beside him. It was Pansy. “Better than Malfoy Manor?”

Draco scoffed. “Of course not.”

She giggled.

“He’s not done too badly,” Theo said. “I wonder where he gets his gold? I don’t believe in Slytherin’s treasure for a moment.”

Vincent and Greg stepped into their circle of light. “Dad says he’s found some way around the theft magic of the goblins,” Greg announced. “That he steals it all from the muggles.”

Theo frowned. “I don’t believe that either.”

“Why not?” Vincent asked. “Sounds logical to me.”

“I don’t think—”

“Good evening.”

The four boys and one girl stiffened, then relaxed, but only slightly, as they saw who it was. Alexandra Black, flanked on both sides by the Carrow twins.

“Heiress Black,” Greg and Vincent muttered.

Theo and Pansy both parted, giving their leader a clear path to him, Draco. That minor feeling of dread pooled in his stomach again. He bowed slightly. “Alexandra. You wished to speak with us?”

“I did. Please follow me.” She then turned and walked down the path, which a signpost proclaimed led to the docks.

Draco felt a shiver run up his spine as the others all fell into step behind her. This felt different. This didn’t feel like the normal Alexandra Black he thought he was getting a grip on. And he was pretty sure he knew what was about to happen. Alexandra was going to demand they pledge themselves to her for the rest of their time at Hogwarts. She hadn’t exactly been subtle about her purpose.

The problem was he wasn’t sure he was ready for that. Pledging was a big deal. Yes, Alex looked like their only chance for power while at Hogwarts, but over five years was a long time. Things could change.

They reached the waterfront with little fanfare. It was far quieter down here than up at the manor. The water lapped at the pebbled beach and around the legs of the small wooden pier that jutted out from the island.

Alex turned and regarded them all, but Draco in particular, with an intense look. “I wish to speak to you of the future.”

Draco had expected that.

“About Hogwarts, and beyond.”

And that … less so.

“What about beyond Hogwarts?” Pansy asked.

“Yeah,” Greg added. “That’s ages away.”

One of the Carrow twins growled. “Maybe if you listened to the Dark Heiress, instead of interrupting, she’d tell you.”

“I wasn’t interrupting,” Pansy bit back.

“Yes, you—”

“—Hestia,” Alexandra cut her off.

Hestia Carrow bit back her next words, looking contrite.

Alexandra turned back to stare out to sea again. “The Dark is in trouble.”

Draco frowned.

“For years now, the pureblood cause has been losing power and influence. Before it was to the Light and now it is to the Gray. The Dark knows this, but it has been unable to arrest this decline. Without the Dark Lord, the Dark noble houses have no nexus to coil around. I want to change that.” She turned back to face them. “Do any of you have any idea what Lord Slytherin is capable of?”

The assembled teenagers shuffled their feet.

“Why does it matter?” asked Pansy.

“It matters,” Alex said. “Because your heads of houses all know what Slytherin is up to, but they do nothing. They just sit there, waiting for their fate to seal itself. If you do not act now—if we do not act now—there won’t be any great powers left for any of you to inherit.”

Theo looked sceptical. “Surely you overstate things. Slytherin is on the upswing, yes, but his faction is still the smallest of the three. What could he be doing that would so endanger our families?”

Alexandra pulled something from a pouch and started handing it around. “I intend to show you.”

It was gillyweed.

Draco’s eyes widened. “Hang on! You’re asking us to sneak off to break into some Slytherin secret? Do you have no common sense?!”

“More to the point,” Pansy interjected with narrowed eyes. “How do you know where to lead us?”

“I have allies in the Gray.”

Pansy’s eyes widened, then narrowed, again.

“Allies?” Theo said. “You mean a spy?”

Alexandra just smirked and started chewing on a thick strand of gillyweed.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

The house elves had done a magnificent job. Back up in the main ballroom, all the tables and chairs were gone and the stage had been dissembled, replaced with a much smaller version for a magical orchestral quartet. All around the room, masked wizards and witches were pairing off for dances, safe in the knowledge that exactly who they were dancing with would always be subject to a certain amount of plausible deniability.

One wizard in particular was in high demand, which made the sensation of dancing with him all the stranger for Clare Cooper—former prostitute and current second-year student at Madam Goose’s Home for the Magically Gifted.

“I feel like an imposter,” Clare muttered. She was dressed in by far the most expensive robes and jewellery she’d ever worn. “Everyone’s looking at us.”

Lord Slytherin danced like he fought, with grace and power. Clare couldn’t help feeling a little swept off her feet. “You are doing fine, Clare,” he rumbled. “And everyone is staring because you are beautiful.”

“They’re laughing at me.”

“The women are laughing to hide their jealousy and to play down the threat they feel you represent. The men are angry because they think we are sleeping together and are bitter they cannot do the same.”

They twirled past a couple of older witches giggling behind a pair of fans.

“My lord? Why aren’t you sleeping with me?”

Lord Slytherin didn’t say anything.

“I mean,” Clare hurriedly continued, “I’m not looking for that. I just wondered. I mean, you could easily—I’m not in any position to resist and—”

“—Clare,” Slytherin interrupted. “Please put such matters out of your mind. I am promised twice over and that is all there is to it.”

“Oh.”

Honour. It wasn’t exactly unexpected, but she had to keep reminding herself that the man who now owned her debt wasn’t quite like the others.

Lord Slytherin looked over his shoulder before gazing back at her. “Are you looking to put yourself on the market? Because that is possible, but it would require a lot of preparation on your part.”

“No!” Clare hastily dropped her voice. “No, I mean, I’m not looking.”

“That’s probably for the better. I think continuing your education is important. Although I think it might be a good idea to speed it up as well.”

Clare’s eyes sharpened. “Could I?”

“I believe so. I understand you are doing quite well. Top grades, signs of boredom in class.”

“Who tells you these things?”

Lord Slytherin ignored the question. “If you think you can handle it, I’d like to have you start skipping years.”

“You can do that?! But the teachers always say I have to exactly follow the curriculum schedule.”

“You would if you didn’t have someone to vouch for you. A name like Slytherin takes you a long way in this world. Tell me, what do you think of the Shoe’s teaching staff?”

Clare wrinkled her nose. “Terrible.”

“Why?”

“It’s like they don’t even care about magic. It’s like teaching is just a job. And half of the stuff we learn isn’t even about magic, it’s all stuff you’re not allowed to do, or whose boot you’re supposed to lick if you want to do something.”

“There are no exceptions?”

Clare thought about it. “I suppose the art and music teachers are okay. Why?”

“Apart from general interest in your education? I’m always looking for people who care about what they do. They tend to acquire my respect more easily.” The music slowed and Slytherin dropped down to a slower waltz. “If you’re interested, I’d like you to run some errands for me at your school.”

Clare was instantly on her guard. “This is in exchange for letting me skip years?”

“No, I’ll help you with that, regardless.”

Clare thought about it. “What kind of errands?”

“Running messages, meeting with people about stuff, making friends, being charming and helpful to key individuals, that sort of thing.”

“No sex?”

“Not unless you want to.”

Clare thought about it some more. “Okay,” she eventually said. “I’ll do it.”

“Wonderful.”

They continued to dance and despite herself, Clare couldn’t help feeling just a little bit safer about her position in the world. “My lord?”

“Yes, Clare?”

“What about the others like me?”

“Mmm?”

“The other muggleborns who were tricked into being prostitutes. Isn’t it possible to save them?”

They danced in silence for a moment. Eventually Slytherin asked, “This is in exchange for your working for me?”

“No, I’ll help you with that, regardless.”

Slytherin chuckled before returning to solemnity. “Well, it is not easy,” he said. “Merely buying their debt would not solve the problem. Not so long as there are more untrained muggleborns out there to fill the supply. If anything, I would effectively become a subsidy for the trade, making such snatch-and-obliviate operations more profitable.”

“Oh,” Clare said. She should have guessed it wouldn’t be that easy. “But what about the law? You’re powerful in the Wizengamot, aren’t you?”

Slytherin made a non-committal gesture with his hand before returning it to her waist. “There are many factors to take into account. There are good reasons why I haven’t helped pass any laws for years now.”

Clare’s head dropped. “So, it’s impossible.”

“I didn’t say that.”

She looked up.

“I can’t promise anything, but it so happens that I may soon be in possession of a rather significant piece of leverage over certain powerful Wizengamot members and their associates. Who knows, maybe immigration reform could be stealthily slipped into an upcoming piece of legislation?”

Clare smiled. Her first genuine smile of the night. Satisfied, and no longer feeling quite so self-conscious, she finished her dance with Lord Slytherin and went to stand with Lady Lovegood, carefully putting out of her mind exactly what kind of ‘significant leverage’ her lord might be talking about.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Cold! Every extremity in Draco’s body felt like it was going to drop off. Even with his heated robes, even with the magic of the gillyweed, even with the multiple warming charms that everyone in their group who had a licence to cast magic over the holidays had applied over them, this was still the North Sea in December, and magical Merlin, it was so damn cold!

Ahead of him, Pansy and Alexandra were leading the way, escorted on either side by the Carrow twins, while behind him, Theo, Greg, and Vincent brought up the rear.

The darkness was near-absolute. It was all he could do to keep an eye on the four girls in front of him.

Eventually, Alexandra waved them to a stop and pointed at the rock to their left.

Draco squinted. There was a cave.

Alexandra waved and started swimming inwards. They were going in.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Just outside the front doors of Slytherin Manor, Bill Weasley gazed around the congregating nobility of Magical Britain with a sharp eye. Slytherin had set up benches around the lighted gravel pathway to allow those tired of dancing or mingling the opportunity to cool off in the Scottish winter air. His eyes fell on Lord Greengrass of the Gray, who held the monopoly on the British mandrake trade, among many other important herbs and foods, and who employed over thirty witches and wizards. Then onto Lord Rumalittle of the Dark, whose house owned the public floo network, and employed over forty. And there was Lord Knight of the Light, who owned the Knight buses, lorries, and half of the Hogwarts Express. He employed over seventy.

Bill Weasley frowned. They may technically all be opponents, but as far as he was concerned, where it really mattered, they were all on the same side.

“I’m bored,” Ginny announced, rubbing her shoulders. “Why don’t we go back inside. It’s cold out here.”

Of the 114 noble houses currently sitting on the Wizengamot, there had to be at least fifty or sixty here tonight. And no doubt Slytherin would have invited the most important of the lot. That meant that standing around him, both outside and back in the ballroom, were the employers of possibly a quarter of the whole magical workforce.

“Bill, why do you want me to stick so close to you, if we’re not going to do anything fun?”

And these employers held near-total control of the legislature. They made the laws of Magical Britain. Even before the Gray had put a freeze on new laws being passed, would it shock anyone to learn that the number of pro-labour reforms that had been passed in the last one-hundred years numbered precisely zero?

“Can’t we at least go to the duelling arena? I heard some heirs got into an argument and decided to settle it down there. Can we go, huh? Huh?”

Bill snapped. “No, Ginny. You know Dad asked me to keep an eye on you.”

“But why can’t we go?”

Bill hesitated. He couldn’t say the real reason of course. Dumbledore had entrusted him to keep an eye out for Harry Potter, but at least so far, he hadn’t spotted the boy even once. This difficulty was compounded both by the masks and the presence of John. “We should stay close to the manor,” he said, fishing for an excuse. “Just in case your brothers decide to cause a scene.”

Ginny snorted. “Not likely. I know Dad talked to you about their business with Slytherin. They wouldn’t risk that for anything.”

Bill grimaced. He and his father had had a rather intense argument about that. “I don’t believe our family should be going that route,” he said. “I’ve seen what these family-run businesses can be like.”

Ginny gave him a funny look. “But, all businesses are family-run, aren’t they?”

“Well, yes, but …” He hesitated. How to explain? More importantly, how to explain to his baby sister who had never travelled extensively outside of either the global Wizarding World, or the British one? Just then, he saw a very Harry-Potter-themed individual detach itself from the crowd and slip away into the darkness.

“Ginny,” he said in a firm voice, “go back inside and wait for me near the entrance.”

“Hypocrite!” Ginny shouted as he strode away. “What happened to sticking with me?”

The darkness quickly became a cloak to shield him from watchful eyes as he moved out of range of the magical lights around the manor. But he wasn’t going to rely on that alone. Several charms later, he was disillusioned, scentless, and silenced. He extended his magic sensing out as far as he could to detect whatever magical trip-lines or wards might be up to shield different parts of the island from unwelcome attention.

He tripped none.

Soon, he found his quarry.

The boy was meeting two witches down by a shingle beach overlooking the small island offshore. He crept closer trying to get close enough to overhear what they were talking about. Whatever it was, it could very well be important. The trio kept their voices low, like conspirators, or plotters. He could see that one of them had taken up a large stick and was drawing diagrams in the shingles.

Just then, he realised that he recognised one of the witches.

Virgo Malfoy.

And wasn’t that Susan Bones?

Bill Weasley cursed under his breath. This wasn’t Harry Potter. This was John Potter.

Annoyed, he turned back. It wasn’t as if they were going to have anything important to spy on.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Through the floo they came.

Like a hurricane they bore down.

A horde of crying, hand-wringing, oven-door slamming house elves.

They zoomed past Appleby-in-Westmorland, banked sharply right, zoomed up the east coast, and flew past first Montrose, and then Banchory. They shot like speeding bullets all the way to the coast of Scotland, under the dark North Sea, and finally saw their destination, which they then crashed into, face-first, like a squadron of domestic chickens flying straight into a double-glazed window.

The house elf ward rang like a gong throughout Slytherin Manor.

“Someone get the driver of that bus,” one of the house elves groggily said, before collapsing onto the floo pipe floor with a loud thunk. On closer inspection, all the smashed house elves were wearing the Potter crest on their pillowcases.

There was a loud pop sound, and another, rather better-dressed house elf landed just outside the mess of bodies now trying to untangle themselves. Plato smirked. “I’m sorry. Is you having an invitation?”

“We must be speaking with Lord Potter!” squeaked the female leader.

“No, I is being Plato.”

“What?”

“What, what? And what ho!” Plato waggled his eyebrows. “Plato is talking just to you then.”

The leader stared for a moment before shaking herself. “Lord Potter must be told!”

Plato turned serious. “No outside house elves tonight. Absolutely forbidden. Master’s orders.”

“Lord Potter must be told!”

Plato sighed. “Well, Plato supposes that if Potter elves wanted to write a note, Plato could deign to have it delivered.”

A few minutes later, Lord Potter opened a note presented to him on a silver platter …

Harry is gone! _! We is being SORRY!

… And promptly spat out his drink.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

“A book about your life?!” Gilderoy Lockhart eagerly leaned forward in his chair. He could hardly believe his ears. Nor his luck. It hadn’t been long since he’d been ushered into one of the upstairs side rooms. They’d had some small talk, and then it was down to business. And then this.

Lord Slytherin nodded. “There are many demands on my time. I have a basic outline, but I need a partner well-versed in the subtle art of shaping opinions with the written word. Someone who can weave a compelling narrative and present potentially unpleasant truths as virtues.”

Lockhart preened. “Well, that’s me alright. What kind of unpleasant truths are we talking about here? Spent one night too many with a pretty witch?” He grinned a roguish grin. “Got into trouble with the law back home?”

“That is for later. After you have signed various non-disclosure agreements and sworn an oath of loyalty. But I do not wish to delay too long. There is a lot of work to do and not much time in which to do it.”

Lockhart’s face fell. “Ahh, I do have a lot of work on my plate. Being Headmaster … I did not think it was going to be quite so much. I’m not actually sure how I’m going to work such an intensive project into my schedule.”

Lord Slytherin stood up from his armchair. “Do not worry. I believe there are some functions of your office which you can delegate.”

Lockhart laughed a bitter laugh. “You don’t think I haven’t tried that? The teachers are far too sharp. They spot that trick every time I try it.”

“No, I would not suggest the teachers.” Slytherin paused by the window to look down at the milling wizards outside. “I would suggest the students.”

“The students?” Lockhart asked, incredulous. “Are you serious?”

“Yes. A student Wardrobe—elected in the same way that the Wizengamot elects government heads of departments to the actual Wardrobe. Hogwarts is the training ground for our future elite, after all. It would be only natural that such a program be set up.”

Lockhart’s eyes lit up. “Genius! Yes! It’s all educational! That could work!” His face fell again. “But setting up such a thing would still take a lot of effort.”

“I have also accounted for that.” He snapped his fingers. A door which led off to another room to their side opened, a young masked witch entered, and then took off said mask.

“Miss Davis?” Lockhart hesitated. Wasn’t she only in the second year?

Tracey Davis curtsied to the both of them.

Slytherin gestured to her. “Tracey here will take care of all the administrative details in setting up the student Wardrobe—drafting the constitution, overseeing the process, and ruling on any disputes that arise. As an heiress, she is knowledgeable about our laws and already has great experience in working with students of all ages in both her own house and others. All it requires is a blanket executive order from you granting her the relevant authority.” Slytherin then produced a parchment from the folds of his robes. “Sign here and she can immediately start work.”

Lockhart’s hesitation vanished. After all, Lord Davis was well-known to be Gray. Slytherin would never set the heiress of a key ally up to fail. If she got out of her depth, Slytherin would be forced to support her, and, by extension, him. He grinned widely. “A dealmaker after my own heart!” He quickly read over the Gringotts-approved document, and it all seemed to be in order. “There you go.” He gave his quill a final flourish on the signature line.

Slytherin nodded, retrieved the document, and handed it to Miss Davis who curtsied again and left without a word. Had that been a smirk on her face?

“I will contact you soon to arrange the details of the book deal,” Slytherin said. He turned to go, but came up short by the sound of loud footsteps just outside the door. Moments later, the door burst open and Lord Potter strode in, looking highly agitated.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Draco gazed at the rows of mundane artefacts that lined the cave wall with a mix of curiosity and unease. “What is this?” he asked.

All around him, the other noble children of the Dark strode with equal curiosity along the esoteric and exotic display. They’d swum all the way through the undersea cave to surface into a shabby and dank-looking workshop.

“One of Slytherin’s abandoned projects,” Alexandra answered easily.

“But, it’s all muggle!”

“Astute observation, Malfoy.”

“What is Slytherin doing with muggle fake magic?”

“We will see shortly.”

“What’s this thing?” asked one of the Carrow twins, pointing to a spot on the wall.

“That is a spanner,” Alexandra said. “And that is a wrench.” She hesitated. “I think. Or maybe it’s the other way around. They undo nuts.”

“What?” Gregory asked. “You mean, like, almonds? Pistachios?”

“Nuts made of metal.”

“That won’t taste good.”

“They use them instead of sticking charms.” She wandered over to a huge object hidden by a large white sheet. “Behold!” She threw back the cover.

Draco narrowed his eyes. “That’s a small muggle knight lorry.”

“A van, yes. I was told that Slytherin used it when building the manor to smuggle in contraband.”

“Clever,” Pansy said. “But how? There are no roads to the island.”

“It goes underwater.”

“Surely the muggles can’t drive underwater.”

“I think they can … but certainly not in this. This is part magic.” She threw open the back doors.

Draco recoiled. “But! Combining muggle and magic artefacts is against the law!”

Pansy stuck her head in the van and whistled. “That’s a lot of runes.”

Theo narrowed his eyes. “We could turn information about this place over to the ministry.”

“Sure we could,” Alex said, jumping up and settling down in a chair behind a bunch of metal boxes. “Just so long as we’d be okay with the ministry having a precedent to raid our houses for all the illegal dark artefacts we keep.”

Draco winced.

Alex looked over the top of the metal box. “Theo. You’re not magically weak. Show us your best aguamenti.”

A fine stream of water poured from the end of Theo’s wand.

“Now Pansy, come here and channel your magic alternatively into these two boxes.”

Pansy joined Alex, sat down next to her, and moments later, a torrent of high-pressure water shot from a metal nozzle attached to the boxes. In terms of impressiveness, there was no contest. The difference between Pansy’s and Theo’s efforts were like the difference between a leaky tap and a broken dam.

The water sloshed around Draco’s feet as he looked on in growing horror. The implications were clear.

“See the difference?” Alex asked.

“What the hell was that?!” one of the Carrow twins shouted.

“That is what happens when you mix magic and muggle.”

Vincent grunted. “Why’s Slytherin leave this here, then? This is a powerful artefact.”

Alex laughed. “Because this is just a mere prototype. There’s no way we could get into the actual workshop where they’re working on the real deal. Slytherin is using muggle tools to build magical artefacts that outstrip anything our ancestors created. We are talking Merlin levels of powerful.”

Draco finally found his voice. “If we tell our parents—”

But Alexandra cut him off. “Our parents know! Slytherin has been bidding for an arms contract with MaCUSA for months. All the export parchment has been filed with the ministry. All your parents will know about it. And they do nothing! Slytherin is a rising power. And none of our houses can stop it. Slytherin is not like the Light. If we do nothing, we will soon find ourselves marginalised and stripped. That is what I’m going to stop. I am going to make sure that our families are not on the losing side …”

Pansy’s eyes widened.

“… That is why I want you to pledge yourselves to me tonight.”

Draco Malfoy had been raised many things—intelligent, politically astute, cunning, and many other variants on Machiavellian adjectives. Unfortunately, for this situation, these were combined with a confidence so solid you could build a second Azkaban on top of it. Which is why when Pansy then turned to him and frantically waggled her eyebrows, he simply nodded back.

Obviously, he’d analysed the situation, calculated all possible angles, and arrived at the best possible path forward, both for himself, and for his allies. Draco thought about it for a few more moments before his eyes firmed. “If you believe you can do that, then it is a worthy cause to fight for. I have seen what you are capable of, Alexandra. The House of Malfoy will not fall.”

“Same for the House of Goyle.”

“And Crabbe.”

“And Nott.”

The Carrow twins stood behind Alex, smirking.

Alexandra smiled lightly. “Then step this way and swear your service to me for the rest of your days at Hogwarts.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Three wizards stared at each other, one panting hard.

“Ah.” Lockhart gazed at the irate, unmasked Lord Potter. “Perhaps I should excuse myself.” He got up and quickly left, shutting the door behind him with a click, leaving the two powerful wizards facing each other, face to mask.

Lord Potter looked Slytherin right in the eyehole. “My wife has just left to return to Potter Manor.”

“Oh, dear. I hope nothing is wrong.”

Lord Potter scowled. “Harry is missing.”

“I was wondering why I didn’t see him here.”

“No, not missing like that. He was at Potter Manor when we left.”

“Oh, my. I do hope he’s not in any trouble.”

“Don’t give me that! What are your designs on my house? Only someone of great power could have made Harry the Potter heir.”

“Is Harry Potter your heir now? How interesting.”

“Don’t pretend you didn’t know!”

“I really can’t say that I did.”

“Rubbish! Stay away from my son.”

There was a shift in the feeling of the air.

“Your son.” The words from Slytherin’s mouth carried a cold tone. “What right do you have to call Harry your son? You who shunned him through his childhood. What right do you have?”

“Silence! You have no idea what you are talking about. And you have no right to interfere either way. Harry is a son of House Potter. He is not your son!”

“I agree.”

Lord Potter glared. “What?”

“I agree that he is not my son. But that does not mean I will not continue to do as I please. So long as Harry wishes it, I will continue to shelter and guide him. Just like your parents did for our Lord Black.”

Lord Potter stiffened. This was Lupin. It had to be.

The two wizards stood in silence.

“Your ring,” said Lord Potter.

“I’m sorry?”

“Your ring. Show me your ring. I want to know that you actually are Lord Slytherin.”

Slytherin shrugged and flashed the ring which marked him as such.

Lord Potter carefully inspected it. Yes, it was genuine, alright. Of course it had to be for him to have his seat on the Wizengamot. But even Lupin’s powers didn’t automatically explain how he could have acquired it. But more importantly than that, Slytherin had all but admitted that he was behind Harry’s new heir status. All those Gray children at Hogwarts—Daphne Greengrass, Tracy Davis, the muggleborn girl, and all the others. So long as Harry continued to mix with them, there was no way that he and Lily would be able to maintain the kind of control possibly required by the prophecy.

“Harry Potter will not return to Hogwarts,” he whispered.

“Mmm?” Slytherin rubbed one of his fingers as though checking for a ring that wasn’t there.

Lord Potter drew himself up taller. “Harry Potter will not return to Hogwarts,” he said, louder. “If you will not keep your nose out of my family’s affairs, then I have no choice but to withdraw him—”

“Ooo, look at the time, gotta dash.”

“—and see to his—”

Lord Slytherin apparated away.

“—education elsewhere …”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Of the many traditions that muggleborns find confusing when they first enter the Wizarding World, none are perhaps so misunderstood as the oath.

Not the unbreakable oath, of which only one at a time can be active per person, and which has such a sordid and tragic past that most wizards will refuse to ever swear one. Nor the legalistic magically-enforced contracts of Gringotts, of which muggleborns find themselves perfectly comfortable with, coming as they do from a largely legalistic culture themselves.

No, it is the honour oath that most confuses those new to the Wizarding World.

‘Why not just renege on it?’ they ask. ‘What this guy asked you to swear to is obviously unreasonable. You were under duress. It’s not in your best interests anymore. It’s not as though it’s against the law? It’s just a verbal contract. Not worth the paper it’s printed on … quilled on … you know what I mean.’

Such questions are not entirely without merit.

Since the introduction of Gringotts magical contracts, the conceptual need for honour oaths has decreased markedly. Most business deals are done through the new medium, and internal family disputes are still often handled through the personal law of the Albion Family Magics. Honour oaths are the purview of the nobility, the Dark, and the traditional, taken very seriously, and used in an ever-shrinking range of circumstances across society—the oath an obliviator takes when they first receive their badge—the oath a member of the Wizengamot takes when they first take their seat—the oaths a wizard and witch swear to each other when they are bonded together in marriage.

And of course, there’s the tradition of Hogwarts students pledging themselves to a charismatic leader for the duration of their education.

Down in the tiny sea cave, Draco watched the last of their number swear their allegiance to Alexandra Black. His own oath had been basic but meaningful. He was now a follower of this girl. He would serve her interests, keep her secrets, and if necessary, fight by her side against her enemies. His voice had been calm and firm.

This had been in contrast to Pansy whose voice had wavered like a young whomping willow in a stiff breeze, occasionally shooting him nervous looks as if to say, ‘Is this really okay? Are you really sure about this? I’m not sure about this.’

He’d nodded back.

It was worth the cost. Alexandra Black was powerful. Not counting his sister, she was the only chance his generation of the Dark had to stand up to the juggernauts of the Light and the Gray in a straight-up magical fight.

In the light of their lit wands, Gregory Goyle stood up and bowed. “My lady,” he intoned.

Alexandra nodded back. She waved him away before stepping up onto a random box lying around. She stared down at them all imperiously.

Draco licked his lips.

“Now that you have all sworn,” Alexandra began. “I shall instruct you in our program from here on. I know that you feel that I shall be your weapon against your enemies, but I will not stand to protect weaklings who cannot fight for themselves. Theo, I know you already practise duelling and that is good. From now on, all of you shall work duelling into your education.”

The Carrow twins cheered. Everyone else present all nodded firmly, except Pansy who nervously looked around before quickly nodding as well.

“I also expect all of you to excel in your educations. All of you should be in the top twenty—no exceptions.”

Vincent and Greg groaned.

“Next, we know full well that our bodies are vessels for our magic—the stronger our bodies, the stronger our magics. Therefore, from now on, we will start every day with power exercise around the Black Lake.”

Everyone groaned at that.

“Wait,” Theo said, “we don’t have the time for all this. We already have loads of stuff to do.”

“Au contraire,” Alex retorted. “We have plenty of time. We spend ages every day in the common room, just sitting around. We shall use some of that time.”

Draco frowned. “We have to maintain our station in the common room. If we don’t, the Gray will look more important.”

Strangely, those words caused Pansy to shoot him a look of pure dread. He saw sweat beading on her forehead.

Alex smiled. “Do not worry about that. Now that I am your leader, it is not as important as before.”

“Are we going to know who your spy in the Gray is?” Vincent asked. “We’ve sworn to you now.”

Alexandra nodded. “You will. I already sent them a message a little while ago. They will be here soon.”

Draco noted the lack of specific pronoun. His mind whirled through all the possible candidates. It would probably be someone their age and there weren’t that many of them at the party. It couldn’t be Greengrass or Lovegood. Davis was highly unlikely. He hadn’t even seen Harry yet. It wasn’t impossible for it to be Granger, but somehow he doubted it. But who did that leave?

Just then, the water started to ripple.

There was a massive splash and something burst out from the surface. It took Draco a split-second to realise it was a witch on a broomstick. Long red hair flashed in the wandlight. What happened next happened so fast it was almost impossible to process. Alex flung a stunner at the newcomer with unbelievable speed, which was swatted away equally quickly. The witch threw herself from her broomstick, still in mid-air, rolled, swatted away two more spells from Alexandra, and stood up, right in front of her, both witches snapping their wands against each other’s necks.

It was Ginny.

“Magical Merlin,” Theo whispered.

Draco’s eyes widened. “Weaslette! You’re the spy?”

Ginevra Weasley just flashed him a grin.

Draco’s mind went back into overdrive. If Weasley was the spy, this was brilliant! He didn’t want to admit it, but the girl was also a fearsome power. Everyone knew about the way she’d handled Snape during Defence Against the Dark Arts, and his father had told him there were whispers she would be given special permission to play professionally even while a junior. The position of the Dark was looking better and better by the second.

But for some reason, Ginny’s entrance hadn’t reassured Pansy. If anything, it only seemed to make things worse. Her face was white and her body was curling in on itself as though trying to invent apparition.

“Ginny is not my contact in the Gray,” Alex said.

Pansy whimpered.

Draco frowned. “Then who?”

A deep voice from a corner of the cave said, “Me.”

Draco froze. That voice. Even as it rattled around in his skull, he felt a chill go down his spine. No.

A tall figure stepped out of the shadows. It was richly robed and masked, just like everyone at the party had been, but Draco instinctively knew that this was no body double.

Lord Slytherin.

He whirled his head around to gaze at a distraught-looking Pansy. “I thought you’d realised already,” she mouthed to him. Her body seemed to curl in on itself. “I did.”

Lord Slytherin stepped forward. “I must apologise for this, Heir Malfoy,” he said. “I was originally intending to keep my involvement in this whole affair clandestine for quite a while longer, but events are transpiring against me. I decided this would be better as a bandage ripped off cleanly right at the start.”

“I—I don’t …”

Alexandra and Ginny both curtsied to the Gray Lord as he walked towards them all.

Slowly, a shaking Pansy followed suit, followed quickly by the Carrow twins.

Theo, Gregory and Vincent looked just as pole-axed as he felt. They’d just pledged their service to a witch who was a Gray spy. Their ace in the hand had turned out to be a joker.

“If it is any comfort, I will not force you to bow to me.”

Alexandra’s head whipped up and around. Oppressive magic flared. “Kneel,” she snarled.

Three sets of knees hit the rock floor of the cave.

Draco stared eye to eye with his cousin. He’d never considered it possible. She was too easy. Too naive. Too obvious. But that wasn’t what he saw in those eyes now. Now he saw cold as hard and dark as beads.

Slowly, he too, knelt.

Slytherin clucked his tongue. “Enough. I’m sure you’ve all realised the implications of what has happened here. I shall not treat you unkindly. And I shall ensure that Alex does likewise. If anything, I hope you end up benefiting from this. I believe she will make a good mistress, if a tiring one.”

“Our families …” Pansy said in a shaky voice.

“Please tell them all that has happened here. Except Ginny’s involvement. Leave that bit out.” He stopped in front of the redhead. “I was not expecting to see you here.”

The Weaslette flashed Lord Slytherin an impish smile. “Just wanted to see if I could beat you here.”

Draco wasn’t sure he could feel any lower. Was every powerful wizard their age secretly a member of the Gray? Was John Potter? Was his sister?

“Draco,” Lord Slytherin said, jerking him from his thoughts. “Walk with me.”

There wasn’t far to go into the cave, but they were soon reasonably alone. Draco’s palms were sweating.

“I have plans for Magical Britain, Draco.”

Draco said nothing.

“Many of the old ways are under threat. The future will need powerful wizards of strength and influence. It will need those who understand the importance of family and who value the traditions that have been built up over many millennia.”

“So are you going to throw out all the muggleborns?” someone said. Draco realised it was him. All the repressed anger and frustration was bubbling up, all at once, and he seemed powerless to stop it.

“No,” Slytherin said, simply.

“Then you’re just another Light wizard!” Draco shouted. “If you won’t do something about the muggleborns, then you’re a blood traitor, just like the rest!” Draco’s heart was pounding. “I know you love muggleborns. You have Granger! You invited the Weasleys! Everyone knows they’re Light through and through.” Momentarily spent, he took a deep breath and waited tentatively for the reaction.

Slytherin nodded. “I can see future discussions with you are going to be interesting.” He glanced behind them.

Draco followed the mask’s eyes to see Alexandra ordering what had so recently been the proud Dark leadership at Hogwarts about what they were going to be doing for the rest of the party.

“Do give my regards to your father,” Slytherin said. “I expect this is the kind of thing he’d want to know about as soon as possible.”

There was a crack and Lord Slytherin was gone.

That feeling of dread swiftly returned. His father was going to go full Dark Lord.

—End of Chapter Fifty-Four—

Chapter End Notes

A/N: And the trap snaps shut! Buahaha.

We’re already halfway through writing the next chapter and will start live editing on stream just as soon as that’s ready.

As always, if you enjoy my work, please consider checking out my original projects. All support is appreciated. You can find the links through my website [www * leadvone * com].

A/N: This chapter was drafted and made available early through the LeadVonE discord server, as will the next one. If you fancy discussing this chapter with like-minded people, or anything else DP&SW, feel free to head over there.

A special thank you to the following people for helping catch mistakes on #dpasw-editorial and during the editing live streams: acidicballsweat, Antosha, Arya, ASK, CaptainFlowers (Audio Slave), ChucktheElf, derantx, Dragonbait, drakekiler123, EmergencyAusstieg, FartyArtyPartyPooper, feauxen, Fuuryuu, Gloweye, Hans C, Hawks1129, HylianGhost, Leyrann, Lunatico, MageKing17, Malin, OrigamiGuy2, Ravana, Sauce_salt, sfu, Super Big Mac, Squishysib, themightiestwaffle, Tendra, and TrendyTreky.

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2019’s prices.

Movers and Shakers—Part 3

Through the floor came sounds of dancing. Through the floor came sounds of merry-making. Through the floor came the occasional sounds of a very embarrassed witch or wizard—one who just realised that the charming masked man or woman that they’d just shared an intimate dance with, was, in fact, their wife or husband’s sworn mortal enemy.

Up here, in the private quarters of Slytherin Manor, the muffled sounds of the party below filtered through several layers of wood and carpets, to reach the ears of Daphne and Harry, sitting side-by-side on one of the large sofas, going through large collections of parchment notes on the low table in front of them.

“So much left to do,” Daphne said. “And I’m already tired. I do hope Astoria isn’t embarrassing me down there.”

Footsteps from down the hall caused them both to look up.

“My lord?” Luna poked her head around the corner. She had another stack of parchments under her arm. “Would now be a good time, my lord?”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Outside Slytherin Manor, torch-lit under an ink-black sky, Draco sat on one of the many grassy benches of the duelling arena with his hands under his chin, staring blankly upon the circle of sand below. Down there, his new mistress was going toe-to-toe with a wizard eight years her senior. Black was holding her own, swatting and dodging, shielding when needed and casting out nasty-looking hexes and curses when the opportunities presented themselves.

It was unbelievably impressive, but, Draco noted glumly, it was nowhere near as impressive as taking on the whole Slytherin common room single-handed.

How had he believed, even for a minute, that was possible?

What had been the trick? Had it even been Black? An illusion? Polyjuice? Had there been help? Had her opposition been infiltrated with sleeper agents? Traitors? Informants? Or had the illusion been woven on the fight itself?

It was Harry and John Potter’s fault, that was it.

After they’d completely dismantled the duelling tournament last year, he’d come to see that kind of overwhelming power as normal.

Of course it wasn’t.

Everything about Slytherin’s protégés was ridiculous. Even Weaslette was on their side. Only John and Virgo weren’t … probably.

He shook his head.

No, he couldn’t start thinking like that. His father had Virgo under control, certainly.

At least the pledge he’d made to Black didn’t endanger his family secrets. That was a small blessing.

Down in the arena, Alexandra released her Black chains. They shot towards the shocked-looking duellist and cracked his wand clean out of his hand with a snap that sounded all around the island. Her opponent let out a cry of pain and dropped to his knees.

All around Draco, a mix of indignation and applause emanated from a dozen-ish other spectators.

Red sparks shot into the air. “Disqualified!” called out Lord Slughorn. “No family magics in Standard Class A.”

“WHAT?!” Black shouted. “Potter used his at Hogwarts!”

“This is not Hogwarts, young lady. Hogwarts uses a different variation.”

Draco turned his eyes skyward as the argument escalated. Weasley was up there, somewhere, happily zipping around on a broomstick that she’d found Merlin knew where. One of her hundreds of older brothers had stood around shouting at her to come down for about ten minutes before giving up and going back inside.

At least he didn’t have to deal with that kind of nonsense. Draco shuddered. No, he just had to deal with telling his father how badly he’d messed up.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Back up in the residences, Daphne was sat to one side, taking notes while Luna spoke with Harry. When Luna had said she had some ideas on how they should position the Gray, Daphne had expected many things, but this hadn’t been one of them.

Harry sighed. “It would be nice if my future knowledge extended further. Even if it’s very poor at predicting specific events—except under very special circumstances, like Mount Vesuvius or the Azkaban Earthquake—it’s still invaluable for seeing the shape of what might come. How the wizarding world enforces the International Statute of Secrecy was always going to be a massive issue—but I’ve no idea how different policies might play out.” He looked at Luna, sitting across the table.

“I believe we need to be proactive, my lord,” Luna said. “Even if we were to have an evacuation plan, like Hermione is playing with, we will still need to have the ISS until that is possible. And such an evacuation plan may not be possible, even just for us, for many decades.”

“And you do not believe full integration is an option?”

Luna tilted her head. “We have hundreds of years of separate culture. We are everything muggles fear. We are secret. We live among them. We are powerful. We do as we will. We are answerable to none but ourselves. To muggles, our most powerful could commit the most heinous of crimes with impunity, while our weakest could be easily stopped by a simple bullet to the head.”

“And this,” Harry flipped through the large document Luna had brought with her. “This is your solution.”

Luna nodded. “The ICW obliviators are the most effective, most efficient organisation in the wizarding world. Their reach is global. They operate within each country, nominally under the jurisdiction of each ministry, but in reality separate. They have to. Even one incompetent ministry in some war-torn part of the world could easily blow the secret. But the ICW is not a world government. It is an organisation that operates with the collective will of its members. But even if many scorn the ICW, no one scorns the obliviators. They are the guardians of the wizarding world. Only the aurors are held in greater esteem. And everyone is always so focused on their own problems. Sometimes, they just do not get it. You know that from your talks with Dumbledore. If we position ourselves as the obliviators’ best friends … if we help them with the problems our world is going to face in the future …”

Harry flipped through the document. “I see you’ve put a lot of thought into this.”

“Mum and Dad helped a lot.”

Daphne was reading one of the pages she’d plucked from the pile, fascinated. “Can we really petition the ICW to found our own obliviator squad?”

“There would have to be a good reason, but yes.”

Harry leaned back in his chair, staring at the ceiling for a good few moments before looking back down between her and Luna. “Well, I can’t see any massive problems with playing with this as an idea. We have plenty of irons in the fire. I’m sure I can dream up some way to get that permission.”

Luna smiled. “I know you can, my lord.”

“But in the meantime, I’ve got a bunch of other lords to woo. Daphne?”

Daphne reached into her pocket and drank several potions in quick succession before standing up as Lord Slytherin. “Yes, Harry,” she said, even as her voice changed. “Let’s go.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Down on the arena grassy benches, Pansy Parkinson nervously wrung her hands. “I’m so sorry, Draco. I thought you’d figured it out, too. I mean, Black was being awfully obvious. She said that Slytherin was a rising power. She said that none of our families could stop it. She said that she was going to make sure that we weren’t on the losing side!”

“It was rather obvious, in retrospect,” Nott grumbled.

Draco sat with his head in his hands, watching two other lords loudly going at it in the sand below through the slits in his fingers. Torchlight flickered across the arena.

“It doesn’t have to be so bad,” Pansy said, sounding for all the world like the person she was most trying to convince was herself. “It’s just for school. We’ll be free before we know it. How much does this change, really? What if we’d known Black was Gray from the start? We’d still be faced with Potter and Greengrass and Granger and Weasley and Black. At least this way we do get to be on the winning side while at Hogwarts.”

“Speak for yourself,” Draco muttered. “It might not be so bad for you. Your family was neutral for ages. You’re massively in with Slytherin already.”

“Yeah,” Nott said. “Your dad said he built all this.” He swept his hand around the arena. “And he did the house elves for the manor. That can’t have been cheap.”

Pansy nervously rubbed an arm. “But that doesn’t have to change anything, Draco. I mean, if you ever need help—”

“I don’t need—!” Draco snapped, then instantly regretted it.

Pansy stepped backwards.

“Look,” Draco said in a softer tone. “Right now, I just need to be alone. I’m going to go talk to father soon, and the last thing I need is a pity party.”

Pansy nodded.

Draco stood and walked towards the arena exit, hardly looking where he was going.

Maybe he could find someone willing to give a teenager a glass of firewhisky. Liquid courage layered over occlumency might just help him over the four-dozen doxies playing merry-weather in his stomach.

His mood was not helped by almost walking into two figures leading a small party into the arena as he left.

Lord Slytherin and Harry Potter.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Lord Tempest watched, amused, as the boy who’d almost walked into Lord Slytherin muttered an apology and sulked off.

“That was Malfoy’s squirt, wasn’t it?” asked Lord Smith.

“Probably,” Tempest replied. He couldn’t help but admire the duelling arena they were being led into, even if the circumstances in which they were being led here could charitably be called mysterious. He wasn’t worried. He, Lord Smith, and Lady Pinkerton had all been top duellers back in the day. Nevertheless, the feeling of fresh sand under his feet stirred old memories in his blood. His wand hand itched and a breeze blew through the air, otherwise protected from the fierce winds around the Orkneys.

“Well, Lord Slytherin?” Lady Pinkerton asked with a wrinkle of her rather long nose. She was one of the few guests who had elected to wear her muggle Christmas robes again after the Potter’s Party. “Why all the secrecy? Why did you call us specifically, here?”

“Yes, why?” Smith echoed.

Slytherin gestured to the boy at his side. “I said I would give you a chance to meet Harry, and here it is.”

Tempest snorted. “I don’t believe for one moment you brought us to the duelling arena just for that.”

“No.” Slytherin put a hand on the boy’s shoulder. “I wanted to bring you three into my confidence. Harry here has been training under me for many years and I intend, one day, for him to take over from me as leader of the Gray.”

Lord Tempest felt his blood stir again. “Oh, really?”

“Yes.”

“Why?” asked Lady Pinkerton. “I know he can fight—we all saw his duels last year—but it takes more than that to do your job.”

“Harry,” said Lord Slytherin, “show them.”

Harry Potter, who had been silent this whole time, smirked. He rose his hand and a ring appeared on his finger. “I am Heir Potter.”

Lord Tempest’s eyes went wide.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Back up at the manor, James Potter’s eyes went wide. “Lily!” he hissed, desperately motioning for his wife to lean her head close to his. “I just felt it. Harry broke a family secret. He just told someone he is the heir!”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

“How?” Smith asked, clearly nonplussed.

“The how, I cannot say,” young Harry replied. “All that matters is the fact.”

Lady Pinkerton narrowed her eyes at Slytherin. “You are playing a dangerous game, my lord. Messing with the line of succession of the Albion Family Magics rarely ends well for the meddler.”

“I assure you, my lady, I know exactly the game I am playing.”

“It certainly will be a coup if it works,” Smith said, hefting his massive war hammer over his shoulder. “A good few of the noble Light are reliant on House Potter for their businesses. It wouldn’t give us the majority by any stretch, but it would still be substantial. Was that a family secret?”

“Yes.”

Lord Tempest could feel the wind flowing through his blood.

“Ballsy,” Smith continued. “But it’s all rather academic. That succession won’t happen for decades—possibly as long as a century. Lord Potter is young and arrogant. He is not the kind of man to hand over his Lordship to the younger generation, and certainly not if his son has turned to a major political opponent.”

Lord Tempest wasn’t listening. His eyes were locked with the Potter boy’s—unflinching, cold, calculating. He could feel himself being analysed for any kind of weakness those eyes could find—and those eyes could evidently see plenty. It had been a long time since he’d felt a gaze like that.

He broke eye contact.

“You want us to give our blessing to this boy.” He looked up to stare into Lord Slytherin’s mask. “Like some kind of king of old, calling his lords to swear allegiance to his bastard son. You want us to crown a prince—a child of whom we know nothing of except that he is strong.”

Tempest felt the wind in his blood scream into a full-on gale. His wand slipped into his hand. “Lord Slytherin!” he called out. “If you wish us to recognise this child on strength alone, THEN HE HAD BETTER BE STRONGER THAN MERLIN!”

And the arena was engulfed in a blinding sandstorm.

Lord Tempest would always remember the following fight.

It was as if he, Lord Smith, and Lady Pinkerton had instinctively understood the rules of engagement. The three of them versus the child. As ridiculous as it sounded. If this Potter couldn’t hack it, then tough beans. It would be Slytherin’s mistake for bringing all three of them to the arena. Hard luck for the boy. Squashed like a bug and humiliated by his elders and betters.

But, those eyes.

Lord Tempest had seen eyes like those before.

Eyes hardened by war and a lifetime of suffering.

All three of them were duelling enthusiasts.

All three of them had studied the outlier phenoms that were Harry and John Potter, along with every duellist worth their salt across the whole Wizarding World.

There was no doubt that Harry Potter would put up a good fight.

What he had not expected was power as strong as any opponent he’d ever faced, flames that burned away Pinkerton’s razor flower magic, shields that withstood direct lightning strikes from Smith’s hammer, and a magic sensing ability so fine, that, even through the winds of power swirling around Tempest’s body, the boy was still able to guide spells through the maelstrom.

The fight lasted barely a minute.

“I hope that was instructive,” Lord Slytherin said, walking back across the arena.

Tempest groaned, lying on the ground, head ringing like a struck bell.

Lord Smith was unconscious.

Lady Pinkerton looked up from where she knelt on her hands and knees. “I hope the boy is good for more than just violence.”

Lord Slytherin’s reply sounded amused. “Of course. Much, much more.”

“My lord!” The Davis heiress waved at him from the entrance. “Lady Potter is on her way.”

Slytherin and Potter exchanged a look, and before Tempest’s eyes, Harry Potter faded almost perfectly into the background.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Up near the manor’s large front doors, Draco sat on one of the many provided benches, gloomily watching the many grown-ups enjoying a rest from the dancing inside, and trying to ignore the two witches sitting on either side of him who, it seemed, also knew of his plight.

“Don’t worry, Malfoy,” chirped Daphne Greengrass, sitting on his left. “It could be worse.”

Word among the Gray spread fast, apparently.

“Indeed,” added Granger, sitting on his right. “You should look at this as an opportunity. Our lord is one of the most knowledgeable and brilliant wizards of the age. There is much you could learn, if you put aside pride and embrace his guidance.”

“That’s easy for a mudblood to say,” Draco muttered. “You do best by taking whatever you can get.”

“The best I can get with Lord Slytherin is the best there is.”

“And besides,” Greengrass happily added, “I bet your dad won’t mind too much if it means getting closer to the Gray. Isn’t that what he wanted to begin with?”

“Not if he’s doing the same with Weasley.”

Greengrass pouted. “Now you’re just being a sad and boring boy. We’re at a party! Why don’t you go find a girl to dance with?”

He couldn’t put it off much longer. He was going to have to tell his father soon and it was already getting late.

Draco slowly turned his head and studied the creepily cute expression on Daphne’s face. Something about it just wasn’t right, and with all the subterfuge going on … “Are you sure that’s you, Greengrass?”

Greengrass grinned. “Of course, look!” She showed the heiress ring on her finger.

Draco groaned and put his head in his hands again. As if things weren’t bad enough, being around Slytherin was making him paranoid.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Inside Harry’s shrunk trunk, inside Harry’s pocket, Daphne sat in the plush armchair, wearing only a bathrobe, both eyes closed.

Harry’s dress robes lay strewn on the sofa opposite her.

Daphne focused her divination magic and opened a third eye.

The great and majestic view up someone’s nostrils came into view. Flinching, Daphne pulled back and angled her magic eyeball to take in the more acceptable view of the Slytherin ballroom.

“I do hope you can see the problems we face, Slytherin,” said the owner of the nostrils. It was Lord Malfoy.

“I see many problems,” Harry replied. The two wizards were standing by one of the side doors of the ballroom, deep in conversation. She and Harry had taken flight from the duelling arena sharpish before Lady Potter had arrived, fully intending to briefly drop in to make a quick show of presence before grabbing another pair of lords of the Gray to woo.

That had not happened and she was now very glad Harry had decided to do these rounds in person, rather than rely on her.

Lord Malfoy’s expression barely showed his annoyance … but it did still show it. “What is it you want, Slytherin?” he asked. “You’re obviously angling for certain clauses on the Muggle Protection Act. What are they? I can’t work with you if you won’t tell us. I’m sure that whatever they are, you’re more likely to get them from us than the Light.” The faint hint of annoyance left his face. “I fundamentally believe you and I are more similar than not. Come now, what do you want?”

Daphne sent her eyeball through the wall to check for listeners on the other side before returning to listen in to the conversation.

“Well …” Lord Slytherin started. “I suppose there are one or two things …” He tapped his mask where his chin would be before starting to count on his fingers. “An allowance that muggleborns be allowed to keep banned muggle artefacts on registration when they reach maturity—the inclusion of magical guardians into family law—a monopoly granted to the House of Granger for macro broomstick manufacture—new rules requiring a sixty-day cooling-off period for muggle and half-blood immigration services and for the customer to be visited by a member of the DMLE to ensure they understand what they are signing and to check for magical compulsions—new regulations for obliviators on secondment to the ministry, requiring them to get signed permission from the DMLE before muggleborn parents can have their minds altered—a reconfirmation of the rights of ancient families to properties held in long-term abeyance—an exception on currency controls for allowable goods sold in the muggle world …”

Daphne watched Lord Malfoy’s eyes get progressively larger and larger.

“… And finally, an extension of the printing licence granted to the Noble House of Lovegood for a daily three-page broadsheet edition of the Quibbler focused on muggleborn education and news.”

It took a moment for Malfoy to find his voice. “Absolutely not,” he eventually said firmly. “It is impossible. Yes, some of those things are reasonable, but the others? You want to grant a muggleborn a family monopoly?! Those have always been for nobles and purebloods only. Even if it was warranted, the precedent alone would be horrific.”

Lord Slytherin nodded. “There is one last thing.”

“What?”

Lord Slytherin looked around the ballroom. The energy was starting to wind down now. More waltz and less foxtrot. “A small matter of historical housekeeping,” he said. “A significant financial settlement from the ministry to all victims of the last war—paid for, in part, by public-spirited citizens. Along with a formal amnesty granted to all non-convicted members of the paramilitary wing of the Dark, unofficially known as the Death Eaters.”

Lord Malfoy fell silent. His expression turned guarded. “The Dark long ago disavowed our involvement with that group.”

Lord Slytherin shrugged. “Nevertheless …”

“… Nevertheless, healing the wounds of the past is important.” Malfoy fell silent again. “But no,” he eventually said. “It is still too much. The Dark could never accept all these additions. Perhaps we could talk about individual laws, but as a package? I’m sorry, Lord Slytherin, but you are going to have to do better than that.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

A few moments earlier …

Draco had finally plucked up the courage to go tell his father the news. It hadn’t been difficult finding him. But unfortunately, Lord Malfoy was deep in discussion with the very cause of his problem. There was no way he was going to just walk up to them both and stand waiting like an idiot. Besides, what if his father asked him to explain himself in front of Slytherin? There was no way he could go through with that.

So instead, Draco exited the ballroom through one of the side doors and looped around the long circular corridor to the doorway his father and Slytherin were talking behind.

“I fundamentally believe you and I are more similar than not,” his father said. For whatever reason, Draco could hear his voice through the door! “Come now, what do you want?”

“Well …” Lord Slytherin started.

Draco then listened in mounting horror as Slytherin laid down demand after demand. He was going to be used. He was going to be used as a political hostage against his father.

I’m sorry, Lord Slytherin,” his father concluded at the end of the exchange “but you are going to have to do better than that.”

Draco wasn’t good at magic sensing. Few wizards were. If he was, he might have felt the presence of a magical eyeball slipping through the wall, watching his retreat back the way he came, fist jammed in his mouth, tears in his eyes, doing his best not to hyperventilate.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Draco wasn’t the only one making haste through Slytherin Manor. While Lord Slytherin bid his farewell to Lord Malfoy, and Daphne prepared for their next session with the lords of the Gray, Lord Potter was on the warpath, showing much of the normal condition for armies on the warpath when they can’t find their opponent … eye-watering frustration.

One circle of Slytherin Manor. Two. Three. He checked the grounds and asked anyone whom he vaguely trusted if they’d seen Harry. Most annoyingly, many of them had.

“Why can’t I find him?!”

He burst out of the upstairs washroom after his fourth circle of those areas of the manor open to guests. “I swear I’ve looked everywhere. Lily!”

Lady Potter was advancing towards him up the corridor. “I can’t find him either. I know he was here. Tempest all but admitted Harry was fighting them in the duelling arena before I arrived.”

James ran a hand through his hair. “This is getting out of hand. We can’t let him—” Another pulse of family magic shot through him. “He just told someone else!”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

“Mmmmm, very nice.” Lord Smith carefully inspected the unquestionably expert-level alchemy that young Harry Potter had produced for them in one of the locked antechambers off the main ballroom.

Lord Woodcroft nodded. “And he’s, what? Twelve?”

“I’d expect this level of quality from a journeyman alchemist at least,” Lady Woodcroft added in a voice of mild awe. She had an eye pressed right up to one side of the large glass statue Harry had formed out of sand in the middle of the room. Unlike the wandless parlour-trick glass statues the boy was in the habit of impressing other people with, this statue contained an unbelievable level of alchemical skill and insight. The glass reflected and refracted light as it passed through, highlighting individual runes that had been formed on the inside in wonderful spiral patterns.

Lord Head burst into laughter, again. “I still can’t get over him being the Potter heir. The boy-who-lived must be pitching a fit.”

Off to one side stood Daphne Greengrass, currently Lord Slytherin. She had a fatherly hand on Harry’s shoulder and felt extremely weird about it. “I plan for Harry to one day take my place as leader of the Gray,” she said.

Lady Hailbob raised an eyebrow. “You are playing a dangerous game, Lord Slytherin. The family magics do not respond well to attempts to subvert their will.”

“Maybe. But that game is mine to play.”

Lord Hailbob chuckled. “This is why I like you. What other craft talents does the boy have?”

“Harry?” Daphne said.

Harry smiled a small smile. “I am proficient in rune-cluster exploration, spell exploration, arithmancy, arithmetical occlumency, alchemy, permanent charms, potion discovery, ritual negotiation, Latin, Ancient Greek, Nordic, and Coptic.”

All eyes in the room turned to stare at him.

“Merlin,” Woodcroft whispered.

Lord Head laughed, again. “Literally.”

Lord Smith chuckled. “Very intellectually minded, this one. Not smelting? I feel insulted. Not weaving? Not tailoring? Not woodworking?”

Harry gave an apologetic smile. “I’m currently working on a pottery project, but apart from that, I’m afraid not. I’ve always had more talent for high-level magic, than low-level. I prefer to leave complex manufacturing to others.”

There was a sudden loud banging on the door. “Harry?! Are you in there!? We’re leaving now! I demand you open this door!”

Daphne turned to Harry and extended her arm. Harry took it. No one noticed that it was the boy who apparated out Lord Slytherin.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Draco stared out at the sea of endless blackness. Sitting on the pebbles was uncomfortable, but right now, he couldn’t care less. He picked up a pebble and carelessly tossed it into the surf. It went plonk.

Azkaban was out there, not too far away.

How far could a dementor’s aura reach? He fancied he could feel the happiness-sucking demons’ power through the veil of night. The darkness was like a curtain and those bony hands could just reach straight through it and devour him whole. Maybe it would be better if they did?

Draco Malfoy had never encountered the idea of broody teenage melodrama, but innovation has a habit of developing along the cutting edge of the adjacent possible, and right now, Draco Malfoy was so cutting edge that had he tried to, say, don tight leather pants, they’d have pre-shredded themselves just to save the universe the trouble.

“Oh, what a beautiful nighttime~” sang a girl’s voice. “Oh, what a beautiful dusk~”

Draco grunted. Of course he wasn’t going to be left alone. Why had he thought that just because he’d crept away all by himself, making sure to sink into the darkest shadows, and wind his way down to the least lit bit of beach, that people would figure out he didn’t want any company.

“Ninety-nine phantoms of fear in the brig~ Ninety-nine phantoms of fear~ A prisoner escapes and another gives chase, Ninety-eight phantoms of fear~”

Draco groaned and looked around.

“Hi, there, fellow Slytherin servant,” said Luna Lovegood.

Draco glared. “I am not Slytherin’s servant.”

“No?” Lovegood adjusted her skirts and sat down next to him. “Then why did you pledge yourself to Alex?”

Draco snapped. “I didn’t know that Black was a spy!”

“Mmmm …” Lovegood put a finger on her lips. “I guess that does spoil things a bit. Tricking people like that isn’t nice. But then, my lord is not always a nice person. But look on the bright side. Now that you’re on the winning side, you’ll never have to worry about running a faction of your own. You can just let Slytherin do all that work. Being the responsible one is hard. Better just to lie back and let the big boys handle things.”

Draco clenched his teeth. This didn’t even qualify as rubbing salt into the wound. This was like a beach-going child filling up a wound with coarse sand and then digging it back out again because their castle needed another turret.

“Besides, the worst is over now. I’m sure Lord Malfoy will handle things now that he knows what’s going on.”

There was a moment of silence.

Draco felt his ears burning. He should have just told his father. He shouldn’t have run away like that. He shouldn’t have.

Lovegood snorted.

It was such an out-of-character sound coming from her that Draco did a double-take.

“This is exactly why you joining the Gray will be good for you,” she said.

“What, why?”

“Because~” she said in a sing-song voice, “you are being a pussy~”

Draco coughed, loudly. “A what?!”

“A p-u-s-s-y~” Lovegood’s voice dropped back to its normal dreamy tone. “A coward. A little boy who cannot accept responsibility. A maiden in need of rescuing. A con-man who messed up and now wants to skip town. A little girl who wet her knickers and is now crying because her daddy is going to get mad.”

“Enough!” Draco was on his feet now. “Who the hells are you to speak like this to me? I am Heir Malfoy! Future leader of the Dark.”

“And I am Heiress Lovegood~ Future fuck-toy of Lord Slytherin, leader of the Gray, and future leader of all of Magical Britain—Light, Gray, or otherwise.”

That stopped Draco. He stared at Lovegood.

“Have you not heard what people are whispering?” the girl said. “They are saying that Lord Slytherin is not merely the leader of the Gray, they are saying he is something new, sprung forth from the old—a Gray Lord.”

Draco had heard, of course. The title of lord of lords was as old as the Albion itself. Merlin had been a lord of lords. It had started out meaning, ‘first among equals,’ but over the centuries the meaning had been warped. Nowadays, lord of lords meant someone willing to go far outside the law to advance the political agenda of some faction or other, or so his father had once solemnly explained to him in the secrecy of his family office.

Voldemort had been a Dark Lord—as had Grindelwald, while he’d been active in Magical Britain.

Other nations had adopted the terminology, but mostly lacked the history and tradition. In most places, it simply meant ‘strong man,’ or ‘warlord.’ Only in Magical Britain did the title come with any kind of legitimacy—perversely, given what lords of lords usually ended up like.

“Look at how strong we are, Draco,” Lovegood whispered.

Draco shivered. He could indeed feel incredible power radiating from Lovegood. How had he never noticed it before?

“Look at what Alex, Ginny, Hermione, and even I, are able to achieve. Remember how strong you felt when you summoned that basilisk? Remember the power flowing through you? That could be you. That kind of power.” Lovegood leaned in closer. “You must only submit to my lord’s will.”

Draco stepped backwards. “I—I must go!” He ran.

He wasn’t running away, oh no. He wasn’t being a coward, absolutely not. He was merely engaged in a strategic withdrawal, heading for higher ground, rallying his allies, and seeking advice from knowledgeable sources. In other words, he was going to make sure his father heard about this.

It was that or stay near Lovegood for even a single second longer. Good luck to Lord Slytherin, he thought. He thought he’d known crazy with Black, but Lovegood mirrored her and turned it up to eleven. Even a man as formidable as he would need every drop of it to deal with a witch like that.

Back on the beach, Luna watched as Draco Malfoy retreated up the garden path, a small smile on her face, before turning around and humming her way along the beach, hands stretched out on either side.

“Ninety-eight phantoms of fear in the brig~ Ninety-eight phantoms of fear~ A prisoner escapes and another gives chase, ninety-seven phantoms of fear~”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

“Hah! I see your pair of staves and raise you four good wands.” Lord Davis smacked his cards down on the table and returned his hand to his cane.

Lord Slughorn grunted. “Don’t look too happy. The boy still has to show his hand.”

“Bah! Harry’s bluffing. I know that look.” Lord Davis winked at Harry. “You can’t fool this old politician, kid.”

Harry smiled faintly. He then leaned forward and laid out a magical flush.

The crowd surrounding the poker table broke out into polite applause.

“Oh, I say.”

“Well done, boy.”

Lord Davis looked pole-axed.

Lord Slughorn grunted again. “You should have tried using legilimency, Davis. Then you’d have known he wasn’t playing games.”

“You used legilimency to beat a child at poker!?” exclaimed one of the bystanders.

Slughorn twisted in his chair. “If the boy couldn’t defend himself from something like that, he has no business among us.”

Harry pulled the small pile of chips towards himself. “Quite right, Lord Slughorn. Birthrights and opportunity can only take you so far. When the bagpipes sound, it is the sum of your preparation and skill that cuts out the winners from the losers.”

One of the ladies giggled behind her fan. “Oh, my. Precocious, isn’t he?”

“But, Harry,” said another, “what about those who work just as hard, but do not have the same opportunities?”

Harry smiled. “Many of us in the Gray have businesses that rely on skilled wizards. Surely it is in our best interests to grant those opportunities, where appropriate.”

“Aye,” said Lord Ogden. “I fully agree there. Getting qualified wands is so difficult these days.”

“But meritocratic extremism is also dangerous.” Lord Davis said with a waving of a finger. “You may not know this, kid, but Light Lord Dimwiddy was famous for promoting based on merit—and look how many noble families he wiped out.”

Harry nodded. “And Dimwiddy built one of the largest magical empires the world has ever seen in only five years—something that would have been impossible without generals like Clementine and Adams, and neither of them was noble. Obviously meritocracy has to be managed, but to deny its efficacy is also dangerous.”

“Hear, hear.” Lord Ogden raised his glass of brandy.

“What I want to know,” said Lord Slughorn, gazing at Harry over steepled fingers, “is how you managed to swipe the heirship away from your brother.”

“Walter!” gasped one of the witches.

“I think it’s a perfectly valid question,” Slughorn continued, not breaking eye contact. “If Slytherin wants to make him his effective heir presumptive, then we have a right to know how likely the power of the Albion might come crashing down on us.”

Harry shrugged. “There are many secrets hidden among the families that could bring great trouble to the world if they came to light,” he said. “But the will of the Albion has never descended on any family because of the actions of another. Your personal interests are perfectly safe, Lord Slughorn.” Harry looked away. “Besides, my current position is as much a matter of Fated accident as of purposeful machinations. I am confident the Albion will not judge unfavourably, given the circumstances.”

“Mmmmm …” Slughorn didn’t look convinced.

Harry felt a hand on his shoulder. “Having a good time, Harry?” asked a deep voice.

It was Daphne, or, more usefully, it was Lord Slytherin.

Harry smiled. “I think I have won enough to pay for dinner.”

There was a chorus of polite laughter.

“The lad is quite something, Slytherin,” said Lord Ogden. “You should have introduced him to us earlier. But won’t Lord Potter make a fuss?”

“I dare say he will,” Daphne rumbled.

“I would have liked to see him here,” Lord Davis chuckled. “James Potter was one of the best magical poker players Hogwarts ever saw.”

“Unfortunately …” Daphne gestured to Harry who stood up. “That might very well happen if we do not make haste. While I have no issue dealing with an irate Lord Potter, I have matters to take care of before the ritual. Listening to his protests would get in the way.”

The assembled lords and ladies chuckled again.

Harry and Lord Slytherin apparated out.

When a furious Lord Potter finally arrived, it was to find many of his fellow lords filing out of the door that he’d been tipped off to containing Harry. Many were giving him infuriatingly cheerful looks, and when he finally manoeuvred his way past them and into the empty room, it was to find it, well, empty.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Determined, Draco strode into the main ballroom and took up position several mingling groups away from his father. Lord Malfoy was currently in whispered discussion with his sister. Draco still wasn’t sure exactly what Virgo’s deal was, but she certainly seemed to have his father’s ear. A flash of jealousy spiked through him before he shook it away. He had more important plimpies to pickle.

“What’s wrong, Draco?” asked his mother’s voice.

Draco turned.

Lady Malfoy was still wearing her mask. Some of the guests had started strategically ditching theirs as the night wore on, but most still wore theirs.

“I just need to speak with father,” Draco said.

His mother sighed. “I know that look. How bad is it?”

“Bad.”

“Did you upset someone important?”

Draco shook his head.

“Did someone catch you doing something you shouldn’t have been?”

Draco shook his head again.

“Worse?”

Draco nodded.

“Go on then. Tell your mother. Maybe she will be able to advise you.”

“I pledged my allegiance to Alexandra Black.”

“Oh,” Narcissa’s whole body relaxed. “That’s not so—”

“—It turns out Alexandra Black is a Gray spy.”

His mother stilled. The next thing he knew, she’d firmly grabbed his arm, causing him to yelp, and dragged him out of the nearest door, much to the general interest of lookers-on.

Now in the long curved corridor surrounding the ballroom, she whipped off her half-Slytherin mask, bent down, and looked him straight in the eye. “Are you sure, Draco?” Her face was deadly serious. “How do you know?”

“Lord Slytherin showed up almost immediately after. We had a discussion.”

Narcissa cursed under her breath. She straightened up and looked away, her expression fierce. “This is not good. We had high hopes for Miss Black.” She looked back at him. “But this does not have to be a catastrophe. No doubt the Gray intend to sway you to their cause over the next five years, but that can easily work two ways. You are my son and heir to the Noble House of Malfoy. You will not be so easily won by those children. And now that Alexandra has shown her true colours, the children of our allies can work together to marginalise her influence.”

“Ummm. …” Draco felt that sick dread threaten to overwhelm him again, but he got it under control with several long, deep breaths and a focusing of his occlumency. “That may not work, Mother.”

“Why not?”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Lord Malfoy watched his daughter sweep elegantly away, the very model of pre-teen, pureblood witch. Unless one knew the full story, it would be impossible to tell that Virgo was in fact, neither pre-teen, nor pureblood, nor even a witch … sort of.

He surreptitiously waved his wand over the glass of red wine a house elf had just handed him and took a sip.

She had certainly come a long way in a short time—as to be expected of someone who would go on to become one of the most feared Dark Lords Magical Britain had ever seen.

Very interesting that the teenage Lord Voldemort now wished to pursue a far more traditionally feminine power strategy. He’d have never suspected when they started this little project that the mind could become a slave to the body so quickly.

In many ways, he was relieved. Having Virgo betrothed would be close to ideal.

He hadn’t been looking forward to the questions over the next few years about why he wasn’t accepting offers for his daughter’s hand. It would have been odd—out of place—suspicious. Not damning in and of itself, but little things could easily add up in the minds of people. The last thing he needed was for it to be suspected she was blood-adopted. A bastard he’d sired from an extramarital affair with a long-lost Gaunt was far more preferable in that regard.

And to have his daughter—his Dark Trojan horse—betrothed to John Potter? Lord Malfoy allowed himself a tiny smirk. That would be quite a coup. Now he just had to figure out how to pull it off while extracting from Lord Potter every last possible knut.

At that moment, he spotted his wife surreptitiously flagging him down across the hall. “I’m so sorry, Whittle,” he said to a business associate, who chose that instant to sidle up. “But I’ve just noticed my wife wishes a word with me.”

Interestingly, Narcissa didn’t only lead him outside the ballroom, but insisted they also retreat to one of the many smaller rooms that Slytherin had set aside for all the many private meetings that inevitably took place during any large-scale gathering of wizarding aristocracy.

“Draco?” Lord Malfoy raised an eyebrow. His son stood in the middle of the room, looking oddly determined. He turned to his wife. “What’s this about?”

“Draco here has something to tell you, dear.” Narcissa then sat down in a nearby high-back chair and crossed her arms.

Lucius sighed inside. Draco getting himself into noteworthy situations was becoming increasingly common. He still vividly recalled his own reaction to his son being part-responsible for the death of Magical Britain’s acromantula patriarch, the renegotiating of a decades-old treaty, and the brief uniting of all Wizengamot factions in rushing through legislation banning him from basilisk summoning exploration.

“What is it, Draco?” he asked.

“I have pledged myself to the service of Alexandra Black for the duration of my time at Hogwarts.”

Oh. But that couldn’t be all …

“I then found out that Alexandra is a Gray spy and that Lord Slytherin placed her at Hogwarts specifically to usurp my leadership of the Dark.”

Damn. That was going to be politically annoying to deal with. He’d have to keep a closer eye on his son from now on. No doubt many other lords would panic, if they were in this kind of situation, and do something stupid like waste a huge amount of political capital trying to get their heir out of their oath. But he hadn’t been Lord Voldemort’s right hand for nothing. Slytherin would only have minimal personal interaction with Draco while at Hogwarts and, with good coaching, the Gray children could be worked around. It wasn’t something that their family couldn’t handle and might even give Draco good experience in dealing with more nuanced political situations.

He opened his mouth to say as much.

“Theo, Pansy, Vincent, Greg, Hestia, and Flora have also pledged themselves.”

Lord Malfoy firmly shut his mouth. He closed his eyes, willed his strongest occlumency barriers into being, and silently began counting to ten.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

“I must admit, the boy is quite something,” said Lady Hodgekin.

Daphne nodded.

“Finding him must have been like finding an uncut diamond in a cauldron of congealed potion sludge,” the woman continued. Her husband ran Magical Britain’s only waste disposal service for things that couldn’t simply be vanished, which was actually most things.

Daphne nodded, again. “Indeed,” she rumbled. “I am very proud of him.”

“But, Lord Slytherin,” said Mrs. Fudge. “Isn’t naming this boy as your effective heir to the Gray leadership a dangerous move? What about your own children? Adoptive heirs are exactly the reason blood adoption was made illegal. And aren’t you afraid of retaliation from the Potters?”

Daphne shrugged. “I’m sure my children will be able to make something of themselves without hanging off my robe-cuffs. And grooming a successor to a political faction is very different from raising an heir for a family. But if you will excuse me, ladies, I am going to go prepare for the ritual—”

Daphne made to turn to leave, before spotting who was walking towards her with a very purposeful gait. “Ah.”

Both Lady Hodgekin and Mrs. Fudge raised eyebrows as Lord Malfoy strode over.

“Slytherin, a word, if you will.” His voice was terse.

Oh dear, Daphne thought. She remained silent an appropriately disrespectful amount of time, given his tone, before nodding once and leading them off to an empty room on the second floor, but not before buzzing Harry on her ring.

The moment the door was closed, Lord Malfoy rounded on her. “If you think I will be manipulated like this, Slytherin, then you are wrong.”

On Daphne’s forehead, a bead of sweat formed and ran down her face, but she kept her voice steady. “I really don’t know what you mean. You know I am always looking for talent to nurture. Draco, Pansy, and the others have been quite impressive. I merely wish to contribute to their education.”

“I do not believe that for a second. What will it take to buy you out?”

“Buy me out? I hope you recall that it is not to me that your son has pledged himself.”

“Don’t give me that! Name a price—gold, artefacts, magic, but!” He drew himself to his full height. “Understand this, Slytherin—if it is your full version of the Muggle Protection Act you wish to push through, then absolutely not. Selling out the entire Dark to correct the mistake of a handful of their children is not something I could ever countenance.”

Daphne’s heart was pounding, but at that moment, from the corner of the room, Harry’s hand appeared from nothing and gave her a thumbs-up.

Her body relaxed a tad. “That’s a shame,” she replied. “Then I don’t see what else could be done. I don’t feel I have any need for gold right now. But worry not, Lord Malfoy. I assure you that Heiress Black will make an excellent leader for your son. I believe she is already planning to increase his focus on his practical education and physical fitness.”

She held her breath while Lord Malfoy studied her. She could feel the tension wanting to pool a stunner in her fingers. She had to magically hold it back.

“This is not over, Slytherin,” he eventually said before turning around and sweeping out of the room.

In the darkest corner of the room, Harry dropped the cloak over his shoulders so that just his head showed. “I’m counting on it, Lucius.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

James Potter was getting desperate.

More and more people were learning the secret. He could feel the stares, the snickers. Wizarding aristocracy gossiped like old maids and right now, the gossip was clearly on one topic—the heirship of the Ancient and Noble House of Potter.

Harry had broken a family secret. He’d felt it. Harry knew it. Everyone knew it.

If he could get Harry back to Potter Manor, his role as Harry’s lord would give him far more legal leverage than before. Breaking family secrets was one of the misdeeds lords could try those under their power for in their own manorial courts. But would that even be possible? Qui tenet teneat, qui dolet doleat.

Harry was here, he knew he was. If he couldn’t find him before the night was over, would Harry even return to Potter Manor? Lily was waiting by the floo, just in case Harry decided to make a break for it that way, John reluctantly by her side. As soon as they found Harry, they were leaving.

He spotted another of his quarries coming out of the washroom while walking around the ballroom corridor ring for what felt like the hundredth time. “Headmaster!”

Lockhart turned around and, with a roguish grin that made James want to hex the man, said, “Ah, Lord Potter, dear chap. What can I do you for?”

“I want to inform you that Harry will not be returning to Hogwarts.”

Lockhart looked surprised. “Really? Why ever so? Hogwarts is the best school in the world. Everyone knows that.”

“Nothing against Hogwarts—this is for family reasons. Tomorrow I will be talking to the headmasters of Durmstrung and Beauxbatons to enquire about transfer places. I expect all the parchment-work to be ready when they come flooing.”

Lockhart sighed. “Of course, my Lord.”

“Good.” James turned around again and walked off, and got no further than just out of sight of the headmaster before another wizard he wanted to speak to, closed a door to the ballroom behind him with a sigh.

“Padfoot!”

Lord Black’s eyes lit up. “Prongs! Thank Merlin, you have to save me! I thought I could handle everyone secretly thinking I was Dark, but now everyone thinks I’m secretly Slytherin’s right-hand man! Well, a few people anyway—two at least. Parkinson was furious, and I’m glad I’m an auror, because Nott looked like he wanted to curse me right there and then, but—”

“Padfoot! I need you to arrest Slytherin!”

Sirius stopped in mid-rant. “Say wha … ?”

“He’s going to kidnap Harry! I’ve been trying to find him for an hour now, but he always slips me by and if I don’t find him by the end of tonight—”

“Whoa, whoa! Prongs! Back up a bit, will you?”

James quickly explained the situation to a rapidly worried-looking Lord Black.

“Ah,” Sirius said after he was done. “I do see your problem, but …” He shifted uneasily.

“But what?! Kidnap is illegal! Slytherin pretty much admitted he would help Harry run away from home. That counts! I know it does, Padfoot. I know the law.”

“Yes, but … there is a precedent for this. An heir who ran away from home was granted asylum by another noble house and the court ruled it legal.”

James Potter exploded. “Your situation was different! The court only ruled in your favour because you had ‘justifiable cause’ and were ‘in fear for your life!’ ”

Sirius looked away. “Prongs, mate, look, I know that you wouldn’t ever do anything like that, but, well, you have to see how it looks. Is it true that Harry is the Potter heir?”

“Only until I fix that!”

Sirius winced. “Yeah, see, that’s exactly the kind of thing you shouldn’t have just said.”

James looked horrified. “That’s not what I—”

“—Prongs! I know it isn’t what you meant. But that’s besides the point. Harry wasn’t raised your heir. He was raised by muggles for his entire childhood. And then suddenly he’s back in the Wizarding World and you still didn’t talk to him for his whole first year of Hogwarts. Then, suddenly, somehow, Harry is now the heir, possibly under very dodgy circumstances, and the moment that happens, Harry wants to run away from home.”

“He’s only running away because he broke a family secret.” James’ voice turned pleading. “Look, Sirius, you have to help me. If I can’t pull Harry out of Hogwarts, then he’s going to be stuck in there with all those Gray children for the next five years. Think about what kind of horrible influence they’ll be.”

Sirius’ expression cooled. “Alex is Gray.”

Huh?

James’ mind, so quickly and rapidly powering through the long grass of panic, stepped on a molehill and tripped right into the dirt. “I didn’t mean Alex, obviously.” His brow furrowed. “Alex is Gray?”

“Yeah. You remember I told you that Harry said I shouldn’t worry about Alex hanging out with the Dark kids? Turns out it was all a plot. She just got a bunch of Dark heirs to pledge to her and then revealed her ‘true allegiance’.”

“And Slytherin orchestrated all this? Magical Merlin, it’s worse than I thought. Padfoot! We have to stop this!”

Sirius straightened up. “Prongs, I’m not going to try and arrest Slytherin. If you want my advice, take this to court, but argue that Slytherin has a vested interest in keeping Harry away from your family and argue that if asylum should be granted, then it should be a different family that does it.”

“I can’t do that!”

“Then I can’t help you. I’m sorry, Prongs.”

Not long after, the entire ballroom was treated to the unusual sight of Lord Potter storming straight through the dancers towards the floo. “We’re leaving!” he shouted.

John Potter looked shocked, “What? But what about—”

“No buts, John. We’re off!”

Lord Potter grabbed John’s wrist, motioned Lady Potter in front of him, and stepped into the floo.

From not far away, someone shouted something. The voice was young, female, and full of panic. “Accio John Potter!”

Lord Potter’s grip slipped on John’s wrist, just as the green flames engulfed him and he was whisked away through the floo.

John Potter fell on his back and shot towards the spell-caster along the marble floor, eventually coming to rest at her feet. It was Virgo.

“Magical Merlin,” she gasped. “That was too close. Can’t have you missing the Stella Benedictio.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

The path to the bottom of the hill glowed with the light of a hundred curtsying fairies. A wizarding lord cast a warming charm on his tired wife, who smiled and readjusted the scarf around her neck. A pair of young heirs walked a slurring third, gently slung between them by his shoulders. The general slow press of wizardry was out of the manor and down.

And at the bottom of the hill, hidden by a grove of trees off the main path, stood a circle of eight-foot-tall rune stones, surrounded all the way by a simple wooden bench.

Back up at the manor, Alexandra Black confidently strode through the entranceway towards the front doors.

“Heiress Black?” The voice was as smooth as silk.

Alex started and found herself staring mask-to-mask with a familiar masked wizard with long, blond hair and a silver, snake’s-head cane. “Lord Malfoy, what a pleasure and a surprise.”

Lord Malfoy tipped his mask. “I wish I could say that the pleasure was mine as well. The surprise, however, I will grant you. You have been most surprising tonight, Alexandra Patricia Black. I know we must both make haste for the ritual, so I will keep this brief.” Lord Malfoy took off his mask and fixed Alex with his piercing gaze. His voice took on a hint of steel. “Lead my son badly, and I will take steps to ensure he is no longer your concern, permanently.” He then reaffixed his mask and turned away.

Alexandra stared after the leader of the Dark as he swept through the door and out into the black of night.

Damn. Alexandra bit her lip. She really needed to learn how to make an exit like that!

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

The moon waxed crescent. The stars twinkled like the eyes of an old man settling into the twilight of his years.

The guests filled the wooden benches around the stone circle almost completely. A violinist was playing Jonathan Glen’s Sleep of the Thestrals.

Astoria, sitting next to her mother and cleared of ‘sickness’ by Saint Mungo’s, pouted. “But why can’t I do it? I’ve practised.”

“Because we weren’t sure if Alexandra would be able to, but she can, and that’s who Lord Slytherin believes should.”

“That’s not fair!”

On the far side of the circle, Draco Malfoy watched grimly as the three witches in the centre of the circle were eventually joined by a fourth.

In another part of the circle, John sat with his arms crossed while Susan nibbled on peanuts and Virgo scanned the many faces of the crowd as though mentally taking names.

Sirius Black watched nervously as Alex disappeared behind the tall white curtain that had been set up in the centre of the stones. “Don’t worry,” said a familiar voice behind him. Slytherin climbed over the bench to sit beside him. “Harry will keep her out of too much trouble.”

Sirius grunted. “And will Harry be staying here?”

“So long as he wishes it, I will grant him asylum. I did not want things to turn out this way, I assure you.”

“And yet you have somehow usurped John’s right to the Potter heirship.”

Slytherin turned towards him. “No, Lord Black. That was not me.”

The violin solo hit a particularly slow and deep moment.

Three-dozen fairies flittered over the heads of the crowd carrying tiny flaming torches. They flew past the stones and down into the circle of white cotton. For a fraction of a moment, four silhouettes became visible. Then, as the fairies flew about hither and thither, the shadows morphed into abstract shapes, chasing each other across the curved canvas. The violin solo died.

And the chanting started.

First one girl, then another, then another—melodic voices filled the nighttime air. It started slowly, at first barely a whisper, but picking up tempo. Then, at an unspoken command, the first girl moved. A shape flashed across the screen. Then, as with the chanting, the second soon followed. And then the third. And then the fourth.

Magic started to pool around the circle. Minutes passed in a trance-like state. The tension in the air tightened. Then, when the circle felt so saturated in magic, even the most insensitive could practically taste it, the chanting raised in pitch.

Every witch and wizard felt the hairs on the backs of their necks stand on end.

A shimmer of green and blue light weaved up from the ground—a miniature aurora borealis, leaping and jumping to the rhythm of the chanting and the bounce of the dance. It cleared the top of the surrounding trees and shot up into the starry sky.

The chanting died.

The dancing stopped.

The figures behind the curtain fell to the ground.

And the stars began to vibrate.

At first slowly, but rapidly increasing in pace, they moved—up and down, back and forth, swirling around the sky like water down a drain, before settling into a twinkling constellation of a serpent swallowing its own tail.

Every witch and wizard present felt it—the slight increase in luck granted by the ritual, settling on them like pixie dust.

As the party disbanded, some commented that they wished the luck of the magic lasted as long as the iconography Lord Slytherin had chosen symbolised. Others voiced their puzzlement of why the localised starry-sky reverted back to the normal night-sky afterwards, as the ritual effects were supposed to last the whole year. But most were simply happy to walk or stumble back to the manor, and to the warmth of the floo journey back home. It was generally agreed by most that it had been a good party, and that they would definitely be adding Lord Slytherin’s Gala Night to their calendars for next year.

But above all, wizarding aristocracy now saw Lord Slytherin as one of them—a firmly established part of their world—a known quantity—someone they could deal with—reliable and predictable, if slightly eccentric.

If only they knew what even the next few months would bring.

—End of Chapter Fifty-Five—

53

Chapter End Notes

A/N: Bonus Chapter next! Expect that within the month. The next arc starts drafting in January. Until then, Enjoy your Winter Festival ;)

A/N: This chapter was drafted and made available early through the LeadVonE discord server, as will the next one. If you fancy discussing this chapter with like-minded people, or anything else DP&SW, feel free to head over there.
A special thank you to the following people for helping catch mistakes on #dpasw-editorial and during the editing live streams: ASK, Arya_Kshitiz, Blake Belladonna, DeranXT, Dragonbait, Drsooz, Fuuryuu, ForgottenCode, Gloweye, JaydenStevenson, Jinarra, Leyrann, Lunatico, MageKing17, Magic Bird Dust, Malin, Rafilar, Ravana, Salty_sauce, Tendra, and TrendyTreky.
Special mention goes out to DeranXT for successfully tweaking the 99 Phantoms of Fear song from my original version, which didn’t rhyme nearly so well.

A/N: Conversion rate is:
1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds
1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)
1 Knut to 10p (roughly)
All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2019’s prices

Interlude — Nothing Like a Free Press

Diagon Alley, London. All over the wizarding world, it is known for its high-class shopping—a place where modern retail establishments, selling magical sweatshop products from all over the world, rub shoulders with old-school-style workshops, crafting one-of-a-kind artefacts on commission for the more discerning customer. The windows are a riot of colours and interest. Many thousands of visitors from every corner of the globe walk down the street every year, eyes sliding from one window to another, almost as if magically drawn.

Very few of those shoppers regularly look up.

Diagon Alley is more than just one or two storeys.

Above the crazy wizz-bang commercialisation of a thriving magical shopping district, many of the buildings support a host of other purposes—lawyers’ offices, bed and breakfasts, travel agents, and many other minor services that help the world go round.

If the shoppers below did look up, they’d see signs proclaiming the third floor of Olivander’s wand shop to host a watch-maker.

If they looked up above Flourish and Blotts, they’d find Magical Britain’s only art studio.

Such singularity of purpose was not always so.

What had started out hundreds of years ago as a nice apartment for the blacksmith’s family to live in, had, over the natural course of economic pressure, been subdivided, rented-out, space-expanded, and sub-divided again, and again, on so many occasions, that the ministry ended up banning further development, after the humble hag of the time failed to cast a basic lumos spell near a particularly densely charmed area, and was embarrassingly mistaken for a squib.

Those truly labyrinthine upper-floors were then carefully dismantled, but there do still exist a few hold-outs from the days before ministry-controlled space-expansion permissions.

For example, if the shoppers of Diagon Alley looked up just outside a magical greengrocer’s, just a few doors down from a rather nice café (which does, in fact, happen to also serve pudding) they would find not only the headquarters of the Quibbler, but also Witch Weekly, The Practical Potioneer, Transfiguration Today, Top Broom, Challenges in Charming, many other scholarly and special interest publications. But most importantly, they would find the Daily Prophet—the overall most respected publication in the country, and the only one to have not just one full-time journalist on staff, in addition to the editor, but two.

In a corner of a small and cramped room with no paint on the wooden walls, Rita Skeeter sipped on a cup of tea like it owed her money. All around her, the sounds of a questionably free press rattled and slammed away through silencing charms not quite strong enough to keep them out.

“Don’t worry, Luv,” said Bozo, lounging against the desk. “Something’ll turn up.”

“Worried?” Rita snapped. “I’m not worried.”

Bozo carelessly flicked a cigarette into an already overflowing ashtray. “If you say so, Luv.”

“And it’s not as though you’ve found anything,” Rita continued. “A good Slytherin story would do us wonders, but no, we can’t even run the Black girl’s scoop.” She folded her arms and glared at nothing. “Such delicate matters will be handled in private, my dear,” she muttered.

“There’s always the Muggle Protection Act that’s coming up. That’ll be a right to do. All the lords and higher-ups swanning about. Plenty of opportunity to sniff something juicy out.”

“We’d have no doubt gotten something juicy if we’d managed to sneak into Slytherin’s Gala!”

Bozo chuckled. “Don’t be daft, Luv. Slytherin’s not the kind to let a pair of animagi through his gates. You should know that. We don’t have to get a Slytherin story immediately. We’ve still got plenty of angles to play. I hear Crackpot Hall’s in trouble—Updike wants to pull his support. And he’s got Whittle’s scent all over him. Bad time to be in with the loan shark. Should have tried his luck with the green buggers up the street.” Bozo chuckled again.

There was the sound of footsteps from outside. It passed the door to their office and continued on towards the editor’s room.

Rita stuck her head around the door just in time to see the swish of lilac robes and hear a very distinctive voice loudly declare, “Barnabus! How excellent to see you again!”

She ducked her head back into the office. “What on Earth would Gilderoy be doing back here?”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

“A Quick-Quotes Quill?” Barnabus Cuffe asked, peering at the headmaster over thick-rimmed spectacles and a mountain of scrap paper. “Whatever do you want one of those for? Isn’t Hogwarts taking up enough of your time? You can’t use it for parchment-work, you know.”

“No, no, no,” Lockhart beamed. “Just a small project I’m undertaking for a dear old friend. Asked me to help him co-author his biography. Needs a little flair though, so I’m going around collecting interviews. Gives everything a more authoritative bent.”

“Biography, eh?” Barnabus leaned forward. “Anyone important? Anyone I should know about?”

Lockhart waved dismissively. “Oh no, no. Just a traveller I know from the old days looking for a sufficiently impressive tome for his bookshelf. Might sell one to his old mum, perhaps.”

“Mmm … yes, that is quite a common thing for people to do. Still, a Quick-Quotes Quill isn’t something I can hand out to just anyone, Headmaster. It is sort of divination magic, after all. Highly regulated. And a Cuffe family artefact. The only reason it’s not banned is you’d have to kill us all first. You don’t want to know how much trouble I’d be in if—”

A large sheet of dense script parchment slapped itself down in front of him.

“By Jove!” Barnabus’ spectacles dropped off his nose. He quickly replaced them and scanned the document. “You really got authorisation from the minister? He’s tighter than a skint pureblood witch on honeymoon.”

“Being headmaster of Hogwarts does come with certain perks when procuring these kinds of permissions.”

Unseen by either Lockhart or the editor, a small and beautiful jewelled beetle crawled in through a crack in the window.

“I’ll say,” Barnabus agreed. His eyes widened slightly when he read the authorised remuneration he’d be allowed to charge his customer. “Righto! Step this way, Headmaster. Here, let me take your cloak. No, don’t bother sitting down, you’ll want to be standing for this.” He walked to the back of the office, flourished his wand, and tapped a wall panel. It slid back to reveal five beautiful feather quills, all from birds any muggle ornithologist would rip his hair out trying to identify.

“Magnificent!” Lockhart gushed.

“Yes, well. Very nice, certainly. Look here.” Barnabus selected the one on the end—a particularly striking acid-green—and ruffled it. “The Quick-Quotes Quill,” he announced. “A lot of rumours around about these, so here’s the truth—straight from the thestral’s mouth. A Quick-Quotes Quill isn’t just a dictation machine, oh no. Some say it exaggerates the truth, but that’s not quite right either. It pulls information from the aether. Just like how a pensieve memory isn’t just what the eye sees—neither is the Quick-Quotes Quill. With this quill, you can pan for secrets, like panning for gold. But it comes with a danger.”

“Can’t trust the little blighters,” Lockhart chuckled. “Just like pensieve memories.”

Barnabus pouted slightly. “Quite. I see you’ve done your homework. But do you know about the rules?”

“Rules?”

“Different family artefacts have different rules, you know. Some can only be made by the family, some will only work for the family. Some manifest only every second generation. Others are matrilineal. All kinds of wacky stuff.” He opened his hand as if encouraging Lockhart to take its contents. “The Cuffe Quick-Quotes Quill can be used by anyone, but!—” He snatched his hand shut just as Lockhart’s hand was about to close on the feather. “With a time limit.”

“What time limit?” Lockhart asked, brow furrowed.

“Twenty-four hours.”

“You mean I’ve got to come back for a new quill every day?!”

“Not a new quill, Headmaster. You just need me to give you back the quill you just took. That’s all.”

“Still … that puts a serious cramp on a man’s style.”

“That’s magic, Headmaster.”

A little while later, back in the reporters’ office, Rita turned back into a witch, while, by the door, a cocker spaniel, which had been sniffing around the corridor, turned back into Bozo.

Rita was practically drooling. “I want that quill.”

“Good luck,” Bozo drawled. “Family magic artefact? Your best bet is to marry the man.”

“Eww. No thanks,” she snapped. “I’d rather marry you.”

“Love you too, Luv.”

“But seriously, a quill that can write all your articles for you, properly, and can pull secrets from the winds of magic themselves? Uh, I’m wet just thinking about it.”

“Don’t go dry before you next need my help.”

“Fuck you.”

“With pleasure, but not now.” He leaned against the wall. “Do you want to hear who our friend Lockhart was just visiting before he arrived?”

“You smelled it?”

Bozo tapped his nose. “Smelled it loud and clear. And it’s a doozy. It was Lord Jacob Greengrass.”

“Greengrass? What does Gilderoy want with Greengrass? Come to that, what does Gilderoy want with a Quick-Quotes Quill? He’s not a reporter.”

“Something interesting to find out, maybe?” Bozo waggled his eyebrows.

There was a pause before Rita reached for her outdoors cloak. “Let’s follow him.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Gilderoy Lockhart was not a fraud. Oh, many had accused him of it over the years. There had been that unfortunate business with the memory charms in Bolivia. But in general, most of the smears and character assassination attempts were rooted in jealousy.

He’d been places. He’d done things.

True, most of the places he’d been were strategically chosen for their fearsome reputation from events that had happened at least thirty years ago, and when he’d done things, it was always with skilled wizards capable of extracting him from just about any trouble they’d be likely to face. He wasn’t stupid.

That didn’t change the fact that his books were written from real-life adventures far richer than most people were likely to experience even once.

Right now, he felt very much like he was on one of those adventures.

Except he was in Magical Britain—tea drinking, formal bowing, mind your Ps and Qs, please, Magical Britain—with no guides, no local heroes guarding him, and no ready portkey out of there.

Lord Slytherin was a boy not yet even a teenager.

Which would have been hilariously amusing, if not for …

Lockhart shuddered.

And now he had a job to do. Be useful. That was always the key when dealing with the lords and ladies.

The patchwork corridors of Madam Goose’s Home for the Magically Gifted were filled with artwork from the students—low-tier animation magics bringing the occasional piece to life before it stuttered into stillness again. The students were all outside at this time of day—the sounds of play muffled through the leather walls. Gilderoy turned a corner, stopped in front of one of the doors, knocked, waited for the answer, and let himself in.

“Good afternoon, Madam Goose! I hope your fine school is running well.”

The current Madam Goose stumbled to her feet from her chair. “Headmaster, I wasn’t expecting you so soon.”

“Punctuality is the politeness of princes, my lady. So why not be extra polite and turn up ten minutes early?” He flashed her his roguish grin.

“Um, yes, I suppose that’s fine.” Madam Goose started rustling through the papers. “What was it exactly that you wanted? Something to do with a book?”

“Yes, I’m helping Lord Slytherin write his biography, and I’m looking for some good sound bites I can use from people who know him.”

“Well, I wouldn’t exactly say I know him that well. We’ve talked about things once or twice.”

“Capital!” Lockhart summoned one of the office’s chairs and pulled out the Quick-Quotes Quill from his robes along with a piece of parchment. “Let’s get started then, shall we. Testing. Testing. This is Headmaster Gilderoy Lockhart, interviewing Madam Goose.”

The quill instantly started to write.

Gilderoy Lockhart—Order of Merlin, third class, honorary member of the Dark Force Defence League, five times winner of Witch Weekly’s most charming smile award, six times winner of the Daily Prophet’s annual best-sellers list, and current Headmaster of Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry interviewing Rebecca Howeswell, the current Madam Goose of Madam Goose’s Home for the Magically Gifted.

It was a crisp January morning, but I wasn’t at all cold. To call the handsome Madam Goose’s office comfy would be an insult. Housed in a judgement-era magical boot, the walls are cushioned, the chairs induce relaxation, and the warm fire crackles away. One could conduct an orgy on the floor without so much as a—

“That’s enough of that, I think,” Lockhart chuckled, tearing the parchment off while Madam Goose’s cheeks reddened. “Tell me about your first meeting with Lord Slytherin.”

“Yes, of course. But you have to understand that his lordship is a very unique wizard and we’ve made many exceptions for him that we wouldn’t necessarily make for others.”

“I completely understand.” And, oh boy, did he ever, Lockhart thought. He probably understood far better than the witch herself did. “I will of course be discreet.”

“Good.” Madam Goose got herself settled in her own chair behind her desk, and looked off into the middle distance. “Lord Slytherin first approached me just after the summer solstice, some eighteen months ago. He was interested in non-traditional educational opportunities for wizards and witches who might need them. Very charming, he was. In his own way. He has this aura of power around him. And at first you’re nervous, like being a schoolgirl again, but you soon realise that he—”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

“So, is there an animagus ward?” Rita asked impatiently.

“Nah, Luv. Open as a maiden’s heart.”

“Good.” Without further words she turned into her jewelled beetle form and flittered through the basic wards around the Shoe. She wasn’t sure what Gilderoy was up to, but she sure smelled a scoop.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

With wistfulness in her voice, Madam Goose spoke of the many private meetings she and Lord Slytherin had shared together. A sigh passes the still-single witch’s lips as she recounts their last bittersweet parting.

“I’ve done nothing of the sort!” Madam Goose said in a flustered voice.

“Ignore the quill, my lady. Everyone knows Quick-Quotes Quills can’t be trusted … most of the time.” He winked at her. “Please tell me more about how Lord Slytherin handles this, ‘aura of power’ around him.”

“You’re really not going to publish anything about bittersweet sighs?”

“Heavens, no. Slytherin would have my head.”

“Well, okay then.” She settled down again. “It feels like he has this beast on a leash. It feels like standing on the edge of a lake at night and not knowing how deep the water is.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Heading for her goal, Rita bobbed and rode the breezes around Madam Goose’s Home for the Magically Gifted. Flying as a beetle was not like flying as a bird. The whims of the wind made it far more difficult. Even birds sometimes had to take a roundabout route to their destinations rather than ‘as the crow flies’. Attempting the same feat as a beetle could be like riding a hexed broomstick.

Still, she successfully bobbed and flittered her way across the school lawn, only pausing once to listen in on some random teenage drama.

As she reached the window she believed to be the headmistress’, she landed on the sill and found a gap to crawl through.

“His lordship has always expressed his admiration for our education system and what it can achieve, Headmaster,” came a female voice—Madam Goose’s, Rita realised.

“And how has Miss Cooper been getting on in classes?”

“Very well. Amazingly well, in fact. I suppose her maturity gives her an advantage, to be sure, but it’s still impressive how quickly she’s been picking things up, considering her background. Slytherin has even asked if she can be moved up a grade or two.”

“It sounds like Slytherin really cares about her.”

“I’ve no doubt. He’s been getting regular reports about her progress and if there’s ever a problem, he’s quick to respond.”

“Would you consider Miss Cooper’s situation as a case study for how education could be improved?”

Madam Goose frowned. “I don’t see how I could. Her situation is exceptional. But if Slytherin came to me with a proposal, I’d probably be open to suggestions.”

The interview continued on for quite a while after that, covering such things as Madam Goose’s attitude to schooling (traditional), some of the small changes she’d made to the Shoe’s curriculum over the years (new art and music programs as well as an exchange program with ‘The Box’ for seventh years with a strong interest in arithmancy), and where she still wanted to take the school in the future.

By the time Gilderoy was leaving, Rita had heard enough.

“I think Slytherin may be pushing for some kind of educational reform,” she told Bozo when she arrived back at the edge of the school. “This could be exactly the kind of story we want.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

“Still thinking the headmaster’s interested in educational reform?” Bozo drawled as he and Rita concealed themselves behind a tree in a park.

Rita scowled. “What on Earth does Gilderoy want in some random muggle neighbourhood? There’s nothing of interest here.”

“Maybe,” Bozo replied. “Why don’t you go find out?”

“Why don’t you?” She shot back nastily.

Bozo pointed to a sign stuck in the grass showing a silhouette of a dog with a big red cross slashed through it.

“Oh, and you think that all the songbirds around here are a piece of cake to deal with, do you?” Rita spat. “You know what, fine. I don’t care.” She then turned into her beetle form and flittered away.

Bozo sniggered, waited until she was out of sight, then turned into his cocker spaniel form.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Vernon Dursley was sweating.

Next to him, Petunia’s hand trembled slightly as she served normal tea and biscuits, normally, in the most normal way she could imagine. The tea set was new—Royal Dolton’s finest—and it wasn’t the only thing. Their new car parked outside had been imported from Germany and the clothes they wore were made from Italian wools and cottons.

“You’ll have to forgive me if I do anything strange,” said the dandy freak sitting opposite, cheerfully. “I’ve travelled with muggles before and I know that sometimes we can do things that cause distress. I assure you I mean no harm. Hahahaha.”

“Ha-ha-ha,” said Vernon, gripping the sofa armrest tightly.

“W-what happened to the last headmaster?” Petunia asked. “I thought he’d been at that school since the war.”

“Dumbledore? Oh, he was given early retirement. Getting on a bit in years. Time for a new generation to mount their brooms. And naturally, they wanted the very best! Hahaha.”

Vernon wiped his brow. “And this, errr, book, thing, that you’re writing …”

“Just a few choice quotes about Harry. About his life growing up here. How you all got along together. That sort of thing.”

“And does … errr, does Harry know you’re asking?”

“Not specifically, but Lord Slytherin did say to go ahead and interview anyone I felt would help give the best impressions.”

Vernon caught Petunia’s eye.

In that one moment, the director of Grunnings might as well have been a mind reader—his wife’s thoughts were that easy to read in her eyes. He turned back to their, ‘guest.’ “I just want to make one thing quite clear,” he said.

“Yes?”

“Under no circumstances are our names, addresses, phone numbers, or any identifiable details to be published in this book you’re writing, understand?”

“Of course!”

“Right.” Vernon leaned back in his chair. He could already feel the bile rising in his throat as his vocal cords got ready to say what he was about to say. “Well, the first thing to understand is, we’ve always loved Harry …”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

What was this?

Rita buzzed through the perfectly manicured garden of number four Privet Drive, feeling slightly dizzy from the rich assortment of flowery smells assaulting her from every angle.

It was a muggle house—a quite well-off one, if her very limited knowledge of muggles was any judge—but, at the end of the day, just a muggle house.

She forced her way through the olfactory gauntlet and towards one of the many ground floor windows. Unfortunately, someone had been round with a tube of muggle plastic and sealed up all the usual cracks that might have normally granted her access. The same was true for the doors.

Damn it all. What was with these people? Did muggles think they were going to be poisoned by fresh air?

She flittered up to the chimney and looked speculatively down the hole. There wasn’t any smoke coming out of it, which was a plus, but on the negative side, who knew what kind of predator might lurk down in the shadows. Unused chimneys were notorious for spiders.

Rita metaphorically shrugged, given that her current form was rather lacking on shoulders. She’d dealt with worse situations in the past.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

“And there was one time Harry came back from the hairdressers with all his hair already grown back, ha-ha-ha,” Vernon said. “And another time he and Dudders were playing hide-and-seek and he jumped clean onto the school roof, ha-ha-ha.” He was desperately trying to avoid looking at the floating quill and parchment scrawling rapidly at his every word.

“Yeeesssssss,” said the headmaster, eyes widening. Unlike Vernon and Petunia, he was looking at the parchment. Vernon couldn’t begin to imagine why the man’s face was starting to resemble bleached chalk. “I’m glad the lad’s had a well-adjusted upbringing.”

“Of course, it hasn’t all been fun and games,” Vernon said in what he hoped was a good-natured way. “He’s misbehaved occasionally. All boys do. I remember one time he came home with bad marks and we sent him to bed without supper. Might sound harsh, but you have to be cruel to be kind sometimes.”

The quill scribbled away madly.

“But when he disappeared, I won’t mince my words—we were right worried, weren’t we Pet?”

“Yes,” Petunia chimed in, primly. “Very worried.” She smiled and a slight shiver went down Vernon’s spine. “We of course let my sister know right away, but for some reason, she never bothered to respond.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Damn it all!

Rita, the jewelled beetle animagus, contorted herself against a thick strand of web.

No use. Spider silk was strong stuff, even if it wasn’t magical. She decided to give it up as a bad job and transformed. Her human form fell only a foot before she turned back into a beetle, but that only got her another few feet beyond that before she was snagged by yet another web.

Damn it all to hell! Didn’t muggles ever use their fireplaces?!

Wait.

Rita strained her ears, such as there was of them. She could faintly hear a pair of voices muffled through the brickwork.

“Always been a bright lad, Harry,” said a male voice she didn’t recognise. “I’m glad he’s finding his own place in the world with this ‘Lord Slytherin’—even if he’s not a real lord. Oh, thank you, Pet.”

What was this? Rita wondered. Harry?

“Did you know that Harry won the duelling tournament at Hogwarts?” said a voice Rita instantly identified as Gilderoy’s.

“No, we never heard anything about that.”

“He defeated all seven of his opponents in succession. If it wasn’t for his brother, it would have been a record.”

Oh, they must be talking about Harry Potter! One of Slytherin’s protégées.

“A record, eh? It sounds like this Lord Slytherin has been teaching him well. I’m so proud.”

Was this the younger Potter’s muggle house? The muggles who raised him before everyone knew he wasn’t a squib?

“But that wasn’t all that happened at the tournament,” Gilderoy continued. “Someone attacked John during a duel with Harry and nearly killed him.”

“Oh, my,” said a new nasally female voice. “How dreadful. Did they catch them?”

“I’m afraid not.”

But why would Gilderoy be interviewing Lily Potter’s muggle relatives?

Lord Slytherin brought Harry under his wing and trained him to equal his brother, she mused. Educational reforms, she mused. Muggles and Harry Potter. Her eyes widened. That was it! Lord Slytherin was going to bring in muggleborn educational reforms! Harry Potter would make the perfect poster boy. A pureblood noble raised in a muggle household.

She metaphorically grinned from ear to ear.

Now all she had to do was wait until Gilderoy left and a few good compulsion charms would have the muggles spilling everything.

It was at that moment that she felt a tremble shoot through the web. Fear spiked through her whole body and she instinctively changed, just as a massive eight-legged horror lunged onto what was now her face.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

Vernon relaxed slightly. It looked like this wasn’t going too badly. Interesting to finally find out who the boy’s patron was. Say what you liked about the rest of them, this Lord Slytherin didn’t seem too bad. At least he was happy to share his good fortune a bit. Not like his wife’s shrew of a sister. Anything to keep on his good side was a good thing as far as he was concerned—within reason.

“Excellent!” beamed the new headmaster, standing up. “I think I’ve got everything—” was as far as he got before there was a loud female scream, quickly followed by a series of loud bangs descending through the chimney.

Vernon jumped to his feet. “What the?!”

The freak was already pointing his ‘wand’.

“WAIT!”

There was a massive BANG sound and their brand-new electric fire burst out of the grate in the wall.

A figure tumbled out.

“Aha!” shouted the wizard. “A sneaky spy! Rita Skeeter as I live and breathe! I don’t believe I’ve ever had the pleasure, despite our many, many past meetings.”

“Gilderoy,” the woman said quickly, showering soot all over their once wonderfully clean carpet. “I can explain.”

“Don’t bother,” The wizard said cheerfully.

Vernon suddenly found himself looking right down the end of the brightly glowing wand.

“Obliviate!”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

“Damn it all!” Rita fumed, climbing the rickety stairs towards the Daily Prophet’s offices. “Those muggles had a great interview in their heads, and he just—”

“Yes, Luv,” Bozo said.

“And then he threatened to call the DMLE! Just for being in a muggle house.”

“Trespassing …” Bozo drawled.

“Bah! Maybe under muggle law. And where were you the whole time?”

“Sniffing around. Want to know where the headmaster was before this interview?”

“Go on.”

“The Rookery.”

Rita paused with her hand hovering over the door handle to the editor’s office. “The Rookery? As in, Lord Lovegood’s place?”

“That’s the one.”

“I knew it!” She gripped the door handle and flung it open. “Barnabus! We have a story!”

“Rita! Quiet your skank arse down or I’ll throw you out the window!”

“Oh, you’d never do that.” She strutted into the room and slapped down a parchment onto Cuffe’s desk. “And you certainly won’t want to once you read this.”

Cuffe snatched the parchment up and started to read. “Educational reform? Sources close to the headmaster … committee meetings across the country … leading educational policymakers … muggleborn focus … upcoming muggle protection act. …” He looked up from the parchment. “How’d you get this?”

Rita smirked. “I have my ways.”

“Oh, doesn’t she just,” Bozo added, leaning against the doorframe.

“Yes, well.” Cuffe glared at them both and slapped the parchment back down on the desk. “It’s bullshit.”

Rita blinked. “What?”

“I said it’s bullshit, Rita! Do you need me to clean both your ears out with my wand? I have the latest draft of the muggle protection act right here—the very latest version—one of my contacts in the Wizengamot just sent it over—and nowhere in it is anything like what you’re talking about. Not. One. Thing!”

“But … I. …” Rita stumbled over her words trying to get her brain back into gear.

“You may not know this, Rita, given how obsessed you are with chasing kiss-and-tell stories, but our patrons in the Dark have been working closely with Lord Slytherin since the Winter Festival on this act. Do you really think Lord Malfoy strikes you as the kind to give those riffraff any more power and privilege than the Light have already surrendered to them?”

“N-no. It’s just that—”

“It’s just what?”

Bozo flicked a cigarette butt into Cuffe’s ashtray. “We heard the headmaster talking to various people about just that.”

Cuffe transferred his glare to Bozo. “Who?”

“Madam Goose. Lady Potter’s sister. Lords Greengrass and Lovegood.”

Cuffe sat silent for a moment before snorting. “And I suppose you’ll both refuse pensieve memories as you always do.”

“Yep.”

“Then there’s nothing to be said here. Get back out there and get back to your jobs. Lord Malfoy will not be pleased if our output slows before the important vote in March.”

Rita sullenly stuck her hands in the pockets of her robes and marched out.

Bozo followed, closing the door behind him. “Now what, Luv?” he asked. “Fancy a bit of slap and tickle?”

“No I bloody well do not.”

There was a loud bang from behind them. They turned.

Cuffe was leaning against the once again open door, breathing loudly. “Wait,” he huffed. “Who, exactly, did you say the headmaster was meeting with?”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

“Well?” Rita asked.

Bozo grinned. “He’s got the minister’s smell all over him this time.”

“Minister of Magic, Cornelius Fudge,” Rita muttered while scribbling.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

“Any luck?” Bozo asked.

“It was the manager of Bodmin Moor Stadium this time,” Rita said, after transforming back into a witch.

Bozo whistled. “Fingers in every pie, this one.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

It was still dark out. Barnabus Cuffe waved his wand expertly over a massive tray of moveable type, causing several letters to rearrange themselves. Off to one side, a line of expectant owls were already lined up on a roosting pole, eyeing him as only owls could.

“Oi, Cuffe, you ready yet?” asked the chief mechanic of the Quibbler printing press—the only one in the country. “We’ve got a schedule to keep here, you know.”

“Just a few more minutes,” Cuffe grunted. “I’m expecting—”

The door to the cramped printing shop slammed open.

“Rita!” Cuffe shouted. “About time. What have you got for me?”

“Our man was in Cork this time, talking with the mayor for hours! They got through half a bottle of Ogden’s.”

“… And the mayor of Cork enclave,” Cuffe muttered, waving his wand again over the moveable type. “Nothing else?”

“Nothing new.”

“Right.” Cuffe turned to the chief mechanic. “It’s all yours now.”

The man nodded.

Over the next half-hour, a dozen wizards in ink-stained hooded dungarees set everything up just so. And a half-hour after that, the first copy of the next morning’s edition of the Daily Prophet rolled out of the masterwork of runes and enchantments that was the Quibbler Press—highly regulated by the ministry, naturally.

Cuffe, Rita, and Bozo all crowded around to see. Even as they started to read, owls started snatching up copies from the press as they emerged and soaring out of the large hole in the roof.

Cuffe smiled. “Excellent work, Rita—Andrew. Have a drink on me.”

“What I’d really like,” Rita purred, “is a use of that quill of yours.”

Cuffe chuckled. He looked out of the still-dark window. It was a tough life, being the editor of one of Magical Britain’s only newspapers. The deadlines were hard, submissions were unreliable, and choosing story angles was like walking a constant tightrope between ministry regulation, patron obligations, and opponent retribution. There was a lot of weird stuff going on right now—the muggle protection act—rumblings inside Gringotts—that whole business with the Potters since the Winter Festival. But there was one thing he could be sure of and that was the feeling in the words he was about to speak.

“Go stuff yourself.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

And the sun rose.

Far away from the hustle and bustle of Diagon Alley, in a secret place hidden far below even the deepest of Hogwarts’ many dungeons, water dripped off the ceiling and trickled away down a massive hall lined with serpentine stone pillars. A massive statue at the end stared imperiously down the room, although the impressive effect was lessened by the five-dozen metal rods currently clamping its mouth shut.

The rest of the hall was empty—empty except for a lone four-poster bed sitting right in the middle of the floor, a small desk, chair, and two children. The children were sitting opposite each other on the floor, forming their hands around massive pots of clay as large as themselves. The pots spun slowly on large wheels.

“Don’t you think it’s disrespectful?” Ginny asked cheerfully, glancing over to the statue. Her hands were caked.

“Slytherin would understand,” Harry replied. “They’re only there to slow it down anyway. How’s your pot doing?”

“Great! I should be ready soon.”

“Excellent.”

Just then, a faint hoot sound echoed through the chamber. Harry stood up, just as Macavity swooped into the hall, carrying a newspaper. He dropped it in front of Harry and flew straight back out.

Ginny stared. “You’re getting mail down here?”

“No.” Harry picked up the paper. “Daphne must have thought it was important.” He read the headline.

LORD SLYTHERIN FINALLY COMING CLEAN!

WILL SECRETS EXCUSE THE SECRECY?!

UPCOMING BIOGRAPHY MAY BE TOO LITTLE TOO LATE!

“What is it?” Ginny asked, appearing by Harry’s shoulder faster than a man could blink. “Oh, wow.”

“Oh wow, indeed.” Harry glared at the paper. “Is it too hard to ask that every single secret I want to keep remains so?”

Ginny giggled. “What now?”

“Now we’ll need to speed up our plans.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

John Potter, wearing muggle workout gear and followed closely by Susan, slammed the painting of the Fat Lady shut behind him, and marched into the Gryffindor common room. “Have you read this?” he asked, as soon as he got within whisper range of his target.

Virgo looked up from the morning edition of the Daily Prophet. “Yes,” she said. “I think we need to speed up our plans.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD—

And some time later, far away on the other side of the continent, a large black snake stared unblinkingly at the newspaper that had just been delivered.

“News, my lord?” asked a man with fiery intense eyes. Said eyes met those of the snake and he felt a pull on his occlumency shields. Moments later, he was standing in the dark of the chasm between minds.

“Yes, Barty,” said Lord Voldemort. “We will need to speed up our plans.”

—End of Chapter Fifty-Six—

Chapter End Notes

A/N: Hope you enjoyed the bonus chapter! Those of you wondering what happened to Harry after the Winter Festival, have no fear. This is not going to be ignored.

Also, my website, which you can find by searching on google for LeadVonE, just got a major overhaul, and my original fantasy novella, Richard Struggle—Evacuate the Masquerade, is now available to read on there, for free. If you haven’t already experienced a taste of the world of Creakylid, now’s the perfect time to go check it out.

A/N: This chapter was drafted and made available early through the LeadVonE discord server, as will the next one. If you fancy discussing this chapter with like-minded people, or anything else DP&SW, feel free to head over there.

A special thank you to the following people for helping catch mistakes on #dpasw-editorial and during the editing live streams: Arya, Blake Belladonna, CaptainFlowers, Dragonbait, DeraNXT, FartyArtyPartyPooper, Gloweye, Fuuryuu, Leyrann, LordMelvin, Mercury044, Malin, Oliver W. K. Twist, oolaan, Ravana, sfu, and Tendra.

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—a little less than half of 2020’s prices.

Nature Red — Part 1

Storm clouds gathered over Harry’s return to Hogwarts after the Winter Festival Holiday was over.

Many people tried to stop him.

Lord James Potter was the first, hiring a group of hit-wizards to intercept Harry at Platform Nine and Three-Quarters. This didn’t work, because he wasn’t there. But he certainly got off the Hogwarts Express at Hogsmeade Station.

The second people to give it a shot were the Magical Department of Family Affairs. They stopped Harry’s coach as it made its way to the gates of Hogwarts, making their intention to escort him back to Potter Manor perfectly clear. For their trouble, they got three wands shoved in their faces, a quick nap on the icy-cold ground, and a new appreciation for what a trio of noble witches could do, even if the girls in question barely stood up to their chests.

Finally, there were the teachers of Hogwarts themselves.

Harry was, technically, no longer a student.

“I’m sorry, Mister Potter,” Professor McGonagall said at the front doors. “We cannot allow you any further.”

The problem with barring Harry from the school though, was that Lord Slytherin had taken back control over the wards just a few weeks earlier in defence against a free house-elf. And Lord Slytherin had granted Harry Potter asylum.

What followed was a rather ridiculous game of cat and mouse, where the mouse was more of a whisper on the wind.

Severus Snape and Lily Potter were the primary frustrated antagonists of this little game. Polyjuice potion, notice-me-nots, self-transfiguration, secret passageways, the Marauder’s map, disillusionment charms, the actual invisibility cloak of Death, and general access to the wards, influencing such things as staircase direction and which doors led where—between all of these, Harry was about as hard to pin down as the last sliver of soap in the bathtub.

This gave him plenty of freedom to accelerate many plans in many directions. He even went to classes sometimes, usually in disguise and signing himself into the register afterwards. For fun.

And so, storm clouds gathered.

This went on for nearly four weeks.

And now the storm clouds that gathered were not nearly so metaphorical.

Blackness rolled over the country like a blanket—black clouds from what had, only an hour before, been crystal blue sky.

In a grand manor house in Wiltshire, many hundreds of miles away from Hogwarts, a wizarding wireless was urgently giving a warning that was being repeated up and down the country.

… Winds of up to 100 miles an hour are expected for the next few hours along with random bolts of magic. The Department for Magical Disaster Control has issued a statement that all magical beings should under no circumstances leave shelter during the event, and that the muggle Prime Minister has been informed of the storm’s nature and that it poses no direct threat to muggles, outside of the wind. Again, we highly advise wizards and witches not to venture outside, especially to aid muggle relatives.

Rome is also responding to the emergency. A special team of ICW obliviators has been dispatched from Paris, where they were on training exercises, and is currently flying over the channel. The Minister says the British Ministry of Magic welcomes the aid and again urges the population to remain calm during the unexpected magical event—*click*

Lord Lucius Malfoy flicked his wand away from the wizarding wireless and stared up at the darkening sky through the large windows of his private study.

He sighed. A lot of property would need repairing soon.

“Dear?” Narcissa opened the door wearing a very respectable robe. “Lord Potter has arrived. Shall I show him up?”

“Yes.” Lucius sneered. “I hope you warmed him up for our discussion.”

Narcissa smiled. “I made sure to mention how much of a disappointment Virgo was three times.”

“Good.”

Not long after, the door opened again and Lord Potter entered like an explorer investigating a booby-trapped ruin.

“James,” Lord Malfoy intoned.

“Lucius.”

And that was it … for the next five minutes. They sat opposite each other at the office’s low desk, silently taking tea while a collection of house-elves fussed around them.

Eventually, the door closed, and they were alone.

Off in one corner, an ancient grandfather clock audibly ticked away the passing time. Far off in the distance, a deep rumble heralded the nearing of the coming storm.

Lucius set his teacup down with a clink. “You got my owl.”

“Obviously. Lily was not at all happy.”

“Really? I would have thought your wife of all people would jump at the opportunity to sully her husband’s house with more muggleness.”

Lord Potter scowled. “Let’s just cut to the chase. You want Virgo taken off your hands. How much do you want?”

“Whoa. Whoa. Whoa,” Lord Malfoy said in a patronising tone. “Calm yourself, James. There is a proper way these things go. I’m sure even you know that. Virgo may be proving to be a massive disappointment for her attitude and the company she keeps. But there is no denying she is a powerful and talented witch. She will be a great asset to your house and make a superb betrothed for your …” he smirked, “… son.”

Lord Potter scowled. “Heir.”

Lucius shrugged. “She also mastered many of our traditions incredibly quickly upon her return to our world and has taken to occlumency like a fish to water. Then there are the Malfoy family magics she will bring to the union. There hasn’t been a Malfoy/Potter match for over three hundred years—since before the time of the great arithmancy revolution. The potential new combinations are legion. She is top of her year at Hogwarts, and her scores would even be record-breaking, if it weren’t for your heir’s scores last year.”

“Son.”

Lord Malfoy chuckled. “I’m sure you understand why Virgo is among the most valuable commodities that I possess. There are many houses who would gladly pay top galleon for such a match. I can think of many off the top of my head. I doubt they would be so ‘accommodating’ to her eccentricities. Lord Slughorn is still looking for a new bride.”

Rain started to faintly patter against the windows.

Lord Malfoy shrugged. “Virgo is worth far more than Daphne Greengrass was, of that there is no doubt. As such, I could not possibly accept anything less than a bride price of …” He looked Lord Potter squarely in the eyes. “… twenty-thousand galleons.”

Lord Potter sprayed his tea clear across the room.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Lightning flashed across the sky. It arced upwards from the ground before crackling out across the clouds.

“That doesn’t look good,” muttered Nymphadora Tonks.

“It isn’t good,” answered her partner in a gruff voice. A magical eye swivelled in its socket to focus on her through the back of its owner’s head. “C’mon girl. The obliviators will need every hand on deck. And I’ll be damned if we’re shown up by a bunch of foreign memory fiddlers.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Lightning flashed across the sky.

But at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry, all was deathly calm, deep in the eye of the storm.

“I don’t like it,” said Professor Minerva McGonagall, up in the headmaster’s office. “Why now? Why here? These storms are not to be treated lightly. Odd events can happen. Strange creatures can be born.”

“Oh, don’t be such a worry wart, Minerva,” replied Lockhart.

McGonagall frowned.

“I’m sure it will all be fine,” he continued. “Don’t you think so, Miss Davis?”

Tracey took a parchment from the top of the stack she was carrying and slid it over the desk towards Lockhart. “Yes, Headmaster,” she chirped. “This one needs to be signed and charmed in triplicate.”

“Right you are.”

Professor McGonagall’s frown deepened.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Lightning flashed across the sky.

Thunder rolled across the heavens.

But deep down beneath the earth, it may as well have been a balmy afternoon. The only signs of the tumult above were the occasional ripples in random pools of chilly water.

“Wicked,” whispered George Weasley, staring in awe around the massive chamber. In particular, his eyes kept sweeping over the gigantic statue of Lord Salazar Slytherin, where five dozen steel rods still clamped the old wizard’s mouth firmly shut.

“That’s the fourth time you’ve said that,” Ginny replied in a teasing voice.

“It’s just … wicked,” George said again. “I wish Fred was here to see this.”

“He’ll get his turn,” said Daphne. She was standing in front of a massive clay pot that she had hand-turned all by herself. All of them were. Five girls and two boys. Seven in total. Each of the pots was half as tall as the young wizard or witch standing before it, and each was covered in intricately carved runes from top to bottom. A heptagram of phoenix ash on the floor connected all the pots together. And right in the middle of the subsequent heptagon sat a pensieve. Daphne turned to her left. “Harry?”

Harry nodded. “Alex, Hermione, George, and Luna. Welcome to the Chamber of Secrets—Salazar Slytherin’s family ritual room, deep beneath Hogwarts where not even the faintest of magical interference can reach. It was here that Lord Slytherin re-discovered the Stella Benedictio ritual, and it was here, fifty years ago, that the last heir of the time started his work on the ritual that we, today, are going to perform—the ritual that I now dub Septem Anima.”

He reached into the pocket of his robes and pulled out seven smoking pipes, one after another.

“Each of these is filled with mandrake. The ritual is simple in theory, but the effects will be extensive. Once we’ve climbed into our respective pots, we will all take as large a pull as we can and channel our magic into the runes. I imagine this will be quite a trip.”

“I imagine it will,” said Luna.

“Eventually, there will be enough magic in the ritual space to trigger the ritual effect. The phoenix ash and the pensieve in the middle of the circle will then give us a pathway to commune with our spirit animal—our animagus form—much like animagi in Magical America do to achieve their forms. Except we will achieve our forms almost instantly. Or in minutes, anyway. At least on the outside.”

“And on the inside?” George asked.

“A lifetime—until the ritual believes that it is time for each of us to die on the claws of our fellows.”

Alexandra chose this moment to speak up. “What I want to know is how you learn a ritual when no one has ever done it before.”

“Oh,” said Hermione. “That’s simple. You see, there’s this thing called the aether unpacked, which—”

“Hermione,” Daphne interrupted.

Hermione blushed.

Harry chuckled. “You’ll learn more about it in third year. Until then simply know that magic discovery is dangerous and you shouldn’t try it if you don’t know what you’re doing.”

Hermione averted her eyes.

“The nature of phoenix ash is the warping of space and time,” Harry continued. “The nature of a pensieve is the storing and recalling of memories. The combined effect in this ritual will be unusual. We will all live our lives separately and the others will hunt us—all at the same time. In that one moment, there will be seven Harrys, seven Ginnys, seven Daphnes, and so on. But in your pot, the only one of us with an animal mind will be you. Once the ritual is over, we will have achieved perfect balance with our forms and will be animagi.”

“Sounds complicated,” Ginny said.

Harry smiled. “It will all be a lot clearer once we’re in.” He turned to Luna. “Still not going to tell us what your form is?”

Luna smiled back. “It’s okay. I’ll tell you now.”

She told them.

Hermione said a bad word.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Rain lashed the windows of Gryffindor Tower. Sitting in one of the old castle’s alcoves, Susan Bones stared out with wide eyes. At least, she was until she heard her name thrown up behind her.

“Look, John, all I’m saying is that she’s a Hufflepuff. I know we’re open to them, but she can’t be up here all the time. There has to be a limit to these things.”

It was one of the older female prefects. Isabel something, wasn’t it?

“I don’t see why,” John replied with his arms folded. “Dumbledore always talked about inter-house cooperation and reaching out the hands of friendship. You wouldn’t go against Dumbledore, would you?”

The prefect sighed irritably. “John, you’re missing the point.”

“No, I don’t think he is,” Virgo stated from where she sat buried in parchment at one of the common room desks. She didn’t even look up. “I think it is you, Banister, who is in the wrong.”

Banister! That was her name.

“How is it me who—”

“—It is you,” Virgo interrupted, “because you have an ulterior motive. Don’t think we’ve missed the looks you’ve been shooting Heir Potter.”

“He’s not—”

“—And don’t think I don’t know about the arrangement your father made with you at the start of the year.”

The older girl’s face went chalk white. “I don’t know what you mean.”

“You were ordered to seduce John before you leave Hogwarts.”

“I wasn’t!”

“So this isn’t your handwriting on this letter?” Virgo held up a parchment, still not bothering to look up.

Susan slipped off the windowsill and stepped forward. “Duel me,” she said quietly.

“Huh?” The prefect looked around.

“You want a shot at John? Duel me,” she repeated, louder. “If you win, I’ll go back to the Hufflepuff common room.”

John smirked.

The girl stepped backwards. “Are you crazy? I’m not a duellist! I’m in the gobstones club. And I know all about the insane training Potter puts you through. I know about how good you are. And you’re the niece of the head of the DMLE. I’m not going to fight you.”

“Then stop bothering John and leave us alone,” Susan snapped. “If you can’t fight, then you have no business pursuing the boy-who-lived. You have no idea the enemies he has. Just go back to getting spat on by stones and stop trying to dig gold from a boy four years younger than you.”

The girl’s face rapidly went from chalk white to embarrassed red before she turned and beat a hasty retreat up the spiral staircase towards the girls’ dorms.

A flash of lightning chose that moment to silhouette Susan against the window, casting her form in shadows. It lasted for only a moment and made little lights dance across the eyes of all who witnessed it.

There was a moment of silence.

“Holy crap,” piped up one of the first-year boys. “That was so badass!”

That broke the tension. Some people laughed. Others turned back to their homework.

Susan herself smiled shyly and turned back to gazing out of the window.

Only Virgo continued to stare. She hadn’t just seen what she thought she did, had she? In that brief lightning flash? No, it must have been a trick of the light. It must have been.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Down in the Chamber of Secrets, magical power thrummed throughout the ritual circle. The seven participants stood behind their respective pots, each one as naked as the day they were born.

“You’re not going to look, are you?” Ginny called to her brother. “I’ll hex you if you do.”

“We aren’t going to look,” Harry said. “Go right ahead, girls.”

“You can look, Harry,” said Ginny and Luna in unison.

“No, he can’t,” shot back Daphne, Hermione, and Alex.

It took a few moments for the girls to all climb in, followed shortly thereafter by the two boys. At a spoken command, they all took a lung-full of mandrake essence and pushed as much magic as they could into their pots.

At first nothing visible happened.

Then the circle started to faintly glow.

Suddenly, a flash of magical light shot around the circle, up through each of the lines of phoenix ash connecting them all, and ending in a small supernova around the central pensieve.

Then everything went quiet. Another soft light in the middle began to pulse. It slowly made its way up one of the trails of ash until it reached the pot containing Ginny Weasley. The pot made a resounding, BONG sound.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Lightning flashed, again, and again, and again.

In Ravenclaw Tower, Sophie Roper stared intently at the school-wide academic leaderboard that hung over the common-room fireplace where absolutely no one could possibly miss it. Her name was rising, slowly but surely, up the ranks. Soon, she’d be in the top ten. That would be great. Top five would be even better.

Of course, top position would be best, but that would mean beating Hermione—an absolutely impossible task. Before the holiday, it would have meant beating Harry Potter too, but his position as number one had been removed when he’d been withdrawn from school. Not that that stopped him from showing up to lessons, incredibly.

“Did you know,” started Padma, who was sitting beside her, reading from a third-year book, “that chimaera are born into magical storms?”

“I did, yes.”

“Oh.” The disappointment in her voice was clear. “Well, did you know then that chimaera are some of the most dangerous magical creatures that exist? They inherit many of the properties of their component animals, and sometimes can even be magical. They have human-level intelligence, are magically resistant, and eat people. Some can even speak! The ICW has to hunt down a rogue one every decade or so, and it’s always a huge fuss.”

“Actually, I knew all that too.”

Padma snapped her book shut.

“What I don’t understand is why aren’t they evacuating us from the school? What if one was born here?”

Sophie continued to stare at Hermione’s name, right at the top of the board. She’d had a very intense conversation with her mum and dad over the holidays about Lord Slytherin, the Muggle Protection Act, and the dangers of the Wizarding World. “I don’t know,” she eventually said. “Survival of the fittest?”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

The air was dry—the shadows, long. The sound of curious insects buzzed on the air. A tall silhouette could be seen against the shimmering horizon—a giraffe of the African planes.

And the sun rose.

Underneath a clump of bushes in a patch of scrub, a female cheetah licked the head of her week-old cub.

The cub could not see. Born blind and immobile, she was completely dependent on her mother. She didn’t know who she was, or what she was. All that she knew was that so long as that tongue kept licking her—so long as that musky smell was near, she was safe.

The cub didn’t think. Not actual thoughts. Rather, a stream of senses passed through her mind like water through a funnel. The breeze in the air. The wetness on her fur. The smell of safety. There was no time for consideration. No storage location where the meaning of sensory input could be pondered on.

And then the tongue was gone—the smell, fading. A new sense passed through her, one that came not from without, but from within. Fear.

She cried out.

And the smell was back. As was the tongue.

The fear faded.

The cub opened her eyes.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Water. The cub could smell water. She easily followed her mother down the embankment to the small stream to drink. She was much bigger now. She’d grown—now coming up all the way to her mother’s chest. Together they drank their fill.

They’d move on to a new place to sleep before the sun went down. And then her mother would hunt.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

“No, you fool! Leave me alone!”

The cub darted forward to sniff at her quarry before darting back as her prey tried, and pitifully failed, to slither away. It was a tiny black snake, no thicker than a human finger.

“I will destroy you, girl! I will kill you and all you love! I will—No! Put me down!”

The cub pounced and grabbed the snake in her jaws, pinning its little head with a paw. Something about this dangerous wiggly-thing didn’t feel right. It felt bad in a way she couldn’t understand, different from normal dangerous wiggly-things. But a part of her—a part she also didn’t understand—wanted it dead … badly.

“Stop!”

There was a loud BANG that ripped through the air of the grassland and caused several nearby birds to give flight.

The cub jumped in surprise, looking around for what had caused the noise. This allowed the snake to slither away again.

Not seeing any immediate threat, the cub easily caught back up to her quarry and once more pounced on it.

“You can’t! I will be the greatest! I will rule the Wizarding World! I will—”

The cub took its body in its jaws and, with one clean snap of her head, ripped the creature in two. It fell to the ground, dead.

She didn’t eat it. The part of her she didn’t understand felt disgusted at the idea. She instead trotted in the direction of her mother. Except, it wasn’t only her mother that greeted her.

“This one’s a beauty, isn’t she?”

“Sure is. Hold the head up so I can get a good photograph.”

Her mother was dead. Two humans crouched by the body.

Fear. Anger. Loss.

“C’mon. Help me get her up on the truck.”

The cub lay deathly still under a bush, not daring to move until the two larger predators left. When they finally did, she crawled out of her hiding place and looked around. She walked over to the spot on the ground, sniffed at where her mother had fallen, and let out a long, drawn-out moan.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Hunger.

The one feeling overruled all others.

In the grass ahead sat a hare, nibbling away at breakfast.

The cub raised herself on her hindquarters, trotted forward, and broke into a sprint.

The chase was over in seconds.

The hare struggled under her paws.

But something stopped her from delivering the fatal bite.

That part of her she didn’t understand.

It hesitated.

The hare fled.

And the cub continued to go hungry.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

The cub could hardly even be called a cub anymore, but whether she could be called an adult cheetah was still up for debate. In the time since her mother’s death, she hadn’t completed a single successful hunt yet. She lived by scavenging, getting to a carcass first, and eating her fill before the vultures and hyenas turned up. A few times she had managed to steal a kill off a smaller predator, which gave food for days, but in general, things were not going well.

And the situation was about to get worse.

A smell on the breeze caused every muscle in her body to freeze in fear.

“Just going to use the ol’ washroom, chaps. Won’t be a tick.”

A party of humans walked through the brush.

One split off from the others and walked off in the opposite direction.

The young female kept her head to the ground as boots marched on.

Then the one that had split off turned around, and the part of her she didn’t understand roared. It was the same human from before. The one that had taken her mother.

“Just be sure to keep your gun with you!” one of the other humans shouted. “Don’t want to be caught with your pants down if you get jumped!”

Most of the young female wanted nothing more than to hide, but the part she didn’t understand, the part that had kept her hungry most of her life, suddenly wanted to hunt—wanted to kill—even if the predator was bigger and stronger than she was.

“We’ll meet you back at the lodge!”

Quietly, the young female picked herself up and crept around the circle of bushes, through the long grass. She didn’t dare approach through the foliage. The wind was all wrong. She’d be spotted. And if she was spotted, it was all over. She knew, instinctively, that if the human had enough time, it could hunt her, even without getting close.

Eventually, she spotted her target—crouched down in the grass ahead, easily within sprinting range.

Unfortunately, she wasn’t the only one.

“Alright, girl,” the human said, picking up its weapon. “Enough of that. I can see you. No getting any closer, you hear?”

The part of her that needed vengeance screamed. She felt a power surge through her the likes of which she never had. She crouched down to the ground, muscles coiled.

The human sighted down the barrel. “Don’t do this, girl.”

She lunged. From a crouching start to a full sprint in the blink of an eye.

The human cursed, aimed, exhaled, and fired.

But she wasn’t there anymore.

The world changed, and where before had been a young cheetah, hurtling through space, now there was nothing but a stone, falling to the ground. It hit at about the same time as the cat crashed into the human’s back from behind, sending him to the ground in a melee of teeth and claws.

Normally, a female cheetah wouldn’t be much of a mortal threat to the average grown male human, but she had surprise on her side. Oh boy, did she have surprise. The look on the hunter’s face was one of pure, unbelieving shock. Her jaws closed around her target’s throat. She gave one quick snap of her head. And the man fell dead.

She howled her victory.

And the part of her she didn’t understand fell silent.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Now fully grown and strong, the once-underfed cheetah stared around her domain with the certainty that comes from a lifetime of overcoming the odds. Sure, there were threats she couldn’t directly fight, but she’d learned that anything she couldn’t kill, she could simply run away from. They got bored eventually.

Strangely, for an adult female, she never had cubs of her own. That part of her she didn’t understand usually stayed silent when she went out to hunt and kill, but the one situation it certainly would make a fuss was when male cheetahs came sniffing around.

She yawned, jumped down from her rock, walked over to her favourite watering spot, and lapped up the refreshing drink. As she finished, she suddenly perked, every sense in her body now alert.

The wind had changed, bringing with it a new smell—one she didn’t recognise, but which she had to investigate.

It wasn’t long until she found its source. Every hackle on her neck rose.

The massive dog stared at her with bright violet eyes. It was much larger than she was. Still lean, but clearly built for raw power.

It didn’t look easily intimidated, but nevertheless, she rose and hissed loudly.

The dog just continued to stare at her.

So she tried walking forward while growling softly. That often did the trick.

Unfortunately, this only caused the dog to match her behaviour. Soon they were circling each other, a rare face-off on the African grasslands.

She didn’t give the dog any more chances. She lunged.

This did not have the result she expected. Just before she hit her target, it changed into a dog-shaped mist, causing her instead to pass right through and crash into the ground beyond with a yelp.

The dog turned back into dog.

And that was that. Fight hadn’t worked, so the next option was flight.

Except the dog didn’t appear to want to let her go.

She ran fast and the dog followed slowly.

She stopped to pant and the dog caught up.

She trotted away and the dog just kept on coming.

Eventually she could run no further. Her legs were shaking. Her breathing laboured. She felt so hot. Slowly, she collapsed on the ground.

The dog trotted over and put its strong jaws around her throat.

The last things she saw before darkness took her were those violet eyes, and in them, something similar to the part of her she didn’t understand.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Ginny gasped, bolting up in her pot, clutching at her throat. But everything was okay. She was alive. She was Ginny Weasley. She was. … The inside of the pot was pitch-black and the mandrake fumes were still overpowering. Her eyes slowly closed again as she started to drift back off. Even if it was needed, she would really pay Alexandra back for that.

The glowing around the circle faded for a second before flaring right back up. Another line of magic shot up another line of phoenix ash. And another pot went BONG.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

“I don’t care about licensing opportunities from your stupid hair care empire,” said Lord Malfoy sharply. “I insist on open floo access to my grandchildren.”

“They will be my house’s sons and daughters,” shot back Lord Potter. “It is my prerogative to see them raised as Potters.”

Malfoy sniffed. “You are traditional only when it suits you.”

“And you are greedy only when it suits you!”

Both lords glared.

Listening in through one of the walls, Narcissa sighed. The problem with being a powerful staff like her husband, she considered, was that every problem inevitably ended up looking like an incredibly tempting skull to crack.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

An ice floe sparkled in the blindingly bright sunlight like diamonds sprinkled on a mirror.

The rockhopper penguin that housed the impression of George Weasley’s soul hopped across the frozen landscape, vaguely feeling, as it had for its whole life, that a singularly important part of it was missing.

Hop, hop, hop—it bounced from crevice to gulley and up.

It didn’t see the odd collection of animals hidden absolutely still behind the nearest cliff, all pressed up against the wall of ice like prison escapees caught in a floodlight.

It also didn’t see the golden eagle overhead. Why would it look? Such predators didn’t fly this far south. Nevertheless, the eagle that shouldn’t have been there started to dive.

The rockhopper only realised the danger a split-second before a sharp talon ripped straight through its brain.

George Weasley bolted up in his pot, gasping and panting. “Greengrass!”

The Weasley twin’s pot dimmed and another lit up.

BONG!

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

“You can’t add the profit from magical artefact crafting onto Virgo’s bride price if you don’t even know if crafting them will be possible!” James shouted.

“Yes, I can,” Malfoy snapped. “I did have the odds checked by a spell-hunter and valued by a financier. Have you never heard of probabilistic investment analysis?”

Lightning flashed.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

High above the frozen steppes, a golden eagle sighted down her perfect vision to lock onto the perfect prey—a rabbit poking its head up through the crystalline grasses. There was a rather odd pack of animals also moving across the terrain, but they didn’t matter. By the time they reached her, she’d easily be off with her prize. No land predator could come even close to her speed.

Mighty wings spread, she leapt from her rocky crag and swooped across the landscape, quickly reaching the perfect position from which to launch her deadly dive.

The rabbit never saw what hit it.

And neither did the eagle.

Daphne gasped upright in her pot. “Ginevra Weasley!”

Her pot slowly dimmed.

And another pot lit up.

BONG!

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Wind whistled through the trees. The sounds of crashing waves roared nearby. The sky was completely black, illuminated only by the occasional crash of faintly green lightning.

“Is this really a good idea?!” Emma Granger shouted up at the roof of Granger Cottage, clutching her coat around her shoulders, soaked to the skin.

“We’re muggles!” Dan Granger shouted back down. “The storm isn’t dangerous to us!” He was holding onto the chimney, affixing the ghost gem to a long pole. “And we’ve tried everything else to get a bead on this thing! Clare doesn’t have the magical reserves for our next test. This is by far the easiest way to get it.”

“The lightning might not be a danger!” Emma shouted back up. “But I don’t want you to trip and fall!”

“Do you want to tell our patron we weren’t able to find out anything in the whole month we’ve had with this thing?”

Emma cursed under her breath. “No, I guess not! Just please be careful!”

“Of course, dear! Everything will be fine!”

Lightning flashed.

It travelled in slow motion from the cloudy sky above, hit the very top of the Granger Cottage chimney, coiled around the stack three times, and struck a very shocked-looking Dan Granger, still holding the ghost gem in both hands. The bolt then leapt from him and grounded itself in a nearby magical birch tree, which promptly turned into a miniature version of the Eiffel Tower.

“DAN!” Emma screamed.

The head of house Granger tottered, slowly twirled, and fell.

There was a faint pop sound, almost unheard over the pandemonium of the storm. Plato appeared in an explosion of rain-drops, held out his hand, and slowly levitated Dan Granger to the ground. Mud was everywhere. The elf glared at Emma. “These are being Plato’s best robes. I hope Slytherin Vassal is being good at cleaning them.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

“Magical Merlin,” Lockhart whispered.

The sentiment was clearly shared by everyone else in the Great Hall, students and teachers alike. The roof above showed the full spectacle of the encroaching storm. Long gone was the eye of calm. Now the tightening walls of clouds circled closer and closer around Hogwarts like a raging noose, flashing lightning in a near-constant stream of crashes and booms.

Groups of huddling girls shrieked at every new display, while elsewhere on the benches, boys sat alone, putting on brave faces, but still not managing to avoid flinching.

“Where is Black?” Nott asked Draco at the Slytherin table.

“I don’t know.”

CRASH! BOOM!

“You know these storms are supposed to birth chimaera!” Nott shouted over the din.

Draco waited for a break in the noise before replying. “I know,” he said. “I wouldn’t want to be the first to meet it.”

“What if Black did?” Nott said. “Would solve our problem nicely.”

Draco fixed his friend with a deadly serious glare. “Don’t even joke about that. Black running into a chimaera is the last thing we need.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Deep in the darkest part of what looked like a typical English graveyard, a large spectral grim whimpered, hiding in an old badger set with her paws over her eyes. She was being hunted. She knew it. It had been a long time now. This was not the way things were supposed to be. She was the hunter. She stalked prey throughout the graveyard. She didn’t cower hoping to be missed. She was a killer. She crushed bone and ripped tendon. She was a killer!

And right now, she was terrified of what lurked outside.

Her spectral form flickered out, her body now too tired to maintain it.

The night was clear and silent.

The moon was full.

Heavy footsteps neared.

The grim lay absolutely still.

“Come out, Alex,” said a voice like the rumble of rocks being crushed together. “I promise you I will make it as quick as possible.”

The grim couldn’t understand the voice, but it could feel the intent. This predator would kill her—no matter how calm it sounded. She desperately tried to work her way further down into the set, but her body was simply too large. There wasn’t anywhere else to go.

“Hard way it is then,” declared the voice.

The grim went cross-eyed as something heavy smashed onto its head.

The predator outside had used a massive paw to collapse the roof in on her, leaving her exposed and vulnerable. A large jaw clamped around her foreleg. With a yelp, she was dragged out. It was then, for the first time, that the grim got a good look at the predator that before she had only smelled.

If she had been fully Alexandra at that moment, she might very well have wet herself again. Instead, she simply whined and whimpered.

It was a chimaera, that much was obvious—its head and body those of a giant lion, its coat a dull golden sheen. Such a beast would be easily recognisable by any magizoologist worth their salt: a Nemean lion—a highly magical creature whose coat could shrug off even high-calibre muggle armour piercing rounds. Not invulnerable to physical attacks, as some would say, but definitely not weak either. Its tail was that of a thestral. But it was the chimaera’s third aspect that most struck primal fear.

Where one might normally expect a lion’s mane to be, instead writhed a nest of jade-green snakes—hundreds of them. They weaved and darted and flicked their tongues out to the night sky, tasting the air in every direction, before focusing all their attention, in perfect synchrony, on her.

The chimaera pinned the grim to the ground with one large paw.

“Good luck, Alex,” it said. “The chimaera’s birth is here. I don’t know if you will remember this round when it is time for you and the others to hunt me, or if you might have already done so. I hope you will. I can feel the chimaera just below the surface. He is a proud and territorial beast. You will need every ounce of teamwork to take him down. To be honest, I’m not sure what will happen if you don’t manage it. The ritual feels rather ambiguous about that point.”

The grim whimpered under the heavy weight of the paw on its stomach and felt raw terror as those massive jaws closed over its whole head, twisting in one firm movement, and instantly snapping its neck.

Alexandra woke in a puddle of sweat, skin cold and clammy.

“Lord Slytherin,” she whispered. “Harry Potter. So cool.”

She then slowly fell back into trance.

Her clay pot dimmed.

And the pot containing Harry Potter lit up with a loud …

BONG.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

“What the hell is this storm?!” shouted Robert Pike, chief meteorologist at the London Met Office. The windows rattled as winds not seen since the great storm of 1987 buffeted the office building, while the phones constantly rang. It was all the relatively small staff could do to keep the tide of panicked questions at bay.

His assistant stared at a fax readout in bewilderment. “Can’t say, sir. It came out of nowhere. One second clear sky, the next, an actual hurricane.”

“Don’t use that word!” Pike snapped. “Britain does not get hurricanes! You need warm tropical water!”

“Well, with respect, sir, what do you call this?” one of the female assistants butted in, thrusting another grainy fax in his face. It was a satellite image which showed a massive storm whirring around the British Isles, brushing the coasts of France, Belgium, the Netherlands, and Denmark, with a large eye focused on, of all places, the Scottish Highlands.

“Can I see that?” asked one researcher calmly. He took the printout from the assistant’s hands.

“Well?” asked Pike. The thought crossed his mind that the man was dressed rather oddly for a research assistant, especially one so new who’d only been seconded from the Ministry of Defence a few hours ago, or so he’d been told … What was his name? Bob? Richard? Oliver?

The man looked up and smiled. “Everything will be fine. I have informed The Ministry of the situation.”

Pike frowned. “I’m sure we’re all relieved to hear that the army will be on hand if needed, but that doesn’t solve the mystery of what this thing is. I’m sure they don’t know either.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

“What the hell is this storm?!” shouted Ian Mikenther, junior unspeakable, and right now, the most interesting person in the Department of Mysteries. Artefacts and measuring devices were going haywire all around the room. Five of his colleagues were crammed into his little office while another three had their heads poking around the door. “The readings are going nuts! There hasn’t been this great a jump in the Albion Magic’s influence in … forever! It has to be some kind of channelling effect into whatever foci the Albion uses, but why now?”

“Why here?” asked another unspeakable.

“The upper floors will want answers soon,” said another.

“We don’t have answers!” Ian shouted.

“Well, how fast is it spreading?” asked Mary. “That seems like a good place to start.”

Ian paused for a moment before sweeping a pile of parchments from his desk and starting to scribble. “Fast,” he concluded.

“How fast?”

“Too fast.”

“For Merlin’s sake, Mikenther!” snapped one of the older unspeakables. “Stop beating about the bush!”

Ian swallowed. “About a hundred years of spread in a single hour kind of fast.”

The room went deathly silent.

Mary paled. “That’s fast.”

“Yes,” said a new voice. “It is.” The crowd hastily parted to allow a tall, thin wizard to stalk into the room, closely followed by two field-unspeakables, piercing eyes scanning the room with carefully honed situational awareness.

“Chief,” said Ian, getting quickly to his feet.

Saul Croaker stared at the haywire instruments. “Lock away the artefacts and throw all the records in The Deep Library. None of you are to speak of this. If anyone asks, the story is that a chimaera was born, but we haven’t yet located it. Other than that, we know nothing.” Croaker glared at each face in turn. “I declare this—officially—to be a Department of Mysteries Family Secret.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Lightning flashed. Thunder rumbled. Rain beat on stonework, a thousand years old, crumbled and piled-up around half-destroyed castle walls.

Inside the old throne room, the cause of the castle’s downfall lay on a rug surrounded by broken bones, listening to the sounds of the storm with great suspicion.

It really was a powerful storm tonight. Such a storm couldn’t have graced his lands since his own birth, all those years before. Did this herald the coming of another of his kind? The chimaera let out a low growl. A female would be welcome. He’d long sought a mate, but never found one. A male, of course, could not be tolerated.

The snakes that made up his mane all hissed in agreement.

All except one—one with emerald-green eyes and a small lightning-shaped scar on the top of its head. §No. Not another chimaera,§it hissed cheerfully into his ear. §But the storm does have purpose, soul animal.§

The chimaera snarled. “Passenger. What do you want?”

The snake dropped away, quickly replaced at his other ear by one wearing a tiny black and green mask. §Your power for our purpose,§ it declared in a hissing voice of steel.

The chimaera snorted. The presence that he’d come to think of as his passenger had been a constant throughout his life—neither understood nor appreciated, beyond it obviously being one not two. Sometimes the passenger would show up at the most annoying times, often pushing an agenda in total contradiction to what was right and good in the world. He was the king. He had a complete right to rule and dominate any creature in his territory. Their lives were his playthings. Mercy was not a concept he welcomed. “I will never allow you to lead, Passenger,” he growled. “I am the master. You are less than a servant.”

The first snake rose back up to his other ear and together the two snakes hissed, §The choice is not yours to make, soul animal. You are a vehicle of my power. My hunters come. If you will not allow me to lead, they will bring you to heel.§

“You dare speak to me so!? I do not care what you are! I am the king!”

Lightning flashed. Thunder boomed.

The chimaera’s black thestral tail flicked back and forth in agitation. But from the passenger, there was no more.

The storm continued to rage.

Eventually, the chimaera could take no more.

He rose on his four legs and prowled towards the large, oak double doors to the courtyard he’d smashed down so long ago.

The outside world was more sea than land. Rivers of rain flowed across every surface. Ponds of roiling mud filled every depression and gulley. A constant spray of water smacked into his face, putting his whiskers on edge, and his snakes in a frenzy. They fought with each other to all be at the bottom of his mane nest.

The chimaera looked around warily. Any hunters the passenger sent would not be small fry. Not that they stood a chance against him, of course, but an intelligent creature would be cautious and he was a supremely intelligent creature. So naturally, he would be cautious. That was the only reason he was being cautious, and not for any other.

A cry from above caused him to search the pitch-black skies.

There! Up in one of the many courtyard trees sat a golden eagle, staring down at him with piercing blue eyes. The tree was frozen solid. Ice crystals were forming and growing even as he sized up what was clearly no normal bird.

“This is my kingdom!” he bellowed before charging right at the tree, connecting with a force that caused the entire plant to shatter, bringing down trunk and branches like a massive inverted chandelier.

It crashed to the ground and smashed, causing the bird to take to the rainy sky and fly up to the top of the castle’s tallest tower.

“Flee, weakling!” The chimaera roared, shaking water from his coat. “Some hunter, Passenger.”

A pair of growls caused him to turn. The rain was playing havoc with his snake’s ability to pick up on threats.

“A dog and a cat,” the chimaera scoffed, staring at the grim and cheetah stalking towards him together. “I am insulted.”

And in less time than it takes to blink, the cheetah was on his back, snapping madly at the snakes around his neck, trying to find some way through. He roared and flung his weight to the side, throwing the feline off and turned to deal a killing blow.

MORTAL PERIL!

Every instinct in his body screamed at him to move. He continued his turn and fell to one side, just time to see the grim in spectral form fly straight through the space where he’d been only a split second later. The grim turned back solid and the rain falling through its form exploded outwards like bullets. What would have happened if he’d been where the grim was when it turned back solid?

“OH NO YOU DON’T!” he roared.

One perfectly timed swipe was all it took.

The grim’s neck snapped and its corpse fell to the ground.

The cheetah scrabbled back to its feet, hissing and spitting, and quickly retreated.

Oddly, instead of staying on the ground, the grim’s corpse slowly vanished.

“IS THAT ALL YOU’VE GOT, PASSENGER?!” bellowed the chimaera to the stormy sky.

A swoop attack by the eagle alerted him to the fact that he still wasn’t alone. The bird alighted on a tree closer to the gatehouse entrance.

One smashed tree later, and the bird had retreated to a tree even further away.

This went on for several minutes until he found himself leaving the castle courtyard. He was being led away from his throne. “Bah!” he shouted into the night. “Do you think choosing your battlefield will make any difference?”

MORTAL PERIL!

Again, he rolled to the side and stared in disbelief as the same grim from before became solid again, right where he’d been, again, and again showered him in rain bullets. Another expertly timed swipe with his paw produced another dead dog.

“I killed you!” he shouted down at the rapidly fading corpse. “I know I did!”

§Give up, soul animal§ hissed the passenger into his ear. §Give me control and we can end this now.§

“I am the king! I bow to no one!”

§Then we continue the game.§

It was as though a signal had been given. A hole appeared in the clouds above and a single beam of light shot through the darkness. It hit the path down to the lake and slowly tracked the creature walking up it.

The chimaera gave a short sharp intake of breath. “Unicorn.”

§Are you ready to battle again?§hissed the passenger.

“Bah!” the chimaera smashed one paw on the muddy ground. “You expect me to fall for such a simple trick?”

The tiny unicorn arrived at the top of the hill, neighed loudly and charged. The chimaera stood stock still as it galloped forward, head lowered, horn pointed straight ahead. The chimaera looked down as it collided with his front leg, glanced off, and skidded to the side from the force of the impact. It fell to the ground making a high-pitched keening noise.

“I will not be cursed by harming a creature of pure goodness,” he declared to the night. “But if that creature wishes to run into a castle wall, who am I to stop them?”

§Harming a creature of pure goodness,§ repeated the green-eyed snake. For the first time the chimaera could ever remember, the passenger sounded uncertain. §I understood it was the drinking of the unicorn’s blood that caused the curse.§

The chimaera couldn’t stop itself laughing out loud, even as the storm continued to rage. “How ignorant you must be to think such a thing! It is intent to harm that is evil, not intent to benefit.”

The passenger said nothing.

“Well?” The chimaera said. “Any more hunters, Passenger? Any more vicious predators to bring me to heel?”

§By the lake§hissed that part of the Passenger that wore the green and black mask. §There you will find an opponent worthy of your might.§

“There is no such being!”

The grim, cheetah, unicorn, and eagle all followed at a distance as he made his way down to the lakeside. What he found there made him see red.

“WHAT THE HELLS IS THIS?” he bellowed out to the storm. “DO YOU MOCK ME, PASSENGER?”

Further along the shoreline there hopped a lone rockhopper penguin, holding a stick in its beak and making swish, swish motions as though fighting with a sword in its mouth. Crouching low, he threw himself forward at full sprint. It took only a few moments to close the distance and one powerful paw swipe with all claws extended to reduce the flightless bird to sliced luncheon meat.

“ARE WE DONE WITH THIS POINTLESS GAME NOW?” he roared. “ANY MORE PATHETIC BIRDS FOR ME TO KILL?”

A sound made him look behind.

The grim, cheetah, and unicorn had taken up position from where he’d come, sitting up on their haunches, or laying down on the pebbles, blocking his way back.

A swoosh of wings announced the eagle’s arrival, swooping over his head and landing some distance away, blocking his way forward. He now had the animals up and down the shore, the lake on one side and the forest bathed in darkness on the other.

Mortal Peril.

It was a singularly specific talent unique to thestrals, and the ability to know exactly when something was intending to land a killing blow, had saved many of their kind over the eons. It gave them a sense of where to dodge—how to move—what would be the best thing to do in this exact situation to ensure their continued survival.

From the deepest darkness of the trees to his side, something growled. Something huge.

There was no instinct on where to dodge—only to freeze. Every muscle locked up. The threat was too large—the predator, too overwhelming. Every snake on his mane went flat—all except two.

§Long live the queen.§

And in a moment, it happened. Two of the nearest trees were smashed to the sides in a spray of storm water and something massive lunged out of the forest—one massive head, jaw wide open, driving right for him with an ear-splitting roar.

The chimaera had just enough time to find his wits and leap to the side, just before those giant jaws, lined with teeth the size of daggers, chomped shut right where he’d been with a gust of displaced air. There was a tiny moment where ambushed and ambusher crouched motionless as both sets of muscles coiled up again for the second move. And then that massive head whipped around and snapped those giant jaws around the chimaera’s skull.

The chimaera felt the teeth shred his snakes, but fail to puncture his coat—not that this mattered. Titanic neck muscles twisted, crushing bone and rupturing internals. He was flipped onto his side and a clawed foot settled ominously on his ribcage, before a terrifyingly large portion of fourteen tonnes pressed down, pulping everything within, shattering everything without, and bringing all chances of escape to zero.

The monster stepped backwards and for the first time the chimaera got a good look at his attacker. “A lizard bird?” he groaned. He might not be dead, but every muscle in his body felt like it had been through a meat tenderiser. A lightning bolt crashed through the sky, illuminating dirty-blonde feathers all the way down its back.

§Tyrannosaurus rex,§hissed the passenger. §Tyrant lizard king. Or, perhaps I should say, Tyrannosaurus regina, in this case—tyrant lizard queen—my queen.§

“I will not die like this,” the chimaera stated, trying to get to his feet, and failing. “I cannot.”

§Did you forget what happened to my grim when you killed her?§ hissed the passenger. §In this world, all my hunters will return from the dead, again and again and again, until you are defeated. Even if you could beat her, she will return.§

The chimaera groaned as the T-Rex towered over him, thrice as tall he himself. “Fine,” he said. “I submit, Passenger. What do I have to do now?”

§Die.§

The T-Rex lunged. It grabbed him around the waist and dragged him into the lake. He saw the sky disappear, replaced by murky water—the sounds of the storm replaced by the bubbling of air forced from his lungs. The crush around his chest became over-whelming—the force dragging him down, indomitable. Thrashing changed nothing. He felt water rush into his lungs. Pain assaulted him. Panic set in.

The chimaera died.

And the chimaera was born.

And all at once the storm stopped.

Not just in the world of the ritual, but all across Magical Britain. One moment storm, the next, clear sky. Newspapers blowing through the air, all fell to the ground. Trees creaked back upright. Confused motorists stopped on the motorways and stepped out of their cars to stare in wonder at the sudden peace.

And far below Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry, deep in the Chamber of Secrets, Harry bolted upright in his pot. “No one should try and hunt Hermione!” he shouted urgently. “No one should—” and that was as far as he got before the mandrake fumes rushed through his system again, and he dropped back down into slumber.

The pot containing Harry Potter faded and another pot lit up with a loud BONG—the pot containing Luna Lovegood.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

“There, you see, Miss Davis!” Beamed Headmaster Lockhart. The students in the Great Hall all stared in awe at the suddenly blue sky above them. “I told you everything would be fine.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

“Storm’s over,” Virgo announced in a matter-of-fact voice from a window. A small cheer rang out across the Gryffindor common room.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Hagrid stood beside Aragog’s grave, just by his hut near the forbidden forest. He wrung water out of his beard. “Any scent of chimaera, Fang?”

Fang whined.

Hagrid grunted. “Not expecting there to be, either. But ye never know.” He looked up at the castle. “Still not the same without Dumbledore.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

In the London Meteorological Office, Robert Pike stared out the window with his mouth open. “Not possible. Not possible. Not possible,” he continually muttered over and over.

“Sir! It happened. You can’t keep saying it’s not possible. That’s not how science works!”

Pike whirled around. “Then explain what just happened!”

The assistant looked away bashfully. “I can’t, obviously.”

Pike took a moment to centre himself. “We’re going to need some explanation for what just happened. When Number Ten calls, I don’t want to look an idiot.”

Another assistant put down the handle of his rotary telephone. “Sir? You won’t have to worry about that for a little while at least, sir. The line’s dead.”

“What?! That storm had 100 mile an hour winds and the line chooses now to fail?”

“Huh, that’s weird,” said a junior researcher. “The satellite pictures aren’t coming in, either.”

Pike stared at the man. “Your pictures come from the dish on our roof.”

“I know, sir.”

Pike’s gaze turned to his new mobile telephone—the size of a brick and just about as heavy. He picked it up and tried for a tone. Nothing. He put it down. “We’re totally cut off,” he whispered.

There was a rattling sound. The same junior researcher whose satellite pictures were AWOL was trying to get out of the office—trying, because the door was locked.

Pike felt a chill go down his spine. “What the hell is this?”

“Please don’t worry, Mister Pike,” said a calm voice.

He whirled around.

The man from ‘the Ministry’ as he put it, was smiling at him—smiling at him while holding an ornate stick of wood. “This will all be over—”

Suddenly there was a loud whoosh sound and men and women in dark robes were everywhere.

“—Now.”

“Obliviate!”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

The sound of ocean waves washing up against a shoreline. Sea birds crying overhead. The feeling of wet sand on fur.

Harry opened his eyes … all hundred-odd pairs of them, flinched, and instantly closed the vast majority. Magical Merlin that was disorientating.

He spent a few minutes getting used to the idea of seeing through the eyes of snakes in all directions. Not at all easy. That done, he could look around properly. The beach he found himself on was extremely tropical. Palm trees waved in the breeze.

He stretched out his body and noted the way his spine curved out with far greater elasticity than his human form’s ever could. So, this was what being a Nemean-lion/snake-mane/thestral chimaera was like. Oddly, he could feel the animal instincts right below the surface—could practically taste what it meant to be a predator—to hunt and to kill. It was like waking up one day a slightly different person. Was that evidence that he’d already completed his part of the ritual?

He flicked his horse-like tail in an absent-minded way.

No way to know, really. He could only hope that everything had gone well and that when they were out, they’d all have their proper forms.

He looked around the tropical beach again.

“I wonder,” he said out loud in a gruff voice very different both from Harry Potter and Lord Slytherin, “which one of you lives here?”

Daphne was unlikely. The golden eagle typically preferred colder climates. The same went for George Weasley’s rock hopper penguin form. Ginny’s cheetah should prefer the savannah; while Alexandra’s grim form would be more at home around the graveyards of Europe.

That left Luna and Hermione.

The chimaera that was Harry snorted.

Wonderful. So, this was most likely Luna’s hunting ground. And hunting a T-Rex would not be easy. It was easy to imagine who would be best out of their human-thinking animal forms to take down each of their animal-thinking animal forms, in each of their respective hunting sessions.

Alex for Ginny.

Ginny for Daphne.

Etc.

But for Luna … no getting around it, it was probably going to be him doing most of the heavy lifting. At least they’d get as many tries as they needed.

But first, he should find the girls. Hopefully before Luna’s form found any of them.

He sank one massive paw into the silty sand ahead when a thought struck him.

What if Luna found Hermione?

Harry paused.

But he’d already thought about that long before they started the ritual. The hunted (in this case, Luna) was of animal mind, so consuming Unicorn-Hermione flesh, and thus her blood, shouldn’t activate the curse. There was no understanding of the benefit it might give.

So why was he worried?

Harry took another step and the thought invaded his mind again.

What if Luna found Hermione?

For some reason, it seemed incredibly important that he not dismiss this line of questioning. It was as if a strand of knowledge deep inside was dangling just out of his reach. With a growl, he focused in on his occlumency, and the tropical world around him vanished.

“That was quick, for a human.”

Harry opened his eyes again, finding himself this time on the shores of Azkaban Prison—his mindscape. Dark clouds hovered. Dementors floated all around the sky. And on the shore’s pebble beach, sat the chimaera, regarding him with what appeared to be annoyed resignation.

Harry didn’t waste any time. “What happens if Luna finds Hermione?”

The chimaera yawned. “Know that I am only helping you because I can feel our fates entangling, human. I do not appreciate that trick you pulled with your lizard queen.”

“You mean Luna? Then our turn has already been.”

“Yes, your turn has already been. But I will not fully join you until your ‘ritual’ is complete. But I will tell you now what I told you then. It is the intent to harm, not the intent to benefit that causes the curse.”

Harry frowned. “Then, no problem? Animals can’t be evil.”

The chimaera rolled its eyes—all of them. “You are standing before a giant cat with a mane of snakes and a tail made from an undead horse, and you’re telling me that animals can’t be evil? I eat your kind.”

“You’re sapient. That’s different.”

“And you’ve never seen a cat play with a mouse before?”

Harry hesitated. “But that’s not …” he trailed off. What was the standard that magic applied to morality? It certainly wasn’t something Voldemort had spent much time considering. Could he perfectly ascribe motives to an animal that had been dead to the world for over 65 million years? It was easy if the animal couldn’t understand the magical benefit, but if that wasn’t the true cause of the curse …

His Azkaban mindscape vanished.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Ginny Weasley had never felt morealive. Prowling through the foliage on four legs, lithe muscles sliding over each other, that feeling of explosive power ready and coiled just below the surface—it all felt so right.

She wondered briefly whether she’d had her turn yet, or how many of the others had already gone, before shaking those thoughts as irrelevant and turning her attention back to more immediate matters.

Whose world was she currently in? And how was she going to find Harry? Assuming this wasn’t Harry’s world, of course.

Ginny sniffed at the base of a tree. She growled. Nothing. Despite the incredibly rich range of scents she could now discern, she also had to admit that the question of which of her friends this world might belong to was almost completely beyond her. Except for her brother, probably. Penguins didn’t live in jungles. They lived in places with snow and ice, right?

At that moment, the bushes rustled.

Ginny froze.

What leapt out caused every feline instinct in Ginny’s body to scream at her the danger and power of the creature now standing before her.

“Ginny,” Harry stated, slightly out of breath. “Good. I have found you. We need to move.”

When Harry said he was a chimaera, he hadn’t been messing around. His lion form stood at over six foot tall at the shoulder, strong and intimidating. The mane of snakes around his head resembled a gorgon’s, and the thestral tail flicked up and around, showing agitation. That part was actually kind of cute.

“Ginny!” Harry panted a bit louder.

Crap, she’d been staring.

“Have you seen Hermione?”

She quickly shook her head.

Harry cursed and told her why it was critically important they find her.

Ginny’s eyes widened. Crap. Cursed Luna was not good Luna.

Five minutes of casual trotting through the forest later, following behind Harry like a tug following an icebreaker as he powered through a particularly dense bit of undergrowth, and they broke out of the forest and onto an open plain.

“If we find Daphne, she can be our eyes in the sky.”

Ginny couldn’t argue with that. Although that idea would probably have to wait. Her keen eyes spotted two figures rapidly moving towards them (or in one of their cases, hopping) from the other side of the massive clearing. A headbutt against one of Harry’s legs focused his attention in the right direction.

“George and Alex,” Harry said. “I’m not entirely sure what use George will be in the hunt, but who knows? He is a very creative wizard.”

At that point the trees behind the frantically hopping penguin exploded outwards and a sound like a tortured industrial machine arrived in the clearing, along with fourteen tonnes of two-legged predator.

“Oh, damn.”

Her brother barely got another hop in before Luna caught up and swallowed him with one sickening crunch.

Alex was substantially faster.

“Alex!” Harry bellowed, crouching down to charge as they approached.

For the briefest of split-seconds in between switching her attention between the tableau of rapidly approaching grim and Tyrannosaurus rex, Ginny thought she saw awe fill Alex’s dog-like eyes as they fell on Harry.

“Alex! Get ready!” Harry shouted again. “We’ll try and end this now! Explode her!”

Ah, yes. The what-happens-if-a-grim-in-spectral-form-ghosts-into-someone-and-turns-solid-while-still-inside-them question. Does the target explode? Does the grim?

Harry charged.

Alex whipped around to face her pursuer.

Ginny ran to flank them, the better to see and maybe help, if possible.

The T-Rex roared. This close to, it was like being bellowed at by a howler someone had recorded during a volcanic eruption.

Ginny felt a thrill shoot through her blood at the sound. Everything about this was so unbelievably dangerous.

Alex ran straight for it. She turned spectral and leapt, just as the dinosaur lunged. She phased right into the beast’s head, and then presumably turned back solid. The effect was not, however, dead dino. Instead, Alex shot out of the top of its head like a popped cork from a bottle. The rex briefly followed her trajectory upwards and no doubt would have crunched her on the way down, if it didn’t have to deal with one whole tonne of lion, snake, and thestral sprinting straight at it.

Harry leapt, claws extended, mouth open, teeth bared.

The first collision of chimaera and rex made Ginny very happy both Harry and Luna were on her side. She actually felt the smack of the impact as the rex was forced backwards a step. Several huge gashes appeared on the rex’s face as Harry scrabbled for purchase, ferociously trying to get to the throat. Then jaws as large as a car closed around Harry’s waist and smacked him against the ground. The rex seemed momentarily perplexed that it couldn’t bite through its victim, but that didn’t stop it for long. Several smacks on the ground later and Harry clearly wasn’t getting back up.

“Find Hermione!” he coughed out, then went limp.

Ginny winced. She wasn’t an expert, but if she had to guess, she’d say that every bone had been broken and most of his internal organs had probably ruptured. Magical Merlin, that thing was scary. She’d charge in if she thought she’d be of even the smallest use.

The rex roared triumphant over its kill—about a few seconds before Harry faded away. Again, this seemed to puzzle the rex before it quickly lost interest.

Alex had since landed in spectral form, turned back solid, and joined her.

The rex spotted them.

The girls watched as fourteen tonnes of killing-machine turned towards them.

Neither needed the ability to speak with the other to know exactly what they were both thinking. Run now. Find Hermione. Worry about the hunt later.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Sometime later, a frustrated roar sounded out across the island.

High above the jungle forest, Daphne rode the air currents, wind pushing against her chest, rushing past her wings, flipping the tips of her feathers this way and that—an eagle on a mission.

Merlin, she loved this—this space, this freedom. Her betrothed had been right. This was absolutely worth it.

With a flick of her powerful muscles, she banked hard right and swooped across the landscape, eagle eyes tracking the ground below.

Merlin, she loved these eyes. They zoomed in and out like a pair of omnioculars, and there wasn’t a blade of grass or quivering leaf she couldn’t inspect at will.

Another roar, closer this time, announced she was closing in.

Moments later, she soared over the side of a cliff and spotted something on the beach below far more noteworthy than assorted herbology specimens—a cheetah and a grim having an argument. Since neither could speak a language the other could understand, the format this argument took was of dozens of sentences scrawled in the damp sand by paws and claws.

It looked like they’d been at it for some time.

Daphne swooped down between them, mildly satisfied by the way the other girls started in shock at her arrival, and extended a talon of her own to write.

Harry has resurrected.

I have found Hermione.

I am to bring you to her.

Follow me.

She then spread her majestic wings—and yes, they were very majestic, thank you very much—and launched herself back into the air.

Twisting her neck, she was pleased to see both Ginny and Alex now following down below.

Yeah, that’s right. She’d keep these girls in line.

Some while later, they made their way through the undergrowth to a small stream, surrounded by ponds, where they found their Shetland unicorn, bathed in beams of light and drinking from crystal clean water. This was odd, because upstream the water looked murky as all hells.

It took quite a while with leaves and sticks to spell out to Hermione exactly what the problem was, but once she’d grasped the danger to Luna, she was noticeably distressed. Unicorn blood freely given? she asked by rearranging the sticks.

Daphne rolled her eyes, quite an expressive gesture on an eagle. Their only current strategy for beating Luna was to have Harry suicide himself against her again and again until he’d worn her down or got sufficiently lucky or skilled—that or hope she choked to death on one of them. The last thing they needed was a self-healing T-Rex.

Spelling this out took quite a lot longer than any of their previous communications.

Hermione the unicorn looked downcast and neighed.

Daphne was halfway through spelling out her next thought, which was that while Hermione freely giving blood to Luna was a really bad idea, giving it to Harry could possibly be exactly what they needed, when the ground shook.

It was only a tiny tremor, but Daphne froze with a small twig in her beak.

The next tremor felt slightly larger and Daphne noticed a ripple in one of the ponds. She gave an alarmed cry and leapt for the sky. And it was just as well that she did, because only a few seconds later, the T-Rex crashed its way out of the foliage and powered towards them like a raging knight-lorry made of muscle and teeth.

Daphne only just managed to clear the lower canopy before that huge maw chomped down on the air where she’d just been.

The other three had not been idle. All ran for it, and good, because the rex barely stopped to sniff at Daphne’s escape before it was after them again.

Daphne watched from above with her heart metaphorically in her throat as the three quadrupeds darted through the trees this way and that, using the massive plants as best they could to block and parry.

It actually didn’t look to be going too badly.

All three of the smaller animals seemed capable of outrunning the massive killing-machine trailing them … just.

Alex was having no problem at all. Every time it looked like she’d have to stop to pant in the jungle heat, she simply turned spectral and a small whoosh of relatively cooler air rushed through her form.

Hermione, too, was making a pretty good showing. Unicorns were well known for their speed and grace, even if this particular one was much shorter and squatter than normal, with hair that reached down to her knees.

Ginny, by contrast, cheerfully retreated at something between a canter and a trot. Not a full sprint. That would have been suicide in this terrain, but Daphne couldn’t help feeling that the girl wasn’t even trying that hard. The net effect was that out of the three, it was annoyingly the fastest who was the slowest, and thus, the one who came the closest to getting caught by the dump-truck-on-legs chasing them.

Then Ginny tripped, fell, was up again, started running, and came only inches from getting snatched up and devoured.

Idiot.

Daphne scanned the fleeing formation in frustration as they burst out of the forest and onto the open plains. She wanted to shout orders. She wanted to yell at Alex to go lead the rex away from the others. She wanted to yell at Hermione to peel off and head for the cliffs where her smaller form would hamper the rex’s movements. And she needed—needed—Ginny to stick closer to Hermione and stop playing damn chicken with the damned chicken.

But she couldn’t do any of this. She could only watch, powerless, as Luna’s animagus form somehow managed to corner all three of the animals against the very cliffs she’d wanted Hermione to take refuge around, in a closed valley with no exit.

There was a brief moment of hope when her eagle eyes spotted Harry charging at full-tilt towards the rex from behind. But that hope shattered almost as quickly as it formed. Yes, Harry leapt onto the rex’s back. Yes, he managed to scrabble up to its neck. And yes, he managed to sink his jaws in as far as he could go, snake mane snapping at everything it could. But when you added in the layers of dirty-blonde feathers down the dino’s neck and back, however far that lion bite went, wasn’t far enough. The rex bellowed in pain, turned, and slammed Harry against the cliff face.

It seemed the dinosaur had learned from the previous fight. In a deceptively swift movement for something so large, it took hold of Harry by the neck in its jaws and easily crushed the life right out of him—no penetration required. A one-tonne chimaera was a truly terrifying opponent, but against fourteen tonnes of Late Cretaceous monster, it was like a kneazle fighting a thunderbird.

Meanwhile, Alex and Ginny had made good their escape, past the epic battle and back the way they came. But Hermione, critically, hesitated. She was staring at Harry’s limp form in horror.

Daphne wanted to shout. She wanted to scream that it wasn’t real. That Harry was fine. That Hermione needed to run or it was Luna that was going to be the one in real pain.

Hermione only hesitated for a second. But a second was all it took. The rex roared in triumph, turned away from its kill, which even now was vanishing into thin air, and turned towards the only trapped prey left.

Alex and Ginny both saw the danger, but neither were in any position to help. They were too far away. The distance, too great.

The tiny unicorn stood frozen before the great predator looking down on her, turning its massive head this way and that.

It took one earth-shaking step forward and opened its jaws.

The unicorn changed.

White hair became brown.

Four legs became two.

The body and head changed into that of a teenage girl—a naked teenage girl—staring up at a Tyrannosaurus rex in wide-eyed terror. Hermione managed to raise her hands and get off three whole stunners, all of which bounced harmlessly off the rex’s skin, before massive jaws closed over her, and she screamed in pain as she was shaken, bitten in two, and swallowed.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Hermione was still shaking, although from fear of what had so recently happened or shame, she wasn’t quite sure. It certainly wasn’t from cold. All she knew was she didn’t want to look Harry in the eyes.

“How did you do that, Hermione?” Harry asked calmly. His voice was deep and rumbling, exactly what you might expect a lion king to sound like.

“I … I read your notes in your trunk, Harry. It just seemed like such a perfect opportunity. I … explored the ritual, inside the aether unpacked. I saw this as an option. I’m sorry. You said I shouldn’t, that it was too dangerous, and I did it anyway.”

They were all sat in one of the caves high above the cliffs. Harry had to crawl to fit in, but the rest of them easily managed it. They’d all met up again with Daphne’s help—even George Weasley had made it—hitching a ride in the careful jaws of his baby sister.

Hermione couldn’t bear the thought that she’d betrayed Harry’s trust. Disappointing him was her greatest fear. Even more so than getting eaten. But she’d been so sure she was ready. Harry needed her to be the greatest witch the world had ever seen.

“What you did was unbelievably dangerous, Hermione,” Harry said.

Hermione lowered her head further.

“But in this case, you rolled the dice, and won. If Luna had eaten your unicorn form, we don’t know what might have happened. And I daresay being bitten in two and swallowed was hair-raising enough of an experience. I forgive you.”

“Harry!” Hermione couldn’t stop herself. She stumbled over the space between them and wrapped her arms around his neck as best she could. This did involve quite a lot of snakes having to slither out of her way, but she didn’t care.

“Quite,” Harry said fondly. “We had a discussion not long ago that you need to disagree with me more. I’ll consider this a natural evolution of that assignment. But if you’re going to play around with the aether unpacked, then we must arrange proper supervision.” He looked towards Alex who was laying with her head on her front paws. “I suspect you will soon be ready to replicate my feat at the duelling tournament,” he declared. “Thus we should be able to hand off the dream pendant to Hermione for now.”

Alex looked up, obviously confused, and shook her head violently.

“I will test you,” Harry continued, ignoring her, “and if you are not ready, we will find another way.”

Hermione bit her lip while still hanging on tightly. She felt overjoyed at the thought of spending dream time with him—she’d never spent dream time with Harry—but also just as confused about his statement from before as Alex looked. She knew Alex’s combat prowess, and while the Black heiress was undoubtably good, she certainly wasn’t good enough to beat an entire house duelling team back-to-back. That was the stuff of legends. Literally. Only Harry had ever done it (in her mind, John didn’t count). So how did he think Alex would manage it?

From somewhere far away in the jungle world, Luna roared.

“Hermione,” Harry said, his voice now filled with purpose. “Can you teach us all the magic to turn human? I assume it doesn’t void the ritual?”

“No. And yes, I think I should be able to … but why?”

“Change of plans. There is little to be gained by hurling myself at Luna over and over until she breaks. Instead, we’ll use this as an opportunity to practise fighting together as a team against a large and dangerous enemy.”

All the girls and George perked up.

“Prepare yourselves everyone,” Harry said. “Because soon we’re going T-Rex hunting.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Feasting on a carcass of downed hadrosaur, the only Tyrannosaurus rex on the island roared her tired victory to the sky. She only managed to rip off one massive chunk though before she caught a very particular scent on the breeze.

Our friends are back!

The huge beast whined in frustration. It couldn’t understand the voice in its head—nor conceptualise what a voice even was. It wasn’t nearly intelligent enough for that. But the suggestion of meaning still filtered through. The pests had returned. Tiny prey—hardly worth the effort—but they just kept coming.

At first, the hunt was no different to any other. But these prey didn’t stay hunted. They came back. And they got better—more dangerous. If it were up to her, she’d just walk away; give the territory to these pests. But the voice …

We have to fight them. Push them. They must grow. They must become more powerful. We must all become more powerful. For Harry.

The T-Rex roared to the sky and turned, sending small tremors through the ground, to find the source of her frustration staring at her across the clearing.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

That source stood with a grin on her face, wearing simple black robes that had been cut off at the thigh, flowing red hair blowing in the breeze. Her feet were bare, toughened by charms, and in her hand she held an incredibly simple wand of yew and thestral tail hair.

Ginny Weasley could feel her blood pumping—adrenaline rushing through her system as the predator with a bite powerful enough to crush a dragon’s neck turned its full attention on her.

The T-Rex roared and charged.

“Geminio! Reducto! Confringo!” The girl’s spells shot towards the beast and harmlessly bounced off its hide. Seconds later, that huge maw opened up right above Ginny, descended, and snapped shut on a single floating leaf.

Metres away, Ginny fell to the ground, rolled, and fired off a stunner onto the rex’s flank. “One!” She jumped.

A tail weighing tonnes swiped across her path.

She landed and fired off another stunner. “Two!” She snatched up a pebble and flung it high.

The rex finished turning and lunged.

Ginny’s next switching spell connected. She appeared with a rush of air above its back, landed, and fired another stunner at point-blank range. “Three! Whoa!”

The rex shook wildly. Ginny felt her feet slip and gravity start to pull her down.

That massive head turned towards her.

Arms became forelimbs, skin became fur, legs became steel springs of coiled power.

The cheetah landed, the rex opened its steel-crushing jaw, and Ginny was off.

The chomping sound on empty air reverberated around the clearing, right before the rex let out a frustrated bellow of anger and gave chase.

In a blur, grass gave way to scrub, scrub to light forest. Now devoid of easy paths, Ginny leapt, transformed back into witch mid-air, and switched with a falling leaf high above, still flying forward at an appreciable speed for a world champion runner at full sprint, just as the foliage behind her exploded and fourteen tonnes of killing-machine crashed in behind her.

Right then, a Black chain shot out of the darkness and wrapped itself around the two trees ahead.

“I got this!” shouted a new voice.

Ginny zipped past the chain, and Alexandra, dressed much the same, gave her a thumbs-up as she flashed past.

“You ain’t got shit!” Ginny yelled back.

“It’s my turn!”

Ginny landed on a branch and turned back to watch the approaching rex. “Fine! Get eaten!”

The ankle-height chain did little to help. The rex just slowed and carefully stepped over it.

Alex now stood directly in front of the behemoth.

She raised her wand.

The rex looked down at her.

“Imperio!”

Whatever effect Alex might have been hoping for, didn’t transpire.

The rex lunged.

Alex instantly transformed into her spectral grim form right as the jaw would have closed around her. A moment later, she turned back human and shot out of the rex’s head like a champagne cork. A Black chain whipped from her wand, coiled around the nearest tree, and she whirled around it like a slingshot. The chain blinked out of existence and she flew right back at Luna. Alex impacted on her flank, shoulder-first, with a dull thud sound.

“One!” Ginny called out.

Alexandra started to fall to the ground just as the rex started to turn towards her.

“And only,” Ginny muttered.

Then, just before the Black witch hit the ground, she turned back into her spectral grim form, fell right through the ground, and seconds later, shot out at an angle right towards her. Another Black chain whipped around a branch and Alex half swung, half flew past. Ginny’s eyes went wide.

“Move!” she heard Alex shout, just as a roar from behind threatened to deafen her.

It took her four leaf-swaps to finally catch up, still zooming through the forest canopy.

“I got a point!” Alex shouted over the noise of Luna’s closing rampage.

“Good for you! I got three.”

“You just tickled her! My hit was much harder! If I’d had a spear, that would’ve been a game-changer.”

“Still only one hit.”

“And my hit was so much cooler!”

“Still only one. Anyway, Harry doesn’t want hard hits. He just wants us to practise.”

“There wasn’t any way I could practise that move and have it not be hard!”

Ginny only saw the collision moments before it was too late.

Alex slammed into one particularly unfortunately placed tree like a sack of meat hitting a brick wall. Ginny fell and caught a branch in the tree with one hand as Alex fell and caught her head on the ground with none.

“Better practise more then, because that was definitely a hard hit,” Ginny muttered.

A snort like the unclogging of a sewage-pipe made her turn. The rex was standing there, watching them.

Ginny grinned and dropped to the ground, landing lightly.

“Just like old times, huh Luna?”

The rex roared and charged.

And Ginny Weasley laughed and did likewise.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

“They’re doing well, aren’t they?” Harry said. “I’m particularly impressed with Alex. Using a side effect of her animagus spectral form for mobility was inspired.”

On top of a hill overlooking most of the island, two wizards and two witches were watching the unfolding battle between pre-teen girl and Tyrannosaurus rex in a brilliant mirror made of magical ice.

Occasionally, Daphne cast a spell at the ice-mirror to adjust the point of view of her divination magic.

Harry, Daphne, and Hermione sat at a conjured tea table, sitting in conjured chairs, sipping from cups of bark-sap tea, served in conjured porcelain ware. Empty plates were much in evidence, and although it was considered terrible manners not to polish off anything put in front of you, a skilled forensics expert would still be able to detect the remains of nuts, fruits, seeds, root and leafy vegetables, and of course, fish. Lots and lots of fish.

George Weasley stood up from where he’d been tending a smokeless fire with a very basic yew and unicorn hair wand. “Anyone going to be wanting seconds?”

Harry craned his neck away from the mirror. “That probably isn’t going to be needed, but thank you. Are you sure you don’t want a good crack at Luna?”

George put up both his hands. “Noooo thank you. I think Fred and I will stick to inventing stuff. Let me do the fishing and cooking and we’re all good. We’ll leave the fighting to our baby sister.” He glanced at the mirror where Ginny was still going toe-to-toe with the rex, shook his head in disbelief, and turned back to the fire.

Harry nodded. “As you wish.”

“I just wish my form was more useful in combat,” Hermione said.

“Hermione, your form is very useful in combat,” Harry replied. “Maybe not against a non-sapient magical creature, but against anything that can think and strategise? You have a practical get-out-of-Azkaban-free card.”

“How so?”

“No one can attack you with intent to harm while you’re in unicorn form. That gives you a really good stalling option. Good stalling options let you regain your magic and form the backbone of any late-game combat strategy.”

“But people don’t know about that, do they?”

“We’ll bloody well make sure they do know. Which means once you’re out of magic, all you need to do is go unicorn, run away—which unicorns are really good at—regen, then return when you’re back at full strength. That’s one of the main advantages of having an animagus form in combat. Your magic continues to refill while you’re in form, and the amount of magic the transformation takes is almost nothing.”

“Harry and Luna have a double advantage there,” Daphne interjected. “They’re also very large animals, which makes them very difficult to cast direct spells on. And Harry is also physically resistant to piercing attacks. I can fly out of range of most spells. And Alex can pass through physical obstacles like walls, which is a really good stalling tactic.” She put her teacup down with a small clink. “All in all, we did very well with all our forms. We should be extremely grateful.”

Behind them, George Weasley made a polite coughing sound.

Daphne flicked her hair. “Yes, well we can’t all be amazing, Weasley.”

“Just wait until an evil wizard attacks next to an icy pond. My day will come!”

Daphne smirked. “Speaking of evil wizards, how about it, Harry? What do you think your chances are now against the Dark or Light lords?”

Harry chuckled. “Voldemort and Dumbledore have many more tricks up their sleeves. That said, I’m a lot more confident than before.”

George Weasley looked over his shoulder again and raised a quizzical eyebrow.

Daphne smirked.

Back in the magical ice-mirror, Alexandra had finally gotten back to her feet, if rather groggily, and looked ready to charge in again.

“Is that why you’re so confident in Alex doing well in the tournament?” Daphne asked. “Because of the magic regen advantage of the animagus form? Can you even use an animagus form in the tournament?”

Harry smiled. “I don’t know if Alex can win the tournament. But she’s a girl who will push all the harder if there’s a high wall to get over. And failure only makes her push even harder. I’m not actually sure if the animagus form is allowed. It wasn’t in Riddle’s time.”

“It is allowed,” Hermione declared.

Harry and Daphne turned to look at her.

“I memorised the rules last year before Harry’s debut. The form normally isn’t allowed in class A standard rules, but they made an exception for the Hogwarts tournament back in the 1970s along with family magics.”

“Mmmm …” Harry steepled his fingers. “If that’s the case, I’m not going to rule out a 7–0 victory as actually impossible.”

“But does she have the raw power to go against a seventh year?” Hermione asked.

“Alexandra is a very powerful witch, but in a straight battle of power? No. Not a chance. But it’s not necessarily about power. Daphne, who’s on the Hufflepuff duelling team this year?”

Daphne quickly went through the seeds for each year.

Harry frowned. “It’s not actually the seventh year who’s the problem. It’s that fifth year. I remember him. I think he could have taken a sixth-year last year and he’ll have only gotten better since then.”

“Do you want me to try and persuade him to drop out?” Daphne asked. “His father works for the Department for the Regulation and Control of Magical Creatures, and Luna’s parents have a lot of influence there.”

Harry thought about it while they continued to watch the mirror. “No, I don’t think we need to do that,” he eventually said. “But see if your spies in Hufflepuff can get any memories of their training sessions. Alex will need every advantage she can get against him.”

The rex in the mirror roared—not that the watchers could hear. It chased after Ginny in her cheetah form across a grassy plain, while Alex was roughly dragged behind with a Black chain wrapped around its ankle.

“Every advantage,” Harry reiterated.

“You know, it really was lucky that we were able to make wands here,” Daphne said.

Hermione shifted uncomfortably. “I just hope the tail hair grows back.”

“I’m sure it will,” Harry said. “And we’re still not technically in the outside world, so I doubt physical effects on our forms here will transfer over. I’m more impressed that everyone had workable compatibility with a wand made from at least one of us. And quite flattered, too.”

Daphne looked at her own basic unicorn hair wand with a torn expression.

“Yeah, we’ll definitely have to think about wands in this ritual,” Harry continued. “Even ones more rudimentary than these. They’re really useful.”

Hermione looked puzzled. “Why?”

“Your students, next year, Hermione. This could be a golden opportunity for them.”

“And for us,” Daphne added. “The wise general trains his men and officers highly, and does not declare war until he is assured of victory.”

“What’s that from?” Hermione asked.

Daphne smiled. “Sun Tzu’s The Art of War. I read it over the Winter Festival.”

Hermione frowned, although more in doubt than anything else. “Somehow, I can’t see girls like Sophie Roper fighting in a war. But if they’re going to repeat the ritual, I can absolutely see why having wands is a good idea.”

“I suspect Daphne is considering war as an analogue for our current political games more than anything else,” Harry said. “Though war is obviously still a possibility—one we’d like to avoid if possible.”

Daphne smiled again. “Supreme excellence in war consists in breaking the enemy’s resistance without fighting.”

“A wise sentiment.”

There was another silent roar from the mirror, although the action had moved quite far away now.

“Daphne, could you adjust again?” Harry asked.

Daphne cast the remote viewing spell at the ice-mirror again several times, jumping the view forward a corresponding number of jumps.

“It’s really impressive that you can do that, did you know?” Hermione said. “The ice-mirror, I mean, not the divination, although that’s impressive, too. I’ve tried that ice-mirror spell myself several times and I can never get it to work. It’s a very high-level elemental spell.”

“Thank you.” Daphne looked slightly embarrassed, but still pleased, while in said mirror, it was now Alex’s turn to run away from the rex in grim form while Ginny ran behind taking potshots with stunners.

“It’s a good point, actually,” Harry said. “Daphne, you haven’t by any chance ever manifested ice around yourself, have you? Wandlessly? During a time of intense emotion or stress, perhaps?”

Daphne frowned. “No, I don’t think so.”

“Yes!” Hermione blurted out.

The other two looked at her.

“In first year! When Daphne stood up for me against Snape, you remember? You had ice crystals all over your hands and robes. We had to pry your fingers off the back of the chair with a quill because we didn’t know the warming charm yet, and we had to dry your robes in the common room, because the drying magic didn’t work. You said you were extremely disappointed in the rune work on the robes.”

Daphne frowned again. “Oh, yes. I remember that.”

Harry smiled. “That’s something we’re going to have to look into.”

“So!” came the voice of George Weasley from behind them.

The three of them turned.

“If not food seconds, are we still going to be sleeping overnight? Because we’ll have to get some proper shelters set up if that’s the case.”

Harry looked up at the sky. “No, you’re right. It is getting on. I’ve finished setting up a split-personality in my mindscape, which should let me transfer a message between hunts more reliably than relying on the chimaera. That’s really all we’ve been waiting around for. Hopefully we haven’t already hunted Hermione, but we don’t appear to be cursed, so probably not. Unless the curse doesn’t actually work that way, in which case, no worries. But better safe than sorry.” He stood up.

“Good luck, Harry,” said Hermione and Daphne in unison.

He thanked them, waved, and made his way slowly back down the hill. As he went, he allowed himself to enjoy the feeling of the air on his face and the sun on his hair. He wasn’t in a rush. He arrived at the bottom of the hill and wandered down through a small glen. He slipped his wand out of the pocket of his basic robes and idly practised spell motions as he walked. Eventually, he started changing into his chimaera form, just to practise switching between the two with no loss of combat readiness.

Growling and hissing chimaera became wand-waving wizard and back again. And again. And again.

He saw many other dinosaurs on his leisurely walk through the woods. A small herd of four-legged herbivores with armour plating on their backs shuffled across his path at one point, and a larger pack of vicious-looking, two-legged predators with claws on their feet the size of daggers eyed-up his human form for a few moments with an intelligence Harry would normally only associate with magical creatures, before they apparently decided to think better of trying to make a meal of him.

Wise decision.

At one point, Harry took a moment to sit down on a rock and dangle his feet in the stream’s water. It went gurgle around his toes.

Soon though, he reached the grassy plain that had seen so much action since the hours of sun-rise.

The rex was there, now facing off against both Alex and Ginny in their cheetah and grim forms, respectively. The rex clearly felt something change in the air though. It slowly turned its massive head at his approach.

Ginny and Alex perked up their ears and tracked him as well.

“It’s okay!” he called out. “I’ll take it from here.”

Both girls retreated.

The rex swung its massive weight around to face him fully, shaking the ground with its step.

Harry smiled. Both his and Luna’s forms were truly formidable. But it wasn’t the forms that mattered, not really. It was how those forms were used together with the wizard, constantly switching between them at will, that mattered. In chimaera vs. T-Rex there was never any question about who the victor would be, but like this? There still wasn’t any question.

A breeze picked up and blew Harry’s messy hair out of his face.

Seconds later, that breeze became a wind, then a gale, then a storm. Lightning crashed overhead.

The rex roared and charged.

And Harry summoned his magic.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Deep below Hogwarts, Luna Lovegood bolted upright in her pot, gasping and panting, hands instinctively patting herself down—legs, arms, chest, breasts, head, neck, throat—yep, all there.

“Wow. That was intense.” She giggled. “I really love it when Harry is like that.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

“How is Mister Granger—” Plato asked, popping into the room. “—being?” he finished, eyes going wide—wider than usual, that is.

Emma and Clare looked up from opposite sides of the bed Dan lay on, their own eyes a picture of barely restrained panic.

Daniel Granger had a powerful orange aura floating around where he slept.

“Do you recognise it, Plato?” Emma asked, frantically. “It turned up only a few minutes ago. He’s fine. We can both still touch him. It doesn’t seem to do anything. But it can’t be normal.”

Plato firmly shook his head. “Plato is not knowing what this is.” He reached over and cast a diagnosis spell. “Maybe Plato should be—”

The aura faded. Just like that. One moment, the head of house Granger lay in his own little sun, the next, nothing.

Emma and Clare stood stock still.

Plato frowned. “That was being weird.”

There was a cough.

“Dan!” Emma flung her arms around her husband.

“Emma?” Dan coughed. “What’s going on? What day is it?”

Emma kissed him. “Still the same day as before. What do you last remember?”

“Climbing onto the roof in a storm.” He coughed again. “I’ll not be doing that again too quickly. Are you sure it’s the same day? Looks very peaceful outside.”

“The storm cleared up—almost instantly.”

“Well, I guess it was magical. Urgh, my clothes are filthy.”

“Oh!” Clare stood up. “I have a spell for this. One moment. I’ve been looking for an excuse to try this one.” She left, followed shortly after by Plato. It wasn’t easy to tell through the wall, but it seemed like an argument of some kind was starting.

“So, I fell off the roof?” Dan eventually asked.

“Yeah, it was so scary. But Plato caught you. Then this aura randomly came out of nowhere and covered you all over.”

“An aura? Really?” Dan gave a weak smile. “Are we taking more Star Trek force field or Dragon Ball?”

“More Dragon Ball.”

Dan’s smile grew slightly. “Maybe I got superpowers. Hey, maybe I’m a wizard now.”

Emma chuckled. “I’m sure Plato would be able to tell.” She walked to the door. “But we should check anyway.”

A few minutes later, Dan was happily eating a chocolate frog. It fell from the packet completely inanimate. Which meant he wasn’t a wizard. He didn’t care. It was a good chocolate frog.

Emma still didn’t look happy.

“What’s wrong?” he asked, mouth still full of chocolate.

“We lost the ghost gem. When the lightning bolt hit it, it vanished.”

Dan swallowed, hard. “Oh.” He looked out the window to where the newly completed Slytherin Manor could just be seen at the top of the hill, through all the island greenery. “You know, I don’t think we’ve ever been in a situation where Lord Slytherin … Harry … has ever had a reason to be disappointed or angry with us.”

“We swore when we entered the wizarding world that we would do everything in our power to be the best vassals we could be,” Emma said. “When you are helpless, being useful is the best defence.”

Dan groaned. “I’m not looking forward to this.”

“No, me neither. Harry already told the goblins, too.”

Suddenly the door opened again and Clare walked back in. “I’ve found the spell, and Plato here has agreed that as I am a student, he doesn’t have to break my knee-caps for the house-elf menial labour union.” She looked down at the elf. “That was a joke, I hope.”

Plato smiled politely back up at her.

Clare opened the book and carefully practised the wand movements and incantation required for one of the many cleaning charms aimed at household items—clothes, in this instance. Unfortunately, for the second-year student in her twenties, it seemed an incredibly finicky piece of magic to make work. Half an hour later, she was practically tearing her hair out in frustration. “I just don’t get it,” she said. “I mean, I don’t always master a spell this quickly, but I always get some result! Even if it’s only a stray spark.”

She kept trying, but for whatever reason, luck just didn’t seem to be on her side. By this time, Plato had brought in tea and biscuits and everyone was having themselves a cuppa.

“Clare,” Dan said, voice wheedling. “I know you want to practise outside of school, but maybe we can just let Plato do this one now. If you want to practise you can just throw some mud on your old robes, right? I’d rather like to get clean.”

Clare’s head dropped. “You’re right. Of course. I’m sorry. Go ahead, Plato.”

Plato smiled and snapped his fingers.

And nothing happened.

He frowned and snapped his fingers again.

Nothing.

He looked towards the tea tray on the dresser, snapped his fingers, and levitated the complete set from one side of the room to the other. Then he looked towards Mister Granger again and snapped his fingers, again. And nothing happened.

Emma slowly put her own teacup down with an, ‘Oh, my god,’ look on her face.

Plato, now frowning heavily, walked towards Dan, and held his hand up, palm ahead.

Dan, looking extremely uncertain raised his own hand, and together they slowly brought their palms together.

The house-elf squeaked and franticly drew his hand back when everything from the elbow down rapidly started to fade. It quickly solidified again, but he backed away sharply, nonetheless.

Clare was watching the proceedings with her mouth open.

“My Head of House Ring,” Dan said. He was still holding up his hand. “It’s gone.”

Emma suddenly realised that there was something on her finger that normally wouldn’t be there either, and on closer inspection, yes, it was the Granger Head of House Ring. “That shouldn’t happen unless you’re dead,” she whispered.

“Or magic doesn’t work on you,” Clare added.

Dan’s look of worry slowly turned to one of extreme bemusement. “I’m a blank, Emma.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

When Harry next regained consciousness, the forest surrounding him was clearly not the work of man or nature. Everywhere he looked, light sparkled and bounced off the leaves and foliage. The smell of dirt smelled more dirt-like. Crystal-clear waterfalls seemed to gurgle away behind every turn and despite dozens of streams and ponds dotting the vista, not once did mud threaten his conjured robes.

It was like standing in the middle of a breezy, sweet-smelling emerald. Fairies flitted from tree to tree.

Luckily, the moment he woke up, a message left for him, by him, had informed him of what happened in the previous hunt and advised him accordingly, along with a few other key pieces of information. He still couldn’t remember the last hunt, but that was irrelevant. That would all get sorted once the ritual was over. Right now, he had a job to do—making sure they all got out of this without suffering a unicorn’s curse.

Finding the others hadn’t been hard, thankfully. Teaching them how to turn human had taken some time, but now that they’d gotten that out of the way, they could focus in on the problem immediately before them.

“Hermione,” Harry called out softly.

On the other side of the glen, the Shetland unicorn lifted her head from where she’d been drinking from a pond with three separate rainbows curving out of it.

“Is this really the realm of the fae?” Ginny asked nervously. As last to be found, she still wasn’t fully caught up.

“We’re pretty sure it’s just the ritual’s version,” Luna said, not sounding anything like her normal dreamy self. “But if you do see any of the Wild Hunt, don’t hesitate to kill first and ask questions only once everyone else is dead.”

“It’s okay, Hermione,” Harry said. He sat down cross-legged on the floor and beckoned her over.

The unicorn didn’t budge. She stared at them all with clearly nervous energy.

“Oh, for Merlin’s sake. Back up, George.”

“Backing up.” The male Weasley retreated behind one of the picture-perfect trees.

That seemed to do the trick. The short, stocky unicorn walked over and let Harry pet her head.

All the girls turned to look behind them with various states of scandal.

“George!” Ginny said with her mouth hanging open. “When? Who?!”

“That’s my business, baby sister.”

Daphne walked forward. “Now what?” she asked, moving to sit beside Harry to take a turn in stroking the unicorn’s ridiculously long hair.

“Now we have to face the reality of the situation. We only really have two options—go ahead with the hunt and risk getting cursed for the rest of our lives, or let the ritual just keep going on until it eventually runs out of magic. The first option risks the curse, the second option risks being here for a long time, and possibly Hermione not fully getting her form once it’s over.”

Everyone just continued to stare at him.

Harry sighed. “We’re staying put. We’ll take the opportunity to do more training. We don’t age in here, so it’s almost like free life.”

It was like a weight had been lifted.

“That’s it then?” Ginny said. “Camping trip in the land of the fairies? How long for?”

Harry shook his head. “Could be days, months, years, decades even. Although I hope it won’t be quite that long.”

Hermione the unicorn neighed and pranced away back to the pond.

There was silence for a moment. It was a lot to digest.

“I’m going to master switching combat,” Ginny declared.

There was another pause.

“Then I’m going to practise more of my family magic and master chain combat,” Alex said.

Luna clapped. “And I’m going to master RAWR combat.”

“Can you conjure me some parchment?” George asked. “I want to work on artefacts.”

“And teach me ice magic,” Daphne added. “It would be a shame to waste such an opportunity.”

“Sure.” Harry stood up and brushed himself off. “Let’s find ourselves a good place to get settled. It could well be a long haul.”

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

Sometimes, rituals go very wrong. And sometimes rituals go very right. It is rarely wise to play with new rituals. Even the most well-prepared and talented wizards can find themselves in situations they did not anticipate, because of some tiny quirk of magic.

Like living in an enchanted forest, because you don’t want to kill your friend and suffer a curse, for over four hundred days—430 days, to be exact.

Harry relaxed outside the wooden cabin he’d built for himself—one of six that now stood on the top of a small hill, overlooking a large emerald-green field of perfect grass in the middle of the emerald forest. The grass was always perfect. And it didn’t matter how many times it was burned away, frozen, crushed, dug up, or otherwise destroyed by the dogged practice of a small group of young witches and wizards, happily trying to kill each other, it always grew back to perfection overnight.

The first few months were the hardest. George Weasley wasn’t too happy about being separated from his twin for so long, Daphne missed her parents and little sister, Astoria, and Ginny couldn’t help feel that some indefinable piece of her was somehow missing. Even Alex had been quieter than usual during that time.

Slowly though, the isolation from their normal lives became the new norm, and they all began to make rapid and real progress towards their goals.

Harry taught Daphne all the ice magic he knew, which wasn’t actually much, but she’d made good use of it.

George’s cabin was piled high with stacks upon stacks of conjured parchment, and he spent as much of his time memorising everything he drew as he did the actual drawing.

Alexandra was now a monster with her Black chains, combining them with several other family magics, and her animagus form. Harry was pretty sure she stood a very real chance of actually replicating his feat at the duelling tournament now. The main problem first years faced against seventh years, was a seventh year could simply outlast them. But Alex could now just go grim, dive under the ground, and wait for her magic to return. Take away that limitation, and it was all skill. And with an extra fourteen months of solid training, she had plenty of that. She could now even occasionally beat Ginny in a straight one-on-one duel—something Ginny detested.

The moment she’d lost her first duel to the Black heiress, Ginny marched over to him and demanded new magic.

Harry had been only too happy to oblige. Being a one-trick pony wasn’t good—even if that one trick had by now been honed down to a razor’s edge.

Still not good enough to take on Luna though. Not even Ginny, Alex, and Daphne combined could take on Luna.

The ability to shift instantly between thirty-five-kilogram witch and fourteen-tonne Tyrannosaurus rex was a monstrous combination. Predicting her reach was very difficult. No matter at long, medium, or short range, there was always something very scary to worry about. And Luna’s combat inventiveness was second to none. Some of the tricks she’d pull out of her hat. … Well, Harry never regretted that time, years ago, when he’d deliberately set out to bind themselves together.

And he himself had not been idle.

Carefully, Harry flexed his fingers and summoned his magics. The dirt under the surrounding ground started to vibrate, and thousands of tiny particles of sand slowly filtered away from the general loamy soil. When there was enough of them, they started to melt, becoming floating blobs of red-hot heat. Minutes later, he’d split the blob up, levitated the orbs to five points around himself, and formed a pentagram of glass ward-stones, intricate runes engraved perfectly into the silky smooth faces. Such was but one of the many tricks he’d mastered in the last year and a bit.

Harry sighed and closed his eyes, letting the forever perfect breeze cross his face.

He could feel the magic slowly seeping out of the animagus ritual—had felt it for a few days now. There wasn’t long left. That it had lasted this long was close to a miracle. That it didn’t last forever was a blessing from Merlin. The only unfortunate side effect was it was looking more and more likely that Hermione wasn’t going to immediately get her animagus form.

A new presence appeared. Harry opened his eyes.

George Weasley sat down next to him and gazed down at the field below the cabins where Alex was attempting to tie Ginny around Luna-Rex’s flank with her chains in what looked like a battle-royal free for all.

“So, it’s coming to an end. It feels like it’s only been a few weeks,” George commented.

Harry nodded. “In the outside world, it will barely have been an hour.”

“Yeah, weird that. But I don’t feel a year older.”

“You’re not.”

George Weasley idly played with a strand of grass. “You’re Lord Slytherin.”

If any outsider had to guess by Harry’s external reaction, they would have to conclude that the Weasley twin had just posited no more extraordinary a statement as the sky being blue or Luna liking pudding. Harry continued to watch the duel slightly down the hill. “I was wondering if you would ask me about that before or after you told Fred.”

George snorted. “How are you Lord Slytherin?”

“Slytherin Family Secret.”

“Technically, you are Lord Slytherin.”

“Indeed. And technically as Lord Slytherin I technically declared that to be a Slytherin Family Secret. What kind of Lord would I be if I made laws that I didn’t follow myself?”

“An unusual one, from what I’ve heard. So …” George flicked the blade of grass away. “These girls, who happen to include my baby sister. They’re what? Your bodyguard? Your harem?”

“Did your father tell you he is putting together the parchment-work for a contract between us?”

“You’re not really my type, Harry.”

Harry smirked.

“No, I didn’t,” George admitted. “I assume Ginny knows.”

“She does.”

“And she is happy with it.”

“Yes, although getting the signature from my father will be difficult. I have many enemies. It is important that everyone who stands by my side can defend themselves. What are these girls? Let’s call them my inner circle.”

“Like he-who-must-not-be-named?”

“Yes, exactly like him.”

“Why only witches?” George asked. He grinned and waggled his eyebrows. “Apart from the obvious, my sister aside. There must be wizards our age who you could train to fight just as well.”

Harry thought about really was a fair question. “Everyone who ever plotted against me in the magical world was a wizard,” he eventually said. “And witches have far less power than their muggle counterparts do. They also have more to gain. Maybe I just saw it as safer this way. Although that need for safety also suggests cowardice.”

“Sounds like you need some male friends.”

Harry gave George a wry smile. “You think you could keep up with being my friend? You think you can compete with that?” He gestured downhill to where Luna-Rex was fighting Alex, Ginny, and Daphne at the same time, and still winning.

George smirked. “Not a chance. But I don’t have to. I’m an artificer and prankster, not a duellist. So long as I can out-craft you, it should be you who has to worry about keeping up with me.”

Harry chuckled. “Fair enough.”

Just then, the ground trembled—far stronger than would have been the case if, say, Luna had tripped and fallen.

“It’s time!” Harry shouted.

Daphne, Alex, Ginny, and Luna immediately stopped what they were doing and hurried over.

It started in the mountains—the massive peaks fading away until they were nothing.

Next came the forests, following their rocky backdrops into the void.

Hermione trotted over to Harry and softly nudged him with the side of her head.

“It’s alright, girl,” Harry muttered, patting her mane.

The nearest trees faded, the grasses faded, the cabins, the sky, and then the world was nothing but white.

And after many hundreds of days—or, in the case of some of them, years—seven hunts, six kills, and countless deaths, the animagus ritual ended.

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

And in an old study, halfway across the country, another ritual, of sorts, had also come to an end …

Lord Potter bristled. “No, I will not accept these terms.”

“Take them or leave them, James.”

“Fine, I’ll leave them. Good day to you.” Lord Potter stood up suddenly, turned to go, and stormed out, leaving Lucius staring at a shut door with a small confident smile on his face.

… coming to an end, at least for now

—DP&SW: NRiCaD —

And in the Chamber of Secrets, Harry, George, and the girls had just finished climbing out of the pots and getting dressed. Every speck of phoenix ash on the floor, and every grain piled up in the pensieve, was gone.

“It feels like it’s been a lifetime,” Daphne whispered into the cold air of the Chamber.

“Several,” Luna said. “C’mon! If we’re quick, we can be up in time for dinner.”

“How does it feel, Hermione?” Harry asked, catching her arm as she stumbled out of the circle.

“Strange,” Hermione answered. “It’s like, I can feel my unicorn form, but it’s not quite there. I can’t use it.”

Harry nodded solemnly. “None of us have that problem. We’ll have to work on that together.”

Hermione smiled. “I can feel your form though.”

“I think all of us can,” Alex said. “It’s like this dominant aura of power.”

“Majestic,” Ginny chirped.

“Royal,” Daphne said. “Like a king. Lion, snake, and thestral.”

“Yep,” Luna said, happily. “Fast now! Dinner! Chop chop!”

They left the Chamber via broomstick, flying up the pipework to exit in the Slytherin girls’ dormitory—quite a memorable experience for one George Weasley.

Only Harry felt the crack in the Chamber’s early warning ward system as they made their way back through the castle—a little bell ringing in his head like a fire alarm.

But by then he was already outside—too late to do anything but urgently double lock and strengthen the seals on every entrance he knew—not from someone getting in, but from something getting out.

Deep down below, one of the metal bars keeping the mouth of Salazar Slytherin’s statue shut gave way under some immense strain. It fell to the ground and clanged loudly, sending echoes bouncing around the cavernous space. Then seconds later, another bar fell. Then a third, and a fourth. Moments later, every bar had fallen, and a hissing voice from within the statue said,§Open.§

Stone ground against stone, Slytherin’s mouth opened wide, and the king of serpents slithered out into the fresher air of the Chamber.

It looked around, blinked, narrowed its eyes, and hissed, §Only one true king.§

—End of Chapter Fifty-Seven

Chapter End Notes

A/N: It’s been a while! I hope you’re all keeping well and healthy. My apologies for the long period between releases, but as you can see, this one turned out to be extra, extra long—the longest chapter in the entire series so far, in fact.

I hope you enjoyed it and that the wait was worth while.

In other news, the last website launch for DPaSW was a disaster (a slow and buggy mess) and I’m currently working on a new one. It will be up soon and will also host a whole lot of deleted scenes, selected from requests by readers on discord.

A/N: This chapter was drafted and made available early through the LeadVonE discord server, as will the next one. If you fancy discussing this chapter with like-minded people, or anything else DPaSW, feel free to head over there.

A special thank you to the following people for helping catch mistakes on #dpasw-editorial and during the live editing streams:

Alethiphile, Arval, Arya_kshitiz, ASK, Caelwyn, ChRiAn, ciago, cibirochka, ChucktheElf, Damon, deranext, ddr, dragon bait, drsubnautica, feauxen, Fionan254, Flaming-Jaguar, Flashensammler, Flocker646, Gloweye, JaydenStevenson, leeginn, Leyrann, logan231, LordMelvin, Lunatico, MageKing17, Magic Bird Dust, NicholasSteele, Oliver W.K. Twist, PGFuuryuu, Pixie, Rafilar, Rocketeer Gloddy, Salty_Sauce, sfu, Skih, steamdriventurkishstateopera, StormyAngel, Tendra, TNT, topoiso, TrendyTreky, and VanWilder!

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—a little less than half of 2020’s prices.

Reuniting

The Great Hall thrummed with activity. The storm had passed and the sky overhead showed the cloudless night sky, speckled with stars.

Fred Weasley scanned the entrances again for what felt like the hundredth time. Something had gone wrong, he was sure of it. The animagus ritual was only supposed to last a few minutes. For George to be gone this long…

A presence appeared by his shoulder. “Where’s your twin?” Katie asked with a smile. “Off executing some dastardly scheme, maybe?”

Fred buried his worries deep inside and flashed the younger witch a brilliant smile. “Not even going to guess a name, Katie?”

Katie stuck her tongue out. “I can always tell the difference, Fred. George told me how.”

“Oof.”

 “And you didn’t answer my question.”

“That’s for me to know and you to find out.”

“Just so long as I don’t find out by being the target.”

“Katie you wound me. Would I ever?—“ He stopped mid innocent proclamation when he spotted Hermione Granger enter the Great Hall from the door that led down to the dungeons. “Excuse me,” he said, standing up.

Katie followed his gaze. “Dealings with the Slytherins?” She smirked. “Best watch your step around them. You know how slippery they can be.”

Fred ignored her and marched towards the door. He passed right by Granger without even a second glance. He almost collided with Lovegood and Black in the archway.

“Watch where you’re treading, you lanky oaf,” Alex growled.

Fred ignored her too.

What he didn’t ignore though, was the final figure in the pack, out in the main hall way. “Ginny!” Fred skidded to a halt in front of his baby sister. “You’re alright. Where’s George?”

Ginny looked up at him with an impish grin. “What’s this? Big brother Fredrick is worried?”

“Of course I’m worried!”

Ginny’s grin didn’t fade. “He said he’d be waiting for you in that place. He said you’d know what place he meant.”

Fred took off at a sprint.

“No running in the castle!” Filch screeched as he passed an intersection.

Fred ignored that man as well.

“I say!” said the scandalised portrait of a knight as he vaulted over a banister and took the next stairs three at a time.

Fred climbed higher and higher.

At one point he met Daphne Greengrass going the other way.

“Worry not!” the ice princess called out behind him, voice already fading through the walls as he took turn after turn in the maze that was Hogwarts. “I already sorted out his problem!”

Problem!?

Fred ducked into his third secret passageway, ran up the corridor, and pushed through a tapestry of a niffler eating sprinkles.

He knew he was overreacting. He knew that whatever might have happened, it can’t have been that bad. Not if Ginny wasn’t worried. But that didn’t mean he wasn’t anxious. He and George had been practically joined at the hip since birth. They did almost everything together. This was only the second time they hadn’t, and then only because witches were apparently funny about that sort of thing.

In the corridor where the Hogwarts students had set up their own little black market, hidden away from even Filtch, Fred skidded to a halt in front of a single large trunk. Quickly, he opened the lid and climbed down into the depths. There, in the middle of the trunk, stood three smaller trunks, each one just large enough to fit through the first trunk’s opening. Fred picked the middle one and threw open the lid.

A rush of ice cold air hit him in the face.

The reason for this became apparent the moment he stuck his head inside. Ice covered the walls, stairs, and floors — the stools and the benches.

“George?” Fred asked. He couldn’t see his brother anywhere.

He was halfway down the stairs when he heard a small clinking sound above. Too late, he turned his head upwards and saw the bucket tipping over.

“GAHHH!”

Freezing water splashed over him as the bucket clanged away down the stairs.

A loud pleased-sounding chirping filled the air. Then a small black and white bird hopped off a ledge above, landed on its belly on the stairs beside Fred, and slid down a thin icy slide. It slid to the bottom of the trunk, hit a ramp, and started to spin, all the while making those triumphant chirping sounds.

“You—!”

The rockhopper penguin slowly spun to a stop. When it fully stopped, it shifted back into George. “Fred!” his brother beamed. “So good of you to join me. I hop you’re not feeling too cold.”

Fred grinned, even as he began to shiver. “I’ll let that one slide.”

“HAH!” George whipped his wand out of his robes, aimed it at him, and started casting drying and warming charms.

“Thanks,” Fred said as the spells started to really work their magic. “I’m glad nothing went too—“ He stopped in shock as George closed the distance and grabbed him in a hug tighter than any he could remember. “—wrong? George? Are you okay?”

George was fighting back tears. “Brother,” he said. “I’m so happy to see you. You’ve no idea.”

“What happened?”

“Eighteen months happened.”

Fred leaned back to look at his brother in shock. “Eighteen months?”

George nodded.

Fred let out a long breathe and his breath misted in the air. Something had gone wrong. At least the consequences didn’t sound too dire. He gestured back to the trunk entrance, to where their workshop trunk lay. To where they both could brew mugs of hot chocolate and relax on the sofa. “Tell me all about it.”

And over the next several hours, George did.

—End of Bonus Chapter—

Nature Red — Part 2

The Wizengamot all stared — some in horror, others in triumph, and a few in total knee-knocking terror.

Standing before them all, Lord Voldemort calmly drew his wand, a slight smile playing across his face, while outside the hall, muffled screams and pleading could be heard through the doors.

Do you see, Harry? Voldemort thought. Now that I have the Wizengamot, I can effortlessly arrange who should occupy which positions in the wardrobe. And it wasn’t difficult — merely tedious. Own the right people — a bit of torture here, a few death threats there — and the world is yours. Oh, the public will elect their minister, of course, but with our total control of all three candidates, that is a mere formality. Look, Harry, you can see they all know it. You can see it in their eyes.

A fresh set of muffled screaming passed through the locked doors. In the front row, Lord Greengrass’ knuckles were white where he sat beside Lord Slughorn.

And once we control the minister, we can begin work on the princes of Europe, Harry. A third Magical Empire will rise, and the muggle filth will be routed from this world… routed from my world!

A loud crash on the locked door was followed moments later by a shrill scream of anguish and despair.

Harry’s eyes snapped open.

The Wizengamot chamber vanished.

A wave of dread flowed over him, but it was muted and not quite real.

He stared unblinking at the inside of his Azkaban prison cell and noted the angle of sunlight through the window bars.

Ah. Morning. Time to get up.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Harry’s eyes snapped open.

A few inches from his face, hovered a slightly see-through face that was one massive grin.

“Time to get up! Pottery Pottery Potter! Hard it was for Peeves to find Pottery this time. All night Peeves had to look! How did Pottery get up here? Peeves wonders. Oh, yes, Peeves wonders hard.”

“You can go on wondering,” Harry said calmly, sitting up on the roof beam he’d been sleeping on. Far below in the Hogwarts entrance hall, just outside the Great Hall, the first sleepy-eyed students were making their way to breakfast.

“Peeves must tell Professor Lily he has found her missing son! Yes, Peeves must do this.” That grin, if possible, got even larger.

“Again?”

The grin faded slightly. “Pottery no fun! Peeves works hard to play with Pottery. Peeves sets up splendid traps. Peeves sniffs hard for Pottery’s secrets, but Pottery doesn’t fall for anything! Ever! No fun!”

Harry smirked slightly. “My apologies for being such a disappointment. Are you sure you won’t spy for me?”

Peeves stuck out a massive tongue at him, did a loop in the air and zoomed away, screaming, “Found Pottery! Peeves has found Pottery!”

Harry chuckled, shrunk his bedding with a wave of his wand, swung his legs around so they dangled off the beam, and jumped off.

There were gasps and a shriek.

He landed heavily on the stone floor below, but not quite as heavily as might be expected from a drop that high.

He then bowed slightly to the group of shocked girls that had just rounded the corner from Ravenclaw tower, turned, and entered the Great Hall for breakfast.

All eyes were on him as he spread jam on his toast and helped himself to bacon and eggs.

“I can’t believe you’re getting away with this,” said Blaise Zabini on the other side of the table. “You’ve got balls the size of planets. I would have thought that today of all days.”

“It’s an important day,” Harry said cheerfully. “As Lord Slytherin’s protégé, it is important I be seen.”

“Important he is seen,” muttered an older Slytherin. “If it were me, I’d be holed up in whatever hiding place I’d found to sleep in.”

“And that’s why you’re not Lord Slytherin’s protégé, Roberts,” said Daphne, gracefully lowering herself into the chair at the head of the table. “Let’s discuss our plans for today’s events.”

“POTTER!”

“Whoops.” Harry quickly stood up, full plate in hand. “That’s my cue.”

Snape had entered from the door near the teachers’ table and was now striding towards where he stood, robes billowing, wand in hand.

Harry casually swatted away a stunner fired from the defence professor’s wand. Climbing over the bench, he managed not to spill his breakfast while fending off the various spells sent his way. Everyone stared as he backed away towards the massive double doors and nodded to a pair of gobsmacked Gryffindors, who chose that moment to enter the hall, just as he exited.

Really, the situation with Snape was interesting. When he’d first returned to Hogwarts, the man had tried his hardest to actually capture him, but now just seemed to be going through the motions — as though merely fulfilling an administrative obligation.

It was amazing how quickly, ‘Harry Potter gets chased by some of the teachers’ had become a new normal at Hogwarts. Just another example of general oddness, like the ghost teacher, or the Weasley twins’ pranks, or the moving staircases.

Although the moving staircases were remnants from a time when the castle had been used as a prison, so fair enough.

Finishing off the last sausage, Harry ducked into an empty classroom and waited for the visitors he knew he’d be receiving.

He didn’t have that long to wait, considering.

Soon, Daphne, Tracey, Hermione, and Blaise all wandered in, Blaise dabbing at the edges of his mouth with a handkerchief.

It was February, and for the last few weeks, the castle had been in a fervour as it prepared for its first-ever student wardrobe elections — a near-perfect mirror of how the British Wizengamot and wizarding public appointed their minister and department heads.

The Wizengamot appointed heads of department under a proportional representation system and everything was generally arranged and negotiated behind closed doors without the need for an actual vote. Only if a significant portion of the Wizengamot dissented on hearing the appointments read out, would a vote ensue. Such an event hadn’t happened for two hundred years.

The minister, though, was a special case. The minister was elected by the general population, from a selection of candidates that had been put up by the Wizengamot in the same way as heads of departments.

From these three candidates, the wizards and witches of Magical Britain chose their new minister.

In Hogwarts, it had been decided that the Wizengamot would be made up of everyone from a Noble House, as well as purebloods who could trace their lineage back at least five hundred years, to help bulk out the chamber.

“I’m sorry I won’t be here for everything,” Harry said. “But I’m sure you’ll be able to handle it.”

“We won’t let you down, Harry,” Hermione said, eyes firm.

“No, we won’t,” Daphne added.

“How are Travers and Draco handling the pressure?” Harry asked. Travers and Draco were their candidates for the position of student minister. One from the Gray, one from the Dark. Everyone of note knew by now about the events of the Winter Festival at Slytherin Manor and how the children of the Dark had sworn themselves to a Gray agent.

Being put forward as student minister was doing wonders for assuaging Draco that his position wasn’t as terrible as it otherwise could have been. And despite his rather abrasive manner, and tendency to bully a small segment of the students, Draco wasn’t unpopular. He was a polarising figure. And polarising figures could be powerful political weapons.

“Draco is fine,” Tracey answered. “He’s Draco. He bounces back as quickly as a rubber ball. As for Travers… Blaise?”

“I’ve known Cecil since before Hogwarts,” Blaise said. “He was always at my birthday parties, even though he’s older. I’ve never seen him so anxious before.”

“But he will pull through for us?”

“Absolutely. By the way, my Mum still wants to meet you. She was quite miffed she missed you at the Slytherin Winter Festival.”

Harry took this information in his stride. While Harry Potter had never met Mrs Zabini, Mrs Zabini had certainly met Lord Slytherin. It was amazing how many times one could accidentally bump into someone in compromising positions.

“My Lord Slytherin! I’m so sorry! Oh, no, I’ve spilt wine all over my dress! …Oh wow, wandless cleaning charms…”

“Oh, Lord Slytherin! My skirt! Please sir, avert your gaze! …Oh, you already did.”

In any case, there was a lot more stuff that needed to get done today, so he finished up his briefing with the girls and Blaise, and started making his way towards the entrance hall. There was still the matter of his brother and Virgo to deal with, but until he’d figured out a way to extract the horcrux from the girl, he’d let his brother take care of her. It would be all the more amusing when he finally learned the truth.

Just so long as he did it before his brother and father did something foolish. Like, say, try to get the young Dark Lord betrothed to John — as amusing as that might be. But that, at least, was something he didn’t have to worry about. Tom Riddle would never willingly submit to a betrothal contract — not even if he’d been the man in the deal. He would fight it tooth and nail. Harry knew him too well. And the chances of Lucius willingly signing such a document in the face of that wroth would be zero.

Of course, he would still need to do something about Virgo’s attempt on Ginny’s life at the quidditch match the previous term. There was no way he could let that go unanswered indefinitely. He’d need to send a message — a warning — something unambiguous to the recipient, but innocuous to everyone else.

His hand closed on the doorknob leading to the Hogwarts Grounds.

“Harry!” shouted an adult female voice, clearly stressed and worried.

Harry gripped the doorknob harder. He could just duck out of this door, whip the invisibility cloak over him, and be off and away. No one would know where he’d gone or be able to stop him.

“Harry!” The voice called to him again, closer this time.

Harry groaned internally. He turned. “Mother,” he said, simply.

Lady Lily Potter slowed down, panting. She stopped a respectful distance from him, breathing shortly, hands on her thighs. “Harry.”

“You know, you should really join the morning exercise groups down at the lake. The lady of a noble house should not be exhausted from a spot of light jogging.”

“Look, Harry. You can’t keep sleeping just wherever you want.”

Harry gave her an amused look. “Evidently, I can. Because you have been unable to stop me.” Watching Lily Potter’s reactions to her increasingly desperate failed attempts to catch him over the last few weeks had made all the hard stone beds more than worth it. They were now at the point that he knew she knew that even standing this close to him, if he wanted to flee, there would be nothing she could do to stop it.

“It can’t be good for you,” she panted.

“I’ll be the judge of that.”

“I’m just saying, you can sleep in my apartment, if you want. I understand if you don’t want to. But a real bed must be more comfortable than just blankets.”

“And get abducted in my sleep and dragged off to Potter Manor to face my father’s court? I think not.”

Lily Potter looked torn. “I’d keep it secret.”

“Unfortunately, there is no way you can guarantee that. Not unless you’ve learned to cast the fidelius charm while I wasn’t paying attention.”

“You distrust me that much?”

Harry gave her a stony look. “Not by choice, I assure you. I do not enjoy not trusting my parents.”

“Harry, whatever Lord Slytherin might have told you, we’re not bad people. I saw what happened with my sister and her husband. I’m sorry you went through that. That was not the plan.”

Harry raised an eyebrow. “Oh? What was the plan?”

Lily hesitated. Visibly. For many seconds.

Harry rolled his eyes. “Look, I understand this is hard on you. So, to make it easier, I’ll give you a list of conditions that would have to be met for me to accept you as my parents again, both in private and in polite society.” He began listing off on his fingers.

“One: Lord Potter would have to immediately sign a blank betrothal contract, giving me the right to choose my Lady Potter under whatever terms I see fit, as well as secure the agreement from the family of my future betrothed to likewise accept those terms.

“Two: Both of you would declare yourself Gray and guarantee bringing at least a third of the Light with you.

“And three: Lord Potter would abdicate his position as Lord Potter while I am still Heir and hand over all Gringotts vaults and their contents to me, intact, and in their entirety.”

Lily’s look turned pitying. “Harry, none of that is even remotely realistic.”

Harry nodded. “I know.”

Lily’s look of pity vanished.

Harry could see the emotions flash across her face. A moment ago, she’d been standing in front of a naive child, asking for the impossible. Now she faced a brick wall.

Finally, the emotions on her face settled into sadness. “Where did that happy and talented boy go who stayed at Potter Manor over the summer?”

“He’s still here. I learned to pretend to be happy long before I learned what the emotion actually felt like, but now that I do know, pretending is all the easier.” He smiled a bright smile. “I have friends. They make me happy. And I’m not talking about Lord Slytherin.” His bright smile dulled somewhat. “It seems you are trying to present the front of a mother who wishes to do right by a child she feels she has wronged. If that is truly your intention, front or otherwise, then you will not begrudge me the source of my happiness and instead let me get on with it.”

Lily’s look of despondency deepened. “No normal twelve-year-old is that erudite, even with occlumency. Just what has Slytherin put you through?”

Harry didn’t answer. He instead slipped out of the door and out into the damp mist of a February weekend morning. Birds chirped off in the mists. Around his ankles, Mrs Norris rubbed affectionately at his leg in a way she never would have done before the animagus ritual.

Harry leaned back on the castle wall and winced. Looking back, he really had let himself go there, hadn’t he?

To her credit, Lily didn’t open the door to go after him. That probably meant the weeks-long chase was at an end — at least as far as her part was concerned.

But that didn’t matter now. Harry had an appointment to keep — several of them, in fact. So he’d better get a move on. And the first stop would be all the way up North, back to Slytherin Manor.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

At the Gryffindor table, Virgo Malfoy’s ears pricked up as news of Harry’s flight from the castle percolated. Lord Slytherin had not been at all quiet about his leaving for the day.

“Do we know it’s true?” Susan asked.

Virgo’s eyes carefully studied the Slytherin table. “We don’t. But I believe it is. It fits with what I have learned of John’s brother. He would want his minions to get all the credit. Look. Weasley and Black appear far more alert than usual.”

“Bodyguards?”

“Maybe.”

Susan’s voice dropped to barely a whisper. “From you?”

“Almost certainly. They are both dangerous. But Weasley is at a whole other level.”

Susan shivered. “I’m so glad we found that place.”

Virgo nodded slowly. That place, indeed. Unbidden by the busyness around the Great Hall, her mind drifted back to when they’d first found that place.

It had been the Tuesday after they’d all arrived back at Hogwarts after the Winter Festival. Virgo had just finished telling John of the conversation between her father and his. And how Lord Potter had valiantly defended both their interests in the negotiation for her hand, while her father had attempted to fleece the Potters for every galleon he could, but ultimately wound up humiliated.

Bollocks, of course, but John didn’t need to know that. It would only upset him.

The boy-who-lived smiled widely. “My dad is awesome.” The smile faded. “I just hope he does manage to sort something out soon. We need to get you away from the Malfoys.”

“We need to do more than that,” Susan jumped in. “We need to start forming our own inner circle.” She paused. “If my aunt heard me say that, she’d cane my bottom.”

“Obviously we won’t call it an inner circle,” John said. “But we do need somewhere to hold meetings. Somewhere the teachers won’t find us.”

Virgo smirked. “I may have an answer for that. You had the Marauder’s Map for a long time, right? Ever notice a place called the Room of Lost Things?”

John frowned. “No.”

After classes that afternoon, the trio embarked on an expedition into the deepest depths of the seventh floor. They all stood outside the door opposite the painting of the dancing trolls. “Of course, it still doesn’t stop your brother from knowing about it,” Virgo said. “The horcrux merging will have given him that information.” The thought roiled around in her head over and over again. “Really, what we need is a place where your brother can’t find us as well. A place where we could hold the meetings we need in total peace and privacy from anyone.”

Suddenly, a huge whoosh of magic nearly knocked the three students off their feet. They all took several steps backwards.

Susan shrieked.

John cursed.

Virgo merely held her arms to her face to stare through the gap with narrowed eyes.

Several dozen massive locks slammed down on the door in front of them, each one locking into place like an intricate jigsaw with almost creepy mechanical precision. Then a small hole opened in the woodwork and something shot from it with a rather organic farting sound. A small bronze key landed at Virgo’s feet.

The three all stared at it.

Yuck.

Virgo reached down and carefully picked it up with two fingers, holding it at arm’s length as though it were a dead mouse. “Voldemort never knew about this.” Despite her disgust at the key’s delivery mechanism, she couldn’t keep the glee out of her voice.

A quick investigation into the Room of Lost Things found it to have changed completely. Gone were the rows upon rows of lost and found shelves, replaced with a large open area, filled with all kinds of duelling paraphernalia.

Shelves crammed with books covering combat, duelling, war, politics, and seduction lined one of the walls.

Combat dummies stood to attention on one side, while another was furnished with rows of benches facing a raised stage with a podium. And behind that podium was a magic window showing every corridor leading to their new discovery.

“It’s a duelling room!” John exclaimed.

“No,” said Virgo in a low voice. “Not if I’m right. If I’m right, it’s so much more than that.”

She was right. This room could turn into almost anything the wisher needed. Although her first thought to use the room to summon back the Marauder’s Map had not worked, unfortunately. How had her other self not discovered this before?

“This is amazing!” Susan said, spinning around in the middle of the room. “We can totally host our inner circle here.” She slowed to a halt. “Now we just have to persuade them to join.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

On the third floor of Slytherin Manor—the residential apartments—Harry stepped out of the floo and looked around the central living area. There was a noticeable air of cosiness about the place now that he approved of. A difference in smell, perhaps? The new carpets? The fire in the grate? Whatever it was, he liked it.

The walk down to the basement, however, reminded him that most of the manor still lacked that kind of personal touch. The grand ballroom still had the air of a currently unused event space — all chairs and tables stacked in corners. It really needed a standard welcoming setup it could take when not being used for anything else.

He made his way through the various defences he’d set up around his own little department of mysteries and found Plato administering the next dose of Draught of Living Death to the obscurial son of the African warlord he’d subdued over the summer.

Plato looked up. “Master is being here, master,” he said, sounding unsurprised. “Will master be wanting to peek into parasite boy’s head today?”

Harry walked past the table. “No, Plato, thank you. I just wanted to get a book before heading over to the Grangers and Gringotts. The situation with Dan and the gem is delicate.”

Plato grimaced. “As master wishes. Plato is hoping that the magic drain is cured of his affliction before too long.”

A magic drain, Harry thought in dark amusement as he emerged back into the sunlight from the manor’s front door, and started making his way down the path to the Grangers’ cottage. That was an apt description for what Daniel Granger now was. Such a power was both legendary and political dynamite. It almost made his own time-travel look tame by comparison. The potential advantages of having someone like Dan on his staff were legion. And they almost outweighed the downsides.

It was, therefore, extremely lucky for him that Hermione more than made up for those downsides.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Daphne Greengrass stared intently at the open book in her lap — Thucydides’ History of the Peloponnesian War. What could she take from it? What could she learn?

In the ancient muggle war between Sparta and Athens, the Spartans were masters of ground combat. None could stand before their well-trained military machine. Luckily for the Athenians, they didn’t need to. Athens had built an impenetrable wall around their city and ferried in supplies from a maritime empire that the Spartans couldn’t hope to top.

Every summer the Spartans marched to the wall, intent on laying siege to Athens, and every year, when the snows started to fall, they were forced to go home without a victory, having achieved nothing but to devastate the Athenian countryside, again.

In the words of this muggle strategist, Thucydides, the Spartans were the elephant — a terrible force that could trample all they faced... on land. While the Athenians were the whale — a mighty naval power that could sink any enemy they found... in the water.

Two great nations locked in stalemate, unable to bring their respective powers to a decisive battle against the other, forced into unending conflict for as long as the status quo remained.

Daphne bit her thumb. How might her betrothed’s power be like the whale? How might he be the elephant? Perhaps one could think of morality as a kind of strategic geography? The Light liked to occupy the popular moral high ground. They counted on the support of the masses to make up for their sacrifice of the more ruthless political tactics found in Dracula’s Blood is Thicker than Magic.

The Dark, on the other hand, had shown no problem in using such devastating magical tactics under the patriarchal leadership of a lord of lords.

The two felt quite asymmetrical, didn’t they?

What about economic power?

The Light and the Dark felt quite similar there. Many of the lords relied on real estate and rents. Others on monopolies granted by the ministry — or near-monopolies, at least. The wizarding government didn’t like one political faction to have a stranglehold on any one critical resource.

Or it would be more accurate to say that no faction in the Wizengamot liked their opposing factions to have a total monopoly on any critical resource. There was an important difference.

Daphne tapped a light pattern on the book with her fingers.

If Harry chose to attack any strategic moral high grounds, he would probably have to fight for it with the Light — the plucky young bull shark vs the old and massive whale.

On the other hand, if his efforts this afternoon outside of Hogwarts played out well, he might have a whole new geographic playground all to himself. The Dark’s mighty economic elephant of the plains could find itself crushed by Harry’s massive... err... dinosaur? From the... mountains?

Daphne looked down at the book in her lap again.

Maybe she was taking this particular muggle metaphor too far.

Someone landed heavily in one of the armchairs on her right-hand-front.

It was Tracey.

“You were right, Daphne,” she said in a hushed voice. “The Light are putting up Percy Weasley as their candidate for student Minister. They just gave me their nomination.”

Daphne closed the book in her lap with a quirk of her lips. “I thought Humble Hags and Chief Warlocks were supposed to remain apolitical.”

Tracey responded with a lip quirk of her own. “This Humble Hag and Chief Warlock serves Lord Slytherin.”

The two girls snickered.

They both sobered quickly. “Is there anything we have to worry about, Daph?”

Daphne shook her head. “Percy Weasley is an obvious and simultaneously terrible choice. He is a by-the-book stickler for rules, and will surely lose the popular vote. But he is the choice that will give the Light the highest number of important department heads in trade. There is no way the Light can exert actual political weight over proceedings, given how many heirs and other important students we now control. So they must shepherd what resources they have into a few key positions. We have our pieces assembled exactly how we want them. Now all we have to do is wait for events to play out.”

Tracey nodded. “Daph, how much influence do you think these student departments will actually have? I mean, they are only students. They still have to deal with the professors. And the professors still have to listen to the headmaster — who listens to the board and the ministry.”

Daphne smiled. “That’s up to each individual student.” Her smile turned into a rare grin. “And how well they play the game of power.”

“You just went full Dark Lady there, Daph.”

“Gray Lady.”

Tracey opened her mouth to reply, but Daphne beat her to it.

“That’s Gray with an -A, not an -E. I am not that mopey ghost.”

Tracey stuck out her tongue.

“In any case, this will help cement Harry’s expanding control over the school. By the time anyone important enough to do anything about it realises what’s happening, it will be a fait accompli.”

“Doesn’t he already totally control the school? I thought I read something about that in the Daily Prophet.”

“That was a cautionary action taken because of a rogue house-elf. Quite helpful, actually. It gave our lord a good excuse to take control of the wards, setting a precedent, and the squawking in the Prophet will only help us in the long term. Despite their protests, they couldn’t actually have Lord Slytherin back down from his control given the threat, and since they couldn’t tell anyone what the actual threat was, it ended up making them look weak. But no, he doesn’t control the school. Not yet.”

Tracey had a quill and parchment out now. “So, what’s everyone doing before the candidates’ speeches and voting?”

“Ginny and Luna are helping Alex train for the upcoming duelling tournament. Hermione is in healer training, Blaise and Theodore are with Draco, most of the Founders Club are working on their occlumency, the Hufflepuffs and Ravenclaws have the quidditch pitch, the Gobstones Club was cancelled because the captain needs to work on his arithmancy homework, although he didn’t tell the club that, and that one Ravenclaw seventh year I told you about finally succeeded at getting into that Hufflepuff sixth year’s knickers last night. The two are currently waiting in the hospital wing for Professors Flitwick and Sprout, who are probably going to suspend them for a few weeks after getting them the potion they need. Unless the parents object, naturally. It wouldn’t be that terrible a match for them.”

Daphne looked at the ceiling as though deep in thought.

“Oh, and Percy Weasley and Penelope Clearwater have moved from kissing to feeling each other up. Which is almost outside of her parents’ direction for her courting, but not quite enough for blackmail material, unfortunately. Knowing Percy Weasley, he’ll probably stick to her parents’ word of law even if she threw herself naked into his arms.”

Tracey whistled. “I don’t know how you get gossip this quickly. What about John?”

“John, Virgo, Susan, and others are having another meeting in the Room of Many Things.” Daphne shook her head. “And although none of my various means or agents have been able to infiltrate into that particular space without resorting to extraordinary efforts, I honestly don’t know what they think they’re hiding.” She fixed Tracey with a rather annoyed look. “Surely there’s only so much devious stuff you can get up to in a room crammed full of shelves so dense you can hardly move.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“What are we going to do?” shouted Sally Smith.

“Yeah!” echoed an older Hufflepuff. “Greengrass has this whole thing sewn up! This isn’t a fair wardrobe selection. She’s going to steamroll us!”

Over three-dozen other students voiced similar sentiments. The Room of Requirement was buzzing. Behind the small crowd standing in front of the raised platform, several students were practising basic stunners under the watchful eyes of Susan Bones.

John Potter stood behind the dais, doing his best to look firm and confident. “Trust me,” he said. “We have a plan. It’s all about the student minister. If we can win that position, we’ll have everything we need to stop the Gray from taking over the school.”

The crowd as one turned their heads to where Percy Weasley was standing by a blackboard, explaining the finer points of ministry protocol to a small group of glazed-eyed third years. They turned back to John.

“John,” began Oliver Wood, standing in the front row. “I’m not saying Percy wouldn’t make a good humble hag. But is he really minister material?”

There was a chorus of muttered agreements.

“And why don’t we get a say at who becomes the top humble hag?” Sally added loudly. “Why does it have to be Davis? And she’s even Chief Warlock as well!”

“Look,” John said. “I tried talking to McGonagall, but she said that was the headmaster’s decision. I don’t like it any more than you all. Didn’t any of you talk to your parents about it, like I asked?”

There was an uneasy shuffling of feet.

“Oliver?”

Oliver Wood grimaced. “They said Hogwarts was where we were supposed to learn about politics and that I shouldn’t be asking them for help.”

“That’s what mine said too,” added a fifth-year Ravenclaw.

“Mine said teenage politics weren’t important,” said a sixth-year Gryffindor.

“The hells it isn’t!” Sally burst out. “If we can’t beat the Gray now, what makes them think we’ll be of any use to them when we graduate?”

“Yours don’t want you in the Light,” pointed out the same Gryffindor.

“That’s my Grandfather. My mum and dad are Light through and through, and so am I.”

“I wish mine were,” said a fourth-year Slytherin, one of the few snakes in the room. “They told me it might be a good idea to start cosying up closer to Greengrass, with the way the winds have been blowing lately.”

Everyone looked at her.

“What?” she said defensively. “I didn’t have to tell you that. Surely that counts for something? I believe in the ministry as much as all of you!”

John shot off a small firework from his wand to get the attention back on himself. “As I said, we have a plan. Trust me. It will all work out all right in the end.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Dan Granger stood perfectly still, feet exactly aligned with two strips of duct tape that had been affixed to the floor.

He raised his head and cracked his knuckles. “Ready,” he said.

Harry nodded, raised his wand, and said, “Stupefy.”

The bright red light shot towards Dan. It got to within about a foot before winking out of existence as though it had never been.

Harry lowered his wand. “Interesting.”

“The range was only a few inches when we first measured it,” Dan said. “If I focus really hard, I can extend it a bit.”

“Can you modulate the intensity of the effect?”

“I might be able to?”

“I suggest working on that then. Total magical nullification is amazingly powerful, but selective nullification would be a completely different level.”

“But I don’t think I’ll be able to completely remove the effect around me.”

Harry sighed. “I don’t expect you to.”

Dan looked uncomfortable. “Look, Harry. I mean, my lord. I mean....” He stopped. “Do you want me to call you Harry or by title?”

“You can call me Harry when you’re not in the dog house.”

Dan grimaced. “Yes, my lord. Look, I’m really sorry about this. If you want, I can go with you.”

Harry slowly shook his head. He liked Daniel Granger, he really did. But he did have to remind himself sometimes that the man was a muggle. And now he wasn’t only a muggle, he was a super muggle. A man whose muggleness was so intense that he actively sucked magic out of the world.

Harry walked over to a side-table, on which rested several potions, alongside his mask.

“Dan,” he started. “Do you love your daughter?”

The voice behind him sounded mildly offended. “Of course.”

“Yeah, I’m rather fond of her too.” He turned around.

“How do you feel Hermione would feel if her Dad went into Gringotts this morning and never came out?”

Dan Granger said nothing.

“I know very little about how the goblins view these gems,” Harry continued. “I don’t know what they use them for. I don’t know how much they know about them. They could be part of some long-term power strategy to create an army of goblin warriors immune to magic to throw against the walls of Magical Britain. Unlikely, but not impossible. Maybe they’re a necessary reagent in creating the elixir of life, or turning base metals into gold. Maybe they don’t need the gems themselves. Maybe they only need the people who’ve used the gems, for who knows what. The more powerful the ritual, often the greater the sacrifice.”

He gave Dan a significant look.

Dan was back to looking sheepish now.

Harry picked up one of the potion vials. “I cannot stress this enough, Dan. No one. Absolutely no one outside of the family can know about this. No one. The political ramifications of a muggle who can nullify magic are too terrible to contemplate — but contemplating them is my job. It’s the kind of thing that would bring not only the ministry down on our heads, but possibly the entire Wizarding World. We’re talking an ICW task force powerful enough to sweep any question of magical sovereignty aside like so much confetti. Are you familiar with the Brazilian Strangle Vine?”

Dan shook his head.

“It’s a magical plant from the Americas — a parasite that leeches magic from other magical plants to sustain a number of dangerous enchantments around itself. During the last war it became a symbol of propaganda for blood purists. One of their central claims was that muggleborns were simply muggles who had found a way to steal magic from ‘real’ wizards and witches.”

“Oh,” Dan said. “I think I’m starting to see the picture.”

“Indeed. Where does the magic that you nullify go? If anywhere? Do you keep it? Are you ‘stealing’ it, somehow? It doesn’t seem likely, but it is the kind of thing that will be claimed by certain people with an agenda in a heartbeat. And it’s very difficult to prove that it’s not the case. Maybe eventually you will also be a muggleborn? A muggleborn who stole his magic from wizards. Maybe you could drain a wizard dry and turn them into a muggle.”

Harry drunk the potion in hand, followed quickly by the other. His body aged. His face changed. He put on the mask and cast a few spells over himself.

Lord Slytherin carefully adjusted his robes before turning his attention back to the man in front of him. “My job today is to haul your arse out of the fire, Mister Granger,” he said. “And hopefully persuade the Boneslicer Clan to continue supporting us. Your job is to arrange matters with the muggle authorities so that our sunken treasure ship can go on the muggle market as soon as possible at the valuations we need.”

Dan straightened. “I won’t let you down.”

Lord Slytherin walked towards the door. “I’m sure you won’t.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

By now, breakfast had long since passed, and the Slytherin common room was bustling.

“I heard Derik say Margarette said a sixth and seventh year were suspended for trying to rig the vote for Potter.”

“Yeah? Well I heard that the Daily Prophet sent a reporter under polyjuice to sabotage Greengrass.”

“Don’t be daft. Who’d believe something so stupid?”

“At least it’s better than the fool who thought they’d bumped into an agent from the Department of Mysteries and it turned out to be Clearwater practising the invisibility charm.”

“Ah, but why’d she be trying to learn that do you think?”

“Have you ever been a smoking hot girl in a castle full of boys?”

“No, and neither have you.”

“Yes, but I do have an imagination.”

“No kidding. You read the Quibbler.”

Sitting in his large high-back chair on the left-hand side of the much larger and throne-like chair left open for Lord Slytherin, Draco Malfoy surveyed the common room with a regal air. He didn’t just sit though, he lounged. He lounged like a wizard who was already the highest-ranked wizard in the castle — a wizard who sat head and shoulders above every other wizard — a wizard of power and influence.

To Draco Malfoy, this was how it should be. Everything neatly arranged behind closed doors. The voting would be mere formality.

It was just a shame he wasn’t on the other side of those closed doors.

In front of him, a constant stream of students passed by the mostly empty Slytherin court, making their way instead to the archway to the girls’ dormitories. Messages to and from Slytherin’s now undisputed leader. From there, a witch carried the message down the stairways to its final destination.

For while he was about to take on the mantle of most powerful student wizard in the castle, that still didn’t change the fact that above him, there were not one, but two even more powerful student witches.

His master had a master, or possibly an ally, he wasn’t entirely sure, who herself was the betrothed of one of the most powerful wizards in the country.

But still... student minister.

Draco allowed himself a small smile.

Across the Slytherin common room, past the massive windows looking out into the Black Lake, past the older messenger girls stationed at the head of the descending spiral staircase, down, down, to the second-year girls’ dorm, two younger girls stood at attention by the door, eyes scanning the hallways, wands in hand.

“Message from Derik Catwall for Heiress Greengrass,” panted one of the messenger girls.

Ginny nodded, took the message, and handed it to Alexandra, who waved her wand over it, carefully opened the door, and slipped inside, replaced moments later by Luna.

The messenger girl left.

Ginny glanced at her friend. “I’m still not sure Alex will be able to win the tournament.”

Luna hummed, but said nothing.

“She’s come a long way,” Ginny continued. “But is it enough? Even with her you-know-what form. There’s only so much training you can fit into nearly two years.”

Luna turned her face to her. She smiled dreamily. “Everything is going perfectly, Ginny. Whether Alex wins or loses doesn’t matter. What matters is that she fights for our lord.”

Ginny’s look turned uncertain. “Are you sure about that, Luna? Alex really doesn’t like losing. And she’s worked so hard for this.”

“Ginny, if Alex wins, our lord can reward her. If Alex loses, she will fight harder to prove herself. Then the reward will be all the sweeter.” She paused. “Or is that blander, in Alex’s case? Or maybe nice things feel even sweeter when you aren’t always tasting sweeties. Maybe that’s why witches like to ‘save it for someone special’, but then why would betrothal contracts need chastity clauses? I should ask Harry about that.” Luna then put her hands behind her back and proceeded to hum a tune Ginny didn’t recognise.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

The Slytherin second-year girls’ dorm was almost completely vacant.

Pansy, Millicent, Flora, and Hestia had all been told to take a hike for the day. The former two complied respectfully and grudgingly, respectively. The latter two, with almost worshipful speed.

“Message from Catwall,” Alex said, climbing into the trunk in the middle of the girls’ dorm.

Hermione nodded, took the note, opened it, and read. “You were right,” she said, turning to Daphne. “Those two upper years having sex have been suspended.”

“Not only have they been suspended,” Daphne whispered, sitting in her high-back chair, eyes firmly shut. “But their fathers are currently negotiating a betrothal contract for the two. She is not taking the news well.” Her eyes snapped open.

Somewhere in the castle, not too far away, an Eye of Kilrogg faded from existence.

On the wall in front of Daphne, a half-dozen ice mirrors shimmered in the warm air, each one showing a different spot in the castle.

“In other news, Potter has finished his meeting in the Room of Lost Things and is making his way back to Gryffindor Tower.”

Alexandra huffed and crossed her arms. “What is even the point of having a spy network, when you have this?”

“One of the surest ways to form positions for war would be to order movements only after obtaining perfect information. And I want perfect information.”

Hermione and Alex looked at each other before looking back at Daphne.

“Jomini.” Daphne smiled. “A Summary of the Art of War.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

While Harry did indeed have urgent business in Gringotts, this was not his only port of call for his day trip out of Hogwarts.

Whispers followed him from the moment he exited the floo at the British Ministry of Magic.

They always did.

“Look, it’s Lord Slytherin!”

“Merlin, he’s tall.”

“I wonder what he’s here for?”

“Do you think the minister knows?”

“Stop giggling!”

As he entered the magic elevator that led to the Department of Magical Law Enforcement, a small circle of empty space rapidly formed around him as wizards and witches urgently pressed themselves up against the walls.

The doors briefly opened at the floor housing the Department of Magical Games and Sports, but quickly closed again when the prospective new passengers saw just who was standing in the doorway.

Finally, the doors opened for the floor of the DMLE, and Harry strode out of the lift and into the reception area.

The general noise of chatter, rustling parchment, and minor magical shenanigans slowly died.

If Alexandra were to have even a ghost of a chance during the Hogwarts duelling tournament, he’d first have to take care of a small piece of administration for his troublesome little necromancer.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Down in the DMLE’s training area, Chief Auror Lord Sirius Black breathed heavily, standing bent-over, hands on his knees, panting like a dog, which, obviously, was quite appropriate.

“Again!” barked the trainer. “Or did you haul my arse out of retirement for nothing, boy?!”

Sirius shook his long hair and tried to wipe sweat off his naked chest. Why had he thought it was a good idea to bring Mad-Eye back?

Oh, yes.

It was because there was just so much to deal with these days. And things only looked to be getting more and more complicated.

“One second,” he said gruffly. “Water.”

“Fine, you pansy!” Mad-Eye turned to the assembled aurors. “Two minute break! Constant Vigilance!”

Six other aurors all relaxed slightly and turned away.

Walking over to the side of the room, Sirius brought a bottle of water to his lips.

Almost without thought, his wand slipped back into his hand as he felt hostile magical intent begin to form behind his back.

Oddly enough though, the spell wasn’t aimed at him.

A loud crackle of spellfire blasted through the room.

It seemed this time one of the others had been the target of their trainer’s ‘surprise training session’.

He turned.

Sirius’ eyes bugged. “MOODY?! WHAT THE HELLS?”

Mad-Eye stood in the middle of the room, good leg forward, wand thrust straight out in front of him, pointing towards the door that led back to the department. Every other auror, except Nymphadora, all had their wands pointed dangerously at Mad-Eye. Nymphadora had hers pointing in the same direction as Mad-Eye, although unlike her partner, she hadn’t fired a spell.

A large scorch mark gently smoked to one side of the door.

“You have a quick draw, auror,” said Lord Slytherin. The fingertips of his gloves had been burned away, exposing faintly glowing fingers below.

“No quicker than yours,” Moody shot back. “How many more have you got behind you?”

“MOODY!” Sirius yelled.

Lord Slytherin held his other hand up at him. “No, Lord Black. The man is right to be cautious. What’s to say I don’t have an army behind me?”

“What indeed,” Moody growled, right eye staring, glass eye swivelling.

“Do you have an army behind you?” Sirius asked, incredulous.

“No.”

“Then you are not helping! Put that damn thing away Moody.”

“I’ll put my Merlin-damn wand away in the presence of an unknown and potentially hostile enemy when Death closes the Veil and comes back home for a Merlin-damn holiday.”

“I swear—!” Sirius turned to their guest. “Slytherin, would you hand your wand over to show this idiot you’re not a threat.”

Slytherin inclined his head. “I’ll hand my wand over in the presence of eight trained killers who take their orders from politicians when Fate delivers her final prophecy and retires to embroider the complete history of Hogwarts onto one of Dumbledore’s rainbow robes.”

A corner of Mad-Eye’s mouth tugged ever so slightly upwards. “That implies you believe having your wand in the presence of eight trained killers would do you any good.”

“Oh, for pity’s sake!” Nymphadora shouted out, her wand still trained on Lord Slytherin. “Will you two stop trying to out-paranoia each other? You should both just get married and have little paranoid babies who won’t drink from a bottle without first casting twelve different detection charms over them.”

“Seventeen,” Mad-Eye growled.

“I could add another two.”

“Slytherin, why are you here?” Sirius interrupted.

Slytherin turned to him. “Straight to business?” He cast a very obvious gaze around the somewhat hostile training room. Even the aurors who had their wands trained on Moody were eyeing the masked lord with a good deal of suspicion. “Probably for the best. I have some parchment-work for you.”

Sirius felt an overwhelming feeling of frustration well up in him. “Couldn’t that have waited?”

“Normally, yes. But I thought you’d want to handle this personally. Rather than finding out second-hand from someone else.”

“Personal how?” Sirius marched over. “Give it here.”

Slytherin handed over a small stack of parchment forms. He tipped an imaginary hat, turned on his heels, and left without a word.

The air in the room noticeably relaxed at the man’s departure, but Sirius didn’t really notice. He was too busy staring down at the first parchment in the stack, eyes fixed on the first few details. His hands began to quiver. A lump started to form in his throat.

Animagus Registration Application Form

Name: Heiress Alexandra Patricia Black

Animagus Form: Grim

Date First Achieved: January 30th, 1993

Distinguishing Features: Bright Violet Eyes

A tear formed in one eye.

Slytherin’s voice called out down the corridor. “You can thank Harry!”

You can thank Harry.

Sirius wiped the tear away. It was a bloody good thing he was facing away from his men.

He knew being a single father was hard. But when Alex had arrived into his life, he hadn’t realised just how hard it was going to be. The legacy of the Black family, her mother, her unusual birth, family magics, the wrong sort of wizards, Kreacher, the portraits around Grimmauld Place — the list of things to protect her from seemed endless. And at some point that he couldn’t identify Alex had gone from his little angel to resenting him. And in the worst possible way. Alex wanted the legacy of the Black family. She wanted the rituals. She wanted the society, the traditions, the magic. She wanted the power. She wanted everything that he had grown up hating.

And the harder she’d pushed, the harder he’d pushed back.

There were many things expected of the heiress of an Ancient and Noble house, and he’d taught his daughter basically none of them.

Not even the prerequisites for the animagus transformation — the one aspect of being a Black he himself had not shunned.

And now that he thought about it, with how little instruction he’d arranged during her early years, even that particular accomplishment would have long been out of her reach without outside help.

Many things were expected of being a Black. Ruthlessness, stubbornness, a cut-throat cunning streak — but perhaps the one thing that was expected above all else, was being in the know. And a Black who wasn’t in the know...

The memory of a mad cackling filled Sirius’ mind.

...was worse than dead.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

‘Well, that was a good-ish deed for the day’, Harry thought, arriving by floo inside the Leaky Cauldron. There was no doubt Lord Black could potentially be an incredibly useful ally. Quite apart from his being Alex’s father, Chief Auror, and a lord of the Wizengamot, he was also Harry’s godfather.

And while the man hadn’t acquitted himself amazingly well in the past in that regard, he also hadn’t pissed all over him during his darkest hour. There had been many people in that courtroom, back in the last timeline, when Harry had been sentenced to Azkaban, but not Lord Black.

Tapping the pattern on the bricks outside the Leaky Cauldron with his wand, Harry watched as the entrance to Diagon Alley opened and the sounds of a hundred wizards and witches, many from overseas, swept over him.

“Psst! Look, it’s him!”

“Is he really writing a book?”

“That’s what I heard.”

“Dragon liver! Six knuts an ounce!”

“That’s outrageous!”

The goblin guards outside Gringotts noticeably stiffened as Harry approached. Not the best reaction he could have hoped for, but it was better than outright hostility.

They both clicked their halberds in unison as he passed between them up the stairs.

The doors to the bank swung open.

Harry took a moment to centre himself. He had both his wands, the cloak, enough potions to supply a small army, and of course, his new ace-in-the-hole, a chimaera animagus form — part Nemean lion.

He then walked forward, passing through the doors, out of Magical Britain, and into the sovereign territory of every goblin the world over.

His footsteps echoed on the marble floor. The hall was quiet at this time of day and Harry fancied that every clerk caught his eye as he made his way to the end of the room.

The head clerk looked down at him over a desk that magically adjusted its height to be exactly four feet taller than whoever stood before it. “Yes?” the goblin asked.

“Lord Slytherin here to see Account Manager Boneslicer, Chief of the Boneslicer Clan. I am expected.”

“Yes, you are,” the head clerk said, rather acerbically. “If you will wait one moment. Convertible-Security!”

Harry allowed himself to be led away by the summoned goblin. “I was not aware of a Convertible-Security in the Boneslicer Clan.”

The goblin did not answer.

They turned several corners and passed several statues that Harry was sure he’d never passed before during his times in the bank.

“You’re not a Boneslicer, are you?”

Again no reply.

They turned another corner and Lord Slytherin stopped dead. The sound of rushing water ahead was punctuated by a change in decor, from smooth marble to rough rock. It was a thief’s downfall — the illusion-cancelling waterfall Gringotts used to catch vault robbers. Harry’s mind immediately jumped to the anti-magic effects of the ghost gem.

“After you, Lord Slytherin,” Convertible-Security growled.

Shit. As far as he knew, only the Boneslicer clan knew that Harry Potter was Lord Slytherin. Technically, he’d still have the mask, but even that was magic. What if thief’s downfall had additional unadvertised effects? Like for example, magic cancelling?

“Lord Slytherin!” Convertible-Security said again, more forcefully this time.

“This is not the way to Account Manager Ragnok Boneslicer,” Harry said, slowly. “I wish to be taken there.”

“You will be. After you walk through the thief’s downfall.”

“I was not informed this was necessary.”

Convertible-Security snarled. “But you were informed of the sacred nature of the mist jewels, and yet you allowed one to be destroyed. How can we trust such a shadow to walk freely in our halls? Defiler of sacred artefacts!”

“I wasn’t told they were sacred...”

Harry turned just in time to witness the arrival of a dozen armed goblins piling into the corridor behind him, blocking off his line of retreat. They all carried runed weapons and wore armour forged of goblin steel.

Harry felt adrenaline rush through his veins.

“Walk, Lord Slytherin. And if you dare pull a wand, I promise it will be the last thing you ever do.”

The beast king just below the surface roared to be let free — to feel steel turned aside on his coat while jaws crushed bone. Forward or back? Submit or fight? Lord Slytherin or chimaera? His secret persona exposed before he was ready or potential war with the goblins? Which was worse?

Luckily for him, the answer to that question turned out to be irrelevant.

“STAND ASIDE!” bellowed a voice behind the crowd of goblins.

Convertible-Security cursed.

“WHAT IN THE GOBLIN KING’S NAME IS GOING ON HERE?”

In those few moments everything changed. The goblins that had been facing Harry now all had their backs to him, weapons brandished at a second group of goblins, led by none other than Ragnok Boneslicer.

“Stay out of this, Boneslicers!” One of the goblins nearer him shouted. “The shadow must be unveiled!”

“Slytherin belongs to the Boneslicer Clan!” Ragnok roared back. He glanced over their heads and made eye contact with Harry’s mask. “Your account does, I mean.”

Harry nodded. “Do you need any help, Ragnok?”

“No. You just stay there! You’re in enough trouble as it is.”

“Trouble?!” screamed Convertible-Security. “Trouble is for wizards who miss an interest payment! Slytherin destroyed one of the sacred artefacts! He must be punished!”

“And unless our king intervenes, that punishment is mine to deal!”

In the privacy of his mind, Harry cursed. There was going to be a consequence for Mister Granger’s new talent. The question was how large was it going to be?

“So unless you wish to challenge the clan for control again, stand aside and allow my client through!” Ragnok finished.

Silence filled the corridor.

“Fine!” Convertible-Security snapped. “But know that the king will not support you forever, Boneslicer!”

The sheer hostility directed his way as Harry walked through the grudgingly formed rows of armed goblins was almost physical.

Harry did not collapse into the chair in Ragnok’s office. He sat down with all the control expected of Lord Slytherin. But nevertheless, he somehow managed to express the idea of physical relief, regardless.

“What was that?” Harry asked.

Ragnok groaned as he took his own seat on the other side of the table.

“That was the Goldtooth clan.”

“A rival?”

“Very much so. The Goldtooth clan controls the Dumbledore account. They have been hostile to the Boneslicers for hundreds of years. It was pure coincidence that our interests down here in the heart of our nation mirror our clients so closely. They have been trying to win your account ever since you first came to us.”

Harry felt a flash of horror and relief wash through him at almost the same time. “I’m glad that you’ve been able to hold my account for as long as you’ve been able to. I had no idea my secret identity was under threat from such an angle.”

“No clan should ever give confidential information about one client to another. Such an action would directly contradict the edicts set up by the Goblin King.”

Harry took off his mask and looked Ragnok in the eyes. “I trust that the accidental destruction of the ‘mist jewel’ my people found did not count as classified client information?”

Ragnok shuffled uncomfortably. “We had already reported your discovery to the Mistjewel clan. We had no choice but to report the destruction as well. It spread from there. But it will stay with the goblins, I can assure you of that. None of the clans could profit from sharing such knowledge with humans.”

Harry was suddenly very glad that he’d only reported the destruction of the gem and not the effect on Hermione’s father.

“And the punishment?”

“Financial.”

Harry was instantly on guard.

“How go your efforts to raise the boat from the sea bed?” Ragnok asked.

Harry said nothing for a few moments before answering.

“They go well,” he eventually said. “The Grangers should be seeing a muggle law firm as we speak to sort out some of the more important details, but the salient points on the muggle side are mostly accounted for. What about on the goblin side?”

Ragnok nodded once. “I will not insult your intelligence by beating around the bush, Lord Slytherin. What you are planning to do is something that the ICW has been trying to prevent ever since the Carnegie incident in Magical America. The difference in size between the magical and muggle economies is stupidly gigantic and has only increased since the rise of the United States of America. Free flow of money between the two is impossible while maintaining either the ISS or political stability. It only takes one muggle billionaire to completely upset a magical country’s economy. And while you’re not about to become that, you’ll be far closer than anyone in power would like.”

Ragnok paused. “What is the current estimated value of the gold in the sunken ship?”

“In pounds?”

Ragnok nodded. “I believe you said it was thirty million? 600,000 galleons. About thirteen per cent of GDP? But that was before you got the estimate from the muggle auction houses.”

“It was.”

There was a pause.

“And?” Ragnok asked.

Harry looked up at the ceiling, as though trying to remember something that he might have simply forgotten.

“Ehh... about four-hundred million.”

Ragnok groaned. “Far closer than anyone in power wants.” If Ragnok wore glasses, he would have taken them off. “Lord Slytherin. Harry. There is simply no way we can let that amount of money loose in the wizarding economy. Gringotts only exists because the ICW doesn’t trust the world’s economy to the home of the Albion Family Magics. Not after the last empire. There are limits to how far we can push the rules for you. And then there’s the penalty I need to exact for the destruction of the mist jewel.”

He picked up his quill and looked Harry in the eyes. “I think we can both agree that 600,000 galleons should be plenty for you to get by with? That’s what you thought you were going to get originally.”

“Ragnok,” Harry said slowly. “With all due respect, 600,000 is not enough. I have programs I need to fund. People I need to train. Investments I need to make. And if I can’t make them, Magical Britain could easily be plunged into a war that will make the last one look like a children’s playground scuffle.”

Ragnok grimaced. It was clear by the look on his face that he didn’t like doing this any more than Harry did. He put the quill on the parchment in front of him, anyway. “I’m sorry, Lord Slytherin. But you’ll have to make do.”

There was a loud knocking on the door.

Ragnok paused, quill still immobile on the parchment. “What?!” he yelled.

The door opened and Floating-Interest poked her nose through the gap. She looked flushed. “Sorry, Grandfather, but...” Her gaze shot to Harry before travelling back to Ragnok. “But Lord Slytherin has been summoned... by the king.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

The Hogwarts Great Hall was packed. Packed, quiet, and mostly contemplating the wonderful weather outside. On a normal Saturday, students would shuffle in and out for lunch over the course of ninety minutes, but this wasn’t a normal Saturday. Attendance was mandatory.

All eyes were on the high table where second-year Slytherin Tracey Davis was doing her best to Chief Warlock without boring everyone to death.

“And that’s Procedure 424. After that, the student Wizengamot will adjourn for exactly seven minutes, drink the traditional whiskey—err, in our case that will be pumpkin juice—then return and announce their appointments and recommendations for the heads of departments.”

A boy at the Hufflepuff table slowly drifted off to sleep.

Tracey turned to a new parchment. “Then the Scales of Judgement—in our case the Goblet of Fire—will announce the judges who will make up the Student Judiciary. Umm, in the normal judiciary there are six judges and one high judge, but since we’re not as large as Magical Britain it was decided that three would be enough. Please make sure to place your names in the Goblet before the Reformation of Councils.”

An older Slytherin student stifled a yawn.

“Once our new judges have taken up their mantles, we will move onto the announcement of our student minister. We’re determining this by simple majority. And since we lack a Nicolas Flamel, our impartial counter will be one of the staff.”

Daphne sat elegantly at the far end of the Slytherin table, watching the proceedings with eagle-like eyes. Everything was going well.

“And now, I’m going to announce the candidates for minister that I’ve been given. Could I ask each of you in turn to come to the front when I call your name?” Tracey looked around the Great Hall. “Cecil Travers!”

Travers, a fifth-year student, stood up from the Slytherin table to large applause from those dressed in green, and varying degrees of enthusiasm or disdain from the other three tables depending on house loyalty, family affiliation, personal feelings, traditional alliances, current state of favours owed or owing, and possibly current transitional position of Jupiter.

The boy swept up to the front dais, doing his best to look like he wasn’t trying to do his best to look as cool as possible.

Tracey nodded. “Percy Weasley!”

There was a polite smattering of applause, which quickly died as Percy only half stood.

“Chief Warlock,” Percy said in his most pompous sounding voice. “A point of procedure, if I may?”

Daphne’s eyes narrowed.

Tracey looked around the hall uncertainly. “You may, I think.”

Percy adjusted his horn-rimmed glasses. “I would like to remind you that the tradition of informing the chief warlock of the candidates before announcement is merely tradition. Not actually written down anywhere. On the other hand, rule twenty-one paragraph six of Greengrass and Webbs, clearly states—”

Next to Daphne, Blaise Zabini leaned over and urgently whispered, “What is he doing?”

“I don’t know,” Daphne answered.

By now everyone in the hall was paying rapt attention.

“And thus I have decided to step aside,” Percy finished, “for a candidate who I’m sure will acquit herself superbly.”

‘Herself’. Alarm bells rang in Daphne’s mind. This was not in any way helped by the smug look on John Potter’s face.

“I am of course talking about the incredibly talented and charismatic Miss Virgo Malfoy.”

Uproar.

The Gryffindor table clapped and cheered while the Ravenclaws and Hufflepuffs mostly chatted in confusion. The Slytherins, by contrast, didn’t seem to know what to think. Draco had gone white.

Daphne’s mind went into overdrive. What was Potter doing? Why? It made no sense.

“Greengrass,” Blaise urgently whispered.

“I know!” she hissed back.

All the department head positions had already been negotiated. Potter pulling a stunt like this would put him at a sizable disadvantage. The Light students weren’t supposed to get the position of student minster. They were supposed to take the student Department of Family Affairs, DMLE, and Mysteries. By putting up a candidate who wasn’t supposed to lose, she could easily take back Family Affairs, leaving them with just the DMLE and Mysteries — one inevitably unpopular and the other mostly useless.

Was snatching that position back worth it? It was.

Potter was serving her a strategic advantage on a plate. Why?!

Daphne watched as Virgo Malfoy stood up, flipped her hair over her shoulder, and walked to the front, a triumphant smirk playing about her lips.

Daphne’s eyes widened as realisation dawned. Power hunger! Virgo wasn’t thinking strategically. She was thinking in terms of her own personal position. This was teenage Voldemort after all. Such a foolish move would be completely within the diary’s personality!

Okay, one mystery solved. One problem remained.

The cheering started to die down as Virgo reached the dais, turned and surveyed the hall.

Tracey was busily flipping through parchments, presumably looking up the rules that Percy had just cited. “That... yes... technically...” she eventually said.

Daphne frantically did her best to signal her friend without appearing to do so.

Tracey’s eyes caught hers.

‘Call on me,’ she mouthed, praying that Tracey would have even a fraction of the lip-reading skills she’d developed over her time spying on people with mirrors.

Draco was still white as a sheet.

“Heiress Greengrass,” Tracey said to general confusion. “Um, as a respected student in Slytherin House is there something you’d like to say right now?”

Greengrass rose to her feet and caught Draco’s eye. She tried to convey reassurance, apology, and leadership in one brief glance. And was relieved to see relief sent back her way.

Sending the Malfoy heir up to compete against his ‘sister’ would be a terrible idea. Draco was supposed to win for all sorts of reasons. Him losing was not an option. And Virgo clearly intended to win. So they had to lose on purpose but with someone else.

The position of student minister, while prestigious, wouldn’t likely be all that big of a deal in a tiny population with nine student departments running around. It might enable more personal freedom, but probably little institutional power. And Harry wanted institutional power.

“Yes, Chief Warlock. Thank you for allowing me to speak. I felt that since the Light decided to break with tradition by announcing their candidate themselves, that we should do the same.”

Daphne wetted her lips.

What they needed was a candidate who was plausible, but utterly unsuited to the job. Someone politically disposable, but who wouldn’t mind being politically disposed. That narrowed the potentials down a lot.

All eyes were on her as she took a deep breath.

“I’m sure all of you have seen the praise one of our students has been receiving in the Daily Prophet. There is even talk of changing ministry regulation to allow her the best use of her talents in the coming years. And we were all incredibly impressed by her performance before the Winter Festival.”

There was a pause as the entire hall held its breath.

“I therefore announce our candidate for student minister... Magical Britain’s Quidditch prodigy, Ginevra Weasley.”

Daphne noted three important details about what happened next.

First, the hall erupted.

Second, Ginny gave her a look of utter panic.

And third, this time it was the female Malfoy’s turn to have her face go totally white.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“Daphne!” Ginny half-wailed. “What were you thinking?! I can’t be student minister.”

“You don’t have to be. In fact, if all goes well, you won’t. It’s all politics. Just go up there, give a speech that promises a lot of stuff that people like, but which is also obviously impractical, and that’s that.”

“Daphne, I’m not like you! I can’t go up there and speak. I’ve never spoken in front of a crowd in my life! Couldn’t you have stopped her?”

“You’ll be fine.”

Ginny’s shoulders slumped.

“And besides, ‘When the enemy is making a false movement, we must take good care not to interrupt him.’”

Hermione gave Daphne a quizzical look.

“Napoleon Bonaparte,” Daphne supplied.

The common room was buzzing again. Breakfast was over and everyone who was anyone was throwing their names into the Goblet of Fire for the chance to win one of the three judge spots.

“I’m quite interested to hear why though,” said Hermione. “Why the switch?”

At the court of the Dark, Alexandra (sitting at the head), Draco, Nott, Pansy, the Carrow twins, and several hangers-on all quietened down to listen in.

“Virgo Malfoy is... a complicated witch,” Daphne said.

This elicited snorts from everyone in the know.

“She’s clever, cunning, devious,” Daphne continued, “but, most of all, power hungry. I believe that power hunger has led her to make a mistake. The position of minister will give a lot of prestige to the person who takes the position, but that position is reliant on those beneath them to get anything done. This Student Wardrobe is not like the real one, in which the minister holds overall executive power over many departments. The Student Minister will have to govern through persuasion and personality, and if we control all the other positions...” Daphne trailed off.

“—then anything she does will be worthless,” Tracey finished.

Daphne nodded. “As to why Ginny. She is a credible candidate, given her quidditch exploits, but highly unlikely to win. This will give us all the leverage we need to take all but two of the departments. A near complete sweep.”

“And I trust—” said Draco from the other circle of seats, just loudly enough to be heard, causing the Gray all to turn, “that one of those positions will find their way to wizards who may find themselves displaced in all this shuffle.”

Daphne smiled. “Of course you will have a spot, Draco.”

Draco nodded. “I should warn you not to underestimate my sister though. You do not know her like I do.”

Daphne smirked. “I’m sure. But there’s no need for concern. This is the first and only battle for the future of Hogwarts’ student administration. And in this battle, Virgo’s impetuousness has already sealed her failure.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Despite being the largest town in the whole of the Orkney Islands with just over 7,000 people, Kirkwall did not have many electric telephones. Certainly not many public ones.

In a small office above a local grocery store, Dan and Emma sat opposite a rather dazed-looking local solicitor while a crisp-sounding upper-class London accent filtered through the room from the receiver held to Dan’s ear.

“The legal position of these matters is based on tradition and precedent, Mister Granger, rather than statute. And every incident is handled on a case-by-case basis. But the generally accepted position is that unless the owner of the wreck puts in a counterclaim, then ‘finders keepers,’ if you will excuse the phrase. This particular wreck though, being so old, and being found in international waters, has no real plausible claimant. Though I would recommend permanently lending a small number of the retrieved treasures to the nations of Sweden, Norway, Denmark, Mexico, or Peru for their respective museums once you learn more of the wreck’s origins. As well as the British Museum, naturally. As for the Crown... you will be pleased to know that has not been a problem.”

Emma stared intently at the receiver in her husband’s hand. The solicitor whose phone they were using bit his lip.

“I understand that the actual excavation, retrieval, and sale of the found assets will take a good number of years,” the voice continued through the receiver, “but based on the strength of your claim, our bank will be happy to extend your new company an unrestricted line of credit for no less than thirty per cent of the valuation of the assets at minimal interest — 0.5 per cent above base.”

Dan grinned. A wide smile that could no doubt be heard down the phone. “That sounds acceptable.”

The voice on the other end of the phone took on a lighter tone. “Quite. Congratulations, Mister Granger — and your wife too. You’ve just become very rich people. If you need any assistance in managing it, I’d be happy to pass your name onto one of the best managers our bank has to offer.”

“Yes, please.”

“Then he’ll be in touch. Thank you again, Mister Granger. It’s always a pleasure doing business with you.”

The phone went click.

For a moment there was silence.

Then Emma let out a high-pitched squeal, jumped up out of her chair, and threw her arms around her husband.

The solicitor was still in a daze. “Ninety million pounds,” he muttered.

Outside the solicitor’s office, Emma hung on Dan’s arm. “Where to now, my head of house?” she purred.

Dan grinned. “The boat’s on our clock. Why don’t we splurge on dinner? There’s a pub down that way I like the look of.”

“Wonderful idea.” Emma suddenly frowned. “I hope everything is going as well for Harry.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Mister Weasley was a man used to waiting. He waited to speak at meetings. He waited for his employees to turn up to work. He waited for his wife, his children, and his children’s many friends.

Now he was waiting in a Gringotts waiting room.

And while he was usually a very patient man, his patience was wearing thin. It wasn’t as though the matter he had to discuss with Lord Slytherin was a trivial matter.

His thoughts were interrupted when the door opened and a goblin female walked in. Floating-Interest, wasn’t it?

“Mister Weasley, I’m sorry to keep you waiting,” the goblin said, “but I’m afraid Lord Slytherin has run into a situation that is requiring his full attention.”

“What kind of situation—” he started, but didn’t get any further before the answer kicked the breath from his lungs.

“Lord Slytherin has been summoned by our king.”

Mister Weasley stared in horror. “Our king? As in, the Goblin King? The immortal Goblin King? The ruler of all goblins who hasn’t been seen by any wizard since the fall of the last Magical Empire?”

Floating-Interest nodded.

Mister Weasley leaned back heavily in his chair. Suddenly his own business with Lord Slytherin didn’t seem quite so Earth-shattering.

“I’m not sure how long he will be gone,” Floating-Interest concluded. “Will you be okay to wait? I can reschedule the room for another time if it’s inconvenient.”

“No, I’ll wait,” he said, now dabbing at his forehead with a handkerchief. “I can always get some parchment work done.”

“Very well.”

The door closed.

Arthur settled down, pulled out a self-inking quill and documents from his bag, and started going through them. The goblin king. Who’d have thought it.

“Father!” The door banged open.

As it turned out, he barely got five minutes work done before being interrupted again.

“Hello there, Bill. Are you supposed to be here? I thought you’d be working.”

The young man slammed his hands on the table. “Father, I beg you again to reconsider this.”

Arthur groaned. “Bill, we’ve been through this before. Our family is already tied to Slytherin. Ginny and Harry are very close friends and the twins’ business is all that’s keeping our family afloat. Without their efforts I’m not sure where we’d be. I know you feel a strong loyalty to the Light, but that doesn’t—”

“No!”

Arthur stopped in mid-flow.

“You still don’t understand,” Bill continued, slowly. “It’s not about the Light.”

Arthur frowned. “I thought you were talking about pro-muggleborn and half-blood policies that the Wizengamot should pass into—”

“No, I was talking about the working-class!”

Somewhere outside the room, a goblin guard chinked down the hallway.

Arthur looked puzzled. “But, Bill, the muggleborns and half-bloods do work, mostly. Most purebloods work too, come to that. I’m pureblood and I hope you know I work very hard. Even people like Lord Malfoy, curse his arse, work.”

“No, I mean the ones who work with the means of production owned by the bourgeoisie. They who own the tools to make the products which society needs.”

Arthur looked down at the ornate stick of wood held in his hand. “We all own our own wands...”

“No, I mean—” Bill looked around in frustration. “I mean—” his eyes fell on a little bowl on the table used for blood rituals. “I mean things like that! Family magics. Spells that only certain families can use. Working-class people are forced to work for those families because they can’t make those products on their own. Like the Chocolate Frog Partnership.”

Arthur Weasley frowned. “I know Edmund, though. He treats his people well.”

“That’s not the point.”

“What is the point?”

“The point is that you and the twins are moving us closer to those who oppress the people.”

Arthur shook his head. “This still all sounds very Light to me. I’m still not sure I see the difference.”

“The difference is that the Light are all employers! They don’t care about changing the system. They are the system.”

“Now, Bill, that’s not fair. Many Light families have given the ministry a lot over the years.”

“But only because they fear unregulated magic. The Light doesn’t care about giving back the means of production, they are just as greedy as the Dark.” He gave his father a significant look. “Or the Gray.”

Arthur sighed. “Even if your views don’t line up perfectly with the Light, they’ll still be your best bet at getting anything through the Wizengamot. Who knows, you may even find Lord Slytherin amenable to your ideas.”

“But that’s just it! The Wizengamot is part of the system. So it needs to go, too.”

Arthur Weasley just stared blankly at his firstborn son. As though he’d just proposed that they should move the Earth to a different star system. “Bill, I’m not sure where you’ve been getting these ideas, but I’m going to do what I feel is best for our family. Even if you dislike the idea.”

Bill hung his head. “Fine,” he said, quietly, and left.

Arthur sighed deeply. He looked down at the parchment in front of him — a conditional betrothal contract for Ginny’s hand with Harry Potter, just waiting for his signature and that of the Lord James Potter.

He wasn’t sure what miracles Lord Slytherin was going to pull off to get that signature, but for the sake of his family, he hoped the man didn’t fail — or come back from his meeting with the Goblin King missing both his arms.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“But I don’t know what to say!” Ginny wailed.

The Great hall was packed.

“It will be fine,” Luna comforted her. “Start out by promising everyone pudding. That always works.”

“But what if I mess up?”

Luna hugged her. “Just pretend it is a battle.”

“Pretend it’s a battle?” Ginny took a deep breath. “Right. I can do that. Just another fight. I’m good at fights.” A thought seemed to occur to her. “A fight with three-hundred Hogwarts students!” she wailed.

Luna slapped her.

“Ginny! Pudding!”

“Right, pudding. Right.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

The waiting room was vast.

Harry looked around with the clinical interest of one who expects to use every last artefact, pillar, rug, and seat in combat. He was masked again, though it hadn’t been needed. Despite waiting quite a while now he had yet to see a single other goblin.

The grand hallway had just two doors — the one behind him, which he’d entered through, and the one on the far side of the quidditch-pitch-sized cathedral.

Needless to say, he was deep, deep underground.

He didn’t even remember this part of the bank from his memories of when Voldemort sacked it in the last timeline.

Come to that, he didn’t remember anything about the Goblin King either.

Voldemort had never found him.

It was almost unnatural how quiet the hall was.

Experimentally, he reached into his robes, pulled out a sickle, and dropped it on the floor. The sound of silver hitting marble echoed throughout the massive space, followed shortly thereafter by the creak of the door behind him.

He turned.

It was Floating-Interest. “Mister Weasley says not to worry about him and to worry about yourself,” the gobliness said.

“Thank you.”

The gobliness shifted uneasily. “Also, I have been sent to tell you that it is time.”

“Good.” Harry rose from his seat. Standing at a little over six-foot, he towered over the four-foot Floating-Interest. “I was wondering if there was a problem.”

“No problem.” Floating-Interest motioned him to follow her up the hall, towards the door on the far side. “Just many things going on. The Goblin King is always very busy.”

They reached the door.

Floating-Interest took a deep breath. “The Goblin King shrouds himself in secrets within secrets.”

There was a strange ripple in the air and the door that had been there vanished — as did the rest of the far wall. And in its place.... It was like being on the inside of a life-sized children’s pop-up book. Suddenly, everything was everywhere.

Lord Slytherin tensed.

They were surrounded.

Sound assaulted his ears.

Colours flooded his brain.

And then his mind caught up with the pop-up book.

 Lord Slytherin relaxed, but only slightly.

They were surrounded, on all sides, by a veritable sea of goblins — female goblins. They lounged on cushions and chaise longues, eating grapes and looking sultry. A poet might have described them as nubile, if the poet in question had green skin, grew up underground, and enjoyed ritualistic combat to the death.

Harry was suddenly very glad he hadn’t done anything foolish while waiting for his summons and mentally increased the number of people he knew for certain could cast the fidelius charm in Magical Britain up to four, with another several probables.

Beside him, Floating-Interest noticeably fidgeted. Compared to what Harry could only imagine were the many concubines of a truly massive, and actually real, harem, Floating-Interest was dressed like a nun.

The many females surrounding them could probably have produced barely enough silk and golden chains between them to fully clothe a single human witch.

“Oh, Goblin King!” Floating-Interest intoned, raising a hand to her chest and producing a series of giggles from the females in the room. “I bring before you Lord Slytherin, as per your wish.”

“Thank you,” came the smooth reply from everywhere.

Harry stiffened again. Deep inside, the chimaera roared.

Harry liked to think of himself as an expert in making people wet themselves, in one way or another, with a voice deep enough to make the soul vibrate, but the Goblin King was in another league.

His voice was like having dark melted-chocolate, suffused with cinnamon and power, slowly dribbled into your ear.

One goblin girl sighed dreamily while staring at an empty point in space right in front of Harry. Although for the life of him, he couldn’t figure out why.

“Leave us,” the smooth voice commanded.

The smiles on the gobliness’ faces fell. One by one, they trailed out of the room, into the darkness beyond, where Harry could not see, until it was just him and Ragnok’s granddaughter.

“You too, Floating-Interest,” The Goblin King whispered, somehow making it sound more like a proposition to bed than a command to be left alone.

Floating-Interest curtsied shakily and backed out of the room by the way they’d both come.

Two clicks indicated two doors locking.

Once they were alone, the Goblin King laughed like a waterfall of chocolate splashing into a pond of diamonds. “I am not an incubus, Lord Slytherin.”

Harry started. How had he known that was exactly the thought that had been going through his head?

“I cannot read minds, either. Not any better than any abnormally skilled legilimens, anyway.”

Harry pulled himself together. “I imagine being immortal gives one plenty of time to master a wide range of interesting skills.”

“A few.” The voice sounded amused now.

Well, that was better than angry. Probably.

“Let us cut the chase, Lord Slytherin,” The Goblin King continued. “Ragnok has told me of the war that came before. He has told me of what he knows of your past timelines. He has told me of the sacking of Gringotts.”

An acknowledgement of something he would want to avoid. That was good.

“But yours is not the only voice I hear, Lord Slytherin.”

That was not so good.

“You returned to the past and changed many things. Your political movements in Magical Britain have already had profound effects. My agents throughout the world whisper of the rise of Gray Lords from Sub-Saharan Africa to Japan and Peru. When Magical Britain coughs, the rest of the world catches a cold.”

“I’ve met one of them,” Harry replied through his mask. “Gray Lord Tebola. A bit on the nose for someone who can turn into a Tebo.”

 The Goblin King snorted. “When the last Magical British Empire fell, the ICW gave Gringotts statehood within Magical Britain as one of the terms of surrender. Magical Britain had proven it could not be trusted to manage the world’s magical economy and Nicolas Flamel agreed to never again use his stone to make gold, outside of a ‘small’ stipend for his own personal use.”

Harry said nothing.

“And now here you are, Lord Slytherin — wanting to use my bank to funnel money from the muggle world to the magical. You want to do this so that you can fund a war that will most likely see a new hegemony rise on the British Isles.”

“I want to funnel the money so that I don’t have to fight a war,” Harry immediately countered.

“But you don’t deny the hegemony bit.”

Harry bit his tongue.

The Goblin King sighed. “For me to give my blessing to this endeavour could be incredibly costly to me and my people. We exist at the blessing of the ICW. The Ministry of Magic would love to annex Gringotts. For us to make such a risky move, we would have to be compensated with something equally valuable.”

Silence.

“What kind of equally valuable thing?” Harry asked.

“The mist jewels.”

Shit.

“I know what happened on the night you became animagi, Lord Slytherin.”

How?!

“All our records suddenly declared him to not exist. Not dead, but actually not existing. And during the magical storm, as well. It doesn’t take an auditor with high-level occlumency to figure it out.”

Ahh.

“We quickly altered the records so that the ministry would not find out.”

“Thank you.”

“Daniel Granger is a valuable customer of the bank. Many of my people have already spilt blood fighting over his account. I suspect, in the future, that number will only grow.”

More silence.

Harry got the impression the Goblin King was looking for the right words.

“The mist jewel you found is lost,” the voice eventually continued. “That is unfortunate, but it does present an opportunity for us. We now have a powerful wizard who knows of the mist-jewels’ true nature and what they can do. Most of our human contractors — your friend’s brother, Bill Weasley, for example — they believe we like the jewels because they are shiny. Or if they have other suspicions, they keep it to themselves. They are useful in locating some of the more simple to find mist-jewels, such as those buried in the curse-filled tombs of Egypt. But others... they are rather more difficult to acquire.”

“And you want a more powerful wizard on call to help you acquire them?” Harry asked.

“Yes.”

“And in return for this, you will assist in smuggling more money into Magical Britain than ICW regulations normally allow.”

“Yes.”

“I do have an extremely busy schedule.”

“I am aware. I would respect your schedule and only call on you for moderately short time periods at irregular intervals.”

Harry nodded. “No longer than three days per call. And no two calls within two months of each other. Five calls total.”

“Seven,” was the immediate reply. “And I will grant you a five-month grace period before your contract becomes active. I understand you have a lot on your plate right now.”

Harry thought about it. “That seems acceptable.”

“Good. And one more condition.” The voice changed from dark chocolate to steel. “You must not speak of this deal to anyone who does not already know the nature of the mist-jewels or who does not know your plans for your gold. Not to anyone! And if you must speak of them, you MUST speak of them only under fidelius. Do not even hint of them at any other time. Is that clear?”

Harry nodded.

“Wonderful.” And just like that, the voice was back to its usual ear-dribbly chocolate tones. “I look forward to having you around to clean up my problems, Lord Slytherin. Good help is so hard to find these days. Floating-Interest will have your contract ready for you soon.”

That sounded like a dismissal if ever he heard one.

“And one last thing, Lord Slytherin.”

Harry stopped in the act of turning around.

“Beware of the Family Magics of the Unspeakables.”

Two clicks indicated two doors unlocking and the goblin females swayed and sashayed back into the hall, draping themselves on the many rugs and cushions. A pair walked straight towards Harry before suddenly vanishing. The sounds of feminine giggling filled the room, and not just from the empty space that his brain refused to acknowledge.

Back in the entrance corridor, Harry closed the door behind him to find Floating-Interest waiting for him.

“Have you ever seen the Goblin King?” he asked.

Floating-Interest shook her head. “I have never had that honour.”

Harry grunted. There was no way it wasn’t an incubus. There was absolutely no way.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“Is this really okay?” John asked.

Virgo smirked. “Trust me. It’s all going according to plan.”

“But... Ginny.”

The smirk dropped from Virgo’s face. “John, I understand how you feel, but you have to understand, she is the enemy now.”

John winced. “And it’s not just that. Sally and Hannah have been asking very difficult questions. I know what we’re doing, but keeping them on board is very difficult when I can’t tell them what we’re up to. They keep saying making you minister is throwing the game.”

“They trust you, don’t they?”

“Well, yeah.”

“And they really trust Susan.”

The two looked towards where Susan, Sally, Hannah, and Professor Sprout were busy overseeing a group of Ravenclaws putting their names into the Goblet of Fire.

John nodded. “Yeah, they do. She’s pretty amazing like that.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Deep under the streets of London, two men carefully eyed each other over a goblin-wrought-iron table.

One was dressed in an old, but well-worn robe that had clearly once been a serious investment, but which by now had been patched so many times as to be more patch than robe.

The other was dressed without so much as a speck of dust anywhere on his person. Black dragon hide could be seen hiding beneath spider silk and niffler fur. He was also masked.

Between them, lay a small stack of Gringotts contract parchment, filled with tiny ink-quill scrawl. On the top of the parchment read, Betrothal Contract Between the Ancient House of Weasley and the Ancient and Noble House of Potter for the Hand of Ginevra Molly Weasley to Harry James Potter.

Of course, Harry’s name had one extra name after that, but thankfully the Albion Family Magics could be relied on to identify him correctly.

“I hope you don’t find my question presumptuous, Mister Weasley,” Lord Slytherin rumbled. “But have you not considered replacing your wardrobe? I know you can afford it.”

Arthur Weasley smiled. “Molly sewed every patch on this robe by hand. No magic. I will get rid of it when Death walks through the Veil.”

“That’s a level of loyalty I can respect.”

Arthur nodded. “I love all my family. And I do what I have to do to protect them. Not all my children are happy with what we are discussing, but if it means Ginny has a future, then it is what must be done.”

“What does your wife feel?”

“Molly thinks Ginny is too young to be contracted, but she has accepted that it is necessary.” He gave the tiniest of smirks. “You will need to warn young Harry that when you deliver on your half of our agreement, he will have to deal with the full scope of her attentions.”

“Young Harry will handle it, I’m sure. I consider him to be my own flesh and blood.”

Arthur’s smirk turned into a smile.

“I hope our talks here are not hurting you too badly,” Lord Slytherin continued. “I know how important it is for a head of house to consider family unity.”

The smile faded. Arthur sighed. “Bill is young and headstrong. He travelled widely after Hogwarts, doing odd jobs for Dumbledore — picked up some very odd ideas from some of the people he met. Charlie was practically his brother’s shadow until he got that job offer from the Romanian Dragon Preserve. Percy has big ambitions in the ministry and being Light aligned only helps there — at least, on the outside. The twins you know, of course, and Ronald is still finding his feet. But he is close friends with John Potter, so I doubt he’ll take this well. No, we haven’t told him yet — just Bill and Charlie. As for Ginny, well.... Childhood friends, am I right?” He smiled tiredly.

Lord Slytherin picked up the contract. “I think I hate seeing families fall out,” he muttered. “If you need any help, do not hesitate to reach out.” He handed over the contract.

Arthur smiled. “Thank you. I’ll keep it in mind. There is nothing I will not do to keep my family together. Nothing.” He took the blood quill on the table and put it on the line marked, Mister Arthur Weasley, just below the spot marked, Lord James Potter. He signed.

Lord Slytherin took the contract and stowed it away in a pocket of his robe.

Arthur stood up and extended a hand. “For the sake of my daughter’s future, I hope you can work a miracle and secure that other signature.”

“I will.”

Arthur hesitated. A look of uncertainty took over his face. “I know that we’re committed now, but do you really think Lord Potter will accept Ginny’s bride price at 10,000 galleons?”

Beneath the mask, Harry smirked. “Ginny has the hallmarks of an incredible witch. Driven, talented, hardworking, fearless, and ruthless. Harry will be a very lucky boy.”

“Yes, but do you think Lord Potter will see it that way?”

“I will endeavour to persuade him. And I trust Ginny as well as Harry. I’m sure she’s not going to do anything that will make this any harder than it needs to be.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

A cheer sounded throughout the Hogwarts Great Hall — students on their feet, clapping, cheering, whistling.

At the very back of the hall, Daphne sat at the end of the Slytherin table, poker-faced and wooden.

“And if you elect me minister, I’ll double our quidditch matches!”

Another cheer.

“And I’ll arrange field trips into the Forbidden Forest!”

Another cheer.

Ginny looked around the raised dais at the front of the room, eyes dilated, breathing heavy. She caught Luna’s eye who gave her an encouraging nod.

“And... and... Pudding at every meal!”

The crowd roared.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Outside of Gringotts, Harry was brought up short by a figure waiting for him that he had not anticipated. “Lord Black? I was not expecting—“

Exactly what it was he was not expecting he never managed to reveal. The reason for this being that of all the things he wasn’t expecting, he really wasn’t expecting to be pulled into a tight hug.

He instantly went stiff.

“Listen, Slytherin,” Lord Black whispered into his ear, voice thick with emotion. Already people were staring. “I know exactly what you’re doing. I don’t like politics, but I’m not clueless. I know you’re courting me for the Gray. And I know you’re using my daughter to do it. But I still appreciate your helping her, okay? But know this, hurt her and I will kill you.”

“I hear you.”

Lord Black pulled away, face now rather embarrassed.

Harry felt the telltale feeling of accumulating apparition magic and a second later he was staring once again at an only moderately packed Diagon Alley, much of which was now staring at him. It wasn’t every day you saw the Chief Auror hug Lord Slytherin.

Well, Harry thought. They’d already watched said Chief Auror break the apparition rules in Diagon Alley. Not much harm in emulation.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

The Great Hall was silent. All eyes were on the front. Travers had already given his speech — a plain and boring affair compared to the quidditch match that was Ginny Weasley — and now everyone wanted to see how the Malfoy daughter would fare.

No one at the Gryffindor table seemed surprised when Virgo produced, of all things, a rather beat-up violin.

When the girl put the chin rest to her neck without saying a word, a pair of older Ravenclaw giggled.

The giggling stopped the moment the first note played.

Across the hall, several sets of occlumency shields immediately slammed shut tight, but even they weren’t enough to completely keep out the sorrowful melody that began to pour forth.

The music didn’t force the listener to relive their worst experience over and over again.

It wasn’t a dementor’s aura.

But it did reach right down into the very soul through the ears, bypassing the conscious brain and pulled at the collective hurt of a lifetime of disappointment.

Then, slowly, with the skill of the talented prodigy, Virgo pulled the song from sorrow to anger, then from anger to hate, stabbing at her instrument like a betrayed lover. Then came the agony, echoing around the Great Hall, gaining speed and power, moving to violence, and finally from violence to victory and triumph, a last long deceleration to the world that evil was vanquished and good restored.

The final note played.

The hall became deathly still.

“When you vote me as student minister,” Virgo said. “I will right all that is wrong. That is all.” She then turned and left the hall.

Shocked in silence, the students all looked at each other.

At the Slytherin table, Daphne Greengrass frowned. Very impressive, as they should expect from the Dark Lord’s horcrux. But would it be good enough?

As the students started to file out and the caskets for voting were dragged in and lined up next to the now full Goblet of Fire, Daphne motioned for Ginny to join her.

It was time for her betrothed’s little ninja to prove her usefulness.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Alex pouted. “Why is it you get the mission?”

“Oh, come off it, Alex,” Ginny replied, pulling on a pair of acromantula silk leggings. “This needs stealth and sneakiness. You do stealth like an obscurial in a wand shop.”

“I can be sneaky!”

“Luna, can Alex be sneaky?”

“No,” Luna chirped.

Alex looked betrayed. “Luna!”

“—She falls on her enemies like an obsidian swarm.”

“Well, I guess that’s fine,” Alex mumbled.

Ginny finished donning her ‘creeping around the place’ outfit. “Anyway, the mission needs someone really good at the switching charm, and we all know who that is.”

Alex frowned. “Is that really going to work though? Surely any competent vote counter will notice something strange like that.”

“Oh, don’t worry. Harry made sure to have Lockhart pick the absolute best candidate to be in charge of counting.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“Right’o,” said a rather uncertain Rubeus Hagrid, sitting down at the massive table in the Grand Hall. Most of the students were taking advantage of their Saturday afternoon to be elsewhere. “Guess I’d better be making a start of it.” In front of him sat three massive caskets, each one labelled with a candidate name and each one securely closed with chains.

These lasted about as long as it took the half-giant to get his dustbin-lid sized hands on them. Moments later, the contents of all three were in a pile on the table.

“Oh dear... all these little pieces of parchment.” A tongue came out the side of his mouth as he managed to pick one up with the air of an industrial robot lifting an egg. “Let’s see who this is. Ginny!” He frowned. “Nice girl, from what I’ve seen. Shame she’s in Slytherin. Used to know ‘er brother Charlie, you know. Gave him a recommendation for the dragon reserve, I did. Merlin, I’d love a dragon...”

“Hagrid,” said Professor McGonagall in a tired voice. “You’re supposed to count the votes, not yell them out for the whole hall to hear.”

“Oh, right, errr, sorry, Professor.”

As Professor McGonagall left the Great Hall table, a shadow in the air slipped past the temporary ward line that had been set up to keep inquisitive students out. Two shadows in the air, in fact.

Hagrid frowned at the next piece of parchment. “Virgo. Odd that. Never heard of a Malfoy in Gryffindor before. Can’t say she doesn’t play nice music though. Very relaxing. And she is friends with John, so she can’t be that bad. I’ll have to get John to bring ‘err ‘round for tea sometime.”

The two shadows circled around the table from opposite sides, each approaching Hagrid from behind.

Each shadow noticed the other at almost exactly the same time.

Both shadows froze.

“Now, what about that third one... Travers. Slytherin name that.” Hagrid looked urgently around the sparsely populated hall. “Not that there’s anything wrong with Slytherin,” he said loudly and clearly to the rafters. “There’s always lots of funny folk around. I’m sure he’s a right nice evil mask once you get to know him.”

One of the older Hufflepuffs doing homework halfway up his table face-palmed.

Behind Hagrid, the two shadows had carefully edged towards each other with the air of two fog-mired armies who aren’t quite sure if the shapes before them are going to start cheering or shooting.

“My lord?” Ginny whispered.

There was a pause. Then, “You wish, Weasley.”

Ginny nearly bit her tongue off. “You,” she hissed. Of course the diary would want to make sure it won. But wait... didn’t that mean...?

“Here to make sure you win, huh?” Virgo whispered back. “How Slytherin of you.”

Ginny snorted. “Actually, I’m here to make sure you win.”

In front of them, Hagrid started to whistle while he opened another piece of parchment.

There was another pause.

“So, Greengrass has that much faith in her political sense.”

Ginny felt a jolt of irritation. “Shouldn’t she?”

“I’m sure she knows what she’s doing. In any case, it seems that this time we’re going to be working together.”

Ginny said nothing. She may not be the political animal Harry had trained Daphne to be, but she still had more than enough sense not to take that bait.

She then felt an incredibly intricate and sophisticated magical intent form on the enemy wand in front of her. Just like that, many of the names in the pile rewrote themselves in their original handwriting from Ginny to Virgo.

Ginny scowled. Feeling incredibly annoyed, she flicked her wrist and the one parchment that Hagrid had just picked up switched likewise.

“Not bad for a peasant girl.”

“Not bad for a thing that shouldn’t exist,” Ginny shot back.

Another pause.

When Virgo next spoke it was with exactly the viciousness that Ginny would expect from the teenage Dark Lord.

“Tell your lord that when I’m done with him, Lovegood’s theory of feminine fucktoy-ness will be true, because the only way he will dig himself out of the hole that I will dig for him, will be by whoring you both out to anyone who wants a go.”

Ginny struggled to restrain herself. The diary was trying to rile her up. It wanted her to attack it. It wanted her to blow her cover. She wouldn’t! She was better than that. But still, it took every speck of iron discipline she’d gathered over the years not to pull out the dagger strapped to her inner-thigh and finish off the job she’d failed to complete at the start of the year. She contented herself instead with spitting right in the other shadow’s face, then instantly switching the spit with the contents of a nearby pitcher of water.

As the two shadows parted ways, Virgo made her way to the base of Gryffindor Tower before relusioning herself. Her face was red, pupils dilated, clothes heavy, and not just with water from the pitcher. Her entire body felt clammy with sweat.

Virgo wrung out the cuffs of her robe and took a long calming breath.

Had she really just said that?!

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Daphne, Alex, Luna, and Hermione all looked up as Ginny sat down at the Slytherin table in the Great Hall.

“Is it done?” Daphne asked.

“It is done,” Ginny answered.

“Good.” Daphne smirked. “Hogwarts is ours. This battle is over.”

“I just wish we could move more openly,” Alex said, sounding miffed. “We all know what that girl is.”

“Patience,” Daphne replied. “Her time will come.”

The other girls all nodded.

“Miss Greengrass?” rasped a voice that rattled with chains. The Bloody Baron floated over their table. “Miss Weasley. Miss Black. May I ask you all to accompany me. Thank you.” He turned and floated off.

The three girls extracted themselves from their benches and marched after him.

“May I ask what this is about?” Daphne asked, reaching the Baron’s stride just as they were leaving the hall.

“You have a visitor.”

“Who?” Alex asked.

“Your father.”

Alex stopped in her tracks. “What?”

“It must be about the animagus forms,” Ginny called back to her over her shoulder.

Alex groaned.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“I’m not saying it’s not an amazing achievement,” said Professor McGonagall, nose flaring. “But the sheer irresponsibility of it! The danger they put themselves in!”

“Yes, Professor McGonagall,” Sirius replied, head down. He couldn’t quite shake the ridiculousness of the situation. Here he was, Chief Auror, the Hammer of the Light, the most bad-ass fighter the ministry could field, getting a dressing down from a witch who probably couldn’t even lift his shield without a feather charm.

“If it was up to me, I’d have them all in detention from now until year’s end.”

“Yes, Professor McGonagall.” It was the reflex of the situation, is what it was. His old head of house’s office just brought out the little school boy in him. He and the gang had been in here more than enough times during their time at Hogwarts.

“I suspected they were on mandrake more than once! How they got that past me, I’ve no idea.”

Sirius couldn’t help smirk. If Alex were smart, she’d have used the same sticking charm on the roof of the mouth trick that he’d used. His daughter may have lacked the traditional lessons from him, but clearly she’d been managing.

“Are you smiling, Black?!”

“No, Professor.”

“You are smiling. I can see your lips.”

The smirk turned into a grin.

Professor McGonagall sighed. “Well, I suppose—”

She was interrupted by the door to her office creaking open.

Three witches entered. The first one walked in as though she owned the world. The next darted in behind her. The final one slouched through the gap like a criminal on her way to the executioner’s block.

“Miss Greengrass. Miss Weasley. Miss Black.” McGonagall glared at the three girls who lined up in front of the desk. “I’ve no doubt you all know why you are here.”

“Yes,” answered the Greengrass girl — the one betrothed to Lord Slytherin. “We are here to fulfil our legal obligations to the ministry as is our duty as good citizens of Magical Britain.”

Sirius let out a silent groan.

McGonagall’s nostrils flared. “Miss Greengrass. Your extracurricular project, while it may have been legal, was still very much against school rules. The animagus transformation is incredibly dangerous. An adult novice can face permanent damage if they are incautious. And you are all second and first years! It is incredibly difficult. So, what do you have to say for yourself?”

Ginny put up a hand. “Go us?”

McGonagall turned her glare on her. “Miss Weasley, given how distressed your mother and father were after your last quidditch match, I’d have thought you would be willing to show more caution and common sense.”

Ginny shrunk back a little.

“And what about you, Miss Black? Do you have anything to add?”

Sirius tried to catch his daughter’s eye, but she had her face turned away. Wasn’t she going to look at him at all?

“Not really,” she muttered.

“Not really?! You violated school rules, smuggled in a controlled medical drug that is suffering from a global supply shortage, performed magic in class under the influence of a hallucinogenic, and then performed partial self-transfiguration on yourself for who knows how long without a healer on standby if anything went wrong! I’d expect this sort of thing from other students—from other families, maybe—but you are a Black. I’d expect you to know better.”

Sirius stopped trying to catch Alex’s eye.

He turned very slowly towards his old professor.

“Excuse me?”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“—other families, maybe—But you are a Black. I’d expect you to know better.”

Ginny put a hand over her mouth while her eyes darted to Alex. She did not just say that, did she?

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“Excuse me?”

Lord Black stiffened.

Daphne smirked. That seemed to have struck a nerve.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Alex was not looking forward to this meeting.

As she slouched her way through into Professor McGonagall’s office... yes, there was her father, standing behind the teacher’s desk, looking like the head boy, come to report on a bunch of unruly students.

Never mind the fact that he was a lord.

Never mind the fact that he was Head of the Most Ancient and Noble House of Black.

She knew he hadn’t been head boy, of course, but that didn’t change the comparison.

And of course, he did nothing as Professor McGonagall laid into them, just stood there like a fool. Nothing like Lord Slytherin. Or even Harry, for that matter. At least when Harry did nothing it was because he was deploying cunning. She wished he would stop trying to catch her eye. He was so desperate for approval.

“And what about you, Miss Black? Do you have anything to add?”

“Not really,” she muttered.

The admonitions continued, and Alex couldn’t help but wonder what the point of it all was. It wasn’t as if McGonagall could do anything except dock points. If they got detention, Harry could just have the Bloody Baron overrule them, if he was feeling generous. But that was the point. Harry might or might not do something like that, but it wasn’t because he was afraid.

Not like someone she knew.

“I’d expect this sort of thing from other students—from other families, maybe—but you are a Black. I’d expect you to know better.”

Her father slowly turned towards Professor McGonagall like a ship’s gun being brought to bear on an enemy vessel.

“Excuse me?” he growled.

What happened next was not what Alex was expecting. What she expected was for her father to continue on as he always did — about as effectual and empathic as a dead dog.

Alex turned her head forward in total shock as her father started laying into their professor with all the hesitation of a blasting curse.

By her face, it certainly wasn’t what Professor McGonagall expected, either.

Alex had never before seen her father this angry.

“And I don’t care if it was dangerous!” he roared, getting redder and more out of breath as he worked himself up. “I did the same when I was her age, and, you know what? I’m proud of her! More than that! She’s younger than I was by a long way! You want to rag on her, fine, but don’t you dare rag on her for being a Black! Have you ever read my family’s library? No, you haven’t! So, you’ve no idea what kind of things we got up to! My animagus transformation was the only thing my parents ever praised me for after I was sorted into Gryffindor! Did you know that, huh? And you know what? If Alex does more of that, I don’t care. You hear that, Alex? I don’t care. And when we get home, I’ll open up the ritual room again, oh yes, and I’ll show you some of the stuff our family has, because you know what, you’re clearly ready for it. Yeah. And you, Professor — your job here is to oversee your student’s completion of the animagus transformation that they’re registering, as the law requires. So start overseeing!”

If Alex wasn’t expecting the rant, Professor McGonagall certainly wasn’t. She was leaning back, eyes wide. When her father stopped shouting and started breathing heavily, there was a momentary pause while everyone waited to see if more was forthcoming.

When it was clear it wasn’t, McGonagall, rather flustered, readjusted her bun and cleared her throat. “Miss Greengrass, if you would.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Students filed into the great hall.

They took their seats and waited expectantly.

Tracey fidgeted nervously at the front of the hall.

Daphne and the other girls weren’t back yet. If they didn’t arrive soon, they’d miss the judging of the judges.

The Goblet of Fire flared blue.

And Daphne still was nowhere to be seen.

Oh, well. Nothing to be done.

The goblet ejected a slightly singed piece of parchment.

Tracey snatched it out of the air while the now assembled students looked on intensely. It was no wonder why. This would be the only chance many of the common born would have to be involved in the student government.

She read the parchment and suppressed a wince.

“The position of chief judge will be... Heiress Susan Bones!”

Applause and cheering — some polite, some enthused.

John Potter jumped onto the table and cheered louder than anyone.

Tracey nodded as Susan joined her up at the front of the hall. It would be good to get this over with so they could get onto the important business of announcing the heads of departments.

The goblet of fire flared blue again.

But rather than one parchment being ejected, instead, there were two.

The chattering of the hall died.

Everyone stared.

Seconds later, the goblet of fire died as well, its flames snuffed out like a candle being blown.

Tracey caught both parchments in her hand and frowned. Yes, they were supposed to get two more judges but why both at the same time? She opened them and understanding dawned. Twins.

Tracey raised her head and took a deep breath. “And the last two judge spots will be taken by... Marigold and Violet Chesterfield!”

The hall erupted into confusion. Some cheered and clapped while others looked at each other, nonplussed. One Ravenclaw sixth year exclaimed, “Is that stupid goblet saying two first-year Muggleborns have better judgement than me?!”

Marigold skipped up to the front dais with her sister walking behind. She wrapped her arm around a shocked Susan’s waist and beamed at the crowd. “Thank you everyone! We’re here till Tuesday! Mugglepuff Powaaaaarrr!”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“A very impressive form, Miss Greengrass,” Professor McGonagall muttered. “One final measurement — total wingspan, if you would, please?”

The golden eagle puffed out her chest and spread her wings.

“2.18 meters,” the older witch muttered. “That seems to be in order. Thank you.”

Daphne crouched down on her summoned perch, leapt off, and transformed mid-air, landing lightly on her feet.

“May I be excused, Professor?” she asked. “I can’t afford to miss the vote.”

“Won’t you wait for Miss Weasley? Surely the same applies to her.”

Daphne smiled. “I assure you that will not be a problem.”

McGonagall sighed. “Very well. Miss Weasley, you next please.”

Daphne left.

On the other side of the room, two grims were awkwardly sitting on the floor next to each other.

“Woof?” one asked, sounding nervous.

“Woof.” the other answered, deadpan.

“Woof?” the first asked again.

Alex transformed back into a human and glared at the questioning grim next to her. “You know I can’t understand what you’re asking! So unless that question was about your suddenly growing a spine...”

Sirius transformed back next to her, sitting cross-legged, hand behind his head. “Look, Alex, I’m not promising everything, but...”

Alex looked away. “You know, I already learned a load of the family rituals.”

Silence fell between them while Ginny the cheetah was measured and inspected.

“Alex,” Sirius said. “I just want to say that I’m proud. I completed my animagus transformation in fifth year. I know how hard it is. And you did it without family help. Without our shortcuts.”

“Very nice looking teeth, Miss Weasley. You must make sure to keep them clean.”

Alex slowly turned towards her father. “Shortcuts?! I didn’t find—” She bit her tongue, looking angry at herself.

Sirius smiled wanly. “I hear you’re going to be in the duelling tournament this year.”

“Yeah. Are you coming? —Not that I care,” she quickly added.

“Yes, I will, I promise.”

Alex harrumphed. “I’m going to smash your old record.”

“I’m looking forward to it.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Hagrid coughed loudly. The whole Great Hall fell silent. “It’s Miss Virgo Malfoy.”

The Gryffindors erupted in cheers.

Virgo stalked up to the front podium, “Thank you, everyone,” she said. “And now let me announce my wardrobe.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“For Magical Games and Sports, Ginevra Weasley.”

Daphne clapped politely.

“For Control of Magical Creatures, Sophie Roper.”

Next to her, Hermione and Luna were also clapping.

“For Prevention of Magical Catastrophes... Luna Lovegood.”

Luna cheered as many uncertain eyes turned to her.

“Slytherin, help us all,” Hermione muttered.

“For the Department of Family Affairs, my brother, Draco Malfoy.”

“For Magical Trade and Crafts, Theodore Nott.”

Hermione leaned towards Daphne. “I can’t believe she would be so stupid as to not see how this is worse for their side.”

Daphne sniffed in return.

“For the Department of Mysteries, John Potter.”

Another loud cheer from the Gryffindors.

“For the Department of Magical Law Enforcement, Susan Bones.”

Daphne caught Hermione’s eye. Neither needed to say what the other was thinking, even while the Hufflepuffs cheered. “Congratulations on scoring a job that will be useless if you’re ineffective and horrifically unpopular if you are.”

“And finally, for the position of International Magical Cooperation, Heiress Pansy Parkinson. Chief Warlock, the floor is yours again.”

Daphne nodded. The battle was won. The Hogwarts student leadership was theirs. Harry would be pleased.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

A week later, applause broke out among the gathered wizards and witches at an informal gathering at Malfoy Manor.

At the top of the large stairway leading down to the ballroom, Virgo stood in her best dress robes and smiled.

“Lords and Ladies,” said Lucius to the assemblage, holding up a half-full glass of red wine. “It gives me great pleasure and honour to present to you, my daughter, the first-ever student minister of Hogwarts school of Witchcraft and Wizardry!”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

The lords and ladies of the Light applauded as Virgo pushed open a pair of upstairs doors and walked out onto the balcony.

“My friends and colleagues, wizards and witches!” James Potter called out across the ballroom of Potter Manor, “A close friend of my family, a personal confidant of my son and rightful heir, and possibly one day, even more — Miss Virgo Malfoy, the first-ever student minister in a thousand years of Hogwarts history!”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“And do you have any final words you’d like to give our readers?” asked Rita Skeeter with a sly smile.

 The loud machinery of the Lovegood printing press next door clanked and whirred through the thin walls of the Daily Prophet HQ.

“Any tips or advice for anyone wanting to do what you’ve achieved?”

Virgo smiled back. “I think it’s incredibly important to be who you are. If you dream hard enough, and follow your star, anyone can do anything.”

“Very sentimental,” Rita murmured. She snapped her notebook shut. “Thank you for a good story, Miss Malfoy.”

Minutes later the girl was out of her office.

Rita collapsed in her chair and poured herself a double vodka. Magical Merlin, that girl was slippery. It took one to know one.

Several hours later, Rita did a double take as she realised that her almost empty desk had a new addition. A small cigar box now lay there, locked with magic.

No matter how much she tried over the next few hours, nothing she did could break it. The only clue was the writing on the top.

‘Be ready. I will open when the time is right.’

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“Are you sure you don’t want an escort to Gryffindor Tower, Miss Malfoy,” asked Professor McGonagall.

“No thank you. I should be okay.”

“As you wish.”

Virgo let out a sigh of exhaustion as the professor left her alone. The front doors of Hogwarts closed behind her. No one ever said being the greatest witch who ever lived was easy, and if they did, they were a fool.

Halfway to Gryffindor Tower, she stopped dead in a darkened hallway. The fact that it was darkened was a huge clue.

“Miss Virgo Malfoy,” spoke a rumble from the darkness.

Virgo’s adrenaline started to pump.

Lord Slytherin (Harry Potter) stepped out of the shadows. The fact that Greengrass was behind him, looking somewhat sheepish, settled her anxiety a little, but not by much.

“Lord Slytherin,” she echoed. The words, ‘what do you want?,’ were on the tip of her tongue, but at the last moment they changed to, “To what do I owe this pleasure?”

“Nothing much,” Slytherin answered. “Have you been enjoying yourself since you became student minister?”

“Enjoying might not be the right word. It is hard work.”

“Indeed. And so much of that hard work seems to take place outside of Hogwarts, too.” He glanced at Daphne who, if anything, looked even more embarrassed.

Virgo smirked. “Did the little general finally realise there was more than one battlefield to fight over?”

Daphne flashed her a look of pure anger.

“No one is perfect, Miss Malfoy. We all make mistakes. I make mistakes, Daphne makes mistakes. Even you make mistakes. I have several mistakes in mind, in fact. I cannot prove that you made them, of course. You are clearly having a good time. Nevertheless, consider this a warning. If you continue to ‘make mistakes,’ then...”

He reached into the folds of his robe and pulled out a muggle-looking paper diary. He slowly tore it in two in front of her and let the halves drop to the floor.

Daphne leaned forward. “You’re going to tear up her diary?” she asked in a puzzled voice.

“Yes, Daphne,” Lord Slytherin replied, deadpan. “That’s exactly what I’m going to do. I’m going to tear up her diary. Because that’s the kind of evil man I am. That’s how I make threats to pre-teen witches. I threaten to tear up their diaries.”

“Why not just apply a spanking hex?”

“That would be at least a level-four punishment.”

The sardonic back and forth between the two continued on for quite some time, getting more and more over the top as they went, but Virgo was buying none of it. It was clearly an act for anyone who might view these memories later on.

“Lord Slytherin,” Virgo interrupted them.

The two stopped and turned to her.

“Message received,” she bit out, before turning and heading in a completely different direction than the one she’d been intending on.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

In the Room of Requirement, John and Susan were alone and busy. Homework sat finished to one side, and now both were working on paperwork for the Student Wardrobe. Nothing major had happened yet and everyone was still very much feeling out their positions. That was sure to change though.

At that moment, the door burst open, and Virgo stormed in.

Both John and Susan spun around.

“Did you plant the story with the Prophet?” John asked.

“Why are you still wearing your travel robes?” Susan added.

Virgo growled. “Your brother needs to be dealt with.”

“Isn’t that the plan?” Susan asked. “You anonymously deliver all the details to the papers and then we wait for the perfect opportunity when Slytherin gets some bad press.”

“We need it done faster!” Virgo shouted. “We can’t just wait around for an opportunity to present itself. We need a way to make Slytherin look bad now!”

From all around the Room of Requirement came the sound of stone grinding against stone.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

No one quite knows how luck magic works — though the effects, over the years, have been dramatic. Some theorise it bends the universe around the subject, ever so slightly, like gravity. Others, that it gives Fate more leeway to act in our world. Either way, the results can turn up at any time and in the least expected places.

From all around the Room of Requirement came the sound of stone grinding against stone.

Susan dropped her quill.

John’s breath drew in sharply.

Virgo’s eyes widened.

Behind the podium the three had used to hold meetings for the Light, a stone portal ground itself into sight. Stone snakes pushed out through the cracks in the wall, forcing it open, making room for a large circular stone door, covered in more stone snakes.

“Umm...” Susan started.

Virgo and John’s eyes met.

“Is that, you know, the entrance?” Susan continued. “To the chamber?”

“It’s one entrance,” Virgo said, eyes locked with John. “One I didn’t know about. The others have all been sealed by John’s brother.”

John’s eyes widened slightly. “Of course. You know what the monster is, don’t you?”

“I do.”

“Can you control it?” His words were eager.

Virgo smirked, even as her heart started beating faster, and the adrenaline started flowing. “I’m willing to give it a shot.”

“H-hang on!” Susan darted between the two. “Are we seriously considering this? This is the Chamber of Secrets we’re talking about here. That thing is supposed to kill people!”

Both Virgo and John were silent for a moment. Virgo didn’t need legilimency to know they were both thinking the same thing. That there was at least one death neither would mind. On the other hand, one had to work with the team one had.

“It doesn’t have to kill,” Virgo eventually said. “The monster has a ‘safe mode’. So long as I can control it, no one has to die. We just need to set a trap, that’s all.”

“I don’t like this,” Susan muttered.

Virgo focused and shifted into her lamia form. Her massive tail snaked out across the floor and around a nearby training dummy. §Open§ she hissed.

The stone snakes acting as a lock on the portal all slithered aside and the doorway opened to reveal a massive pipe heading straight downwards into dark, inky blackness. A small stone teetered over the edge, then fell. The sound of bouncing rock against metal echoed for quite some time.

“Oh, I really don’t like this.”

“Don’t be a pussy,” Virgo hissed. “Just get on. Thisss way wasss made for Sssnakesss.”

Reluctantly, Susan joined John on Virgo’s back and the three slithered their way straight down into the blackness of the Slytherin pipe network.

As they neared the entrance to the chamber proper, Virgo began to have doubts. She could hear whisperings. Whisperings that were getting stronger.

§Release me!§ I am king!§ Only one king!§ One true king!§ This nest is MINE!§

Virgo paused at what had to be the final extra secret entrance to the Chamber of Secrets. “Close your eyesss, both of you. Just to be sssafe.”

“Virgo, what is the monster?” Susan asked.

“Thousand-year-old Basilisk.”

Both Susan and John let out shocked chokes, but it was too late to object. Virgo was already slithering through as the door opened.

Behind John, Susan was trembling.

The chamber was just as magnificent as Virgo’s memories informed her it would be. The huge stone pillars, the massive statues, the cathedral-like air of sanctity.

A hissing voice in the air immediately smacked her out of her wonder.

§You... you are my master... but you are also... not§

Virgo’s heart leapt into her throat. §I am your master!§ she hissed back into the seemingly empty chamber. Merlin only knew how such a large snake kept itself hidden.

§You smell like my master. Your soul tastes like my master. But you are not him. And you are highborn snake. Only one king.§ Then from behind a pillar, it came, sliding out into the open, twenty tonnes of digestion factory with death at one end and bones at the other.

Virgo could feel Susan and John on her back, clutching each other.

§I am not a king! I am your master!§ Virgo hissed desperately, inventing wildly. §No, I am your mistress!§ Close your killer gaze! I demand it!§

The basilisk paused. Its huge head, lined with fangs and dripping venom, now hovered over the trio.

§Not a king?§ The basilisk asked. §No, not a king. Not master, either. Mistress, maybe? But a queen — a queen, yes. My queen! Yes. My gaze is closed. Your humans are yours.§

Virgo swallowed. The implications of the queen statement were too horrifying to contemplate; but Dark Lady she was, so contemplate them, she did.

“Potter?,” she eventually ventured, “I have a plan now. And no one needsss to get massively hurt,” she added, for the benefit of Susan. “But it will require you to be a hero.”

She had to give him credit. Even in the face of death, John Potter could summon stones like few wizards she knew. “Well, of course,” he said, voice barely wavering. “I am the boy-who-lived.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

It was next week. It was also late. Dinner would be finished soon, but Hermione had only just completed healer training with Madam Pomfrey. Food these days was an on-the-go affair. Her studies were progressing well, although not as quickly as she’d have liked. What she really wanted to start on was the aether unpacked. Harry had assigned her so much reading in preparation even she was having difficulty keeping up. This was not helped by the fact that after living over a year as a unicorn, while the rest of the girls trained, Hermione felt behind like she had never felt before. And Hermione hated feeling behind. Soon, she would be ready. So very soon. But soon was not now, and that irked her.

She turned a corner, heading back towards the Slytherin dungeons.

All thoughts of her next assignment or essay died as she caught sight of something that should not have been before her. She gasped. “Harry!”

She ran up to the figure, but slowed down just before arriving. She frowned. The figure was petrified, but...

“Oh, it’s you,” she said, the final word dripping with disdain. John Potter. And he’d apparently been attacked.

Hermione wasn’t worried. The small snake in her pocket, which was there specifically to warn if the basilisk was near, lay restful, just as Harry had ordered it a long time ago.

Nevertheless, Harry should be told about this right away.

She was about to send a quick coded message through her lightning-bolt ring, when she caught sight of what was written on the wall above her.

She stared.

Suddenly, there was the loud sound of dozens of students filing out from the Great Hall. Dinner was over. If she was found here... Hermione thought a bad word.

Her eyes darted towards the dungeons, but no, running would be even worse.

They all stopped and stared when they saw the sight before them.

Hermione Granger, standing next to the petrified form of John Potter.

“It wasn’t me!” she said indignantly. “He was like this when I got here!”

The crowd read the message, written in blood, above the petrified hero of the Wizarding World.

THE CHAMBER OF SECRETS HAS BEEN OPENED.

ENEMIES OF THE GRAY, SHALL PAY.

— End of Chapter Fifty-eight —

Nature Red — Part 3

In Hermione’s trunk, in the girl’s dorm-room, Harry sat at his new conjured meeting table. It was a round table. Very Arthurian.

Over the last few years, each of the girls around this table had proven themselves loyal to him, in one way or another, again and again. He could imagine many other ways that he could’ve operated after he came back in time, but sitting here and watching the girls debate and argue among themselves, he wouldn’t change a single thing. He felt no need to interrupt the heated discussions. He just listened, considering each point of view on its merits, while parsing it through his own practical modus operandi.

“We need to restrict Virgo’s movements,” Hermione said loudly, thumping her fist on the table with unusual forcefulness. “This whole situation is getting ridiculous. People keep looking at me as though I’m some kind of assassin! Me! Alex I could understand, or Ginny! But me! When did I ever do anything to make them think I’m capable of attacking that no-good horrible pile of—”

She would have continued, but she was interrupted by Ginny. “—We can’t just restrict her movements. I already told you. I’ve been trying to get a bead on her all month! She’s never alone. She never leaves Susan’s side outside of Gryffindor Tower, and even inside, she has a small bodyguard all around her. Even Fred and George can’t get close.”

“That wouldn’t be much help anyway,” Luna added in a dreamy voice. “Not unless we told them that Virgo was Lord Voldemort. I doubt they would accept kidnapping her otherwise. And you did attack and defeat a troll, Hermione. Did you forget? And you faced down Dumbledore. Because most people have not forgotten.”

“That’s not the same thing at all! And it’s just getting worse! Are we sure we can’t just tell people it’s Virgo?”

Daphne sighed. “Hermione, we don’t know how Virgo is doing this. She shouldn’t be able to speak parseltongue. Not if Harry was right about the magic being parsed down through the Riddle line. The diary gave up being a Riddle for being a Malfoy when it became Virgo. It’s not even impossible that the snake isn’t being used. We haven’t caught it, and not even the Marauder’s Map is giving any clues, despite us watching it 24/7! There are other ways to cause petrification. Until we know what’s going on, accusing Virgo isn’t possible. It might not even be the best option, even if we did know.”

Harry continued to watch the discussion with his fingers steepled under his chin. Since Hermione had found his twin brother petrified with a threatening message above his head, two more students had suffered the same fate.

The second attack had been on Colin Creevey, one of the muggleborns Hermione was working with.

The third attack had been on Draco Malfoy.

That was when shit had really started to hit the fan at Hogwarts. Lord Malfoy stormed into the Great Hall, demanding Mandrake from Professor Sprout that still wasn’t ready. The Daily Prophet had run an article about the attacks, the ministry had gotten involved, and the Wizengamot, now backed by both the Light and Dark, had made a statement decrying the attacks as intolerable.

It was all so inconvenient. There was so much outside the school that required his attention.

There was the furnishing of Slytherin Manor, the continued observation of Dan Granger’s new powers, the surveying of the sunken treasure ship, regular social events with the Gray, fielding investment opportunities, working with Lockhart on the upcoming book, researching the obscurial, fielding requests from governments about his broomsub manufacturing operation, dealing with parchment work, and finding more and more ways to politely deal with a miriade requests for betrothal contracts.

#

Those were mostly for Lord Slytherin, but they also included Tracey and even Astoria. Tracey was understandable, since Lord Davis had made it known that Slytherin was handling his grand daughter’s arrangements, but Astoria had been a surprise ever since the Harpers had asked the previous year. Apparently, many people felt he had enough sway over the leadership of the Gray that a word from him on their sons behalf would be as good as a done deal.

He forwarded all those letters to Lord Greengrass.

Both Tracey and Astoria’s letters had started to take on a more foreign flavor recently, too. The Gray’s standing as a legitimate power was strengthening, not only in Magical Britain, but also beyond its borders.

It all just made the current situation all the more irksome. If he was being honest, he rather hoped his generals would be able to handle this matter by themselves.

He brought his attention back to the discussion in front of him to find the girls still arguing.

“What about the Aurors?” Ginny asked. “Couldn’t we bring them in? They might have good ways to deal with a such a large basilisk.”

“That would cause a massive panic,” Daphne jumped in. “The school would be evacuated. Harry could lose his control of the wards.”

“And we might have to give up the body!” Alex added.

Hermione snorted. “Do you really think you could raise such a ridiculously powerful inferi?”

“I could with Lord Slytherin’s help.”

Harry pursed his lips. Even if these attacks didn’t originate from the basilisk, the mere presence of the giant snake had gone beyond mere inconvienance. They’d put off doing something about it as long as they could. But now circumstances were coming to a head.

“Okay,” Harry said out loud, silencing all discussion around the table. “Daphne, I will be out of the castle for the next few days. I’d like you to lead some brainstorming session for how to tackle the Basilisk. In the meantime, Ginny, keep tailing Virgo. Try not to let her out of your sight.” Harry looked at each of the girls in turn before taking a deep breath. “We’ll do it on the day of the Hogwarts duelling tournament.”

#

Just as it had been ever since the attacks had started, over the next few days, Hogwarts castle was in tumult. Students whispered, ghosts flew constantly alert, and the professors tried their best to keep their classess focused on academics, rather than on the two questions on every’s mind.

Who was the attacker? And who would be the next attacked?

The fact that two of the victims were John Potter and Draco Malfoy, two of the most important students in the school, sent chills through the noble and pureblood students. The shared fate of Colin Creevey did the same for the muggleborn and halfbloods.

The Hogwarts Black Market bustled with trade, hawking everything from garlic in case the attacker was a vampire, to shrunken live roosters, in case it was a basilisk. It was too bad the later only worked on young examples.

Opinions on who was to blame, both inside the castle and out, fell into three broad camps.

The first group was those who took the message painted at the wall at face value. The Gray did it. Case closed. Look, they even confessed. It’s written right there!

The second group pointed out that it would be pretty silly for the Gray to confess to a crime like this. Lord Slytherin was many things to many people, but stupid was not one of them. The Gray was obviously being framed. Although exactly who was doing the framing when both John Potter and Draco Malfoy had been attacked was, they had to admit, a bit of a problem.

The third group just shook their heads and rolled their eyes. Obviously it was possible that the Gray were being framed. But writing a message taking credit for an attack like this was so obviously stupid that it could actually be the Gray who did it. Once the conclusion of a double bluff had been drawn, it easily led to the possibility of a triple bluff, a quadruple bluff, etc. At the end of the day, it could be anyone, and since no one from the Gray had been attacked, it could easily have been them.

The problem for the Gray was that the majority of Wizarding Britain tended to fall into the first group of thought, while most of those who mattered fell into the last.

It went without saying, that tensions, in every common room across the school, were high.

Tensions were especially high for a young witch with yellow and black trimming on her robes, sitting in the Hufflepuff common room, doing her best to ‘act natural’, and finding she wasn’t all that good at it.

“Come on, Susan,” Hannah said, “You need to relax, nothing’s going to happen to us here. They’ll catch whoever’s behind the attacks soon. And then your aunt will toss them into Azkaban. Bam!”

Susan barely suppressed a flinch. The collar of her robes felt far tighter than usual. “Hahaha,” she said. “Yes, I guess you’re right. I’m not really that worried,” she lied. “I’m just feeling a bit stressed out from the student court stuff.” The first session had been held a few days previously and to no one’s surprise, every problem brought before the three judges were petty cases of teenage drama. In one fell swoop, Susan had been catapulted right into the number one target for gossip. So it was understandable if she was a bit stressed. Even if that wasn’t the real reason.

“Jeez,” said Ernie Macmillan. “I never thought I’d see a seventh year crying over being dumped on a Hogsmede trip. He’s almost a grown up.”

“But you severed him justice, Susie!” Hannah said, clapping her friend on the back. “No means no, and not, ‘please hex my pet cat to beltch itching powder in my clothes.’”

“Haha, yes,” said Susan.

The sofa fell quiet.

Hannah’s face softened. “Don’t worry, Susie, I’m sure John will be cured and back with as soon.”

For the first time in the discussion, Susan felt something other than guilt. Her heart clenched. She fondly muttered under her breath. “That idiot.”

#

“Hey, Black!”

It was in-between classes. Alex was on her way to potions when the aggressive voice called her. She stopped dead with several books held to her chest.

She wasn’t alone. Pansy, Nott, Crabbe, Goyle, and Millicent walked with her. They also stopped.

The group turned.

Alex did not.

“Creswell, what a surprise,” said Pansy in a mocking voice. “Are you sure you can afford to take time off making cheese to talk to us? Our time is very valuable.”

Alex smirked to herself. Creswell? She was the fourth year Hufflepuff seed for the duelling tournament. Her lord had showed her his memory from their ‘exchange’ last year, if such a curbstomping could be called an exchange.

“Go away, Parkinson. I’m not hear to talk to you, I’m hear to talk to Black. Hey, Black!”

Alex still didn’t turn around. “Can I help you?” she asked.

“No, I don’t need your help. I just wanted to give you a warning. I’m sure Harry has told you all about what happened last year at the tournament. I just warning you that won’t happen again!”

“Harry?” Alex let an amused tint into her voice. “Not Potter? Wow, did you feel his smack down that hard?”

There an embarrassed silence for a moment.

Alex finally turned around to face the fourth-year Hufflepuff. She was athletic, as was to be expected, a half-dozen inches taller than Alex, and wore her strawberry blonde hair in a ponytail.

The girl was actually blushing. “Look, Black, I know you think you’re hot shit, but let me tell you, compared to Harry, you are nothing. I’ve been hearing rumors that you want to do what Harry and John did last year. A full sweep 7-0. That is not happening. The Hufflepuff team has been practicing hard all year. Trying to fight Harry is like trying to fight a force of nature. You clearly have never felt Harry’s power yourself or you would never be spewing such self-important rubbish.”

Alex’s smirk slowly morphed into a grin. “You think I haven’t felt ‘Harry’s’ power?” She burst out laughing. The laughter went on for so long that even Nott and Pansy started looking at her oddly. “Was this really all you came to talk to me for?” she eventually asked. “To shit talk a week before I smack your ass down into the dirt myself?” Her grin morphed back into a smirk “Maybe then I can get you to blush for me too.”

Creswell did not look impressed. “You won’t be talking so big once you’re on your knees on the arena floor after losing to Heiress Bones. If you even get to me, I’ll eat my hat.”

“It won’t be me on my knees,” Alex answered. “And I don’t care about your hat.” She smiled smugly. “Why don’t we make a bet, instead. If you’re so sure about winning?

The fourth year Hufflepuff narrowed her eyes. “What kind of bet?”

A few minutes later they shook hands and parted.

As they went their separate ways, Pansy leaned in closer to Alex and said in a low voice, “Did none of them see the memory of what you did to the Slytherin Common Room at the start of year?”

“Most people think that was fake now,” answered Nott in a low voice of his own. He gave Alex a calculating look. “Now you’ll have to prove yourself for real. Are you sure you can back up that level of smack talk? You’re going to look really stupid if you can’t.” His voice took on a fiercer note. “We’re going to look stupid.”

“Relax,” Alex said. “I got this. Hang on.” They were just passing the last bathroom before the dungeons. “I’ll catch up with you all. Yes, I’m sure.”

The moment Alex knew she was alone, she faced the mirror and did the Dark Lady Dance. “Oh, yeah! Who’s so cool? You’re so cool. Yes, you are.”

She then quickly did her business and hurried off to potions. Professor Potter had gotten a lot stricter in the last few weeks.

#

“You need time off for what?!”

The head of the DMLE, Madam Amelia Bones, Regent of the Ancient and Noble House of Bones, looked over her parchment work at the man who’d just had the temerity to ask for less work when everyone else was being run ragged.

“I need time off for the Hogwarts Dueling Tournament,” Sirius replied calmly.

“Black, you know we’re still dealing with the fallout from the magical storm?”

“Yes.”

“And that the ISS is getting on out backs about our obligations to the obliviator squads?”

“Yes.”

“And that the Department of Mysteries is still insisting the storm birthed a Chimera, and we still don’t know where it is?”

“Yes.”

“And that despite it being over a year, we still have no leads on the rogue Necromancers that we know are active inside Magical Britain?”

“Yes.”

“And most importantly of all, that despite your secret contact insisting that He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named is still alive, that we still have no more leads on that either? You know all this?”

Sirius took a deep breath. “Yes. But I promised Alex. We’ve barely had any time together recently. Honestly, it feels just like yesterday when she was still so tiny. She’s growing up fast now. I’ve decided I can’t miss this.”

Madam Bones rubbed her face. “Don’t you think that I wouldn’t also enjoy taking a day off to watch Susan compete?”

“Maybe you should. We could go together. We could even make sure no funny business goes down. You remember what happened last year.” He grinned. “You might as well have been there to begin with and saved the bother of being dragged there anyway.”

A look of massive internal conflict flicked across Madam Bone’s face. Finally, she sadly shook her head. “I can’t justify taking a day off. Not now. Susan is a responsible witch though. She understands.” She then gave Sirius a thoughtful look. “Maybe you do have a point though. Given what happened last year, maybe having an official DMLE observer at the tournament wouldn’t be a bad idea.” Her voice became one of command. “Black, I’m putting you on special assignment at Hogawarts for the Duelling Tournament. Keep your eyes open and make sure everything is nice and legal.” She stamped a parchment in front of her and handed it over. “Talk to the Department of Magical Family Affairs to get a good ticket.”

Sirius grinned. “Yes, Ma’am.” He turned to leave.

“And Sirius?”

“Yes?”

“I think I should warn you, that if Alex meets Susan in the tournament, your daughter will not win.” she smiled evilly. “My niece has become quite a powerhouse.”

Sirius matched her smile with one of his own. But he didn’t reply. He just quietly left the office, closing the door behind him.

#

Just behind the space between souls, Hermione Granger peeked her unusually bushy-haired head out of Hogwarts’ massive front doors, and stared into the void beyond.

Total silence.

Here, there wasn’t even a shifting of air.

There was no echo. The sound of her footsteps were simply sucked right into the cavernous space ahead.

Hermione took a deep breath and stepped out onto a stone balcony, fenced by tall iron railings.

There was no soul bridge. Hermione Granger had nothing to bridge to.

She did have strings though.

They sunk into circular orbs that ran the distance around the iron railings – at least five of them that she’d found. There had been six, but the moment her dad became a magical null field, one of the strings had vanished.

It had taken her quite a long time to confirm that, because the strings were not easy to detect. A few in particular, were so thin and wispy that they might as well not have been there at all.

Not so for the one she cared for today.

One string shooting off from her soul balcony shone bright white in the ever-darkness of the chasm. As Hermione stepped towards it, she felt the comforting feeling of rightness. Of goodness. And of an incomplete part of her that yearned to join.

When Hermione reached the string, she placed a hand on the orb anchoring it to the balcony railings and closed her eyes.

Magic flowed out from her mindscape behind her and into her avatar here. It flowed through her body and mind in a very specific pattern. Hermione took a deep breath. She did not say any words. She didn’t even think words. This went beyond the normal ritualistic casting of mere spells. Instead, she yearned, in turn. But what she yearned for, was not to join, but to know.

In that instant, the chasm between souls vanished. Wind from a place unknown blasted past Hermione, whipping at her hair and skirts. The balcony stopped holding her weight, and the feeling of falling started, and just as quickly stopped. Then there was a tug, as though a hook was attached to the front of Hermione’s robes and she felt as though she was rocketing through space.

All this while, Hermione repeated a mantra over and over in her mind. ‘I am Hermione Granger. I am Hermione Granger. I am Hermione Granger.’

A pinprick of light far off in the distance got nearer and exponentially more massive in an instant. Hermione found herself floating in a sea of stars, orbiting a planet of pure white light. The feeling of goodness from her string washed over her from the orb, so massive it held her its gravity, but so near it was as though she could reach out and pluck it from among the stars.

Hermione did nothing.

She did not try to cast magic or play games from her mindscape. She merely starred at the purity and goodness before her.

The moment didn’t last.

Suddenly, her whole universe shuddered, sending magic star dust everywhere, as though someone had just knocked on a snow-globe while she was inside it.

Hermione’s eyes snapped open.

The space between souls was just as dark as ever.

Hermione’s eyes snapped open.

Her mind-scape was just as it always had been. The glass that showed the great lake in the Slytherin dorms, just as green and murky as she remembered.

Hermione’s eyes snapped open.

All around her, the Founders Club went about its business, just as it always did. Footsteps, voices, and laughter echoed off the stone walls. In the middle of the room, Violet and Marrigold Chesterfield were sparring with a ferocity that most in the Wizarding World would never expect to find in mere first years, and certainly not muggleborns. Off to one side, a small circle of students were in deep occlumency practice with their partners.

“Huh?” Hermione said, momentarily forgetting that well-brought-up, intelligent young witches don’t say, ‘Huh?’

She turned her head to find Justin Finch-Fletchley lying bent on the ground, craning his shin, his face a rictus of pain. He was laying exactly how one might expect one who had tripped over, say, a chair leg. A small mountain of books lay around him.

What had disturbed her exploration practice was as clear as day.

“Sorry, Hermione,” Justin groaned. “Wasn’t looking where I was going.”

Hermione huffed. “You couldn’t have picked a worse time to be clumsy. And Madam Pince would be furious if she saw you handling library books like that.”

“Sorry.” Justin rubbed the back of his head. “It’s just— I think we’re all a bit on edge. There’s so much going on.”

That much at least was true. The activities of the Founders Club were always a strange mix of the practical, academic, philosophical, and political. But right now, all those aspects were overlapping each other. The scope of the club had long expanded beyond just the first and second years, and now their customary empty class room practically bustled. There were even a few halfbloods around — those who’d grown up mostly in the muggle world and knew little of traditional wizarding culture.

Of course, not everyone was getting access to Harry’s special teaching techniques — not everyone had proven themselves yet, not like her — but the number was increasing.

There was a feminine clearing of throat. It came from the portrait of Elizabeth Greengrass, hanging behind the two on the black board. The aristocratic witch glared down at Justin. “If you are quite finished being an embarrassment, perhaps we can get on?”

Justin immediately leaped to his feet and started apologising again, this time to the portrait.

A loud cheer erupted from the spectators around the middle of the room as Marigold—who was also the Hufflepuff first year dueling seed—successfully disarmed her twin sister with a wandless expeliarmus.

Seeing just how red-faced Justin was, Hermione suddenly felt guilty for snapping at him. On the other hand, what was it Harry sometimes said? If you are always a source of pleasure, they will take your goodness for granted. If you are sometimes a source of pain, they will fight to keep your favor. Of course, Harry had gone on to say that most people had no idea if they were a source of either, and even fewer knew how to consciously create the effect.

It wasn’t easy for her. She knew she wasn’t Daphne. Hermione had to work hard to think in terms of other people and the way they saw the world. It was just so difficult when the way they saw the world was so obviously wrong.

Hermione cut Justin off just as a few other students arrived around the lectern Hermione had been sitting behind. “There is nothing to apologise for,” she said. “I should have been more careful.”

In the middle of the room, Marigold got in a cheeky stunner on an over confident third year.

After all, Hermione added in the privacy of her own mind, if Harry hadn’t meant her to explore at least this much in public, he wouldn’t have given her his blessing.

Below the silk fabric of her robes, she felt the lightning-bolt-shaped dream amulet pressed firmly against her skin.

#

In the Room of Requirement, another, far less equally matched battle raged. Bookcases reached high up to the vaulted roof. Broken desks blocked off escape paths. The very room molded itself to its mistresses’ whim. An explosion of magic sent dust flying from shelves.

Susan crouched, panting in one of the narrow pathways, wand clutched tightly in hand. Her eyes darted up and down the path between the shelves. Sweat beaded on her forehead.

There was a faint rumble form behind her. Her eyes widened in panic. She had just enough time to throw herself forward before a giant hand made of second-hand books thrust out from the shelf and snatched shut where she’d been just moments before.

“Incendio!” Flames shot out from her wand and engulfed the paper and parchment hand. She didn’t stop to see the result. Already, more hands were sprouting. Susan dashed down the passageway as fast as her legs could take her.

“Incendio! Incendio Incendio!” Susan threw herself around the nearest corner. A fist covered in fire grabbed for her but missed by barely a hair. Susan stumbled back and fell. Her wand clattered onto the ground only a foot away. Six paper hands shot out from the surrounding shelves.

Susan rolled to the side and snatched up her wand. “Incendio Columna!” The effects were pronounced. A small firestorm sprang up around her. Wind roared in her ears. Heat scorched her skin. It seared away the paper fists making grabs at her through the flames.

A few seconds later, the fires winked out.

Susan got to her feet shakily. Her clothes were soaked with sweat. Her breath was ragged. Her chest heaved. Parts of her skin were shiny and the tip of her nose started to flake.

A faint rustling sound was the only warning she got. Something large and papery dive bombed her from above. She had just enough to time to raise her wand and scream “Incendio!” but all that came out the end was a sad little ‘Phut’.

A giant parchment butterfly barreled into her, sending her sprawling across the floor. Her wand clattered away again. Her robes tore. Her knees scrapped. The butterfly soared back into the air. Susan rolled over onto her hands and knees, wincing at the pain, and groaned. She coughed. blood spattered onto the flagstone floor.

“Get up.” The voice came down from on high.

Susan snarled before pain wiped it from her face again. She got one foot under her and raised herself on shaking legs. She craned her neck to look up.

Virgo stood atop the shelf next to her. The paper butterfly on one arm and both their wands in hand. “Do you now see why learning the wandless summoning spell is important?” Virgo asked.

“Yes,” Susan ground out through clenched teeth.

“Good.” Virgo tossed her wand back down.

Susan managed the catch without dropping it.

“And what else have we learned?”

“That you are far more dark lord than you first let on. That or you just waited until John was petrified to show how much of a sadist you are!”

Virgo’s look turned cold. “Voldemort would never risk teaching someone the way I am teaching you, Bones. And what we are doing now is the only way either of us will live. En Garde!”

Susan had only enough time to raise her wand and summon a stray book from the smouldering piles that lay all around before a nasty looking purple spell impacted the tome and exploded in a hundred shredded pages.

“I’m empty!” Susan screamed.

“Deal with it.”

Susan ran. She ran to get away from the curses. The hexes. The rain of offensive magic that poured down on her from the rafters above. She could feel her magic replenishing itself from her core. That little trickle of power that normally sloshed around inside her like a comforting hot water bottle. It wasn’t refilling nearly fast enough now though, and with every shield she had to throw up, her ability to evade the next spell lowered further and further.

“Do you think an enemy will give you a break!” Virgo shouted down at her, following on behind, somehow managing to keep up while still only walking. “Do you think a battle is like a duel?! Do you think your aunt trains her aurors to fight with time limits and courtesy and a proper announcement like they were going to a ball?!”

Susan screeched to a halt. She blocked another spell with a random tea tray and snapped around. “My aunt!” she started, face furious, panting to get her breath back. “My aunt would not drag innocent people into her political schemes!”

Virgo stopped and looked down at her.

“John was okay!” Susan continued. “He agreed to it! But Creevey didn’t! Even petrifying Draco wasn’t right!”

Virgo didn’t look impressed. “You know they will suffer no long term harm. Once they are administered mandrake drought, they will as be as they always have been.”

“And what about their education?! Creevey might have to be held back a year! It’s hard enough for muggleborns as it is! And not even Draco deserves having his hard work staying ahead stolen from him!”

“Draco is my brother. I will decide what is best for him. This is war, Susan. John trusted us to fight for him while he is gone. We are doing what must be done. Once the time is right I can release the story to Skeeta and our task is done.” Virgo’s eyes cooled. “Or are you just terrified your aunt might learn the truth?”

It was like the little first-year Gryffindor witch had punched her in the gut. And with an attack no shield could block.

“What if you lose control of it?!” Susan shouted, defensively.

“I will not lose control of it,” Virgo stated simply.

“But how can you know that?! That thing is dangerous! Really dangerous!”

“That’s why it is perfect. Not even Slytherin will attack it by himself.”

“What if he tells the ministry?!”

Virgo transformed into her lamia form and coiled herself down a pillar to the ground. “Then he would have to admit that he’d known about it for the last three yearsss and done nothing. We proved that when John was petrified and we received no blow-back.”

“Or maybe he’s planning something and waiting for us to dig our own graves!”

“Perhapsss,” Virgo replied. But it was clear from the look on her face that she didn’t believe it. She smirked. “Tell you what. If I lossse control of the basilisk, do whatever you want. I doubt I’d care at that point.”

Susan spat blood off to the side and wiped her mouth with the back of her hand.

Virgo raised her wand again. “Now, enough rest! Ssslytherin may be powerful, but magical creatures are the classic hard counter to powerful wizards. Ssstrike me!” Her voice raised into a shout. “And this time actually try!

Susan screamed and charged.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Roughly a thousand kilometers away, one Jane Clearwell took a deep breath in front of her domitory mirror and checked her hair one last time. In her hand, she clutched a letter.

“Oh, for pity’s sake,” said her room mate, Sarah, from her bed. “You look fine! You look better then ever!”

Jane had to admit that this was true. There were several empty and expensive potion bottles on the bedside counter to prove it. She took another breath. “You’re right. You’re right,” she repeated. “Positive thoughts.” She hefted her satchel and walked to the door.

“And remember to put in a word for me too!” Sarah called as Jane crossed over into the hallway.

There weren’t many students around at this time of day. Jane made her way down the stairs of The Shoe towards Madam Goose’s office, somehow not sure if what was about to happen was real.

“Come in,” Madam Goose called through the door when she knocked.

This was only the second time Jane had ever seen Madam Goose’s office. The first time had been when she’d been enrolled. And that was almost seven years ago.

Madam Goose looked up from her parchment work. “Ah, Miss Clearwell. I see you are ready.”

“Yes, Madam Goose.”

The older woman looked over her glasses at her. “I hope you appreciate what an opportunity this is for you.”

“Yes, Madam Goose.”

“Most students do not get the opportunity to work part time while they are studying.”

“No, Madam Goose.”

“You are to be back at school before lights out and if any of the teachers tell me your work is suffering I will see to it that this arrangement is pulled.”

“Yes, Madam Goose.” Jane found herself fiddling with the strap of her bag.

Madam Goose steepled her fingers and leaned over her desk. “Just so we are clear about this. I want you to remember that you are representing not only yourself, but all The Shoe as well. Your success or failure here might be what keeps future students from enjoying similar opportunities. So I will accept nothing less than your best effort. I will be receiving regular reports from our partners on this little experiment. Do I make myself clear?”

“Yes, Madam Goose,” Jane practically squeaked. As if the pressure wasn’t already high enough.

Madam Goose pointed to her personal floo. “Off you go, then. But I expect you to use the entrance hall floo in future.” She paused as though remembering something. “And while you’re there, please tell Clare that I’ll have to reschedule our next Tuesday appointment to Thursday.”

Jane nodded. She walked to the floo, took a pinch of powder, flung it into the flames, stepped in, and, with a clear voice that sounded a lot more confident than she felt, called out, “Slytherin Manor!”

The flames whooshed past her. The ride was the longest she’d ever experienced — from Southern England to the Scottish Orkneys. It made her far better appreciate just what Clare had to go through every single day.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Jane did not arrive in the residences on the third floor, as Harry was want to do. Nor did she arrive in at the entrance hall, as those who arrived for Slytherin Gala Night did. She instead arrived on the second floor on the left hand side of the manor, in the closed off section designated for the staff.

Jane stepped out of the floo and was immediately struck by how empty the place felt. After seven years of living at The Shoe, with every wall covered in patch-work quilting, it was odd to find a magical building without so much as a painting on any of the walls.

There was an empty desk in front of her, like one might expect a receptionist to sit at, but there was no chair, no shelves, no stationary, and most importantly, no actual receptionist.

A cough that echoed around the hallway drew her attention to the only other presences in the room — two other wizards, both of whom looked young, like her, sitting on chairs in a corner. The fact that there was only one other chair clued her into what she was supposed to do now.

“Hello,” she said nervously, folding her long skirt under her as she sat.

“Morning.”

“Hello.”

No sooner had she sat down though, then a door opened and an older wizard walked in, causing her to practically jump out of the chair. She cursed herself.

“Relax,” the man said in a clear voice that projected all around the echo hallway. He looked to be around middle age, although with wizards that could easily mean he was in his mid sixties. “We’ll have tea ready soon.” He smiled. “But we’ll have the tour first. Are you all ready?”

They all nodded.

“Excellent. My name is Daniel Granger. And if all goes well, I will be your new boss.”

He confidently shook the two guy’s hands, then turned to her.

Powerlessness. That was the feeling that swept over Jane the moment their palms touched. Mister Granger was tall. He was handsome. He clearly kept himself in shape. And the moment that his firm hand closed around hers, she felt about as in control of her own destiny as a leaf in the wind.

She barely managed to squeak out her own introduction.

Mister Granger nodded back with a smile and turned away. “Follow me.”

A glance out of the window showed the island that Jane knew they were on.

The wizard opened a door in the wall and led them down a set of spiral stairs. The stairs went down far further than the grass Jane had seen growing outside. Deep, deep underground. Eventually the reached a passageway that was far longer even than the descent they’d just endured. Their footsteps echoed endlessly as they walked in silence down the stone corridor.

“Sorry for the walk,” Mister Granger said when they finally arrived at the end. “The goblins have agreed to install a mine cart eventually, but we’re waiting on the all clear from the king.”

The three prospectives exchanged glances with each other before being led into the beyond. And for the first time since she’d arrived on the island, Jane actually felt like she was in a place of work.

It was a vast underground cavern. Off to one side, a small lake was surrounded on one side by cave wall, and on another by wooden pier. Cables and pulleys hang from the ceiling. Strange machines hugged the walls all around. Brightly colored tape marked out zones on the floor. The smell of wood shaves came to her nose, mixed with the smell of the ocean. The sounds of raised voices mixed with the banging of hammers and the sizzling of welding tools.

And in the middle of the huge space, lay three massive wooden cylindrical objects in various states of construction, lined with ornate metal plates and surrounded by iron scaffolding.

It took Jane a moment to realize, with a jolt of surprise, that the dozen or so workers around the room, were goblins, and that the huge objects being built, each as long as a bendy bus, were broomsticks.

“Our broomstick assembly area,” Mister Granger said waving to what to Jane looked like organized chaos. “We’re getting ready for a big order from the Americans so we’ve got plenty of work needed doing there.”

“What are they using them for?” one of the guys asked.

“Kelpie patrol in the great lakes is the stated official use. But we’re upgrading for other use cases as well.”

They walked over to another area filled with tables, desks, chalk boards. “This is our research area,” Mister Granger said sweeping his hand across the mostly empty open office. “We’re currently working on upgrading our broomstick rings with additional charm work overlaying the runes, so that’s another area we’ll need help.”

He gestured to the lake. “We’ve also got a deep sea project that’s going to need some able wands, and a we’re looking to upgrade our trunk engines, redesign our air scrubbers, and come up with a way to impart physical thrust through the bristles, charm the water canons. Yes?” This last question was directed at Jane who had her hand held up like a school child.

“Umm, I don’t really know how to do any of that?” she said nervously, fully aware that this probably wasn’t the best thing to admit to what was basically a job interview. “Our school didn’t really teach stuff like this.” She was relieved that the two boys were nodding a murmuring along the same lines.

“Don’t worry about it,” Mister Granger said. “You’ll get on the job training. We’ll start you off with four or five basic charm spells. There are plenty of pieces that just need the same charm applied over and over again on-top of the runes. We would have brought you in earlier, but we’ve been working on a system to ensure the security of our intellectual property. We’ve read your school reports. It will be hard work, but easily within your skills. If you do good work, you can learn more and start helping us with more advanced projects. Look around you.”

The three of them turned back to looks round the large cavern.

“The goblins are only helping us as a curtesy and at quite a premium. Soon this space will be filled with wizards and witches. If you want it hard enough, you three can be the first. Lots of room to grow, if you catch my meaning. I’m not saying it will be easy, but I can guarantee that working with us will be more fulfilling than stocking shelves at Witch Co. So, are you interested?”

“Yes!” one of the boys blurted out.

Jane couldn’t help but chuckle.

“One question,” said the other boy.

“Yes?”

“What’s behind that door?” He pointed to a massive set of double doors near where they stood. Unlike the rest of the cavern which was either made of stone, or had the feel of a muggle workshop, these doors were made of oak and iron and looked like something out of a fantasy book.

“Ah,” Mister Granger frowned. “That section is off limits to employees. That’s all you really need to know. All I will say is that it is secured by the very best of goblin and wizard magic combined, so please do remember not to accidentally try to force your way in. It won’t end well. It will also result in you being fired and having your memory altered as per the terms of your contract.”

“Does it have a dragon behind it?”

Mister Granger smirked. “Nah, too large. We went for a chimera instead.”

Jane giggled. Even if he was a bit frightening for some reason she couldn’t quite put her finger on, It was good to know her new boss at least had a sense of humor.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Meanwhile, behind the door of iron and oak, stood a creature so rare that it only existed in myths and legends. The chimera animagus smiled. “Looks like you’ve made a lot of progress.”

Emma Granger smiled back. “Yes, my lord.”

They were both inspecting the automated rune inscription system that would automatically mill rune plates, then fuse another plate on-top to secure the knowledge hidden within.

“We’ve also come up with some solutions to help you with the battle against the basilisk,” she continued. “We didn’t have as much time as we’d have liked, but we did the best we could.”

“Wonderful.” The two made their way over to a table covered in white sheets — five in total.

Emma Granger gripped one of the sheets and whipped it off revealing a pile of absolutely massive nets.

Harry grinned. “Rather theatrical. Am I rubbing off on you?”

“Oh hush. Let me have my fun. Acromantula nets, my lord — sized for 60 foot long killing machine. We’re not 100% sure it will hold, but the design works for dragons, so it should at least have an effect.”

“Good to have the option.”

They moved onto the next table.

Emma pulled back the second sheet to reveal a gigantic scarf of, again, acromantula silk.

“And this is?” Harry asked.

Emma grinned. “A witch’s bra, my lord.”

It was the first time Emma had ever seen Harry look nonplussed.

“Umm…” the boy said.

“Technically, a giantess’s bra,” Emma continued with the air of a predator that has sensed weakness. “It’s the biggest size I could find. But it works the same way as a witch’s breast scarf, self-wrapping thing. Never could get used to them myself. I prefer a good pair of lacy push ups.”

“Good… to know.”

“Anyway, fling it around the snake’s head and it should self wrap, just like around a pair of woman’s bobbies.”

“…have you been hanging around Luna?”

Emma smirked. “No, I’m just happy to finally have found something that makes my super strong and powerful lord uncomfortable.”

Harry ignored this and pointed to the silk wrap. “Do you have a back up if this doesn’t work? A snake head isn’t exactly the same shape as—“ he paused. “—your chest. and a conjured wrap stands no zero against a death glare that old.”

“We have lots of back ups!”

They reached the third table of five. The third sheet was pulled away. “Behold!”

Harry let out an audible groan. “I am not a gryffindor.”

On the table lay three sets of Goblin silver swords, along with scabbards.

Emma smirked again. “Of course not, my lord. Although I do think you would look extremely dashing wearing a sword. These ones have been suffused with blindness solution, which may or may not have the desired effect on the basilisk’s gaze.”

“Great!” Harry clapped his hands together with false cheerfulness. “I just have to make sure I get close enough to this killing machine’s lethal fangs to impale it in the mouth, because I’m pretty sure that not even goblin silver will pierce the hide of a thousand year old king of snakes.”

Emma didn’t let her lord’s frustrations phase her. “That’s what the next toy is for, my lord.”

Unlike the first three, the shape of this next ‘toy’ was quite a bit larger. Emma pulled the sheet clear.

Harry grinned. “Now this is more like it!” He stared at what could only be described as a small portable ballista. It was loaded with a bolt that was the size of a grown man, and the tip was also clearly goblin silver. “suffused with blindness solution as well?” he asked.

“Of couse, Harry.”

“Brilliant.” Harry frowned. “Although there is the trouble of moving it. I certainly won’t be able to shrink that bolt and something this large would be very unwieldy in battle. It’ll still need a mouth shot to work.”

“I think we’ll have a solution for that too, my lord, although we’re still not quite ready for that. But we’ve already proven the principle with the last um— ‘toy’.”

Harry raised an eyebrow at the way Emma had put quotation marks around the word toy.

“This one is more of a last resort, my lord. Because. Well, I’m sure you’ll see why.” She moved over to the fifth and final sheet. She took a deep breath and pulled off the white covering.

“For if the worst comes to the worst,” Emma said finally.

Harry stared. “A trunk?”

It was a trunk. Just like the one he carried everywhere in his pocket. At least that explained how she was planning to make the ballista move maneuverable.

“Look inside, my lord.”

Harry walked over to the trunk, opened the lid, and stuck his head inside.

A split second later he jerked his head back in shock. More cautiously this time, he edged his face over the lip of the trunk’s edge to find himself looking straight down the barrel of what the layman could only describe a really big fuck off gun. Harry knew better.

Emma had taken a shrinkable space-expanded trunk, and mounted an M2 Browning 50 caliber heavy machine gun on the wall, pointing straight at the trunk’s opening. Instead of the usual stairs, a small ladder led down into the trunk, stopping at a mesh walkway with a huge hole in the middle for the rounds to pass through. The walk way followed the wall off to one side where the normal stairs completed the journey down into the trunk’s depths. On the floor were stacked several creates of what could only be 50 caliber BMG rounds.

Because of the nature of expanded trunks, the floor would always point downwards, regardless of which way the trunk was angled. This meant anyone operating the machine gun would have to sit vertically against the wall, and indeed, there was such a chair mounted behind the gun, a silk harness ensuring they wouldn’t fall out.

For a moment, Harry was actually rendered speechless.

“If the worst comes to the worst, huh?” he eventually muttered. “Just how did you get hold of this?” It didn’t need to be said that a 50 calibre heavy machine gun wasn’t the kind of thing that everyone could just buy in the UK. Or anyone for that matter. Harry’s own foray into arms dealing over the summer made him appreciate just how unlikely it was for the Grangers to get their hands on something like this. There were exactly zero approved reasons for a UK resident to possess a functioning M2 browning. Only the British Military held them. And machine guns going missing from British Military bases wasn’t exactly the kind of attention he wanted.

Emma Granger shrugged. “You’d be amazed what you can get hold of with a house elf, millions of pounds, and an undetectable submarine that can effortlessly zip between here and Northern Ireland.”

Harry sucked in his breath through his teeth at the implications of that. He gave the former dentist a good long look. “Emma, I think I’m going to have to revaluate my opinion of you, again,” he eventually said. “You have balls of steel. The Wizarding World has clearly been a bad influence on you.”

“If the Wizarding World has taught me anything it’s that monsters don’t care if you followed the rules.”

Harry smiled before shaking his head ruefully. “They do care if you break them though.” He followed her gaze. “I’ll have to add this to the list of things the Wizarding World would collectively decide to wipe us off the face of the Earth for, if they ever found out. Not that they couldn’t defend against it, but the creation of things like pocketable machine-gun emplacements is exactly the kind of reason that people actually listened to the likes of Voldemort and Grindelwald.”

He looked around the room again. “Good job, though. Seriously. Damn good job. This all just might help get us all through this without dying.” He looked Emma square in the eyes. “You have official permission to tease me about breasts.”

Emma Granger grinned.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“Alright, yeh lot!” cried the Hogwarts game keeper, carrying his customary crossbow over he shoulder. “Tha’’s enough trainin’ fer tonight. Get yer selves back up to the castle. I need to lock up.”

The pronouncement was met by a chorus of despairing complaints.

“But, Hagrid, sir!” called out the oldest student — a Ravenclaw sixth year. “Tonight’s the last night our team will have the dueling arena before the tournament this weekend.”

“Now, don’t be giving me that. Should have gotten all the practice you need before now. Don’t make me call the professors down here. You get yourselves back up to the castle.” He made large gestures towards the exits. “Go on.”

Grumbling, the Ravenclaw dueling team picked up their stuff and starting trudging towards the changing rooms. Once all the students had cleaned out, Hagrid locked the large duelling arena doors shut, picked up the rope attached to his latest kill—a stag from the deeper forest—and gestured to the large boar hound by his feet. “C’mon, Fang.”

Together, the two made their way up the hill towards Hagrid’s hut, Hagrid dragging the carcass as they went.

As they neared the crest, a bark from Fang alerted Hagrid that something was nearby.

Hagrid looked down and found his canine tracker staring up into the trees. His gaze rose and he sucked in an appreciative breath under his beard.

“Oooo. Yeh are a beautiful one, aren’t yeh?”

The golden eagle stared down her beak at him. It was surely female. Only the females usually grew that large. He reached down with his knife, sliced a piece off the deer, and expertly tossed the morsel up into the tree.

With equal expertise, the eagle snatched the meat clean out of the air with her beak and proceeded to neatly swallow it.

Hagrid chuckled, but the chuckle died a second or two later as the eagle continued to regard him in a way he knew no pure beast would.

No one would ever call Hagrid the sharpest knife in the draw, but when it came to animals, there were few wiser (at least when it came to their care and behavior). He was the master of keys and grounds at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry, after all. Dumbledore trusted him to keep on top of things, as did Headmaster Lockhart. Even the Department for the Regulation and Control of Magical Creatures occasionally called on him to help with particularly sticky problems. And while he certainly wasn’t the kind of man to read the latest reports that came from under Whitehall, he did keep his ear to the ground down at the Hogshead.

This all is why he cleared his throat and said in an uncertain voice, “Heiress Greengrass?”

The eagle’s gaze became just a tad more narrow.

“Ahhh.” Hagrid tugged respectfully at the bit of his hair that he though counted as his forelock — there was so much it was hard to tell. “I hope you don’t take what I said before the wrong way, miss.”

The eagle continued to stare.

Hagrid cleared his throat again. “Just make sure yeh’re also inside before curfew. I don’t want to find yeh locked out. Although, I suppose tha’ won’t actually matter fer yeh, will it? Seein’ as yeh can jus’ fly into the owlery.”

He paused for a moment before slapping a hand into his face. “I should not have said tha’.”

The eagle spread her majestic wings and leapt off the tree branch and up into the air. Hagrid gazed admiringly after her as she left — then took up the slack on the rope and continued pulling his kill up to his hut. But even then, he couldn’t help stealing glances upwards, where even now the beautiful eagle had been joined by two owls, one midnight black, the other snowy white, soaring together through the skies around Hogwarts.

He was so distracted, in fact, that he failed to spot the long line of spiders desperately evacuating the castle for the forest — fleeing, even though the temperature was near freezing.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“I’ve found the perfect spot to watch both the castle entrance and the dueling arena,” Daphne announced. She entered the girl’s dormitory with Freekey on one shoulder and Hedwig on the other. She was also clutching her stomach. “Also, remind me never to eat hairy meat again.”

Hermione raised an eyebrow. “Not agreeing with you?”

They were currently the only two in the dorms. Hedwig leapt from Daphne’s shoulder and flew over to alight in Hermione’s outstretched arm.

“Not at all,” Daphne groaned. “It would probably be fine if I stayed transformed, but I doubt I will have that luxury any time soon.”

Hermione untied the letter from Hedwig’s leg. “But you’ve found a spot for our plan now?”

“I have.”

“Harry will be happy to hear that.” She started reading the letter, then lowered her voice. “Mum says dad’s ‘situation’ is working out with the new employees.”

The ‘situation’ of course being that the muggle was now an effective class XXXXX wizard killer — even if he’d never actually done done the deed. Daphne knew all to well that that wouldn’t matter one jolt to how the wizarding world would react to him.

“That’s good.” Daphne started changing into her sleep wear, making Freekey jump down and start nibbling on the nuts that always sat by Daphne’s four poster. “It’s just a shame he can’t help us deal directly with the you-know-what problem.”

Hermione shivered. “I’m not. I don’t want my dad anywhere near that thing.”

Daphne climbed under the covers and stared up at the ceiling.

Hermione only just heard her whisper in a vulnerable voice she rarely heard the blonde employ, “And what about Harry?”

Hermione rested a hand on Daphne’s shoulder and spoke softly. “We just have to trust him to come back to us, safely. Don’t worry, Daphne. It’s not just us. Our lord has a lot of resources. He will use everything he has. He will use everything.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Harry stared with a calculating gaze at the huge pile of assorted weaponry and artifacts arrayed on the table in front of him.

On either side of the table, Fred and George stood like proud merchants, eager to show off the fruits of their labors.

“Potions?” Harry asked.

“Draught of living death,” George responded, deftly plucking what looked like a perfume bottle from the pile. “Air delivered in particle form, maximum five meters, use within ten seconds of breaking the seal.”

“That all?”

“Blinding solution,” Fred countered, snatching a small wooded box the table for display. “Effective for twenty four hours on a wizard. Delivered as darts with a banishing curse.

“Puking Pasties,” said George. “Take one half to feel like the bottom end of a butter beer bucket. Take the other to feel right as rain! Suggested administration as a cocktail in bait.”

“Then why not just straight out poison?”

“Because!” Fred pointed at a series of small cauldrons bubbling away in a corner of their workshop trunk. “Because, why settle for just one poison, when you can have them all?”

“The top seven most deadly magical poisons known to wizard kind,” George continued. “Well, known to us and that we can brew, anyway,” he corrected himself. “Still pretty damn lethal!”

“And the bait?”

“Transfigured animal. Recommended goat. That’ll be on you.”

“Wonderful. What else?”

Fred smacked the table and a series of glowing seeds the size of eggs wobbled on the surface. “Movement denial! Venomous tentacular infused with empowered growth solution. Simply cast a finite to dispel light charm on a seed and chuck it into the darkness. Tentacles vs. snakes, you’ve gotta love it. And then you’ve got to run away screaming.”

“Portable swamp!” George continued, picking up what looked like an ordinary suitcase. “Open the lid and stand well back. Primative uncontrolled space expansion charm downwards. Instantly turns the floor into quagmire.”

“And finally, a big ass net. Because the classics are classic for a reason.”

Harry nodded. “That all meshes well with my newer runic skills. What about exploiting possible weaknesses?”

“Air!” Fred said, pointing to a ballon that was floating upside down with the string dangling up to the ceiling. “Pop to insantlly evacuate all the oxygen in a small room and replace it with helium. Lasts five minutes.”

“Temperature!” George continued, holding up what looked like a crystal made of ice. “Essence of an ice elemental. Combine with elemental ice magic to freeze a large station wagon.”

“And finally, eyes!” George declared, holding up a recognizable length of magical fabric. “Feed magic into the cloth to instantly have it wrap around the target. It might work, it might not. But if just one out of ten options works, you’ll be in the monster slaying business and no mistake!”

Harry stared, deadpan. “George, whose bra is that?”

“Errr…”

Suddenly both twins looked very sheepish.

“Never mind!” Harry said quickly, waving a hand. “Just make sure she gets it back without noticing it’s gone, okay? I already have one anyway. Anything else?”

“Plenty!” Fred grinned and threw an arm over his shoulder. “We’ve got dead drops, glue traps, scent bombs, mud tombs, smoke screens, gum stoppers, acid baths…”

#

Ginny breathed heavily, tightly gripping her wand.

Next to her, Daphne did likewise.

On the opposite end of the large empty classroom, stood Hermione and Alex, hands on their thighs, both bent over, panting hard.

In the middle of the room, exactly halfway between the two pairs, stood a blonde girl with little radish earrings hanging from her ears. Her breathes were loud, expansive, and comically exaggerated. It sounded like she was trying to pass enough air through her lungs to feed a steam engine. Luna was also blindfolded.

Ginny grinned manically, then coughed when a bit of spit went down the wrong way. “Kurh—Kurh—Blugh.” She wiped her hand over her mouth. “Again!”

Hermione, Daphne, and Alex all straightened and started moving around the room in random directions, silent and slow.

Luna’s ear twitched. Her tongue wetted her lips.

Ginny saw her small nose expand as air and scents passed through. Ginny felt her skin prickle.

Alex’s eyes met hers. The two shared a soundless nod.

Daphne flexed her fingers.

Hermione raised her wand.

They attacked.

All at once, the quiet classroom became a maelstrom of flying spells and rushing bodies. Alex shot her chains. Hermione weaved a complex incantation. And Daphne sent a bolt of pure ice magic searing towards her target.

Luna side stepped the first, melted the third with a gout of magical flame, and brought a powerful shield to block the second, just in time, as a flurry of loaded syringes smashed against the magical defense and tinkled to the floor in a growing puddle of steaming liquid. Several stunning spells were swatted away, there was a flicker in the air, and one of the broken syringes vanished.

Ginny felt the world flicker.

She thrust out a hand, all fingers glowing blood red, ready to unleash!

…And found Luna kneeling on the floor, hand raised up, also glowing red, pressed firmly into her waist, still blindfolded, and with a faint smile playing around her lips.

Ginny’s world went black and when she came to, Luna was reaching down to help her up, her blindfold now worn around her neck like a scarf.

“Merlin, damn it!” Ginny shouted.

“Oh, come off of it,” said Alex. “This fight doesn’t count. If we were really trying, there’s no way even Luna would be able to take all four of us from four different angles, blindfolded.”

“That’s not the point!” Ginny replied hotly. “You know what us losing like this means, don’t you?”

“It means exactly what it should mean,” Daphne said calmly. “Harry will only let us fight the monster if we can do so without the aid of sight. Luna has proven herself. You have not.”

Ginny winced. Her own attempts to fight by sound, touch, and taste alone hadn’t gone nearly so well.

“Despite how good you are,” Daphne continued, “if you can’t fight blindfolded, the risk of you dying is too high.”

“But this is my fight!” Ginny practically shouted. “This is… from back then…” She struggled to articulate her frustrations with the previous timeline without actually speaking about it out loud. She wanted to say that fighting the basilisk and Virgo was primary her battle. That this was her crucible. Eventually she settled for, “If I can’t fight this fight, what did I spend all this time training for?!”

“Ginny.” Luna laid a soft hand on her shoulder. “Harry needs us. Harry saved us. It is for him, we fight. Not ourselves.”

Ginny’s shoulders slumped. “If I’d known it was going to be like this I’d have spent our ritual year training blind.”

“Ginny, stop sulking!” Hermione said with her arms folded. “Honestly, you’re supposed to be some kind of deadly ninja assassin.”

“Yeah,” Alex added, face scrunched up in distaste. “Seeing you moaping feels wrong.”

There was a moment of silence.

Then Ginny’s lip quirked upwards. “Then how about you give up your spot on the dueling team to me?”

Alex recoiled. “Hells no!”

Ginny’s quirked lip cracked into a full gin. “Why not? Still four days to go. Are you afraid I’d do better than you?”

“Oh, Hells no!”

“Then prove it!”

And within ten seconds, every one of the girls were going at it again, graceful and ferocious in equal measures.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“A one thousand year old basilisk, eh?” Lord Lovegood stood up from where he’d been peering closely at some ancient artifact on his study desk. “Quite a tall order, that, young man.”

Harry snorted. “Indeed. I was hoping you might provide a different perspective.”

“And you came to the right place! Different perspectives is what I’m all about. Or so everyone keeps telling me. The polite ones, anyway.” Xenophilous collapsed into an armchair and put his knuckles under his chin. “How about the fae? Any of them owe you favours?”

Harry gave a wry smile. “No.”

“Shame. What about demons?”

“Also, no.”

“Vampires?”

“Nope.”

“The Hidden Fortress of Dun-Ra-Mine?”

“I’m pretty sure that don’t exist.”

Xenophilous gave Harry a look of triumph “Oh, that’s where your wrong! I have sources.”

Harry raised an eyebrow. “And you can contact them?”

Xenophilous deflated. “No.”

“Shame.” Harry started perusing the shelves.

Xenophilous snapped his fingers. “What about the goblins?”

“I have a meeting with them tomorrow.”

Lovegood nodded in approval. “How about the hallows?”

Harry paused his inspection of an ornate scroll. “What about them?”

“If you knew where the cloak was hidden you could hide from Death himself. I’ll wager it would work on a basilisk. Or if you had the wand, you might power your way through its hide.”

Harry weighed the risk of revealing his possession of the cloak to one of his closest political allies. Then weighed it against the possibility that man already knew. He was Luna’s father, after all.

Xenophilous clearly saw his contemplation. “You know where the hallows are?” he said eagerly.

“The cloak,” Harry answered. “It is an heirloom of the Potter family.”

“Hah!” Lord Lovegood slapped his knee. “I knew it! James was always far too slippery at school for his own good. And the stone or wand?”

Harry shook his head.

“Shame. But with the cloak, well, that should give you quite the edge.”

Harry nodded. “I had it with me the last time I encountered the basalisk. It was bare feet away, but didn’t spot me. That was when Dumbledore’s Phoenix turned up and started trying to peck its eyes out. The two crashed away pretty soon after that. And I was left alone”

“The power of the cloak, indeed,” Xenophilous whispered. “What about the phoenix?”

Harry shrugged. “No idea. Never saw it again after that. Maybe it was eaten. Or petrified and shattered?”

“Maybe.” Xenophilous stroked his chin. “Well, if you need backup, I can alert the Department for the Regulation and Control of Magical Creatures of the situation.”

“No,” Harry quickly replied. “Too many inconvienant things too explain. Too many political oppenings.”

“You misunderstand me,” Xeno smiled. “I can alert the Department of the situation, without anyone knowing they’ve been alerted.”

“Ohhh!” Harry smiled back. “Then by all means, Lord Lovegood. Alert away. It’s always a good idea to have backup.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Hogwarts Castle rearranged itself daily. Sometimes new corridors pointed to new floors. Other-times a secret passage way, long forgotten, make it self known for a single hour to help a single student in dire need. And yet other times, new rooms that didn’t even appear in Hogwarts: A History, would randomly pop up out of nowhere.

This last example had happened twice in the last thirty days. The first was for the student wardrobe — a large oval room containing a single oval table — accessible, appropriately, through a large wardrobe just outside the student library. Several meetings had already been held and to describe the proceedings as ‘tense’—with Virgo and Susan sitting next to each other, surrounded by agents of the Gray and Dark, would have been the understatement of the century.

The second room was for the court and had appeared as an add-on half way up the Astronomy Tower. Small and cramped, it gave all who entered the impression of a bathroom, if going to the bathroom was a spectator sport.

Susan looked off the edge of the railing that circled the room, down into the small entrance way below where a pair of Hufflepuff and Ravenclaw fourth years stood.

One either side of her, stood Violet and Marrigold Chesterfield, gazing down at the pair, the first looking bored, the second looking amused.

“Please say that last bit again,” Susan said, not quite believing the words coming out of her mouth.

The Hufflepuff jumped right in. “I said, right— I said that if he’d help me with my homework for Potions that week then I’d cover him on that last Hogsmead trip. But when I gave him the goods, he said that he’d already got the stuff he needed from the third-floor Bazzar and that he didn’t need it any more, and now he’s refusing to pay for it!”

“That’s a lie!” said the Ravenclaw, hotly. “I did pay. You agreed I didn’t have to pay for it all it once, so I could sell it off and make the money back.”

“Yeah, but now I need the money for something else. So you need to pay right now.”

“But that’s not what you said.”

“Doesn’t matter. I bought that stuff for you with my own silver in good faith. Now I’m stuck holding your crap.”

“Rubbish! Your silver was part of the original homework deal!”

“But I didn’t know you were going to reneg on paying right away!”

Susan put a hand over her face while the two older students raged at each other below.

“Would it be unethical to start a betting pool on them?” Marrigold asked with a grin, elbows on the banister, hands under her chin.

“Yes,” Susan replied with a blank face.

“We could always give them trial by duel,” Violet suggested.

“No we are not going to have them fight each other.”

“Why not? Pain is a great teacher.”

“Or we could have them duel us!” Marigold chirped up. “Who ever lasts longest wins!”

Susan gritted her teeth. “No! We’re not doing trial by combat, duel, or anything else. We are here to judge, not to play for our own fun.”

“Spoil sport. You need to loosen up.”

They eventually ruled that the Hufflepuff was in the right and that the Ravenclaw had twenty four hours to produce the owed silver and take possession of the ordered goods.

The fact that the goods in question appeared on Argus Filches’ banned item list was never brought up.

Five more cases followed, each as small and petty in Susan’s mind as the last. Ever since becoming the head judge and head of the Student DMLE, it seemed everyone turned to her to solve their problems — so long as the problem was annoying enough.

Twenty minutes later, Susan ducked out of the court room and snuck away under a disillusionment charm, the best to hide from random students who might accost her in the halls. Really, this was one of the few charms she was unequivocally thankful to Virgo for teaching her.

Susan reached the Room of Requirement on the Seventh floor and slowly turned the handle.

“Back so soon, Susan?” Virgo asked from inside, a vicious smile spreading across her face.

The muggleborn twins were right about one thing though. She did need to fight more. The dueling Tournament was only three days away.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“Just two days until your tournament, Lord Slytherin,” Ragnok commented, almost lightly. The goblin was leading Harry down, once more, into the bowls of the bank, carrying his customary war axe. “Will we have a repeat performance of last year’s demolition?”

“I doubt it,” Harry answered, dressed in his Lord Slytherin Persona once again, “Though I doubt it will be uneventful.”

“Mmmm,” Ragnok mmmed. “I hear promising things about your friend, the Black heiress. Do you not believe she could at least match her father’s performance during his own time at Hogwarts?”

“Maybe. Truly, I do not know. I have prepared her the best I can. How far she gets will be up to her.”

Ragnok grinned a toothy grin. “Perhaps she will crush two years above her. That would be a worthy performance.”

“Perhaps,” Harry hedged.

Ragnok looked askance. “You do not believe her capable of defeating a third year?”

Harry shook his head. “Oh, no. Alex can defeat a third year, no problem. I’d be disappointed if she couldn’t defeat a fourth year, or even a fifth, if it was a straight one-on-one. But first she has to get to the third year.”

“You speak in riddles, Lord Slytherin.”

“Let’s just say, the most exciting duel of the tournament will probably be Slytherin vs. Gryffindor, First year vs First year.”

“Again?!” Ragnok stopped in front of a huge iron double door and turned to face him. “Ahh,” he said, understanding dawning. “The Malfoy girl. The Minister of the Student Wardrobe. Quite the enigma, that one.”

“Enigma?” Under his mask, Harry raised an eyebrow. “Ragnok, do you perchance have records that could prove Virgo’s true—“

“—Lord Slytherin,” Ragnok interrupted. “I must remind you that such matters are private. Just as are your own.”

Harry bowed slightly. “Of course.”

“And speaking of your own matters,” Ragnok turned to the double doors and put his hands to them. “I hope you appreciate the trust that is being shown by brining you here. No wizard has set foot in these chambers for four hundred years.”

“The trust of Gringotts is an honor I always hold dear.”

Ragnok nodded as though that was the bare minimum reply he would accept, before firmly pushing open the doors.

A wave of heat the likes of which Harry had only experienced a few times before hit him almost like it was a physical punch in the face. The heat was accompanied by an orange light that bathed every surface of the huge cavern beyond, sending stark shadows dancing and flickering across the walls. The sounds of dozens of hammers hitting metal rang in his ears, accompanied by goblin shouts and oaths, and even the occasional scream. A hundred forges lit the space, all fed from a central giant chamber, and next to the chamber, lay the largest dragon Harry had ever seen, chained down to the floor, slowly blowing dragon fire into the giant structure.

As they made their way across the room to a door on the far side, Harry could pick out snatches and snippets of many conversations in the Goblin tongue.

“Grip it tighter, idiot! I swear if you mess up one more billet I’ll have you down with the dragon shovelers.”

“Ai-Po! Nickel and Chromium, now!”

“Just one drop of virgin’s blood...”

The items the goblins were working represented every classification of artifact Harry could recognise and even a few that he had no idea the purpose of.

Nor was it all metal work. Off in a corner, a small crowd of goblin females were busy working with silk, leather, and gem stones the size of a wizard’s fingernail. Although why they were working in here, which had to be incredibly uncomfortable given the constant heat, Harry had no idea.

The thing that most supprised him about the goblin forges though, was that many of the items being worked on didn’t seem to hold any value to the goblins working them. He saw more than one wonderful-looking example carelessly tossed away as they traversed the room, and even as they reached the door, Harry saw one goblin grip a sword blade the likes of which any wizarding lord would drool to own, shake his head in disgust, and pitched it into a nearby pile of gleaming silver scrap.

The two stepped through the archway and the door closed behind them, shutting off the heat and muffling the sounds within.

“The last time I had the chance to see that room,” Harry started, “it was desolate and smoking — an empty husk of a place. It’s surprising to see it so full of life and energy.”

Ragnok snorted. “The crafting chamber is kept busy at all hours.”

“Even when there is no need for the objects it makes?”

Ragnok shoot him a piercing look. “Yes, even then.”

“Hmmm,” Harry hmmmed.

“Now this is what you are here for!” Ragnok said loudly, hefting his war axe off his shoulder and propping it up against a wall. He reached a large cabinet and opened it, letting Harry see the full extent of its contents.

“If you’re going to be fighting a one-thousand year old basilisk, then you’ll need something that can actually pierce armor that magically powerful.”

Despite himself, Harry gave an appreciative whistle from under his mask. There was enough sharp goblin silver hanging in front of him to start a small war, and there was no doubt the examples here were all a cut above even what he’d seen in the crafting chamber.

Ragnok took a sword, seemingly at random, and presented it to Harry by the cross guard. It felt utilitarian in his grasp, well balanced, but nothing special, not like he felt when he held his wand.

“I think—” he started to say, but didn’t get any further before Ragnok snatched the sword back.

Harry couldn’t help smirk. “This all feels incredibly familiar. Are you perhaps going to tell me that the sword chooses the goblin?”

“No,” Ragnok said simply, working his way down the line of weapons. “I just needed to be sure.”

“Sure?”

“Of this!”

“Oh.” Harry stared at the sword now held in Ragnok’s hand. “Yes, I can see that would do the job.”

To call this sword snakey wouldn’t be doing the word justice. Serpents coiled all around the handle, the cross-guard, a good way up the blade. Even the pommel, a clear ball of crystal filled with mist, was clamped down tight in the mouth of a sharp-fanged snake.

Ragnok presented the sword to him.

This time when Harry took the blade, he felt a very real power surge up his arm. The blade shimmered green.

“Infused with a powerful dose of swelling solution,” Ragnok supplied. “Just one nick would bisect a troll.”

“Magnificent,” Harry murmured. “I hope I don’t have to use it.”

“If you do, I’d recommend pairing it with a solid iron shield,” Ragnok supplied. “Perhaps even a mirrored shield? You never know your luck. Although, I’m afraid we can’t help you with that. The craft of a good aurar shield is well outside the ability of Gringotts.”

Harry fixed the accompanying thestral leather sheath around his waist. “I have a meeting with Lord Smith before the operation begins.”

Ragnok smirked. “I was not aware the Noble House of Smith had that knack either.” His look turned thoughtful. “And I know the two of you are allies, but if you would accept my advice, I would not be too cavalier about showing off your new blade around him. The Smiths and Gringotts—” He paused for a moment as though looking for the right word. “—Don’t really get along.”

— DPaSW:NRiCaD —

Lord James Potter, political leader of the Light, tensed as he was led into the ornate office of one of the most dangerous individuals in Europe, if not the world. He had no idea, when he’d started this particular quest, that his efforts would lead here, but in hindsight he supposed he shouldn’t have been surprised. The more powerful the individual, the more pies they’d have fingers in, and this individual probably had enough pies to require hiring assistants, just so there were enough fingers to go around.

The bronze plaque on the desk read, First Transylvanian Minister of Magic, Count Dragos Dracula, Mugwump, Electorate, Eighty-six times Gobstones Champion.

Lord Potter bowed respectfully as the minister rose from behind the desk.

“Ahh, the stag lord,” said the ancient vampire in greeting. “Do come in. How are things in the Albion?”

“Quite okay,” James replied. He’d already decided keeping his chards as close to his chest as possible. “Everyone’s looking forward to the dueling tournament on Saturday.”

“Ah, yes. I recall your heir’s performance was quite impressive last year.” Dracula gave a pointed smile.
James nodded, stiffly.

“It’s just a shame it doesn’t look like he’ll be well in time to compete this year.”

James blinked in surprise. He’d been expecting a barbed comment about Harry now being his heir. But apparently the minister had been talking about John. So many of his peers had been on his case about that since the Winter Festival, many asking very awkward questions...

‘So, you have a new heir, ehh? How’d that happen?’

‘So, is this like, The Muggle Prince of Atlantis?’

‘So, when are you going to make an announcement in the Prophet?”

The answer to that last question, at least, he could give. Never. By the time the question of John not being his official heir became relevant, he planned to have already solved it. Remus Lupin would rue the day he took on the mantle of Lord Slytherin and started messing in the affairs of the Noble Houses.

Dracula, by contrast, seemed to be far more gentlemanly about the whole business. Then he realized the other implication of the vampire’s statement about John. The First Minister of Transylvania knew exactly why he was here. Damn it.

A small wooden box was produced and placed on the desk between them. Dracula opened it to show the contents. Fresh Mandrake.

James Potter sucked in his breath. “What do you want for it?”

Dracula closed the box lid. “Nothing.”

James Potter blinked. “Nothing?”

“Nothing.” The vampire repeated. “That has all been taken care of.” You apparently have a friend in the shadows, Lord Potter. It was they who smoothed your pathway to me. It was they who alerted me to your need such that I could arrange this—‘ he patted the box—‘ to be here in time for you arrival. And they have already arranged payment as well.”

James Potter frowned. “I can’t—“

“—I also need to say, Lord Potter,” the vampire cut him off. “That this is the only supply of Mandrake that I can currently divert from other, more critically important shipments.”

James Potter stared at the box for several long moments. “Very well,” he eventually said. “Please give my thanks to this friend in the shadows.” He took the box proffered him.

“I will,” Dracula answered.

James paused at the door. “And if this friend in the shadows happens to be Lord Malfoy, let him know that he can go to hell.”

The door to the study closed.

Dracula listened to the footsteps retreat down the stone-floor corridor outside. Then he chuckled to himself.

“Perfect future in-laws.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Lord Smith growled as a beautiful length of true silver was drawn from its scabbard.

“I imagine there’s a story behind this,” said Harry Potter, or Lord Slytherin, as Smith now knew him to be.

“There most certain is a story,” Smith said through gritted teeth. If anyone else had flashed true silver in front of him after acquiring it from the goblins so brazenly, he’d have smacked them through the nearest wall with his hammer. But this was the Gray’s lord of lords, the child that had lured him away from the Light, the one who had unified a ragtag alliance of houses at the age of eight and forged them into a true political power. And so, he stayed his hand. That didn’t stop him from glaring though.

“You don’t have to tell me, if you don’t want to,” Slytherin said. “We do have other matters to attend to tonight.”

Smith glared for a few long more moments before grunting under his breath.

The two started walked away from the floo Slytherin had arrived at, up the corridor and towards the armory.

“The full story’s too long to tell now,” Smith said. “The short version is that when the goblin’s gained the skill to forge goblin silver.” He spat the last two words. “The records show that we gave it to them in a marriage alliance. And forever forsook the knowledge of it ourselves. The truth is that they stole it. Filthy mongrol bastards.”

They both stopped at one of the many portraits in the corridor. It contained a bear of a wizard, even more so than Lord Smith himself.

“Reginald here was lord at the time, isn’t that right, Regi?”

The figure in the portrait glared at the scabbard into which Slytherin had re-sheathed the silver snake sword. “It is. You’re telling this boy about the Great Betrayal?”

“Not a boy, you old coot!” Lord Smith barked back. “Don’t go all lordly on me just because we have guests. Lord Slytherin is our lord of lords. He commands our earned respect.”

The portrait scoffed. “A lord of lords is nothing compared to a champion of a higher power! I’ll do what I damn well please, boy!”

Lord Smith smashed his hammer right into the portrait, causing the cloth to tear, the occupant to flee, and the wall behind it to explode into the random room beyond. He turned back to Slytherin, who, as much as Harry Potter ever showed uncalculated expression, was definitely looking like someone who’d seen something they were not expecting.

“Ignore him, Slytherin” Smith said as they continued.

“The champion of a higher power?” Slytherin asked, catching up to him and falling in at his side.

“That part of the story is a Smith family secret. It is nothing like what you see in the theater. I respectfully ask you to forget what you have already heard.”

“I just find it hard to imagine the goblins stealing from the champion of a higher power.”

“Hah. Our house made them pay for it a hundred fold. Green blood flowed through goblin caverns like souls flowing down the river styx!”

“Then why the ongoing animosity?”

Lord Smith glared at Slytherin. “Do you want this shield or not? I’d hate all my hard work on those micro-runes of yours to go to waste because I accidentally chucked it into the furnace.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“Oh, I say!” Professor Flitwick did a triple back flip, landed lightly on his feet, and thrust his wand forward. “Miss Malfoy, that was magnificent!”

On the other side of the room, Virgo breathed heavily with her hands on her knees.

“I must declare,” Flitwick continued. “I was initially dubious when John suggested including you in our private tutoring sessions, but you have surpassed all my expectations. Why, if you keep this up, you might even reach John’s level before long. You will never be as powerful as him, but in terms of finesse and technique? You have already well passed him.”

Virgo took a deep breath and straightened up again. She looked the professor in the eyes. “Do you think I can go seven for seven in the dueling tournament?”

Flitwick look dubious. “Unless you have some secret weapon in reserve, I would say unlikely. Not without a lot more practice.”

“I do have a secret weapon,” Virgo replied, thinking of her animagus form. It wasn’t one she wanted to use. Not unless she had to. The implications of her being a parcel-tongue were problematic right now. What with the basilisk attacks. “But I don’t want to use it,” she concluded

Flitwick shook his head.

“And there is no more time to practice,” she continued. “The tournament is tomorrow.”

— DPaSW:NRiCaD —

Morning dawned.

All across Magical Britain, wizards and witches everywhere woke up to their morning edition of the Daily Prophet, delivered by the army of owls employed for the purpose.

HOGWARTS DUELING TOURNAMENT TODAY, The headline read. PAGE 5: COMPETITORS, PAGE 6: HISTORY, PAGE 7: ANALYSIS.

Hundreds of discussions across hundreds of breakfast tables. Would this year’s tournament be as spectacular as last year’s? Surely not without the Potter twins. But that did little to stop the building feeling of anticipation. Those who had tickets thanked their lucky stars. Those without fiddled with dials on their Wizarding Wirelesses.

Toast was buttered. Jam was spread.

In Diagon Alley’s Pensive Parlor, several wizards were going over their last minute plans to capture the competition from every critical angle.

 In the Ministry of Magic, close to a dozen members of the Department of Magical Games and Sports filed into their bosses office for a final briefing.

At the Floo Office HQ, wizards covered from head to toe in green soot were already hard at work, fully expecting the massive surge of floo activity thirty minutes before the first wand draw.

The Hogwarts Dueling Tournament had always been a highlight of the Wizarding sporting calendar, but the nail-biting performance of the previous year had catapulted its prominence to levels no one in living memory could remember.

At Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry, the house elves were frantically cooking up a storm, preparing food not just for the students, but also the hundreds of outside visitors that soon would fill the stands to standing room only.

In each of the four house common rooms, the more enterprising students were finalizing the castle-wide betting pools. Others were determined to bring the Hogwarts student bazar to the visitors in a big way.

In the Professor’s lounge, the teachers were strategizing ways to stop them.

And in the headmaster’s office, Headmaster Gilderoy Lockhart, Order of Merlin Third Cass, Honorary Member of the Dark Force Defense League, and Five times winner of Witch Weekly’s Most Charming Smile award, was sweating.

“Umm, complete control, you say? You want me to give up complete control of the wards?”

In the chair opposite him, Lord Slytherin radiated power. And it was Lord Slytherin. Though Lockhart knew intellectually that this being in front of him was also Harry Potter, one of his own students (sort of), and a boy of only twelve years, that didn’t change anything. Lockhart had traveled widely to write his books. He’d hired the most experienced and dangerous bodyguards and mercenaries he could to investigate some of the most dangerous places on Earth. And whenever shit hit the fan, as it inevitably sometimes did, he was smart enough to hide his ass behind the people who knew what they were doing and let them get on with it.

Except now he had no bodyguards. With Voldemort gone, he never thought he’d face such a monster in his own homeland. But now he knew better. He was more than halfway through writing Slytherin’s book and probably knew more about the man than anyone. He knew exactly what kind of a monster was sitting opposite him.

He tried loosening his collar, but it did nothing to help the sweat trickling down his neck. “I can’t just do that, my lord,” he tried. “The headmaster has a duty...” he trailed off in the force of that aura.

“It will only be for the duration of the tournament,” Slytherin said. “I have a critically important job that needs to be taken care of in the school. It requires its complete evacuation. The tournament is the perfect time to accomplish this.”

Lockhart tried to object again, but Slytherin continued.

“It is for the safety of the students.”

“But—”

“It may be related to the Chamber of Secrets.”

That forced Lockhart’s jaw to snap shut. His eyes widened. “You know where it is?” He leaped up out of his chair. “That’s what this is about?!” His face slid from anxiety to hope. “You can fix that?! Please say you can. I’ve had countless parents, and the teachers, and the ministry breathing down my neck about that.”

“I have received infomation,” Slytherin said vaguely. “But to sort out the problem, I need the wards.”

Lockhart hesitated again.

“The ministry, of course, has been informed.”

That did it. Lockhart firmed his jaw. “Very well, then. They are yours.”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Argus Filtch knew how to grovel. Argus Filtch, in fact, had only two modes of operation, of which groveling was one. The other was malicious cruelty against whoever he smelled weakness in.

The lords and ladies were not such a group. And this particular lord had Argus Filtch in such a heightened state of grovel, that he might as well attach his floor mop to his nose.

“And once the tournament begins, I want everyone out,” Lord Slytherin said, walking briskly down the corridor.

“Yes, my lord. Of course, my lord,” Filtch simpered, now practically hopping to keep up. “Your every whim is my humble command, my lord. Just say the wor—”

“And once everyone is out, I want you to finish locking up and withdraw yourself and Mrs Norris to the Green Houses.”

“I live to serve, my lord. I won’t let you down, my lord.” Filtch’s hat fell off as he jerked along, forcing him to stop a moment to pick it up. By the time he’d retrieved it, Lord Slytherin was already well ahead.

“See that you don’t,” Lord Slytherin called behind him. The man obviously had places to be. “What happens in this castle today, is not for you.”

Filtch watched after the retreating figure. He might be a squib, but that didn’t mean he couldn’t feel the raw magical power radiating from the figure. “Not for you, he says,” Filtch muttered, once he was quite sure Slytherin couldn’t hear him. “Is there anything around here that is for me?”

Around his legs, Mrs Norris mewed after the retreating lord.

“And you can stop pining after him, as well!”

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

In the Slytherin girl’s dormitory, Alex stared herself down in the bathroom mirror. Quick as a whip, she snapped her wand from its holster and thrust in it front of her. She flipped her hair over her shoulder and smirked. “You think your win is garenteed, Virgo. But you have no idea the powers you face, now. Behold! For I—“

“Alex?”

Alex’s heart leapt into her throat.

“Are you done yet?” A clearly naked Luna stuck her head around the door. “Only some of us still need to shower.”

“Yes!” Alex yipped. “I mean, yes! Yes, I am done.”

“Yay!” Luna skipped into the room.

For some reason, Alex couldn’t stop herself staring. “Um, how much of that did you hear?”

“Mmm? Oh. All of it. Quite acceptable villain trash-talk. Eight of out ten. Your practice is paying off. But you had better get properly dressed.” Luna stepped into the shower. “We can’t meet Harry in just underwear, you know. Well, not until—”

Alexandra didn’t give her closest friend time to get any further. She quickly fled the tiny room, ears burning hot.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

“You wish the ghosts of Hogwarts to leave the castle?” Nearly Headless Nick looked askance down the long table, lined with ghosts on either side. “Ridiculous! The ghost council has never before been asked something so outrageous!”

At the foot of the table, Harry stood tall next to the Bloody Baron, mask firmly in place, now on his second aging potion of the day. “Of course, I wouldn’t ask you for something so sensitive without bringing something of value,” he said. “I learned from the last time I stood before you, that the ghosts of Hogwarts are not so easily swayed.”

Nearly Headless Nick made a disbelieving sound in his throat. “Something of value, he says. And what, Lord Slytherin, could you possibly have to offer such august persons as ourselves?”

The other ghosts around the table looked to him, some in interest, others in disbelief, yet others with silent resentment.

Harry smiled grimly under his mask. In truth, there were only a few ghosts of the dozen around the table he needed to sway to tip the balance in his favour. He turned to the Gray Lady. “To you, my lady, I offer news of your mother’s diadem.”

The Grey Lady’s eyes widened.

“Through great effort, I have found it, and eventually intend to return it to the House of Ravenclaw, once I have figured out a way to remove a particularly nasty curse that has been laid upon it. The one you knew as Tom Riddle defiled it with dark magic the likes of which no wizard should wield. But I believe I can return it to its former state.”

The Grey Lady said nothing for long moments, just as she usually said nothing. Then, she spoke. “If what you say is true, then you have done me a great service, Lord Slytherin. I look forward to seeing it rest on my mother’s head again.”

Harry nodded, then turned to the Fat Friar. “Father, I thought long and hard about what a wizard such as you would value. But in the end, it was obvious. You were one of the greatest healers in the land when you lived. While I am not anything close to a healer, I do possess the talent of silver limbs. I offer you my services to heal one soul you come across at your discrection, whenever you will it.”

The Fat Friar immediately laughed. “I thought so!” He gestured around the table. “Did I not tell you, my friends? I knew Lord Slytherin deserved a chance. No man who wields the healing powers to aid of his fellow man can be that bad a person.”

“In trade,” Sir Nicholas said dismissively.

“Oh, pish,” the Fat Friar retorted. “Besides, I want to see what he has for you, Nick.”

Sir Nichloas sniffed.

In reply to the stated challenge, Harry unsheathed the Slytherin sword at his belt. “I can grant you membership to the Headless Hunt.”

There was a pause. Then all the ghosts around the table burst into laughter. All except the Bloody Baron, and, importantly, Sir Nicholas. He did not look amused. Even the Grey lady giggled.

“Lord Slytherin,” Sir Nicholas eventually said in a frosty voice, once the laughter had died down. “If this is your idea of a joke, then I do not find it amusing. Even if that is a true silver sword you wield, such a thing will not finish the job that my executioner so incompetently started. To do that, the blade would need to be etherial, and the magics capable of that were lost long ago. Long before the Smith family first smelted the first such blade. Not even Gryffindor himself could have done that.”

Harry didn’t try to argue back. Instead, he merely reached into his robes, withdrew a small silver bell, and gave it a faint tinkle.

The door to the room opened, and in walked his favorite Necromancer duo. Alex and Luna wore simple matching dresses of black and white respectively, completely devoid of magic. He knew they were magic-less, because he’d bought them himself from a muggle department store, given them to Dan to hold for a minute, then kept them stored in his ritual room until needed.

“A Black?” Sir Nicholas asked. “And a Lovegood? What good will they...” he trailed off as Alex smirked and withdrew her dementor bone stake from her robes.

Sir Nicholas frowned. “Are you serious?”

Alex scowled.

“No, that’s her fath—“

“Luna!”

“Yes, we are serious,” Harry said. “It took some delving into the Aether Unpacked, but I completed the missing part of the ritual that Luna’s family has kept for over a thousand years. If you will follow us to the Hogwarts Ritual Room?”

Twenty minutes later, Sir Nicholas was laughing uproariously, his head cleanly separated from his head by a ghost-like copy of the silver sword he still wore by his side. The vote passed, and the ghosts officially decided to vacate the castle for the day.

“But where are we going to go?” the Grey Lady asked.

Harry rung the bell again and pandemonium filled the room as two dozen headless riders on horseback crashed through the stonework.

“Welcome to the club, Nick!” bellowed Sir Patrick. “Get on!”

One of the rider’s hoisted a squealing Grey Lady up onto his horse. The other ghosts just as quickly joined the hunt, each one behind a rider.

Sir Nicholas practically bounded up behind Sir Patrick.

“We’ll have to get you a horse, of course,” Sir Patrick said. “But that won’t be a problem. And now, away!” He pointed dramatically and the host shot away out of a closed window.

Luna threw the window open.

“And I intened to move Angelystor into the castle!” Lord Slytehrin shouted after them.

“Be our guest!” came the rapidly fading reply.

— DPaSW: NRiCaD —

Deep below the ground, Virgo was sweating. She wasn’t even aware that lamia could sweat.

The basilisk ran its much larger body up against her, drawing back and forth across the chamber like a pacing cat.

“When, my queen?” the basilisk hissed. “When will we mate?”

$Sssoon,$” Virgo hissed back. $Sssoon$,” she repeated, racking her brain for another reason to put this off. “$It’sss that time of the month.$ Virgo winced. She was rapidly running out of excuses.

The basilisk weaved back towards her and loomed. Its forked tongue tasted the air less than a foot from Virgo’s face. “My Queen will serve her king.”

“$We must depose the falssse king,$” Virgo hissed back. Sweat was now definitely pouring down her back.

“Yes. But you do not let me kill. One look is all I would need. One look, and the false king would fall.”

$The falssse king will have protection! He will not sssuccumb ssso easily. We must be cunning. We must be discreet. Our plans are working! People are beginning to suspect him. Soon, with just a few more attacks on the right people, the Wizengamot will demand action. They will demand it of him. And he will have no choice but to admit he knew all along.”$

“And my queen is not afraid the false king will accuse her?”

$No.$

The basilisk leveled its gaze at Virgo. “Once the false king is gone. You will hatch my clutch.”

Virgo submissively lowered her head before quickly bolting for the portal. Once Lord Slytherin was exposed and ousted from Hogwarts, she was sealing up the chamber using every spell, enchantment, and trick the teenage dark lord knew.

#

Torches flickered on the walls.

“Girls,” Daphne announced “It is time. From here on out, I want your full attention.”

Around the table, Hermione, Alex, Ginny, and Luna all nodded.

“It is currently Nine o’clock,” Daphne continued. “Synchronize pocket watches, now.”

Four silver pocket watches were produced from various purses, pockets, and—luna’s case—a drawer in the body of her witches’ hat.

Daphne placed her own watch back inside her purse. “Ear mirror pieces on, now.”

Everyone except Alexandra retrieved one of the tiny magic earpieces they’d used the previous year and placed them inside their right ear.

Inside Daphne’s purse, a shrunk trunk held the matching ear piece mirrors, all pointed towards each other in a circle.

“This is Eagle Eyes,” Daphne said. “Call ins, now.”

“Healer,” “Bulldozer,” “Shadow,” replied Hermione, Luna, and Ginny. Their voices echoed in their ears.

“Babysitter,” said Alex in a deadpan voice.

Daphne nodded. “Today’s operation will be a two phase plan. Our primary goal is the destruction of the main threat, the basilisk, by any means. The secondary goal is the absolutely secrecy of the operation. A third goal is the recovery and securing of the basilisk corpse.”

Daphne brought a finger down on the table, on which had been placed a map. “At or around eleven o’clock, the guests from outside the castle will start to arrive...”

#

Lord Potter felt a thrill as he stepped down from the headless carriage which brought him and his wife up from Hogsmeade. The Hogwarts Dueling Tournament always did that for him. He was rather less thrilled when he realized just who was stepping down from the carriage ahead of them.

“Lord Malfoy.”

“Lord Potter.”

“Lily.”

“Narsissa.”

The four magicals gave each other nods before turning towards the walk to the arena.

It took a moment for Lord Potter to realise that Narsissa had taken Lily off to the side, leaving him alone with the leader of the Dark.

“I believe we have seating next to each other,” Malfoy said.

Lord Potter checked and saw that it was true. He scowled.

“Now, come on, James,” Malfoy said in an oily voice. “Do you truly hate me so much?”

“Yes.”

“Ouch. ”

They soon found their seats in the quickly filling dueling arena.

“It should be quite a show,” Malfoy said, raising his voice above the general hubub. A random cheer went up from the crowd as Ludo Bagman took the mic. “Shame that John couldn’t be here. You didn’t get the mandrake brewed in time?”

“No,” Lord Potter scowled.

“Not to worry. This will be the perfect opportunity to show you just how strong my Virgo is. And why she will be worth every galleon I ask.”

#

Daphne jabbed her finger again. “...Along with Lord Potter and Lord Malfoy, other persons of interest include the minister, the humblehag, several department heads, over fifty other lords, and Alex’s father, Lord Black...”

#

Sirius Black stared in shock across the arena. Was James really sitting side by side with Lord Malfoy, just chatting away as though they were best friends?

“I say,” said a random wizard beside him. “Is that Lord Potter sitting side by side with Lord Malfoy, just chatting away as though they were best friends?”

“It does seem so,” said another.

#

“...Ludo Bagman will officially open the tournament will officially at exactly eleven thirty. I will place myself on top of the owlery, keeping an eye out for critical events. After that, we all play our roles according to the plan.” Daphne nodded to where Harry stood watching the meeting by the door. “Good luck.”

#

“And now!” Bellowed the voice of Ludo Bagman across the space. “I welcome you all! My lords and ladies, wizards and witches, to the annual Hogwarts Dueling Tournament!”

#

Far off in the distance, behind the walls of the arena, the crowd cheered. Standing at the gates and looking up at the castle with a nostalgic gaze, Albus Dumbeldore took a moment to sort his feelings out before stepping back onto the grounds he’d been so unceremoniously booted from the previous year.

“Dumbledore!” exclaimed a surprised Professor Vector, she who was checking the tickets of all who arrived. “I didn’t know you were coming.”

“I couldn’t stay away,” he said with mild amusement. “I may not be headmaster anymore, but I can’t help wanting to know how well the next generation is progressing.”

#

Up on the owelery roof, a golden eagle turned into a young blonde haired witch with blue eyes. “Snake Crown, this is Eagle Eyes. Light Goat has been spotted and is walking towards the arena. I repeat, I have eyes on Light Goat. Please advise.”

An echoy voice echoed in her ear through the headpiece. “Eagle Eyes this is Snake Crown. Keep eyes on path to castle and alert if Light Goat moves towards. Do not. I repeat do not engage. Hopefully he’ll be too busy being freaked out by Alex and Virgo to notice anything odd going on.”

#

“—and after the events of last year,” echoed the voice of Ludo Bagman, all around the arena, “I have been required to remind you all that Hogwarts dueling rules do in fact allow family magics, as well as other, err.. historically important transfiguration abilities.”

In the Slytherin girl’s changing rooms, Alex smirked as she pulled her dragon hide boots on over her socks.

Standing by the door, Hermione, the only other girl on the team, was already dressed. “Dumbledore just arrived,” she whispered into the stillness.

Alex grinned. “Going to face him down again?”

“If he tries to arrest you, yes.”

The two girls gazed at each other.

Alex finished tiying her laces, pattered down the skirts of her dueling robes, and walked to stand beside Hermione, facing the corridor leading to waiting room.

Then walked together down the corridor.

“For Slytherin?” Alex asked.

Hermione nodded. “For Harry.”

#

The moment he arrived in the arena, the part of Virgo’s soul that was Tom Riddle screamed in fury.

Dumbledore. Even through the walls she could feel him.

Virgo gripped her wand tighter.

“The first match will be Ravenclaw vs. Griffindor!” bellowed the voice of Ludo Bagman. “Please welcome into the arena, the Ravenclaw first year seed, Timmothy Adams!”

“It’s time!” said the Gryffindor dueling captain, jerking up from his bench. “I want you all focused.” He opened the door. The sounds of the crowd outside flooded into the room. “Good luck, Miss Minister.” He grinned at her.

Virgo looked up at the seventh-year. He was boyishly attractive, but didn’t come close to John in either power or ambition.

“I do not require luck,” she said, evenly, standing up and brushing herself down. “I will destroy them all.”

“Glad to hear it.”

“And now, please welcome into the arena, our Gryffindor first year seed and Hogwarts’ first ever Minister of the Student Wardrobe, Miss Virgo Malfoy!”

Virgo walked out at the head of the team to applause that was deafening. It would be interesting to see how Dumbledore reacted to an incredibly talented student whose childhood wardrobe he hadn’t set on fire.

#

Dumbledore stared in fascination as a child that should not exist walked into the dueling arena.

She was Julia Olsen, a muggleborn from Sweden, or so the records showed. Yet the same records showed that she’d originally been a squib, cast out by the Malfoys and shipped abroad to spare the family the embarrassment.

When the Lucius and Narssissa realized their mistake, they’d sent for her back, and she’d accepted, with open arms, apparently.

And now here she was. Confident, poised, powerful, well-liked, by all accounts. And a Gryffindor... That last bit was surprising.

She marched up to the Ravenclaw boy and boldly offered her hand to him.

#

The boy was determined, Virgo could see that. They shook hands and she used the cheering of the crowd as an opportunity to lean in close. “I will beat you,” she whispered into his ear. “And then I will beat your second-year. And then your third. Your fourth. Your fifth. You will be angry and humiliated by your loss. But when you see how effortlessly I crush your teammates, you will understand that fighting me is like trying to punch a flood.”

Virgo leaned back and saw the boys eyes wide.

She flashed him a smile she knew would be described as cute. It would only add to the boy’s shame. “No hard feelings.”

The noise of the crowd started to settle down.

“Quiet please!” Bagman called out.

The crowd grew silent.

Virgo moved to her position and bowed in time with the Ravenclaw.

There was a moment of stillness.

Suddenly, a bagpipe sounded a note.

#

Inside the Slytherin Dungeons, Harry couldn’t hear anything from the arena outside. He was entirely dependent on the girls for critical infomation.

Suddenly, his earpiece activated. “Snake Crown this is Book Worm,” said Hermione’s echoey voice in Harry’s ear. “Diary is engaged. Phase one is go.”

“Copy that,” Harry said. “Phase one is go.” He turned to Luna. “Ready to play our part?”

“Yes, Harry,” Luna said dreamily.

“Good.”

They both readied their wands. They were in the very deepest part of the dungeon — in a dead-end that normally, not even Filch bothered patrolling.

With his total control of the wards for the day, Harry reached into the ancient magic that protected Hogwarts and deactivated a very specific protection.

“Go!” he barked.

The two ran up the corridor, and split at the first junction. They both immediately shouted, “Stupefy!” and the two paintings on either side of the adjoining hall froze in place with looks of shock on their faces.

Harry raced left, while Luna raced right.

“Stupefy!” “Stupefy!” “Stupefy!”

Painting after painting froze in place.

They dashed around the dungeon covering every corridor they knew. Every secret passage way. Every nook and cranny.

It was a race against time now. They had the entire school to cover before they could safely engage the basilisk with no witnesses, and only the time of the dueling tournament in which to do it.

#

“Rictumsempra!” shouted the Ravenclaw.

Virgo said nothing. She merely slashed her wand diagonally and a hurricane force wind blasted out, sending dust and grass flying.

The Ravenclaw’s spell vanished into the cloud and a split second later, he himself was knocked back across the ground, falling with a cry, skidding on his shoulder, stopping the fall with his hands.

When the dust cleared, Virgo stood unmarked in the epicenter of a flattened circle of grass. She smiled. “Come!” she shouted. “Show me your worth!”

#

“Oh! Look at that!” Bellowed the voice of Ludo Bagman. “That was a close one. Stunner right by the ear. Banishing charm full in the chest! Ouch! I say, was that a slug belcher?! Don’t see that much these days. Whops! Got to be more careful there, young man. Great scott! I thought she was going for the kill there!”

The whole arena ooo’d and ahh’d as the two first years dueled. Or rather, while Virgo dueled and her opponent got smacked around like a rag doll.

In the Hufflepuff team pit, Susan could barely watch. She sat with her hands over her face, peering through cracks in her fingers.

Beside her, Marigold Chesterfield elbowed her in the ribs and cheerfully commented, “She’s really good, isn’t she?”

Susan didn’t reply. Her face was flaming with embarrassment.

“I mean, she could just end this in an instant, but she’s giving him lots of time to have fun as well.”

Susan gritted her teeth.

“That’s so thoughtful. I can see why she’s your friend.”

Susan snapped. A moment later she was on her feet. “Virgo!” she screamed across the arena. “Stop playing with him and win!”

She saw Virgo turn her head in their direction. One red spell aimed properly later, and the Ravenclaw first-year fell face first into the dirt.

“First match to Gryffindor!” Bagman bellowed. “Gryffindor — one. Ravenclaw — nill!”

Susan breathed out.

“My turn!” Marigold sang. She hopped up and brushed down the folds of her dueling robes.

“Marigold!” called an older voice behind them. They both turned. Cedric Diggory gave the muggleborn a look that said he meant business. “Remember your role,” he said. “Black is not to be taken lightly. Wear her down and expose as many of her tricks as you can.”

“Yes, Captain.” And with that, she practically ran into the arena. She didn’t even wait for Bagman to announce her.

“I’m not captain yet,” Cedric grumbled.

#

“Come-on!” Filtch yelled. “Out with you!”

“But I told you I’ve got homework to finish!” complained the third-year Gryffindor Filtch was dragging along by his ear.

“And I told you you can do your bleed’n homework outside!” He yanked open one of the many smaller doors to the castle and practically threw the boy out.

The boy stumbled away with a curse.

“And that’s the lot of ‘em.” Filtch said.

Not too far away, Ginny scowled under her breath, crouched and hidden under the invisibility cloak. That was not ‘the lot of ‘em’.

She inspected the Mauradeer’s Map and saw that four students were still in the castle — four students and one teacher.

“Eagle Eyes, this is Shadow,” Ginny whispered into her ear mirror. “Caretaker has ceased his role with non-combatants still in the castle.”

“Understood, Shadow,” said Daphne’s echoey voice in her ear. “Begin rounding up the stragglers. Snake Crown, Did you hear that?”

“I heard,” said Harry’s voice, sounding like he was running hard. “Shadow, take only the students. I’ll handle the teacher.”

#

Hermione frowned as she listened to the chatter on her ear mirror. What teacher was still in the castle? She could see Professor Vector in the crowd. There was Mcgnagall. And there was Snape, Pince, Lockhart, Babbling, and Lily Potter. Flitwick was sat with his Ravenclaws, as was Sprout with her Hufflepuffs. Sinistra and Burbage were also sat together. And she knew Binns had been taken with the Headless Haunt, much to the old geezer’s great displeasure. Hooch didn’t live in the castle, Pomfrey was down by the arena pit with her wand at the ready, and Kettleburn was in Saint Mungoes, again. So who did that leave?

Alex stood up. “My time is now,” she whispered.

“And now!” Bagman bellowed. “For the Slytherin team, please welcome, Heiress Alexandra Patrica Black!”

Alex walked down the steps and into the arena, dueling robes billowing out all around her.

Hermione stared after her. There wasn’t a single guest of wind anywhere to be felt. Had she charmed them to do that?

#

On the other side of the stands, Sirius chuckled as Alex walked out into the arena like a pint-sized morgana le fay. Had it really been almost twelve years?

“I say, fancy seeing you here!”

Sirius started and looked around. He sighed when he saw who it was. Lord Lovegood, and behind him, Lord Greengrass.

“Sirius!” Xenophilius sat down cheerfully next to him. “Just in time for Alex’s debut! How do you think she’ll do?”

“She’ll win,” he said simply. “But what are you—”

Before he could make any kind of protest, Lord Greengrass sat down on his other side.

“—doing here?” he finished. He suddenly felt rather trapped.

“Just looking for the best view,” Greengrass said in a polite voice. “Xeno saw two seats free and I hoped whoever was already here wouldn’t begrudge us too much.”

“Not at all,” Sirius found himself grumbling. He hated politics, and there was no doubt in his mind the real reason these two had pinned him like this.

“So, who’s the competition?” Xeno asked.

“Err, not sure,” Sirius said. “A muggleborn, I think.”

“And now, for the Hufflepuff team!” Ludo’s voice echoed. “Practically already in the fight! With the way she just ran in like that… very enthusastic. Please welcome, Miss Marigold Chesterfield!”

The crowd applauded.

Jacob clapped politely. “Anyone fancy a flutter?”

“On if Alex wins?” Xeno asked. “No one’s taking that bet, old chap.”

“No, on how far she gets. I would put five galleons on two rounds.”

“Five galleons, hmm? I don’t think you’re giving the witch enough credit, Jacob. I say three rounds.”

Three rounds? Sirius frowned as he watched his little girl square up against the hufflepuff. He knew she was good, but could she really go three rounds? Sure, she had the advantage of being an animagus, which massively helped with magic regeneration, and he’d been suspecting for a while that the missing Black Library was in some way her doing, but that wouldn’t help against an older opponent who simply knew more magic. On the other hand, he was her father, and he’d promised himself to be more supportive.

“Seven rounds!” he shouted, making Jacob flinch and cover his ear. “I say seven!”

“Okay then,” Xeno replied with an amused look on his face. “Clearly you know something we don’t.”

“Harry has been training her,” Jacob said with a thoughtful look.

“You know Harry?” Sirius asked, suddenly all ears.

“Why, of course. Are you surprised?”

Sirius thought about it. “I suppose I shouldn’t be.”

Xeno smiled. “And there is that thing announced in the back of the Daily Prophet that everyone who pays attention knows about, but most people don’t so they’ll all be very surprised when Alex whips it out.” He caught Sirius’ eye. “But I took that thing into account with my bet.”

Jacob stared at Xeno. “What thing?”

“Hah!” Xeno laughed. “The leader of the Gray, not being in the loop? For shame, Jacob.”

Sirius ignored this and stubbornly folded his arms. “Seven rounds.”

#

Alex’s heart beat like a drum. Her pupils were dilated. Her breathe was short. Her vision narrowed down to the happy Hufflepuff in front of her, bouncing up and down on the tips of her sensible shoes. Alex could feel the gaze of thousands on her.

She held her wand firmly. How should she do this? She couldn’t show off too much. That would spoil the surprise. Last year, Harry had slowly ramped up over the course of the tournament. She’d watched the memory more times than she would ever admit to anyone.

That’s what she needed to do.

She needed to slowly ramp up her powers. She had her animagus form — her secret weapon that would allow her to safely regain her magic and let her outlast even the seventh years. She had her family magic — the Black chains, her favorite, but also several choice hexes that would be more than useful. Spell swatting, a bit of wandless magic, a bit of silent casting, and, of course, magic sensing. She also had a few special tricks which she’d been working on during their time stuck in the animagus ritual.

Marrigold waved at her, and around the arena, the spectators started to quiet.

Alex nodded, put a hand behind her back, angled herself to the side, and thrust out her wand arm with a flourish.

For this duel, she’d just rely on stunners and shields. There shouldn’t be any need for anything more complicated. Even before she came to Hogwarts, she’d been fighting against Ginny and Luna for nearly half a year. Alex smirked.

“Quiet, please!” boomed Bagman.

Alex heard her own breath.

As soon as the bagpipes sounded, she jabbed her wand forward and, at exactly the same time, both her and her opponent shouted, “Stupefy!”

The red spells shot towards each other, collided in the middle, and exploded in a small wave of magic.

Alex already had her shield up, ready for the follow up chain. But the chain never came.

Marigold smiled at her across the arena.

Alex frowned.

“A synced test shot!” shouted Ludo Bagman across the space. “They’re feeling each other out. A powerful exchange for first years. I felt that smack from here! We don’t often see caution like this, but I’m sure the follow up will be quite something.”

Alex controlled her breathing, not taking her gaze off the Hufflepuff Muggleborn for even a moment. Which was just as well, what came next required every once of her concentration. Marigold let loose a torrent of spells at her, most of which she blocked. The last few broke through her shield though, and Alex watched with wide eyes as a bright red spell came at her. Time seemed to slow as she leaned away, and the spell passed only a few inches from were her head had been mere moments ago.

Then the world sped back up again.

Alex gasped.

“I say, that was a close one!” Bagman bellowed.

Marigold smiled and waved at her again.

Alex gripped her wand tight. She felt blood rush to her head. Was her opponent even taking this seriously?! Her occlumency alerted her to the fact that her emotions were starting to get the better of her, but at that moment, she didn’t care. Anger was the correct reaction here. She should just unleash everything she had. If she went full Grim and chains, there would be nothing this witch could— No! Alex mentally shook herself. That wasn’t the correct thing to do. Think of how Lord Slytherin would deal with the situation. He’d be cool. He’d be awesome.

Alex straighted and flicked her black hair over her shoulder. “Impressive,” she called out while raising her wand again. “But can you take as well as you give?”

#

Harry ran down yet another corridor in the Hogwarts Dungeons.

“Tag! You’re it!” Luna cheerfully shouted as he passed her at an intersection

“You do know we’re about to fight an apex killing machine, right?” he called after her.

“That’s why I’m having fun now!” came her fading reply.

#

“Fwoah! This is pretty intense!” Xenophilus had to shout to make himself heard over the exclamations of the crowd. The first Gryffindor/Ravenclaw match had set the expectation bar high, for sure, but while the fight between Virgo Malfoy and her Ravenclaw opponenet had been a one-sided beat down, this was something else.

Sirius watched intensely with eyes locked on the arena. He wasn’t sure at what point Alex and the Hufflepuff muggleborn had really stopped playing around, but it was clear that neither was doing so now.

Their spells were basic and the power in each wasn’t anything to write home about, comparatively speaking, at least. But that wasn’t what had the crowd so worked up. No, that was down to the first years’ sheer speed.

“Great Scott!” Bagman bellowed. “Stunner! Breaker! Tripper! Basher! Disengage! Back to shield! Stunner! Hello! Rail! Into shield! Backroll! Down! Swat! Swat! Swat! Disengage! Another hello!”

The number of spells in the air at the same time was ridiculous. They’d seen something like this last year, when Harry had gone up against Nymphadora, but Nym couldn’t spell swat. Both of these two could.

And when had that happened?! Sirius asked himself as he watched Alex and Marrigold dance around each other like professional duelists twice their age. Just when had one of the most difficult to master feats of magical combat been reduced to a first year’s warm up spectacle?!

Hells, he’d only mastered spell swatting not too long ago.

“Duel disengage! Both combatants take their distance! Looks like they’re letting their magic recharge!”

That look on Alex’s face though. Sirius watched the snarl and practically felt the hackles raise on his neck in response. She did look amazingly like a tiny Bellatrix when she did that. Why wasn’t she going Grim? He knew she could. He knew she knew she was allowed to. Why wasn’t she doing it? Not pride, surely?

#

The crowd roared encouragement.

Alex got her breath back and straightened again. She glared daggers at her opponent. This was supposed to be a simple fight. She swore, Granger was going to get an earful for not mentioning that her student could spell swat! Did she think that wasn’t an important piece of information or something?!

Marigold looked similarly winded to her. She gave Alex a faint smile that said they were ready to go at it again.

Alex shook herself. She raised her wand. “I think we’ve danced long enough!” she declared with a snarl.

“I agree!” Marigold called back.

“Let’s end this!”

“Let’s!”

“They both look ready to go again!” bellowed Bagman.

The crowd roared.

Alex planted both her feet firmly into the dirt, squared her shoulders and yelled, “Come at me, mugglepuff!”

And so it began.

“Stunner!” Bagman shouted. “Breaker! Shield! Swat! Swat! Tripper! Basher! Re-shield! Hello! Closing the distance! Stunner into jinx chain! Tripper—WHAT?!”

It seemed to happen in slow motion. Alex felt the intent to trip form in the muggleborn’s empty hand. She felt the magic concentrate, felt the power raise to the tips of her fingers, felt it destabilize.

She felt the tripping spell detonate right in its caster’s own face.

Alex acted on instinct. She didn’t shield or worry about her own defense. She was in the middle of forming a different spell on her wand, but that didn’t matter. Intent to stun formed on the finger tips of her own free hand. Her spell flew straight and true right at the muggleborn who even now was falling forward.

Marigold landed face-first in the dirt and a split-second later, Alex’s stunner tagged her right between the shoulder blades. The Hufflepuff witch didn’t move.

The arena went silent. This lasted just long enough to become awkward.

“Err, victory to Heiress Black!” Bagman finally announced. “Slytherin 1 — Hufflepuff 0!”

#

“Tag,” Harry declared as he and Luna met at another crossing.

“Oh, poo!”

They both turned and started sprinting up a flight of stairs, out of the dungeons.

“You got all your paintings?”

“Yes, Harry. Also, tag!”

“You can’t tag me on the stairs!”

“Can too!”

They reached the top of the stairs and sprinted past the side door to the Great Hall. “I go left, you go right.”

“Yes, Harry.”

“Also, tag!”

#

Dumbledore watched Sirius’ daughter return to the Slytherin dueling team and start to visibly argue with Miss Granger.

Very impressive skills for one so young. But of the two, he was honestly more shocked at Miss Chesterfield’s performance. He’d never have considered it possible for a muggleborn to display such talent and magical sophistication so early in her magical journey. Even accounting for that misfire right at the end, the mere fact of being able to attempt a wandless spell was rather astounding. Of course, Miss Granger probably could, but that would be explainable. She was being directly trained by Lord Slytherin…

#

"Gryffindor Versus Ravenclaw — year one, Miss Virgo Malfoy vs. year two, Su Li of the Chinese House of Li! Miss Li’s first showing was last year against John Potter, the first time we saw Heir Potter’s—Um…” Bagman hesitated for just a second, and anyone who knew him could hear the internal struggle between the desire to stay on Lord Potter’s good side, and speaking the mostly known, but as yet unspoken inconvientant truth. Eventually, he compromised by putting on his most dramatic voice and bellowing, “the time we saw our first taste of what a dueling powerhouse our most valued national treasure, the boy. Who. Lived, would turn out to be! Let’s see how Miss Li fairs this year against Miss Malfoy!”

Up in the oak bleachers, James Potter scowled.

Beside him, Lord Malfoy chuckled. “Don’t worry, James. I won’t insist on more galleons for Virgo’s contract owing to your son’s embarrassing situation.”

“Good.” James glared at him. “Because I fully intend to sort out the situation with my rightful heir well before it becomes important.”

Malfoy sucked in through his teeth. “Tut-tut. You really shouldn’t say things like that. You never know when that kind of declaration could come back to bite you.”

James blanched. “I don’t mean it like that!”

“I’m sure you did not. Murder in the old families rarely ends well. You would do well to remember that you are an old family, James. The greater the responsibility granted to us by the Albion, the greater the punishment for abuse. That’s not to say that it isn’t done, but I wouldn’t wish my daughter to marry into a family with that kind of modus operandi.”

James spluttered. “You’re lecturing me on the morality of blood warfare?!”

Malfoy gave him a cold look. “And what are you insinuating?”

James bit his tongue. He despised making nice with Lucius, but he had to remind himself why he was doing this.

Malfoy nodded. “That’s what I thought.”

“Quiet please!” bellowed Ludo Bagman.

The crowd silenced

Malfoy turned forward in his chair. “I may not charge you more for your son’s heirship situation, but I certainly will charge you more for this.”

Bagpipes sounded. Within thirty seconds it was over.

The crowd roared.

Su Li lay face down in the dirt. She’d ultimately faired little better than when she’d faced John in the last dueling tournament.

“Gryffindor — 2! Ravenclaw — 0!”

Lord Malfoy clapped with the rest of the crowd, looking very satisfied.

“I thought you hated your daughter,” James grumbled.

“I despise what she is becoming and the company she keeps. That doesn’t mean I am blind to her value. She is a Malfoy. She will serve your son well. You know this to be true. And if not your son, then I know a few older lords who are still shopping around for a younger bride.”

James cursed. “What about your heir?”

“Once Draco is awake, I will direct my efforts to making sure the one who put him in that state pays for it.”

They watched the healer enervate the Ravenclaw and then lead both combatants out of the arena.

“And if you’ll excuse me for just a moment,” Lord Malfoy stood. “I think I just need to use the bathroom for a moment.”

#

“Excellent job, Virgo,” said Samantha North, current dueling team captain, when Virgo arrived back at the Gryffindor dugout.

“Yeah, excellent,” said Cormac Mcluggen. “I hope you’re not going to go all Potter on us, minister? I’d actually like the chance to do something this year.”

“Mcluggen,” Samantha replied in a warning voice.

“Sorry, Captain.”

Virgo ignored him and sat down, but barely any time at all passed before a charmed origami bird flapped into her hands and unfolded itself.

Please meet me at once. I’d like a quick word.

- Your father.

Virgo pocketed the note. A quick look around the arena revealed that, yes, it did look like there would be a few moments before the next match started.

“I will be right back,” she said, standing up.

“Don’t be too long!” Miss North called after her.

Once in the relative darkness of the arena corridors, Virgo took stock. Her father wanted a word. Of course, she’d been expecting it. There was only so much it was wise to speak of in an owl, and unfortunately, Dobby could no longer get into the castle to pass a private message.

She had to get her best dark lady together.

The consequences if Lord Malfoy learned that she was no longer pure Voldemort were still terrible to contemplate. But, again, she was a Dark Lady, so she’d still contemplated them, just like she had with the basilisk.

Still, this meeting would be short. There simply wasn’t much time until her next match.

Virgo walked along the corridor until she felt the tell-tale feeling of crossing an alert ward. Naturally, Lord Malfoy would have completely warded the meeting spot against eavesdroppers and snoopers. She turned the next corner and, as expected, found her sort-of adopted father waiting for her.

He looked taller than she remembered.

“Virgo,” he said.

“Father,” she replied.

“You will understand that I have questions. What exactly is your plan?”

Virgo smirked. “As per my original plan, we are locating and lodging evidence with our agents in the Daily Prophet that will severally undermine Lord Slytherin’s position.”

“The nature of Slytherin’s monster.”

“More than that.”

“More?” Lucious raised an eyebrow. “Then, what, daughter of mine, might be the nature of this evidence? And why deem it necessary to lodge it yourself? I could have effected this far easier than you.”

That was technically true, but would also hand over too much tactical power. Virgo wanted to keep her hands on the levers as much as possible. Plus, there was also a secret trump card to think of, and letting Lord Malfoy in on that would be unthinkable. She tried an all-knowing look mixed with bored disdain. “I discovered another way down into the chamber. One not blocked by Lord Slytherin. I investigated, along with the boy-who-lived and Amelia Bones’ niece. After reconfirming control of the Basilisk, we continued to explore and found evidence that Lord Slytherin had been there, and even Harry Potter. They had clearly been engaged in a high-level ritual when they abandoned the chamber. Massive clay pots. Furniture. A recently-made bed. Even a few papers, though nothing too damning, unfortunately. I am still researching the nature of the ritual, but I have my suspicions.”

Lord Malfoy raised an eyebrow. “You trust Potter and Bones not to expose you?”

“Potter is much less of a goody too shoes then you’d expect. And Bones follows Potter everywhere like a puppy. They will be no problem.”

“Maybe, but I still do not see why I could not have handled this for you.”

“I am planning to deal Slytherin a series of damaging blows, one after the other. Negative press on top of negative press — culminating in one final death blow. One that will destroy the credibility of the Gray as a faction and allow the Dark to hoover up the scattered noble houses. It requires tactical awareness on the ground.”

“You are in school.”

Virgo said nothing.

Lord Malfoy clicked his tongue. “In truth, I am not that perturbed, at least, not with any of that. Any damage you can do the Gray is welcome.” He leaned closer. “Now, perhaps you can explain your other recent actions.”

“Father?”

For the first time that Virgo could remember since Julia had been kidnapped, Lord Malfoy’s tone turned sharp. “Don’t play coy with me, Virgo. You know exactly what I’m talking about. I’m talking about your brother — your brother, who is currently in the Hogwarts Hospital Wing, petrified.”

“He was the logical choice, for multiple reasons.”

Lord Malfoy’s eyes narrowed. “When you became my daughter, you took an oath to protect your brother.”

“And I am. That is one of the multiple reasons.”

“How is petrifying Draco, protecting hi—” He stopped. There was a long moment of silence. Slowly, realization dawned in his eyes. “Oh,” he said.

Virgo smiled. “Yes.”

Lucious gave her a incredibly calculating look. “You used an ancient monster who’s gaze means death, to petrify your brother, in order to protect his mind against the poison of Lord Slytherin, while under his influence.”

Virgo gave him her best superior smirk.

Malfoy just looked annoyed. “That was not necessary. I had plans in progress to mitigate the damage from my son’s foolery.”

“You do not know the full picture. If you did, you would consider my actions prudent.”

“And when will I learn this full picture?”

“Soon.”

At that moment, they both felt the magical ping from the alert ward that indicated someone was approaching.

Virgo quickly retreated, but before she turned the corner, she paused to look over her shoulder. “I have given you a chance, Father. I advise you not to waste it.”

Virgo didn’t look back again. Soon she was out back in the sunny outdoor arena.

“—Black!” Bagman finished bellowing.

The crowd roared.

“And for the Hufflepuffs, the niece of the Department of Magical Law Enforcement! Heiress Susan Bones!”

Virgo sat back down, leaned back, and got chills all down her back. Her robes were soaked with cold sweat.

“The Chief Auror’s daughter vs the Department Head’s niece! This should be a spectacular one!”

#

“Butter beer, dear?”

“Oh, thanks, Lily.” James took a sip then did a double take when Malfoy retook his seat next to him. “What’s up with you?”

“Nothing,” Malfoy replied. “Incidentally, I want another one thousand galleons.”

James spat out his beer.

#

“Come on, Ludo,” Sirius groaned. “Don’t do this to me.”

Down in the arena, an animated alex was making angry swishing motions with her wand. Whatever she and her muggleborn friend, Granger, had discussed, clearly she wasn’t happy with it.

“Cheer up, old chap!” said Xeno, slapping him on the back. “Your girl’s kicking arse. Only six more to go to win your bet.”

“True,” said Jacob. “But that is a Bones down there. It would be wise not to under estimate her.”

#

“Stop playing around, Alex,” Alex muttered, putting on her best impression of Hermione. She swiped with her wand again. “Overwhelming force, Alex. You’re not Harry, Alex. So what if I want to put on a show?!”

“I can hear you, you know,” Susan called out to her.

The two girls locked eyes.

Alex steadied her breath. “Sorry, Susan.”

“Alex, if you don’t fight me seriously, I swear I won’t come to your next birthday party!”

Alex grimaced. Damn it. She glanced back to where Hermione was watching with her arms folded. “Fine!” she eventually called out. “You want to face my full power? Then you shall have it! Just for you, Susan!”

Looks like she was going to play her major cards right here and right now.

Overwhelming force. Alex cast her mind back to her time in the animagus ritual — to swinging around a fourteen tonne killing machine while it did it’s best to bite her in two at the waist — to dodging and swatting spells from up to three combatants at once.

“Quiet, please!” Bagman called.

The crowd went silent.

Seconds passed.

A bagpipe sounded.

Immediately, Susan waved her wand and half a dozen rocks shot up into the air, around her.

Alex thrust out her wand straight in front of her, firing a Black chain right at Susan.

A rock moved to intercept. A second rock shot at her like a canon ball.

With a flick of her wrist, Alex caught the first rock and sent the second careening up into the air with a wandless stunner.

“A draw!” Bagman shouted.

Alex’s lip curled upwards as she let go of the first rock and sent her chains up after the second. A flurry of spells shot towards her.

“Wandless spell swatting!” Bagman shouted. “The question is, can Heiress Bones match her?”

The rock finished it’s climb into the air just as the chain caught it, along with a quick engorgio fired off in between spell swats, massively increasing its mass. Alex snapped her chain back to herself and held on for dear life.

“Merlin!” Bagman bellowed.

Susan’s eyes went wide, but only for a moment, as Alex left the ground and arced through the sky right at her.

The crowd watched in stunned silence, but only for a moment. As one they surged to their feet as the chain rotated around the now massive boulder like a Cathrin wheel and powered the Black Heiress on a high speed collision cause with a very hard ground.

“Pull up!” Bagman shrieked.

The Black Heiress did not pull up. She continued her path right to the earth, traveling at a respectable speed for a top class racing broom.

Susan screamed.

What happened next was not what anyone was expecting. Instead of colliding with the ground and breaking every bone in her body, something shifted just a. split second before she hit the ground.

The crowd went silent as the Black Heiress vanished through the floor.

“I—“ Bagman started. “I—what?”

immediately after he spoke, something phased out of the ground, right behind Susan, like a ghost. It shot up into the air as though fired from a catapult, but not before firing a spell right into Susan’s back at point blank range.

The massive grim in spectral form completed its arc in the air before landing lighting on the ground. It reverted back to its solid form.

Susan fell forward into the dirt.

Somewhere in a nearby a try, an actual fucking cricket chirped.

“S—Slytherin wins!” Bagman bellowed.

Alexandra transformed back into her human form.

And the crowd chose that moment to go nuts.

#

Harry passed one of the second-floor windows at a dead sprint just as a roar of approval sounded out from the direction of the dueling arena.

“Bookworm this is Snake Crown. What’s the racket?”

“ALEX JUST ABSOLUTELY DESTROYED BONES! MERLIN, IT WAS SO GOOD!”

Daphne’s voice cut in. “Quieter! Crying out loud, that almost deafened me!”

#

Hermione winced. “Sorry, Eagle Eyes.”

#

On the other side of the arena, Dumbledore clapped along with everyone else. Very impressive. Although it did leave the question as to how exactly the Heiress Black had managed to change the direction of her swing while in spectral form under ground.

#

“Well hello there, young miss,” said the painting of a regal looking knight. “We don’t get many people down here. What can I do for you?”

Luna waved cheerfully. “So sorry. Can’t talk today.” She put her wand behind her ear. “Stu-pi—” she puffed out her cheeks to comic levels. “—fi!”

#

“Wow,” Jacob said looking down into the arena where Alex was being swarmed by her teammates.

“I was not expecting that,” Xeno concurred.

Sirius felt like he was going to have a heart attack. He was on his feet. And he suddenly realized, that he couldn’t be more proud if he wanted to be.

#

Unaware that her status as ‘most awesome ninja’ was potentially under threat, Ginny Weasley lurked, just outside the entrance to the Hufflepuff Common-room, under the invisibility cloak, like a see-through shadow. Her ear-mirror was turned off. There was simply too much noise coming from the arena to keep it on. Get in, get out, turn the ear-mirror back on.

After a final inspection of the Marauder’s Map, she took out her wand and tapped the needed pattern into the beer barrels that made up the Hufflepuff security system.

The portal to the room behind opened for her.

The Hufflepuff common-room was a lot more homey than the Slytherin one, Ginny noticed. It reminded her rather of the Burrow.

Quietly, she crept forward.

Then, even more quietly, she crept up to the boy’s fifth year dormitories.

She pressed her ear to the closed door.

The sounds of two people happily enjoying each others company came to her, muffled through the wood. Ginny bit her lip. She could only imagine how pissed off she’d be if she was like that, with, say, Harry, and some bitch stunned her out of nowhere and stashed her in a trunk for several hours.

But it was better to be frustrated than to be dead.

She cast a quick silecning charm on the door and then, ever so carefully nudged it open. Once wide enough, she slipped through.

“Hey,” said the boy’s voice in a whisper. He was sitting on the nearest bed with the girl in his lap, and despite what Ginny feared, they were both fully clothed. That made her feel a bit better. “Why’d the door open?”

“The wind?”

Ginny carefully pushed the door closed behind her.

“Maybe…”

It had to be done carefully. Preferably from a direction neither was looking in, with no mirrors or reflections.

The girl giggled. “Ignore it. Kiss me.”

The couple locked lips.

Both their eyes closed.

Ginny smiled. Perfect.

#

“Match Virgo!” Ludo Bagman shouted amid the cheering. “Griffindor 3 — Ravenclaw 0!”

“Mmm,” said Lucious, “Maybe I should add another hundred galleons on for that.”

#

“Match Black!” Ludo shouted as another wave of applause swept the arena. “Slytherin 3 — Hufflepuff 0!”

“And now?” James said back to Lucious. “Seems Virgo’s performance is nothing too special.”

#

“Tag!”

“Tag back!”

“No fair!”

“Hey, no running in the corridors!” yelled the painting guarding the third-floor entrance way.

“Stupify!” “Stupify!”

#

The magically enhanced voice of Ludo Bagman sounded out of the arena, across the grounds, and up to the top of the Hogwarts Towers. “Match Malfoy! Gryffindor 4 — Ravenclaw 0!”

Daphne tilted her head as she watched the grounds… ‘Like a hawk’ would have been literarily appropriate if not literally true.

Of course, the young witch reflected, there was one very clear weakness to using an eagle animagus as a sentinel. Animagus forms allowed for many types of clothing—even magical clothing—to be merged directly into the form on transformation, stored safe from the world and ready to be used on assuming humanity again—but the same could rarely be said for magical artifacts. Wands were one of the few exceptions, and that was theorized to be due to the strong connection between wand and wizard.

The ear mirrors, made from the union of Bell and Harper family magics, combined with the Granger’s micro runes, did not fall into this category.

Even if they did, it would only allow her greater mobility without having to carry the ear piece in her beak, or attached to a bag tied to her talons. Merging with the ear mirrors wouldn’t allow her to use them while transformed.

Her eyes spotted movement.

She transformed back into her human form. She picked up her ear mirror and pressed it to the side of her head. “Snake Crown this is Eagle Eyes. An upper year is making her way back to the castle.”

“Eagles Eyes, this is Snake Crown,” came Harry’s breathy voice. “Understood. Shadow, can you intercept?”

“Sorry,” said Ginny’s voice. “I’m still in the dungeons. I can get her when she comes in. I see her on the map. But will she be able to get in?”

“Against Finch’s muggle locks?” cut in Hermione’s voice. “I bet I could have done that as a firsty by halloween.”

“Understood,” Ginny said “Snake Crown?”

“Do it.”

#

Anne Creswell’s legs were shaking. The fourth year Hufflepuff, who had so brazenly shit talked her current opponent only a few days previously, was now having serious second thoughts.

Alexandra Black was grinning at her. The Black heiress’ third fight had not been like her second. She hadn’t gone all out, but neither had she shied away from fully using her grim animagus form to her advantage. Easily waring down their third-year seed over a few minutes of combat. Her opponent hadn’t stood a chance and Black had barely broken a sweat.

A grim animagus form!

Anne felt a serious sense of dajavu.

How was it even possible for a first year to have an animagus form?!

She was going to get creamed!

And this time it was much worse because of the bet she’d made. Sweat poured down Anne’s face and they hadn’t even started yet.

“Umm… Black,” she started. Her voice trembled. “Is it too late to renegotiate?”

Black just grinned back.

“Quiet please!” bellowed the announcer.

#

Sirius leapt to his feet and cheered louder than anyone around him.

“Slytherin 4 — Hufflepuff 0!” Ludo bellowed.

The Cresswell girl was levitated out of the arena by Madam Pomphrey, leaving Alex standing there alone, basking in the crowd’s adoration. Or was that bloodthirst? Either way, he found he didn’t care.

“She did better than expected for a family of cheese makers,” Lord Greengrass commented. “Did they ever have anyone at Hogwarts before?”

“Not that I know,” Xeno replied.

“So, first-gen Hogwarts student.”

“Seems like it.”

“Bit unfair, asking her to duel yours, Sirius. When did that animagus rule get changed anyway? I’m pretty sure it wasn’t in place when I left Hogwarts.”

“You don’t know?” Xeno said loudly over the crowd. “Sirius here is the reason it was changed. Only, he was a sixth-year at the time, so he never had the chance to flex on the much older students. Isn’t that right, Sirius?”

Sirius grinned. “I flexed hard enough on the seventh years. Were you on the team? I don’t remember.”

#

Behind several feet of solid wood walls, the muffled sound of cheering filtered through to where Susan Bones sat on the floor, in a corner up against the walls, with her arms around her knees.

Susan was not happy with herself.

Obviously, she wasn’t happy with her performance. She’d been training so hard with Virgo. Last year, she’d been training hard with John. Both were monsters. Sure, Alex might have been trained by Lord Slytherin — by Harry Potter, she corrected herself — but so what? Alex wasn’t a time traveller. She didn’t have a whole bunch of teenage Voldemort’s memories. She wasn’t a chosen of Fate and Death. She was just a young witch, like herself. Hells, Alex was a whole year younger than she was!

It was humiliating!

Susan clenched her fists.

But even more than she was unhappy with her performance, Susan was unhappy with what she was doing right now. Straight being enervated, she hadn’t stuck around to get healer treatment. She hadn’t stuck around to accept the condolences of her team mates, or watch Virgo’s next fight against Ravenclaw.

Nope, she’d run away like a Merlin-damned coward.

Why had losing this duel affected her so much more than last year’s?

She wasn’t sure.

Maybe it was because last year’s loss had been so unexpected. That whole tournament had been like something out of a farcical theater production.

This year, she thought she’d ben ready.

Ready to be more than just John and Virgo’s third wheel.

She’d even sworn that if Virgo’s plots got too out of hand, that she’d be the one to clamp down on them.

What chance did she have on that if she couldn’t even beat a student a year younger than her, while Virgo demolished year after year?

“And now for the next match!” came the muffled voice of Mister Bagman. “Malfoy vs. Gomez!”

Susan stirred.

She couldn’t take this.

A bagpipe sounded.

Susan stood up, whipped her wand around herself, and cast a disillusionment charm.

The sound of faint chanting started.

If she was going to be ready to fight Li in the Hufflepuff — Ravenclaw play offs, she needed to clear her head. That meant getting away from here.

#

Ginny dashed up another corridor, noting as she went, that all the portraits had been stunned. A flex of her magical powers later, and she felt her body shift. Her muscles lengthened. Her body grew fur. A tail sprouted. Her hands turned into paws. Her clothes melded into her body.

Her ear mirror and the map dropped to the ground. She picked up both with her cheetah-form’s fanged jaws, and carried on a gentle lope. Not as fast as her human form could sprint, but definitely faster than her jog.

No need for stealth now until she arrived at her next target.

“Virgo’s won another round,” came the echoey voice of Hermione through the mirror in her mouth, amid a background of other raised voices. “Looks like it’s starting to tax her.”

Ginny shifted just before the next corner to check her target’s location on the map, just in time to realize what she was coming from the ear mirror.

Could she really hear the crowd chanting, “Malfoy,”?!

#

“Yes, they are chanting Malfoy,” Daphne spoke into her ear-mirror, now sitting on the tree branch she’d scoped out before when she’d been interrupted by Hagrid. It wasn’t the absolute best position, but it was a lot easier to sit on this branch as a witch than on the sloped roof. It certainly wasn’t dignified for a young lady of her standing, but what was the point of being an eagle animagus if it didn’t give you a bit of license to adventure. “I only hope they start chanting Alex’s name as well,” she muttered.

She kept her eyes trained on the pathway between the dueling arena and the castle.

Dumbledore still hadn’t made a move.

Not that she was expecting it.

Hermione would have alerted her if that one left.

She quickly shifted into her Eagle form for another wide area scan. And not a moment too soon.

She shifted back to witch so fast she almost lost her balance on the tree.

“Shadow, this is Eagle-Eyes. I caught a disillusioned figure unlocking the side door.”

There was silence.

“Shadow, this is Eagle-Eyes,” Daphne repeated. “A disillusioned figure just entered the castle!”

Nothing.

“Give it a moment,” Harry’s breathy voice came. “She might have entered stealth—“

“No! I’m here!” said Ginny’s panting voice. “Sorry, I was in cheetah form. It’s Bones!”

“Can you intercept?” Harry asked.

“I’m almost at my last target,” Ginny replied. “I’ve got her on the map. I’ll finish this up, then grab her.”

#

“Black! Black! Black! Black!”

In the arena, Cedric smiled softly and inclined his head to Alexandra.

Alex inclined her head back.

“—And the next match, Black vs. Diggory!”

“Black! Black! Black! Black!”

“Quiet Please!”

“Black! Black! Black!”

“Quiet! Quiet, I say!” cried an increasingly desperate Bagman. “This isn’t a quidditch match!”

“Black! Black! Black!”

“Duelling is an ancient and honorable tradition!”

“Black! Black! Black!”

“Thousands of years of practice and custom! The brutality of the war mage honed down to the art form of the gentleman wizard. A battle of wits and power! A meeting of wands! A dance! How many great conflicts of the Wizarding World came down to two powerful and mighty foes, facing off in a duel?! Will you make a farce out of such a noble sport?!”

“Black! Black! Black! Black! Black! Black! Black! Black! Black! Black! Black!”

“Oh, whatever.”

“Black! Black! Black!”

“Just hit it, Mister Bagpipes man.”

“Black! Black!”

“And there they go! Opening salvos! Duellers Hello vs. Goodbye. Diggory pushing hard, but Black making excellent use of her swatting to keep up. He’ll need to push harder than that if he wants to—oh! Elemental water! Diggory has advanced quite a bit since we last got a really good look at his abilities two years ago. But will it be enough? Pushing Black back. She’s looking tired. There it is! Black transforms and dives under the ground in her spectral form. She’s regaining her magic, but is there anything Diggory can do? Yes! Oh, my! Screeching charm straight into the ground! That’s gotta hurt. Yes! There’s Black! She’s airborne! Transforms back human! Can Diggory take advantage? No! Black uses her chains to dodge midair! But I don’t think she was able to stay underground as long she wanted! Another trading of spells! Diggory keeping up the pressure. Water’s getting pretty mudding now, but Diggory’s keeping it under control! Black on the defensive. Transforms and dives back underground! But we know that trick is going to cost her now. There’s the screeching charm. But Black had to know that was going to happen! Diggory keeping up the spell. Just how long can Black hang on for? There she is! Oooo! Not looking too good and she’s pissed! And quite understandably! Instantly back on the defensive! Black’s going to have to think of something quick if she wants to stand a chance here—what was that?! Spell backfire! Black hit by one of her own spells, but doesn’t look like it’s stopping her. Diggory advancing strongly now. Black looks like she’s on her last legs — goes Grim! Underground! She’s desperate now. Wait. No screeching charm?! Extraordinary! Diggory chooses to forgo his winning strategy in favour of pulling together a mud golem! Just what is our intrepid Hufflepuff thinking? And with every moment that passes, Black is recharging her magic! And while she’s recharging, Diggory is expending his magic at a prodigious rate. Will he have enough reserves left when our Slytherin Black finally reemerges from the depths below? That is a rather impressive mud golem though… There! Ladies and Gentlemen, Black is back! And immediately on the attack! …Are those her ears bleeding? Wait, that backfire—DID SHE CAST A DEAFENING CURSE ON HERSELF?! Diggory on the defensive! Low magic! But with a golem as backup! Black tries her chains, but they just sink through the mud! She’s stuck! And here comes Diggory! Black drops her chains! Swats the stunners! Diggory closing! Full spell barrage! Black can’t go grim! Diggory shielding! Face-to-face! Mud golem from behind! Black’s hand caught! Drops wand! Wandless spell swat!—!!!!!”

The mad cheering of the crowd became a roar.

“Lords and ladies! YES! WE ALL SAW THAT! Diggory is down! Wizards and witches! Our Hufflepuff went for a physical wrist grab, landed it, and with his size and strength, that should have been it! But Black turned the tables on him and threw him straight into his own mud golem, following that up with an easy wandless stuner! How any girl is that strong, I’ve no idea! Now, just a second! We’re still waiting on the decision from the judges as to whether that self-cast deafening curse was legal… Yes! I’m getting a nod! It’s allowable! Lords and Ladies, what a match! Diggory may have lost, but by Merlin, we saw some impressive dueling today! Not even I spotted that Black had cast a deafening curse on herself, thereby negating the effects of a screeching charm, but this young man did, and instantly adjusted his strategy! And damn near beat her! Wizards and witches, we’ve yet to see someone come up with a rock-solid strategy to counter heiress Black’s magical animagus transformation, but I think we’ve just seen by far the best attempt! My lords and ladies, I give you our victor! First-year Slytherin, Heiress Alexandra Black will be advancing to face the Hufflepuff sixth-year competitor! Slytherin 5 — Hufflepuff 0!”

#

“Bookworm, this is Snake Crown. That sounds like quite a lot of cheering.”

“Alex just took Diggory! Since Tonks left last year, he had to be Hufflepuff’s best duelist!”

Harry smiled. It looked like his necromancer was faring better than expected.

“How about you, Snake Crown?” asked Daphne’s voice.

“On schedule,” Harry replied. “We’ll be starting the final sweep soon.”

#

“And there goes the sixth round! Victory Malfoy!” screamed Ludo’s tinny voice from an ornate wizarding wireless. “Gryffindor 6 - Ravenclaw 0!”

In front of the magical radio, in a massive luxurious chair, a black snake sat coiled up, eyes glowing red.

“Quite an impressive tournament, my lord,” said a young man standing next to a fire place.

“Quite so, Barty” replied the snake, straight into his mind. “And very mysterious, as well. It makes me wonder…”

#

“Victory Black!” screamed Ludo from the radio. Slytherin 6 — Hufflepuff 0! Is there anything that can stop these two monsters?!”

In the kitchen of the Burrow, Mrs Weasley finished charming the lid shut on her latest batch of home-made rumbleberry jam.

“She is doing well, isn’t she, Dorothy?” said Mrs Catamole from over the hill, sitting at the kitchen table.

“I hope she isn’t pushing herself too hard,” replied Mrs Wood, who was visiting her sister from out of town. “But I suppose she is a Black. Right odd family, that one.”

“I just can’t help wonder what’s going to happen against the Malfoy girl.”

“Fancy a flutter?”

“Oh, go on.”

Mrs Weasley levitated the dozen glass jars onto the top shelf of the pantry.

“Should have a better chance this time,” Mrs Catamole said. “I’ve always had a keener ear for dueling than quidditch.”

Mrs Weasley turned to face the two. Her expression was singularly smug. “That’ll teach you to bet against my little girl, then, won’t it?” she said.

“I thought you hated that Ginny was playing quidditch? You said such masculine persuits would ruin her chances to find a good husband when she was older.”

Mrs Weasley had the good grace to at least look embarrassed. Arthur’s talks with Lord Slytherin about Harry Potter, the new heir of the Ancient and Noble House of Potter, were not public knowledge. “I just don’t like that she constantly puts herself in danger,” she said. “Of course I’m increadibly proud of her.”

#

Virgo stood still over her downed opponent while all around her, the arena went wild. She was bleeding from the mouth and nose. Several large bruises were forming on her arms and one nasty one on her chest. Her dragon skin dueling robes had protected her from any slashes across her body, but that didn’t mean that the robes themselves didn’t need repair. She might have a soul age a few years younger than the seventh year now lying in the dirt— more like a fifth year—but in the end, her vast repitour of spells and magics, and her ability to create on the fly, had won the day. She was Virgo! She was neither Tom nor Julia. She was her own witch! She would prove herself greater. No matter what it took.

#

From under the invisibility cloak, Ginny stared in frustration at the locked door to the Room of Lost Things. By the time she’d spotted exactly where Susan Bones was going on the Marauders Map, it had been too late to reach her.

“What do we do?” she whispered into her ear mirror.

“Keep the door staked out,” came Harry’s voice from the other side. “You have everyone else, right?”

“Yeah. But what if she doesn’t come out?”

“We’ll cross that bridge when we come to it. Which may actually be soon.”

The sounds of crowds cheering erupted in Ginny’s ear.

“ALEX WON! —oops, sorry, I mean, Snake Crown, this is Bookworm, Alex won.”

#

Alexandra Black wanted to be cool. She wanted to stare down at her defeated foe and quip out some witty one-liner. She wanted to turn her back with a swirl of robes and walk back to her team as though she hadn’t just joined the pantheon of the mythical first-year-full-seven sweep — current members four — two of whom were time travellers and the other being a seventy-year-old Dark Lord soul fragment.

She didn’t.

Instead, she collapsed to her hands and knees and vomited all over the grass. Then she coughed. Blood spattered everywhere. Warm liquid ran down the sides of her face.

The commentator said something amid the faint buzz of the crowd, but she couldn’t make it out.

She didn’t know it, but the repeated casting of the deafening curse on herself was taking its toll.

Alex scrunched her fist in the grass. The pain didn’t matter to her. She had to be better than the pain. She had to get ready for the next fight. Next would be the Hufflepuffs vs the Ravenclaws. She had that long to recover. Harry had beaten John last year. She would not lose to Virgo. She had too much riding on it. She had to prove herself worthy — worthy to lead her own house — and worthy of the respect of Lord Slytherin. She would not lose.

#

High up in the tree she’d chosen for herself, Daphne stared towards the arena, watching with razor sharp eyes, as Marigold Chesterfield square up against her Ravenclaw opponent.

#

“Where’s Susan?!” shouted the Hufflepuff seventh year captain. “If she doesn’t get back here soon, she’s going to forfeit her matches!”

“I hope she’s alright,” Cedric said. “Missing her duel would be highly out of character for her.”

“Maybe Marrigold can hold on for long enough for her to get back,” said one of the other duelists.

“What? You think Hufflepuff is lucky enough to have a first-year monster on our team, as well? Get real.”

#

“And Miss Chesterfield wins the first round! Hufflepuff 1 — Ravenclaw 0!”

#

Any moment now, Ginny thought to herself, crouched down in the hallway, just to the side of the tapestry of the dancing trolls. Her wand was trained on the locked door of the Room of Lost Things. Any moment now, Bones would emerge, panicked at being late for her match, and she, Ginny, would instantly stun her.

Then she’d sprint outside, and dump her outside the castle along with the others.

If she was quick enough she might even make her match.

Just a little bit more.

Come on.

Just open the door.

She was ready for her.

Ginny bit her lip — shifted her stance — adjusted the invisibility cloak.

Was something wrong?

#

“Why won’t the door open!?” Susan wailed, thumping helplessly on the locked door out of the Room of Requirement. “I need to get back!” she sobbed. “Why won’t you just open?!”

She’d only meant to use the room briefly to calm her nerves, ready for her next match. But the moment she’d tried to leave, she’d found the only exit inexplicably locked to her. That had never happened before.

No unlocking spell worked.

Attacking the door didn’t work.

The windows refused to smash.

Nothing worked.

The room was supposed to give them what they needed.

She needed to leave!

Susan sunk down with her back to the locked door.

She needed to leave, but it was almost as though the room had decided she needed not to leave.

#

As the dueling competition continued, all over the castle, painting after painting was stilling one after the other. Some met their stunning with dignity, others with surprise, and yet others with outrage. The paintings of the common rooms gave the most issues. The Fat Lady in particular, got as far as three paintings away before Harry hit her with a perfectly timed stunner.

Not that it would have mattered. Painting magic was one of the most potent forms of necromancy, but once all the canvases in the castle were stunned, there would simply be no where else for any rogue paintings to go. They’d be trapped.

And yes, not even Harry, with the memories of Voldemort, the gift of the Marauders, and his own explorations, would suggest he knew all the secrets of Hogwarts. But hopefully, their confrontation with the basilisk would stay in the chamber. If it did come to the surface, the chances of the basilisk coming across a hither-to-unknown part of the castle would be astronomically low. It was a known and mitigated risk.

Harry dashed up another corridor and high-fived Luna coming the other way.

“All done?!” Luna cried out as she ran off.

“Just one more!” Harry called back as he began the climb up the North Tower.

He reached the secret trap door that led to the divination class room.

“GO AWAY!” screeched a female voice from above the floor boards — one that sounded like it was a few cards short of a tarot deck.

Harry paused with his wand just about to cast a spell.

“GO AWAY! the voice screamed again. “I’M NOT COMING OUT! I WANT NOTHING TO DO WITH ANY OF IT! YOU CAN’T FORCE ME!”

He probably could, Harry mused. On the other hand, this was something he could deal with later.

“Colloportus!” he shouted, locking the door with more power and force than someone like Professor Trelawney could possibly hope to match.

That done, he turned on his heels and leaped back down the stairs five at time, each time landing as lightly as a feather.

He met Luna at the Gargoyle that guarded the spiral staircase to the headmaster’s office. “How are the House Elves?” he asked.

“Terrified,” Luna replied. “But they’re all present and accounted for. None of them will be leaving the kitchens.”

“Then we just have to make sure the snake never gets that far.” Harry turned to the Gargoyle, flexed his mind over the wards, and watched it jump aside.

They reached the top of the staircase and quickly stunned all the remaining paintings. Hogwarts was now probably emptier than it had been in a thousand years.

“What about the hat?” Luna asked, dropping it on her head.

“Hey!” croaked out the hat. “I don’t appreciate being on your head, Miss Lovegood.”

“Spoil sport.”

“Leave it,” Harry said. “It can’t speak secrets. Occlumency aside, it’s ability as an interrogation device was destroyed after Dimwiddy.”

“Quite right,” said the hat. “Want to know why such a powerful magical artifact looks so burnt and raggedy? It’s not because of old age, I assure you! Good to see you’re not quite so paranoid now, though. Mellowing out a bit, aren’t you.”

Harry ignored it.

“Shadow, this is Snake Crown. Are you ready?”

“She’s still in there!” came the exasperated voice of Ginny through the ear mirror.

“Times run out,” Harry declared. “Withdraw, immediately.”

“Snake Crown,” came Daphne’s voice. “If Bones gets hurt during the basilisk hunt, it could be disastrous for us.”

Harry groaned, but he knew Daphne was right. “Shadow, don’t withdraw. Drop your current passengers out of a window and resume your watch at once.”

There was silence for a moment.

Then…

“Done. The trunk shattered and they’ve all been ejected.”

“Eagle Eyes?”

“They’re all okay, Snake Crown.”

“Excellent. Hold your position, Shadow. Get Bones out of there at the first opportunity. If you see either I or Luna approaching your position, or you hear even a hint of the basilisk, you are to evacuate immediately, understood?”

“Sure.”

“Good.” Harry took a deep breath. “This is final call from Snake Crown. Is everyone ready?”

“Eagle Eyes, ready.”

“Bookworm, ready.”

“Shadow, ready.”

“I’m ready, too, Harry,” Luna said.

“Right.” Harry approached one of the many devices Dumbledore had kept in an alcove behind the headmaster’s chair — the one shaped like a an ornate bell in the shape of a massive wild boar.

He slammed his hand down on it. “Castle lockdown!”

#

All across throughout and within Hogwarts castle, a wave of magic pulsed outwards as the Hogwarts wards went into full lockdown mode — designed to protect the fortress from any magical attack, allowing not one soul in or out. No one with even an ounce of magical talent could have failed to notice it. And they didn’t.

#

Susan watched in dread as the windows of the Room of Requirement shuttered themselves one after another. Seconds later, the mirror in pocket of her robes began to vibrate.

#

“—What was that?!” Bagman voice bellowed across the crowd. “Was that the war wards?!

Err—! Yes, and It seems Miss Marigold was also distracted by that surge of magical power, tripped, and her opponent took advantage of her stumble to tag her with a stunner. Hufflepuff 3 — Ravenclaw — 1, now what the hells is going on?!”

#

The general babble of a confused and worried crowd wafted around the arena to where James and Lucius were sitting towards the top of the bleachers.

The two lords looked at each other.

“—I know nothing about—” “—it wasn’t me, I assure—“.

They stopped. They both looked to where Headmaster Lockhart was looking incredibly flustered further down their row.

“Slytherin?” James asked with a scowl.

“It seems likely,” Lucius drawled.

#

The moment he’d felt the war wards slam into place, Lord Sirus Black was off. He was making a beeline directly for the one person who he knew could provide answers. Gone was the father watching his daughter destroy the dueling arena. Back was the Chief Auror — the man charged with leading some of the world’s most competent fighters into combat against the most dangerous scum of the Wizarding World.

Back where he’d been sitting, two wizards stared after him.

“Our new friend ran off quickly,” said Lord Lovegood. “It’s too bad. If he’d stayed we might have clued him into what was going on.”

“Is Lord Black our new friend?” asked Lord Greengrass. “I know Harry plans to eventually win Alex’s hand, like he did both our daughters. But he still has a ways to go before that’s going to happen. Lord Black is not known to be a compromising individual.”

“Every wizard has their thumbscrew,” Xeno replied. “And Harry is better positioned than anyone else to turn his.”

#

Dumbledore made his way through the confused crowd with great difficulty. Every time he jostled someone, they’d inevitably look, see who it was, and then he’d be caught in the same conversation that, no, he didn’t know what was going on, yes, he was sure it would all be fine, and yes, he was going to get to the bottom of it. He may not be the Headmaster, but he was one of the most powerful wizards in the world, both magically and politically.

And if the wizard he thought was behind this, was behind it, and for the reason he suspected… well, it was an opportunity he couldn’t pass up.

Slytherin first.

He’d confront ‘Virgo’ later.

#

In the Gryffindor dueling team pit, the confusion was no less palpable.

One member though, was not confused.

Virgo, instead, felt anxious and frustrated.

The moment she felt the wards clamp into place, a dozen possible scenarios quickly ran through her brain. Of those, she’d narrowed down the likely candidates to only a few.

Of those few, the most likely was the one she liked the least.

Harry Potter, AKA Lord Slytherin, was making his move. And he’d chosen exactly the time when she, Virgo, would be least able to react. She was sitting here, in full view of several thousand people. And soon, she’d be expected to fight against Alexandra Black — the enigma who’s performance in the arena made her doubt what she knew about everything that was going on.

At this point, she couldn’t count out the possibility that the Black heiress was also a time traveller. She definitely wasn’t a soul fragment.

That would throw so many assumptions out the window.

Virgo stared up across the arena where a large number of adults were converging on a very flustered-looking Lockhart.

At least she wasn’t the only one having a bad time.

#

“What is the meaning of the headmaster?!”

“Headmaster, how have the war wards been activated?”

“Gilderoy Lockhart! What is going on?!”

Lockhart was sweating. “Now listen here, he told the rapidly forming crowd. This is an internal Hogwarts matter and I assure you, there is no need for alarm. THere’s just a small matter that needs to be—”

“Headmaster!” shouted a new voice that everyone recognized.

“Oh, hells,” Lockhart muttered under his breath. He turned and plastered on his best dazzling smile. “Minister Fudge! I do hope you’re enjoying the event.”

“What?” Fudge looked momentarily thrown off balance. “Oh, yes. Yes, I am. But that’s not—“

“Excellent!” Lockhart continued, beaming. “And no doubt you’d like a full update on our little project?”

“What—? Update? What pro—”

“After all, the ministry is a full partner in the affairs of Hogwarts! You must be kept up to date. Can I suggest we go down to my private office here in the arena? It is a little public here, if you know what I mean.” He winked. ”No doubt these people don’t want to hear about the boring affairs of administration.”

The looks of the people around them said that they very much wanted to hear about the boring affairs of administration, but he pointedly ignored them.

“Well, yes, but—“ started Fudge, but once against Lockhart cut him off.

“—And of course, we simply must share a glass from my private collection of Peruvian snake’s bite that I keep here. I know you enjoyed it the last time you tried. Why, I remember at the Malfoy’s Christmas Party—“

“Okay! Okay!” This time it was Fudge who cut him off. “Let’s go.”

Lockhart quickly led the minister to one of the entrances that led into the arena interior, noticing that they were picking up a small entourage as they went. Lockhart carefully locked down his oclumency barriers. He knew he was a fast talker, but this was going to require bullshitting at Nimbus 2001 speed.

On the other hand, he supposed he should have expected something like this.

Dangerous people always kept their cards close to their chests.

But still…

Would it have been too much to ask the Gray Lord to warn him before kicking over the ant hill?

#

“Susan?! Susan, can you hear me?!”

It was her Aunt’s voice coming through the emergency magic mirror Susan always kept on her.

Susan held up the mirror and tapped on the face.

The visage of the Head of the Department of Magical Law Enforcement flashed into being.

“I’m here,” Susan replied, heart beating rapidly.

“Oh, thank, Merlin.” Then, in less than an instant, Amelia Bones went from frazzled to business. “Susan, What’s going on? Hogwarts’ war wards activated, but we can’t get through to the Headmasters office. No one’s answering the floo. Is there any obvious threat?”

“I don’t know,” Susan replied, trying not to sound like she’d been panicking. “I got trapped inside when the wards activated. Everyone else is down in the arena.”

“What about the headmaster?”

“He was in the arena when I left.”

A string of impressive expletives sounded through the mirror.

Susan blushed.

“And I suppose Black is out there as well, yes?”

“I think so.”

“Right. Can you make your way to the Headmaster’s office?”

Susan winced. “I’m trapped in here, too. The room won’t let me out.”

Amelia Bones cursed again. “There goes that plan. Okay. Fine. Just stay put, Susan, okay? I’m sending a team to Hogsmede. The floo there is much closer than the ministry. If anything changes, let me know. I just wish Dumbledore was still there.”

“Dumbledore is here.”

“What?!”

“He was watching my matches in the arena.”

Amelia Bones was silent for a moment before she spoke again, more to herself than to Susan. “Then his phoenix mustn’t be able to get through the war wards. Otherwise, he’d have opened the way for us.”

Amelia looked back up at Susan through the mirror. “Stay safe, Susan, okay? And if anything odd happens, tell me immediately.”

“Okay, Auntie.”

The mirror flicked off.

Susan leaned back against the locked door and slowly slid back down to the floor.

It wasn’t as though she was going to see anything odd happening while in here.

The clearing of a throat from a corner of the room almost made her swallow her own tongue.

“It looks like we’re in a complicated situation, doesn’t it, Susan?”

Susan stared in shock. It was a voice she well recognized. She’d heard it often enough while serving on the student judiciary. It was Violet Chesterfield — twin sister of Marigold, the Muggleborn Hufflepuff duelist one year below her — stepping out of the shadows like a wraith.

How was she here?

#

“Yes, I’m getting the nod from the judge!” bellowed the voice of Ludo Bagman. “We can’t wait any longer! Heiress Susan Bones is disqualified!”

“BOOOOOO!!!”

#

“Dragon Trap on the stairs!”

“Dragon Trap, deployed.”

“Guillotine by the great hall!”

“Guillotine, up.”

“Instant Swamp in this hallway, here!”

“Instant Swamp, down.”

Across the length and breath of Hogwarts castle, Harry and Luna moved with speed and purpose. At every corner another pitfall. At every doorway, another ambush. Any spot where with room for any kind of extra gambit, plot, or ploy, another magical machination was purposefully placed. The sounds of dueling matches outside occasionally filtered through the warded walls, through a window, or over a parapet, but for the most part, the empty castle echoed with each rapid slap of leather shoes on flagstone, and every raised call out.

“Luna, how many devices have we got left?”

Luna shoved her eye right up against the opening of the tiny trunk in her hands. “Two dozen-ish?”

Harry nodded. “Then lets start making our way to the girl’s bathroom on the second floor.”

#

“And Hufflepuff win! Cedric Diggory takes the match against the fourth year Ravenclaw! Ravenclaw 4 — Hufflepuff 4!”

Down in the backrooms of the arena, Lockhart’s beaming smile was being sorely tested. “I assure you, Minister, I’m sure there’s no problem. Lord Slytherin assures me he has informed the ministry.”

“And I’m saying I’ve heard no such thing! Doloras?”

“I recall no parchment work to that effect passing my desk, Minister. What about you, Chief Auror?”

“Nothing,” Lord Black grunted. “Maybe your new friend there can help, James?”

“He is not my friend!”

“Am I not?” drawled Lord Malfoy. “You wound me. And I’ve no idea why you think I’d know what Lord Slytherin was up to.”

“You knew about our sweeps on Knockturn before we launched them. I thought you knew everything that went on in the ministry.”

“All the more reason to believe that Slytherin is lying.”

“Hah!” Sirius pointed. “So you admit it!”

Albus Dumbledore continued to watch the rapidly deteriorating discussion from the side lines, wondering when he should step in.

“Do you want to go at it, Deatheater!?”

Ah, that sounded like just about the right time. “Gentlemen!” he raised his hands in a calming fashion, right as Lord Malfoy’s hand started twitching towards his wand. “Please, let’s not come to blows about this. Might I suggest we review what we know?”

The assembled wizards and witch stared expectantly at him.

“Lord Slytherin said he has business within the chamber. If we take him at his word, he is ‘dealing’ with the monster within.”

“A somewhat unlikely story,” interrupted Lord Malfoy in his drawling voice. “How do we know he isn’t preparing the monster for the next phase of his plan?”

“Yeah,” said Lord Potter. “None of the Gray students have been attacked. That muggleborn vassal of Slytherin’s was found right next to John when he was petrified!”

Dumbledore raised his hands again. “Lord Slytherin assured me last year that he did not know about the monster in the chamber. Or even where the chamber was. He did say he would look into it though…”

“And he still hasn’t dropped the anti-demon wards on the castle!” added Minister Fudge. “What if he’s using the monster to seize control and turn Hogwarts into a fortress!?”

“I do not believe that Lord Slytherin is directly behind the attacks, or that he controls the monster.”

“Then who?” demanded Fudge.

Dumbledore took a second to collect himself. In reality, there were two possible candidates for who could be behind the attacks. The appearance of Virgo Malfoy was far too suspicious to be mere coincidence, and he remembered his old students well enough to pick up the kinds of spells and tactics they might employ.

On the other hand…

“Let’s think about it,” he said. “Who might have a motive for revenge on the castle? Who is it who has been banished from this home of learning, but still haunts its halls like a ghost? Who has been taken under Slytherin’s wing, granted Slytherin’s protection, even taken into Slytherin’s confidence? Enough, perhaps to betray Slytherin’s trust?”

James looked ill.

“Dumbledore,” Sirius said in a warning tone of voice.

Dumbledore put his hands up placatingly. “I’m only putting forward a possible suspect.”

Fudge frowned. “Are you taking about John Potter’s brother?”

#

The arena roared. Hufflepuff had been declared victorious against Ravenclaw, with Cedric Diggory earning MVP for taking on not one, but three of the enemy team, one after another. He fell to the seventh-year Claw, but his two upperclassmen were able to finish the job, firmly putting Hufflepuff into third place in the over-all rankings. Compared to the fourth place they’d experienced for the last three years, this was a serious step up.

In the Gryffindor dug out, Virgo Malfoy clenched her fists together in frustration.

She needed to get this over with as quickly as possible so she could find out what was happening up at the castle. The lockdown had been in place now for quite some time. Who knew what Potter was up to up there.

He’d fideliused most of the chamber entrances, so he clearly knew where they were, but, critically, she could still remember where the entrance was in the Quidditch stadium — the one in the Ravenclaw girl’s changing room.

No doubt warded to Atlantis and back, but she was a lot stronger than she’d been at the start of the year.

With time, she’d be able to break it. But time was something that right now she absolutely did not have.

She felt a hand on her shoulder.

“Ready for this, Miss Minister?” The captain of the Gryffindor team gave her a serious look. “It looks like wether we win or lose could be decided by this match alone. No pressure.”

Virgo brushed his hand away. “This is nothing. I do not lose.”

“Glad to hear it.”

“And now!” bellowed the announcer. “We will begin the first match for Griffindor vs. Slytherin. Lords and ladies, wizards and witches, I give you, Heiress Alexandra Patricia Black of the Ancient and Noble House of Black, vs. Hogwarts’ first student minister, Miss Virgo Druella Malfoy of the Noble House of Malfoy!!!”

The crowd gave quite possibly their loudest roar of approval of the day thus far.

Virgo stood and made her way out into the arena.

On the opposite side, Alexandra Black did the same.

Virgo’s jaw set. She was the greatest witch the world would ever see. Yes, Black had her animagus trick, but she knew she could counter everything the girl threw at her through sheer spell creativity and skill. Black may be good, but she, Virgo, was better.

It was just a shame that using her own animagus form wasn’t a great option. Her lamia form would completely negate her opponent’ magic recharging advantage and make her victory a fait accompli. But it would also expose her as a possible candidate for opening the chamber. Not great. Plus she hadn’t registered. Not an impossible situation to work around, but it would be annoying none the less. No, far better just to grind this girl into the dirt with the purity of magical creativity and purposeful expression.

Like music.

Virgo gripped her wand in white knuckles.

But it also had be done quickly. The more time she wasted here, the more events up at the castle would run out of control. And that was something she absolutely would not tolerate.

#

Harry stared around Moaning Myrtle’s Bathroom, devoid, for once, of Moaning Myrtle.

“Ready?” Harry asked. His voice echoed off the tiles.

“Ready, Harry.” Luna answered.

Harry nodded. His face turned grim. “Remember, Luna, I know you can handle yourself or I wouldn’t have brought you along. But remember that you are not immortal. If the situation becomes too much, retreat. I did not come back in time just to see someone I’ve… grown to respect… be taken from me.”

Luna smiled.

They stared at each other.

Feeling oddly embarrassed, Harry turned to the last sink with the tiny snake carved on the underside.

$Open$

The stone sink fell away to reveal one of the openings to the chamber of secrets.

“Let’s go,” Harry said, crouching down.

Luna nodded and climbed onto Harry’s back.

Harry’s feet raised a few inches off the ground.

And together, the two began the descent down into the depths below Hogwarts castle.

#

Far away in the Burrow, Mrs Weasley gazed at the Wizarding Wireless as though willing it to tell her more.

*Wibble Wobble Wibble Wobble* We’re very sorry for the break in connection from the duelling tournament at Hogwarts Castle. We’re still trying to establish connection and will let you know if we have any updates. Rumors of the castle going into lockdown have yet to be substantiated. In the meantime, please enjoy this repeat of season six finale of the Diagon Woes.* Wibble Wobble Wibble Wobble.*

Mrs Weasley slammed her hand on the Wizarding Wireless, shutting it off before it could fill the kitchen with meaningless theater drama.

Her guests had excused themselves when the trouble started, leaving her alone to fret about what might be happening.

On the wall over the door, the family clock creaked.

Ice ran down Mrs Weasley’s spine as the spoon labeled Ginny Weasley ground around from ‘School’ to ‘Mortal Peril,’ and her voice, when it emerged was a mere whisper.

“Not again.”

#

In the background, the crowd cheered and clapped, but Alexandra Black barely heard it. Her focus was entirely on the witch before her.

Virgo Malfoy.

The Dark Lord’s Soul Anchor.

There were many reasons why she could not lose this match. She had to impress Lord Slytherin. She needed to show her father what she could do — what it really meant to be a Black. But above all else, she had to stall Virgo. Stall, and maybe provoke. Lord Slytherin knew that Virgo would not take the lock down quietly. That she might try to interfere with their plans in Hogwarts Castle. He doubted she could, but Slytherin was not one to take chances. Not when he could put someone he trusted on the case. That was her — Alex — the witch that Lord Slytherin trusted to stall the soul anchor of the Dark Lord Voldemort — Virgo Malfoy.

Alexandra breathed out.

She flashed Virgo her best smirk. “Bet you didn’t think we’d be here when we first met on the Hogwarts Express. Your brother was so cocksure of himself back then. But he eventually saw sense.” She extended a dragon-hide leather shoe from behind her dueling robes.” If I win, will you also kneel down to kiss my boots?”

Virgo snarled. “You… are a spoiled little rich girl. Everything you have, you were given. Magic, titles, money, connections. Spoiled little rich girl.”

Alex smile slipped. “And you aren’t?”

“No. Everything I have, I have taken.”

“Quiet please!” called the announcer.

The crowd slowly quietened, until the only sound that could be heard was gentle whistle of the wind through the arena.

The signal was given.

And the bagpipes sounded.

#

Sirius dashed out of the exit and into the bleachers just as the bag pipe sounded, and just in time to see the Malfoy girl punch her wand to the ground, firing off what looked like an overpowered mining charm, and engulfing herself in a cloud of rocks and dust.

A split second later, several of the larger shards fired out of the cloud and straight at his daughter.

Sirius sucked in his breath as Alex dodged the first be a hair’s width, shielded the second, and only saved herself from the third by flinging herself across the arena with her chains.

Alex fired stunners back into the dust cloud, showing a fierceness of casting that Sirius never knew she possessed, but they all either missed or were intercepted by more rocks.

The space around Virgo was a maelstrom, and it wasn’t about to get any easier. A flame ignited.

The entire crowd gasped.

A ring of fire pulsed out from dust cloud, scorching the ground, and splashing against the wards of the arena walls.

Alex only avoided it by with a perfectly time dive over the ring.

“Firestorm!” Bagman shouted, but Sirius barely heard the ongoing commentary.

The dust-cloud evaporated, leaving Virgo standing, untouched, in the middle of a raging inferno.

Alex seemed to hesitate for only a moment. Then she was moving, sprinting a full speed right at her opponent.

Sirius’s knuckles went white.

Bagman’s voice reached his brain again. “She’s Insane!”

Alex flung her chains at her opponent, along with a barrage of higher-level spells, but the moment the Black family magic reached the flames, molten hands snapped out to grab them.

“Fire elementals!”

The spells passed by the guardians, but barely put a dent in Malfoy’s defenses. Her shields were small, concentrated, skillfully placed, expertly summoned, and chosen to match the exact spell that smashed into them.

Meanwhile, the fire elementals yanked on the chains, pulling Alex into them, forcing her to break her connection, leaving her open, all while having to swat away spells Virgo started firing her way.

A flaming fist swung in a wide arc.

Sirius flinched. His eyes shut.

“She goes Grim! And she’s away!”

His eyes snapped back open. Alex had shifted and dived under the floor. Sirius breathed out.

Virgo immediately shot a sonic spell into the ground, but nothing resulted. Alex did not reemerge. She’d already cast the deafening curse on herself.

Suddenly, the noise of the arena came back to Sirius. The roaring, the cheering, the Ohhhhs, the Ahhhs.

“—And I don’t think we’ve ever seen elemental fire magic quite that advanced before, my lords and ladies! Or that dangerous!” Bagman bellowed. “I mean, technically it’s allowed? Yes, I’m getting the nod from the judge.”

Sirius scowled, but standing where he was, there wasn’t much he could do. Besides, Alex seemed to be handling it well. Insanely well, actually. Unbelievably well. In fact, if she wasn’t his daughter, he’d almost certainly be trying to recruit her.

And that was a sobering thought.

Down on the scorched sands, the seconds dragged on. Eventually, the seconds turned into minutes, far longer than with any other match.

Malfoy started to get visibly impatient.

She stamped her foot on the ground.

“Come out and fight, you coward!”

#

“Come out and fight, you coward!”

Virgo stamped her foot on the ground in frustration. No. She shook her head. She couldn’t allow herself to get worked up, no matter how INFURIATINGLY frustrating it was!

The crowd was beginning to mutter. What before had been the silence of anticipation was becoming the grumbling of impatience.

“Not to worry, everyone,” Bagman’s voice boomed. “I’m sure the Black Heiress will be with us again soon enough!”

Virgo turned to where Bagman was announcing from. “Isn’t there a rule about this?” she called out.

“Can’t say I’ve memorized the rule book back to front” came the amplified reply. “This isn’t quidditch.”

She turned to the judge, standing on the side of the arena. “Isn’t there?”

The judge shrugged. Then nodded.

“There is?” Bagman boomed. “Well what is it? Spit it out, man!”

The judge just shook his head. Then he made a tapping motion to his wrist as though to an imaginary wrist watch. Then he held his hands up with all ten fingers spread.

“Ten minutes?!” Virgo shouted.

Suddenly the ground began to vibrate beneath her.

Virgo’s eyes widened.

Only a few feet away, her opponenet rocketed out from the ground, wand out stretched and snapping towards her the moment their gazes locked.

“Ten seconds, I think!” Bagman bellowed.

FAST! Virgo started shielding all the spells sent her way while weaving an enchantment that would have the best chance of ending this right now. She had to be fast. She had to find a way to lock this bitch down!

Black reached her zennith and sent a chain snapping out to pull her onto her flank.

Virgo finished her series of complex wand movements, thrust her wand forward and shouted, “Papiliosortia!”

What looked like a hundred butterflies materialized from thin air and immediately soared to bare down on Black’s location.

Virgo followed at a sprint.

She’d never sprinted in a duel before, but she was sprinting now.

“Merlin! Those are Australian Razer Wings!” Bagman bellowed. “Black had better watch out.”

Virgo poured all her remaining magic into the best spell chains she knew, not because she expected them to land — only a fool expected someone capable of spell swatting to successfully land regular spells — but simply to keep the pressure on.

At it was working, Black was being pushed back and the moment those insects landed even a single scratch, Black would be out.

Their eyes locked. And Black smiled.

What happened next almost made Vigo swallow her tongue.

One of Black’s chains changed. What before had been the mere magical representation of dark iron links became, in a flash of darkness, a single thin line of black magic — one that looked very familiar — familiar because she, Virgo, had long wanted to learn how to cast a flame whip.

“FUCK!” Bagman exclaimed as the former chain lunged right back at its creator, almost like it was alive, wrapping itself around Black like a spring. In less than a second half of Virgo’s summoned insects had shredded themselves trying to fly through the cage around Black.

In another second, the rest followed suit.

The whip of darkness winked out of existence.

Virgo skidded to a halt and raised her wand to cast a follow up.

Black held up a hand. “Malfoy, wait!”

Virgo stopped, but didn’t lower her wand. “What?!”

Black paused for a second. She looked considering. “That was pretty impressive,” she finally said. “I didn’t think I’d have to use the any other family magic apart from the chains.”

“Yes?” she spat.

“Yeah. And I’ve just got one thing to say to you.”

“Which is?” Virgo ground out.

Black looked to the side where the judge was watching on. Then she looked back. She tapped an imaginary watch on her wrist. “See you in three minutes!”

Then, before Virgo could do anything to stop her, Black shifted, went incorporeal and dived below ground.

Virgo screamed.

#

The underground was quiet and dark. Naturally it would be quiet, Alex couldn’t damn well hear anything. She really wished Hermione had come up with a better counter before the fight with Virgo. Unfortunately, all the massive nerd had to time to do was patch her up a bit and teach her the counter curse to the one she’d hastily fired into her face.

But, even if should could hear, she wouldn’t be able to hear much. Sounds were muffled, like being underwater, mostly the moving about of dozens of feet.

And also like being underwater, Alex floated, ethereal and untouchable.

In her mind, she silently kept count of the time before she had to pop up again. This time, she’d come up a bit earlier than expected — maybe thirty seconds earlier. Never do what you opponent expected you to do.

Maybe if she was lucky, Virgo wouldn’t have started forming elementals to jump her the moment she returned. It’s what she’d have done in Virgo’s position.

There was also other possibilities.

Virgo might turn the entire arena into an ice sheet.

She could bog the sand or conjure a windstorm so strong that she’d have to use her chains just to avoid being blown away.

It never payed to underestimate even a fragment of the Dark Lord’s soul. It was time to unleash a surprise of her own. The Black Whip was good, but what she really needed was something to keep Virgo occupied when she was down here.

Something to force the soul fragment to keep using her powers while she, Alex, regenerated hers.

In the small part of her occulmency kept reserved for the task, a metronome ticked over 140 beats.

Alex shook her ghost-like hair like the grim she was. Time to go!

She let her magic flow through her. She pushed and pushed until the pressure in her etherial paws was like a dam that wanted to break lose. Slowly, an enchantment began to form.

She went deep in the ground. Deeper than before. She’d need maximum velocity for this.

Then, when she was satisfied she was as deep as she could go and keep control, she shifted.

It always felt like somewhat like a combination of apparition and traveling through a portkey. There was the sudden squeezing of the former, but then the whoosh and speed of the later.

Alex rocketed upward, g-forces pushing, sediments squashing.

The moment sunlight hit her retinas, her wand was out. By the time she was level with the crowd, she’d cast the counter curse on herself. As she continued to rise up, the boom of the crowd hit her far harder than the pressure of being underground.

She reached the zenith of her arc, summoned a chain from her wand hand and swatted away the first few expected spells with the other.

Alex’s gaze followed the path the spells had arrived from and grinned.

Virgo looked pissed.

As Alex fell back to the ground, she flung her chain out to break her fall. Then her gaze saw what was barring down on where she’d end up landing, faster than any summoned creature she’d ever seen.

Apparently, virgo’s next play was, ‘summon absolutely massive fire elemental, more like a giant than anything else, and squash her into pulp before the rules said she could withdraw again.’

Fair play.

And absolutely perfect for her.

Alex swung onto the ground, landed like a badass, right in front of the nine feet tall fire elemental, and immediately shielded, just before a fist like a flaming meteor crashed into it.

A dong like a temple bell rung out and Alex momentarily wished she hadn’t cast the counter curse to the deafening curse.

The second fist came down, but this time, Alex let the force of the blow knock her backwards.

She skidded and rolled.

On one side, she spotted Virgo sprinting around the side of the arena, clearly trying to flank her while keeping her occupied with a constant flurry of spells.

Alex gritted her teeth.

The giant fire elemental went for another overhead strike, but this time she didn’t shield. Instead, she jumped forward.

She vaguely heard the gasps of the crowd and the announcer shouting something as she rolled between the fire elemental’s giant legs.

Then she was up again and bringing her wand to bare. The enchantment she’d been working on, ever since just before she surfaced—straining and fighting against the tips of her fingers, finally found their release.

Black light exploded from the tip of her wand. Her chain writhed like a snake, and snapped up like one, then struck.

In an instant, it was coiled around the elemental’s fists, holding them fast. Then its legs. The it’s chest. With each new restriction, the elemental grew more enraged, until finally, the chains stopped constricting, and instead merely sank inside.

The finery red eyes of the elemental darkened.

Alex fell to one knee, panting.

That spell had taken basically everything she had.

If it hadn’t worked, she was now going to be pancake.

But as she knelt there on the ground, no fist smashed her to the side and no heat scorched her skin.

She looked up.

The fire elemental had changed.

The flames licking along its form were now tinged with darkness.

It looked expectedly at her.

Alex looked beyond the new darkened fire elemental, just in time to see an absolutely enraged Virgo baring down on them both.

Witty banter clearly wasn’t going to work to stall this time.

“Go!” she commanded.

And just like that, the tables turned. Again.

Now facing both Alex and her own giant summoned elemental, Virgo was on the defensive for the first time in the fight. The witch was running out of steam.

It might even be a good time to push for ultimate victory, if she wasn’t under orders to draw this out as long as she could. Alex mentally shook her head.

Now that she’d shown her hand with the possessing chains, summoned elementals were another avenue closed off to Virgo.

After this, it would be all about attrition. She wouldn’t even need to go underground any more. She could just go grim when she was low and whittle her down slowly.

Spell swatting gave her the advantage against flung spells.

Ethereal Grim gave her the upper hand against physical attacks.

It was the perfect combination.

Virgo had already lost.

Alex’s internal metronome ticked over the time to when she could retreat again.

She did so — leaving the still standing giant dark elemental and an absolutely apoplectic Virgo.

#

Virgo fell to one knee, snarled at the ground below her feet, and punched it.

This was unacceptable!

She knew what the bitch was up to. Now that she’d demonstrated what those black chains of hers could do, she’d eliminated the possibility of her using large summons. Small summons had already proven countered by that whip made of darkness. Casted spells could be swatted and physical attacks could be be rendered ineffective by the ghost form of her animagus transformation.

That didn’t leave many options that were useable in a duel like this.

And now she knew she couldn’t simply over power her opponent, either.

And every moment she delayed…

Virgo cursed loudly.

She had to win this match. Then, she had to win the tournament. Losing wasn’t an option. She was sure the other Slytherins would be a cake walk compared to — whatever the hells this girl was.

“Ladies and Gentlemen! It looks like Miss Malfoy is in bind! Can she find a way to over come the unstoppable Black?!”

Virgo’s head snapped up.

No!

She pushed herself to her feet.

She could not allow herself to lose. And she certainly couldn’t appear weak! Not to these people. Not to ANYONE!

But what to do?

The only way she was sure she could pull out a win now was to use her own animagus form. With that, she could hold her own against Black on the surface for as long as she needed. Black might have an etherial form, but she could still use her wand in animagus form. That, combined with the much greater magical resistance inherent in her form, would give her all the edge she needed.

But the cost of showing her form…

Virgo shook her head again.

She’d have to pay it.

She had no choice.

She could not lose!

She could not appear weak!

She was Virgo!

She would NOT be beaten by some arrogant slobbering sorry excuse for a demon dog bitch!

She was the greatest witch the world had ever seen!

And she did not LOSE!

Virgo froze.

A wind blew through the arena.

“But we’ve seen a lot of impressive magic so far, my lords and ladies! Maybe our Miss Malfoy will surprise us again!”

Wait…

Fury still coursed through her, but a sudden thought tempered her rage.

Her mind raced. Everything that she knew about magic — about her situation. Pieces were joined — possibilities analyzed.

Maybe there was another way.

#

On the outskirts of Stockholm, snow whirled around a little girl crying in the snow.

“Julia! Julia! Where are you?” Called out an adult voice in Swedish.

Julia blinked out the tears from her eyes. They were already starting to freeze. “Here, dad!”

Mr Olsen stepped out from behind one of the many pine trees to fine his daughter kneeling next to half finished snowman. “Julia, are you okay? Where’s Anna?”

The tears started again in Julia’s eyes. “She ran off! She said I wasn’t helping enough. She said she wasn’t going to do all the work herself, so she left! And I was trying my hardest!”

Mr Olsen sighed, knelt by Julia, and hugged her. After a few minutes, he put his hands on her shoulders and looked into her eyes. “Listen, Julia. What other people think doesn’t matter. What matters is that you know you tried your hardest, understand?”

Julia wiped snot from her nose and nodded.

“Now, what about this snowman here?” Mr Olsen continued. “Seems a waste to leave it like this. Give us a hand here.” He motioned for the fallen shovel on the ground.

Hours passed in what felt like minutes and by time the two stumbled back into the warmth, to warm numb fingers, cheeks, and noses, Julia had a smile so wide it was almost painful.

#

“Tom! Tom! I know you’re somewhere around here!”

Snow fell around Wool’s Orphanage. Out on the concrete courtyard, Mrs Cole had her hands on hips and a scowl on her lips.

Tom Riddle turned one brick corner and walked up to the matron. “Yes, Mrs Cole?”

“Don’t you ‘Yes, Mrs Cole’ me, young man. Robin has lost his mother’s locket, did you know that?”

“I didn’t, Mrs Cole.”

Mrs Cole glared at him. “That locket was very precious to him, Tom. Robin is distraught.”

“That is most unfortunate, Mrs Cole.”

“If I find out some one took it, I will be furious.”

Tom nodded. “Maybe Robin should try looking under the bed. I often find myself losing things under there.”

Mrs Cole’s stare could have frozen hydrogen. “You haven’t had a fight with Robin, have you?”

“No, Mrs Cole?” Tom’s voice sounded genuinely confused this time.

“Mmm… well, if you should just happen to come across it, make sure you hand it right over and I would say no more about it, you hear?”

“Of course, Mrs Cole.”

Mrs Cole turned and marched back into the large brick building, the inside no more warm than the outside.

Once the woman was out of view, Tom reached into the inside pocket of his jacket, pulled out the cheap tin locket, held it up to the cloudy light, and smiled.

#

“Virgo! Can I have a word, in private?”

Virgo put a bookmark in her copy of the standard book of spells, Grade VIII, and looked up as John marched over to her in the common room. She quirked an eyebrow. “Why, John, you know it’s most improper for a well to do wizard to demand such things of a young witch.”

A series of giggles swept the room.

John blushed red. “Look, it’s just quick, okay. It’s about the ‘you-know-what.’”

Virgo mentally rolled her eyes. A few minutes later, they were alone in the boy’s dormitory.

“Look,” John said, sounding worried. “It’s about Susan. You have to promise me that when we go through with the plan to petrify me, that you’re going to watch out for her.”

“Of course I’m going to keep an eye on her. Who do you think I am?”

John visibly sagged with relief. “That’s good. I think this whole thing is a strain on her. You know what her Aunt is like. Well, maybe you don’t. Madam Bones is really strict with the law and the rules and stuff. Even if what we’re doing is needed, Susan is probably tearing herself up about it.” He looked straight into her eyes. “You’ve no idea how comforting it is to have someone who understands to talk with about all this.”

Virgo felt her heart skip a beat.

She licked her lips and put a hand on John’s chest. “John, if I ask you a question, will you answer honestly?”

“Of course.”

“You know someone’s hunting me, right?”

John’s eyes hardened. “Yes.”

“And we think it’s your brother?”

“Yes.”

“If it is him. If he has sent assassins after me...” Virgo leaned in closer and stared deep into John’s eyes. “Will you help me kill him?”

John hesitated. Then his face hardered again. “If Harry really has tried to kill you, and prison isn’t an option, and we think he’ll try again, then yes, I will kill him.”

Not good enough.

Virgo shook her head. “No, John. It can’t be prison. Think about what he has become. He’s too powerful. He’ll just be let out. And even in prison, he’d still be able to strike at me. At us. Susan, too.”

A fierce battle was clearly being waged inside John’s mind. Eventually, he nodded. “If we find that it was him, I will kill him.”

Virgo’s heart soared. “You will hunt down any who try to hurt me?”

“I will.”

“You will crush all our enemies utterly? No matter who they might be?”

“I will.”

Virgo smiled.

#

Back in the arena, Virgo felt the cool air brush across her face. She took a deep breath.

“There we are folks!” Bagman called out, “It looks like our Miss Malfoy has found her center, but what is she going to do now?”

Virgo smirked. Memories from the past melded with ambitions for the future. She’d already defeated Black’s stir up tactics. Who did the girl think she was? She was no mere child to be baited and toyed with. She was the greatest witch who ever lived!

Virgo laughed. She actually laughed.

She was not the poor muggle born Julia Olsen, and nor was she a mere soul fragment of the Dark Lord. They were gone. And in their place, she had risen. This she knew with the certainty that the sun would rise and the moon orbit the Earth. But that didn’t mean that her memories of the past had no meaning.

They had meaning.

They brought her joy.

When needed.

Virgo concentrated hard on the tip of her wand.

She thrust it out in front of her.

She was no one’s a play thing.

She was Virgo Malfoy — reborn! From the ashes!

“EXPECTO PATRONUM!”

#

Silver light enveloped the entire arena, bathing all who saw it in peace and contentment.

As one, the entire crowd let a collective gasp as the silver light resolved itself into the form a majestic song bird, bathed in flames, spreading its wings and soaring up into the sky.

Up in the stands, next to another exit to the rooms below, Albus Dumbledore stared with wide, unbelieving eyes.

#

Below the surface of the arena, Alex floated in the depths of the earth.

She felt the deep rumble that signified something impressive had happened on the surface.

No matter, whatever Virgo had pulled out this time, she would deal with it.

In the back of her mind, her metronome ticked back and forth, tick tock, tick tock.

Soon, she would pop out on the surface again. Maybe this time, she’d exit at an angle rather than straight up.

Best to keep Virgo guessing.

Alex mentally frowned.

Something felt… wrong.

She couldn’t put her finger on it, but something just felt off.

And it was getting closer.

Alex had no time to prepare, no time to figure out what was going on, before her world was full of silver light, pain, and a something slamming into her with the force a mounted broomstick rider.

The strike came literally out of nowhere.

She couldn’t help it. Without meaning to, she shifted.

Several dozen kilos of witch rocketed upwards through the strata of the Hogwarts dueling arena.

Fuck!

Alex broke the surface and was uncerimonaslly flung into the air.

Time seemed to slow.

As Alex continued to ascend, she quickly noticed two things, the first was the whole crowd on their feet, cheering, clapping, screaming.

The second was the two dozen jagged boulders, each the size of a jumbo bludger floating in a sphere around her.

As if waiting for the exact moment she noticed them, the rocks shot towards her like canon balls being fired from a ship.

FUCK!

Alex shifted. Skin became fur. Face became muzzle. Even before the transformation finished, she was already going ethereal.

And not a moment too soon. The first rock arrived just as her paws finished their transformations and shot right through what only a second earlier had been her chest.

Moments later, the space containing Alex was filled with swirling rock, constantly passing through her body again and again.

Alex cursed in her head.

She began to summon her magics, ready to banish the flying rubble away the moment she landed. Then she’d meet Virgo and crush her.

At least, that was the plan.

As she continued to tumble in the air, she chanced to look down.

And a fucking Phoenix made of silver light burst forth from the ground, traveling at ridiculous speed right at her.

Alex barely had time to brace.

The silver Phoenix crashed into her again, sending blinding pain through her body.

She changed.

The magic on her finger tips burst outwards.

The rocks punching towards her were blasted backwards.

Alex began to fall.

The silver Phoenix soared away.

Alex flung out a black chain to brake her fall.

She landed badly, rolling across the arena.

Stunning intent.

Alex flung herself to the side, just as a bright red spell crashed into the dirt where she’d just been.

Then she was up, frantically batting away spell after spell being fired at her from near point blank range.

She’d been delivered almost right to Virgo’s feet.

And Virgo was smiling.

A second later, another dozen rocks leapt up from the ground and rocketed towards Alex.

She banished the first round away, but such large area spells were expensive, so she shifted to avoid the second set.

She got away with that for two more rounds, before the silver Phoenix reached her while in ethereal grim form and bodied her into the ground and up again.

Alex shifted back, batted away a bright blue spell and cursed.

Her magic was running low. Virgo, meanwhile, looked barely fazed.

Time to retreat.

She flung out her wand, wrapped a black chain around a faraway boulder and let herself be yanked away from close combat.

Virgo followed at a sprint, but now that she had distance, Alex could freely transform into her non ethereal grim form and keep distance while she regained her magic.

Above them both, the silver phoenix continued to circle, waiting for her to go ethereal again. Even from here, the wrongness of the bird seared Alex’s soul.

It just felt wrong.

She had to do something about it.

If she could get rid of the Phoenix, she could stall Virgo out indefinitely. It was the only thing stopping her total victory.

The bird began another pass nearby.

Alex saw her chance.

She took it.

At her command, a Black chain transformed in a whip of darkness.

Alex flung out an arm behind her, brought it around with power, and caught the silver bird just as it soared by.

Silver light flared like a mini super nova.

The bird, which up until this point, had been completely silent, let out a screeching cry. The silver light intensified. Then exploded.

Light showered everywhere, like fairy dust.

The silver Phoenix was gone.

Alex smiled. She’d won. There were no more cards to play. Every play had been played. Every counter had been countered. Now she could play the game she needed to.

Virgo came into casting range.

Alex held up her wand. It was time, not to end this, but to drag it out, for a long time longer.

“Wait!” Virgo called out.

Alex hesitated. But, what harm could there be in waiting. That was what she wanted to do anyway, right? Unless this was another trick. Did Virgo have another ace? Another card to play? What more could she have? The Dark lord’s knowledge of magic was vast, and Slytherin had briefed her well on what she was likely to bring to bare. But he hadn’t guessed what could only be a patronus, and he hadn’t discounted the possibility that Virgo may have learned new tricks since regaining a body.

Alex didn’t let down her guard. “What?” she called back.

Virgo straightened. “You have fought well, Black!” Virgo called. “I honestly didn’t think I would have to use everything I did. And you still countered everything I could throw at you.”

“Good?” Alex said.

Virgo smiled, looking far more calm than Alex felt she had any right to be. “Yes,” she said. “And that is why I have no choice, but to do this.”

Alex tensed, ready for anything.

Virgo thrust a hand up in the air.

“I concede!”

#

“VIRGO GAVE UP!”

In front of the door to the Room of Lost Things, Ginny flinched.

Hermione’s voice practically screamed down the ear mirror, while in the background, the crowd expressed its complete disbelief.

Ginny took moved the ear piece slightly away from her ear.

“A little quieter, Bookworm,” Daphne’s tinny voice came from the earpiece.

“Oops, sorry, but seriously, what the hell? Virgo shouldn’t surrender! Snake King said the chances of Virgo surrending were so low not even the dwarfs would find them.”

“Did you hear that, Snake King?” Daphne asked.

Ginny waited for the response.

It didn’t come.

“He must have gone into mirror silence,” she said.

“That, or the chamber blocks mirror magic,” Hermione said.

“That does seem likely given everything we know about it,” Daphne replied. “How is our girl in the arena doing?”

“She’s here with me now,” Hermione said. “They’re giving us a minute to patch her up before the next fight. Do you want to talk to her?”

“No,” Daphne said. “Not now. Just give her my congratulations. She deserves it. I was watching the fight from up here. Very impressive stuff. That was a really good catch with the shadow whip at the end there. Shadow?”

“Here,” Ginny said.

“Keep eyes on Virgo.”

Ginny unfolded the Marauder’s Map. “On it, Eagle Eyes.” The moment Virgo tried something, and Ginny had no doubt the diary would try something, she’d spot it.

#

Up in the top stands, Lord Malfoy clapped politely, while next to him, Lord Potter stared down into the arena with wide eyes.

“Very impressive,” Lucius said.

“Uh huh,” James replied.

“It almost makes me want to keep her.”

James snapped the leader of the Dark a dirty look. “You know full well House Potter is your best option for Virgo.”

 “Do I?”

“Yes,” James said with force. “You do.”

#

It should have been her moment of ultimate triumph. Certainly the endless cheering, slaps on the back, and respectful nods gave the impression of the return of a conquering hero. But being lifted up into the air by a pair of the older Slytherins and doing a minor lap of honor around the first ring of the arena crowd, Alexandra couldn’t help but feel empty.

She had won, but at the same time… she hadn’t.

Virgo had lost, but at the same time, she’d won.

Not that anyone else outside their little group would realize that.

“Yes, yes,” boomed the announcers voice around the arena, “very good, Slytherins. Can you please now escort Heiress Black back to your pit? Thank you.”

And that wasn’t the only thing that felt off.

There was something else, that she couldn’t quite put her finger on.

Then it came to her.

Her eyes frantically scanned the arena.

Virgo was nowhere to be seen.

#

Well, that was quick, Ginny thought.

“Eagle Eyes, this is Shadow,” she whispered into her ear mirror. “I still have Virgo on the map. She’s broken off from the arena and is currently heading towards the Ravenclaw girl’s changing room over at the quidditch stadium. I think she’s going to try and brake into the Chamber of Secrets.”

“Understood,” Daphne’s voice replied. “Bookworm, prepare to back me up. We’re going in.”

“Wait!” Ginny interrupted.

“What?” Daphne asked.

“There’s a problem."

"Yes?"

"She’s not alone.”

#

Thousands of eyes all on him.

The dueling arena was a lot bigger down here than he remembered from practice.

“On the Slytherin side, Heiress Alexandra Patricia Black!”

The crowd cheered wildly.

Sweat ran down his forehead.

He tried to dry his hands on his patchy, battered robes.

And on the Gryffindor side, Ronald Billius Weasley!”

The crowd cheered again, but rather more subdued this time.

Ronald Weasley licked his lips nervously. His eyes darted back and forth before landing back on the first-year witch standing before him, like a pint-sized omen of death. “Err… say, Black,” he said, loud enough to carry the distance between them. “I know we might not have always been the best of friends, and I know we always made you be the evil dark witch whenever we did stuff together, but you enjoyed that, right? You’re, like, way into that stuff. So, there’s no need to go over the top, right? We can have a nice normal duel, right? Right?”

#

Virgo cursed for what felt like the fifth time in as many minutes. Slytherin had certainly done a good job on the warding surrounding all the entrances to the chamber that he hadn’t covered with the fidelus charm.

This one had been woven into the very wards of Hogwarts themselves.

Normally, such a feat would preclude anyone even making a dent in the layers of protection. One may as well try to breach a castle wall with a sword.

But that wasn’t the case now.

With Hogwarts on total lockdown, much of the magic was being used to maintain ancient war wards. Anything not considered critical was being sacrificed.

That meant the protections around this entrance were far weaker than normal.

The problem was that ‘far weaker than normal’ was a relative term.

Her sophistication in dealing with such protections had increased markedly over the last few months. Once she’d learned what Slytherin had done, she had not been idle. The Hogwarts library was vast and since becoming student minister, she’d even wrangled access to the restricted section.

None of that changed the fact that right now, she was exhausted. Even the most sophisticated ward breaching techniques needed some base level of power. To make matters worse, the headache brought on from magic overuse was affecting her ability to weave the delicate enchantments she needed.

What she really needed was a good twenty minutes to let her body clear out some of the toxins.

But that was twenty minutes Virgo didn’t have.

From far away in the dueling arena, the sounds of the crowd gasping at whatever fate was befalling her second-year upperclassman dueling partner wafted, muffled, through the walls of the quidditch stadium.

Virgo vaguely recalled that the boy in question was one of John’s friends.

Not important.

Not right now.

She refocused her attention back on the ward in front of her.

It never occurred to her that she might not be alone.

And why should it have? Virgo knew she was no master of spell swatting, but that didn’t mean she couldn’t sense magic. She could. It was how she’d survived her assassins at the beginning of the year.

So, when a voice that she well recognized, both old and male, coughed from the door behind her, Virgo almost swallowed her tongue.

The next sentence from the voice consisted of only one word and was spoken with the tone of one who can’t quite believe they are speaking it.

“Tom?”

#

“Well, that’s the last of them,” Harry said, weaving the last enchantment on the various traps and devices now strewn around the chamber. “Time to get this show on the road.”

Luna nodded and skipped up the chamber to one of the large pillars near one of the many entrances.

“Blindfolds on,” Harry called out.

“Done!” Luna called back.

Harry nodded and donned his own.

He turned back to the statue of Salazar Slytherin. Since they’d arrived in the chamber, they hadn’t seen hide nor hair of the deadly serpent. The chamber was quiet. Their words echoed. Drips of water fell from the ceiling.

They’d cleared away the bed and desk that he’d kept down here before, storing them away into the small storage room around the back.

All the while, Harry was acutely aware that all that lay between them and the basilisk’s nest was a stone mouth that was no longer locked quite as tight as it might otherwise have been.

He reached out with his magic, feeling for the presence of the giant snake.

It wasn’t particularly difficult.

The Chamber of Secrets was a ritual room, after all — insulated from outside magics, and even blocking many forms of divination.

In such a magical vaccume, he might as well have heat vision, and the basilisk might as well be a small Hogwarts Express in full chuff.

There was no doubt the snake was there, just behind the statue’s head.

This was the first part of their plan.

If they could negotiate with it, then they would.

It was a low probability, but it was worth a shot.

If nothing else, it might let important infomation slip.

Harry flexed his fingers.

He took a deep breath.

§Speak to me, Slytherin—§ he began in a loud voice.

§Speak to me, Slytherin—§ began an immediate echo of his speech from behind the marble statue.

§—Greatest of…§ he continued, his voice getting softer.

§—Greatest of the Hogwarts four,§ the hissing voice finished as he trailed off.

The mouth of the statue started to grind open.

Harry winced.

Nothing like losing the initiative.

#

“Tom?”

Virgo pursed her lips, still facing away from the door. Dumbledore was sharper than she’d given him credit for. What had it been? Her music? Her magic? Banned divination spells? Whatever it was, he sounded uncertain. And when you enemy was uncertain, best to continue to confound their expectations.

She turned. “Not any more, Professor. The soul of Julia Olsen is far stronger and purer than that of Tom Marvolo Riddle.”

Dumbledore stared at the young girl before him. That single statement answered so many of his questions. But yet, he wasn’t about to take a horecrux’s word at face value. If the muggleborn was indeed dominant, than what a fascinating opportunity this could be, but if she wasn’t…

In the folds of his robe, he kept his hand on the elder wand.

“Stronger?” he asked, mildly. “I would have thought that overcoming a soul fragment of the dark lord would be an accomplishment that many trained aurors would fail to manage, even one so mangled and weak.”

Virgo smirked inside. Baiting her, was he? A predictable strategy — and one that might even have worked, if she hadn’t just beaten Black’s same attempts with a patronus.

The Dumbledore she remembered was incredibly arrogant — so sure of himself and that he knew best. This older version seemed similar.

“My friends in Gryffindor helped me,” she said. “And I wouldn’t have made it without their help. The hat put me there, Professor. It said that it should put Tom in Slytherin, but that Julia had the soul true to your old house.”

Dumbledore smiled, a twinkle in his piercing blue eyes. Flattery, eh? he thought. She certainly had Tom’s silver tongue. Voldemort might have become a monster, but he well remembered just how charming he could be in his younger years. He could easily imagine this incarnation worming her way into Gryffindor house, corrupting the younger students, building alliances — a snake in the lion’s den.

He gestured to the wall behind her. “So, it is Lord Slytherin setting the monster loose in Hogwarts? I see you know of this entrance.”

Virgo frowned to herself. Had Dumbledore actually figured out the entrances to the chamber in her absence? Or was he just fishing? She couldn’t take the risk. She nodded, slowly. “I know of many entrances. Slytherin has warded them all. I’ve been trying to break them since I arrived. But alas, I fear the task beyond me. Not even John was up to it.”

Dumbledore smiled. “If the wards were broken, purchance we would find our young hero’s brother beyond. In truth, it is not Lord Slytherin I worry for. More rather, I fear the trust Slytherin may place where it may not be warranted.”

Virgo smiled. “Ever since John was petrified, I don’t particular care who is behind the petrifications, only that they be brought to justice. After all, if the boy-who-lived cannot walk Hogwarts without fear, who can?”

“Quite,” Dumbledore replied.

Another cheer from the dueling arena filtered though the quidditch stadium walls.

‘He doesn’t know Harry is Lord Slytherin,’ Virgo thought.

‘She doesn’t know Harry is the boy-who-lived,’ Dumbledore thought.

They held each other’s gazes.

‘Best keep that tidbit to myself for now,’ thought both of them.

With a flourish, Dumbledore produced his wand and bowed. “Well, then, my girl. Why don’t we go about seeing what we can do about this pesky ward, shall we?”

Virgo stood aside and motioned to the concealed entrance. “Please, Professor. Be my guest.”

#

Harry had his eyes well closed as the gigantic basilisk’s head poked out of the statue. It flicked its tongue, tasting the air.

§So,§ the giant snake said in its understandably hissing voice. §The pretender to the throne finally stands before this one.§

Standing, as he indeed was, below, Harry said nothing. He was waiting to hear where this was going.

§And yet,§ the basilisk continued, §you stand before me, hidden. Why do you not wear your true form, pretender?§

Harry’s mind raced. Presumably, the basilisk was talking about his Chimera animagus form. That the snake spoke of it as his ‘true form’ answered a lot of questions. Like, ‘why did the basilisk leave its nest, only after they had competed the animagus ritual?’. It had sensed the presence of a competitor. Though it didn’t answer the question of how the snake had found a way to the surface when all the exits were supposed to be warded.

He raised his head upwards, while keeping his eyes closed. §Thisss isss my true form, king of snakesss,§ he replied. §I do not seek to take your throne.§

§Liar!§ The great snake screeched. §I smell your power. I feel your authority. You wear crown of serpents. You would command this one if you could. You do not, only because my master still lives. Face me in your true form, pretender! Or I will swallow you now!§

Harry breathed out. No choice then. He shifted. Hands became giant paws. Fingernails became claws. His weight shifted, forcing him onto all fours. Body hair became fur. His face lengthened. Muscles bulged. The hair on his head became the crown of serpents. And Harry’s mind fractured, but he held it fast, like a man holding a dozen dogs on a leesh. If anyone thought controlling someone with the imperious curse was difficult. They should try controlling more than a hundred writhing snakes.

§We ssstand before you,§ spoke a hundred snakes in unison. Harry separated his consciousness from a single one of the serpents and bid it meet the giant snake’s gaze.

When the single snake didn’t die, he opened the rest of his crown’s eyes, but kept his lion eyes firmly closed.

§This one sees,§ the basilisk said.

It was even larger than Harry remembered, if that was possible. And there was something about it that felt different, but he couldn’t put his fingers on it. Maybe the sheen of its scales? The vibrancy of its colors?

§And now that you stand before me, unhidden§ it continued. §Why have you come? You must know that this one will not sleep on your presence in my domain. Only one king!§

§Can we not agree to territorial borders? One ruler to another?§ Harry asked. §The chamber and its ways for you. The castle and its grounds for me?§

§Noooo,§ the basilisk hissed. §The castle while is my territory. Lord Slytherin gave us our domain a countless skins ago.§

§I am Lord Ssslytherin,§ Harry replied in a hundred-strong snakey chorus. §By right of conquest of your master. Not only that, but I hold prisoner a fragment of your master’s sssoul in my head. I ssspeak, not only with the authority of my position, but with the magic of his being.§

The basilisk tilted its head.

But Harry all but already knew what its next words would be.

§That would matter,§ it said. §If my master had not commanded I not take orders from the soul fragments he saught to imprison.§

Well, it was worth a shot.

Lion-Harry snarled, and his voice, when it emerged, boomed. “Let him have it!”

A series of explosive bangs opened up from the far side of the chamber, powerdirising the statue-head and causing the basilisk to rear back and screech. 50-cal machine gun rounds zipped through the air and smacked into the giant snake’s armour. Unfortunatnly, it didn’t seem to be doing anything.

“The eyes!” Harry bellowed, more out of frustration than because he thought it would add any value. Obviously Luna knew she should be aiming for the eyes, but with her own blindfold on, her ability to do so would be seriously limited.

Eventually, the stream of hot led petered off, leaving the extremely narked off killing machine unharmed, save a hundred or so dents in its scales.

“My turn!” Harry roared. He leaped at the basilisk, just as it was dropping down. They met in the middle, still falling, claws scrabbling for purchase, fangs trying to sink into flesh. Harry managed to dig his way up just before they both hit the floor. He jumped onto the head and bit down hard behind the skull. He wished he hadn’t. He felt one of his incisors crunch as they failed to brake through the tough armor.

The basilisk was already starting to swing its head about, hissing in rage. Harry shifted into his human form, pulled out one of the goblin silver daggers laced with blinding solution, and stabbed it downwards.

Clang.

The silver dagger bit into the armor, but did not pierce through.

The snake whipped it’s head back again, this time throwing Harry off. He fell to the ground and shifted back into his chimera form, just as dagger-like teeth the size of a sword sunk into his flesh. Or at least, they would have, if his Chimera fur wasn’t pretty much impervious to all forms of piercing damage. Instead, it felt like someone kicking him extremely hard in the gut.

He roared and scrabbled with his claws at the open flesh of the snake’s mouth.

It screeched in pain and reared back as Harry finally scored first blood.

Harry changed back and rolled backwards, clutching his already bruising stomach.

“Now!”

Something large and pointed wizzed through the air. The goblin-tipped ballista bolt flew straight and true right into the basilisks mouth. It punched right through the roof of its mouth, exited out the back, hit the ceiling beyond, and clattered back down to the chamber floor.

The basilisk swayed.

Then collapsed.

It hit the stone floor with a thud that caused the floor to shake.

Harry looked at the downed snake with a feeling of anticlimax. “Well, that wasn’t nearly as hard as I thought it would be.”

Luna trotted up. “We didn’t even have to use the magic bra.”

#

Dumbledore wiped his brow. No matter what anyone said, even as powerful as he was, breaking into the wards of Hogwarts, even those underpowered as these were, was no easy feat.

“Progress?” ‘Virgo’ Malfoy asked.

“Patience, my girl,” he replied. “These things cannot be rushed.”

“I am well aware,” she replied. “But we must be quick. Every moment we delay is oppotunity wasted.”

Dumbledore ignored her, turned back to the wards, and bent his concentration to them again. He had no doubt he would break them soon. He wasn’t known as one of the most skilled wizards in the world for nothing.

Still, he couldn’t help but think about how much easier this would be if Fawkes was still with him. The wards of Hogwarts did not count anti-phoenix travel among its number. Well, nothing that would stop his entering, anyway. But Fawkes had been AWOL since the last time the monster had been released.

A thought struck him.

“Virgo, my dear, what is the monster in the chamber?”

“Basilisk. And I am not your dear.”

Dumbledore nodded grimly to himself before resuming his work with a new sense of purpose. That new fact raised the chances of one of the more gruesome possibilities for what had happened to his familiar. And if so, then actually killing the monster could be quite a bit challenge.

After all, beings cried not only when they were sad, but also when they were in pain.

#

The stillness of the chamber felt unreal. Harry, now back in human form, gazed at the massive body in front of him, considering their next step. “Looks like Alex may get a chance at raising it after all,” he muttered.

“Hey, Harry! Look! I’m riding it!”

Harry smiled. “Very good, Luna. But we need to get a move on. Can’t have all those traps lying around before we reopen the school.”

“Yes, Harry! Eww! You can still hear it gurgling away in there.” She had her ear pressed to the snake’s body.

Harry ignored her and turned to leave. Impressively, the shear amount of magic radiating from the beast hadn’t decreased even a little bit. He shuddered to think what a confrontation might have looked like if they weren’t so prepared.

He took a step towards the exit. He also needed to get back in contact with the others.

“Harry? Can you hear that?”

Harry stopped, putting his current thoughts on hold. He listened. “What am I listening for?”

“It sounds like bird song.”

“Bird song?” Harry turned back to the basilisk.

Luna still had her ear pressed to the giant snake’s scales.

He frowned. “From inside its stomach? Nothing should be able to survive in there.”

A terrible suspicion swept over him. “Luna,” he said, voice turning firm. “Check the exit wound.”

Luna scrabbled up to the head, while Harry followed.

There was a moment while Luna looked around.

“Well?”

“There’s nothing,” she answered sounding puzzled. But I saw—

“Luna! Get down now!”

A shudder ran all the way down the snake’s body.

The large eye next to Harry snapped open.

And Harry found himself staring unprotected straight into a gaze that could kill. Or at least, it no doubt would have, if the entire pupil wasn’t clouded over and milky.

“It’s not dead!” he shouted.

The head jerked around towards him. It’s jaw opened wide.

And was immediately slammed shut when fourteen tonnes of Tyranasourus Rex stamped it into the floor, hard.

“Hold it there!” he yelled, whipping out his Goblin Silver sword infused with swelling solution. He put all the strength he had into the thrust, stabbing at the only unprotected bit of snake he could see — the eye right in front of him — only to have the sword bounce off an eyelid that snapped shut right at the last moment.

The snake spun, going into a death coil, freeing itself Luna’s pressure.

“Luna!” Harry shouted, fully intending to tell her to retreat. But Luna had shifted back into human form the moment she’d lost her control over the venomous end and was already sprinting away.

He just had time to shout out, “Phoenix inside!” and “It’s blinded!” before the snake turned its attention back to him and lunged, mouth open. Harry swung in pure self defense.

The goblin silver sliced a line clean in its open mouth. The results were out of all proportion to the size of the cut. The swelling solution amplified the wound, gushing dark brown blood everywhere.

The basilisk reared back and screeched, but now that Harry knew what to look for, he could even now see the wound starting to knit itself back together.

He shifted back into his Chimera form and roared.

They’d defeated it once before and they could do so again. And this time, they’d make sure it stayed dead.

The basilisk snapped its maw shut and stared down at him with those white, unseeing, milky eyes.

Harry readied himself for round two.

The blinding solution that had been infused into that ballistica bolt wouldn’t last forever, but it would certainly long enough for what was going to go down right here, right now. It was rare for fights to last longer than a few minutes.

The sound of Luna fighting with something large and metal in one of the trunks wafted between the two monsters.

The basilisk bolted.

Wait, what?

Harry barely had time to regain his wits before he was faced with the back end of a snake slithering at speed towards the back of the chamber.

It was running away?!

In just two strides and one giant leap, Harry landed on to back of its tail.

§OPEN!§ the basilisk screeched.

If Harry had been in his human form, he would have gaped as an exit to the chamber not even he knew about opened, and the snake raced inside.

He had just enough time to register that the opening was narrowing as more of the basilisks’ body left the chamber, but not enough time to declaw himself from the scales and jump off before he slammed headfirst into the stone work.

He fell to the floor with a thud.

§OPEN!§ screeched a hundred smaller snakes in unison. This time, the passageway that formed conformed to his body-shape.

#

“So, then, we are all agreed, my lords?”

The four men in expensive robes nodded.

Cornelius Fudge nervously fiddled with the rim of his bowler hat. “Right, then. Then, it will be up to you, Lord Greengrass. Once the tournament is over, if Lord Slytherin has yet to completely finish his… err… business, up at the castle, then you will be the wizard on the spot, as it were.” Fudge laughed nervously. "There's a lot of wizards out there, and they'll want answers."

“I’m sure it won’t be all that much longer,” Jacob said in a cheerful voice. “Slytherin is nothing if not efficient.”

“Truly,” drawled Lord Malfoy. “And yet, I cannot help but ask myself how necessary this all was. Some of us, after all, have places to be. Being trapped like this, while nostalgic, is nevertheless most undignified.”

“I’m sure your dignity can handle a few minutes of inconvenience,” Lord Potter said in a snarky voice. His tone became more serious. “More importantly, what are we to make of Albus’ assertions? Lord Slytherin may have confided his plans in you, Lord Greengrass, but plans can go awry, and if Harry did decide to act alone…” he broke off, looking angry.

“James, don’t talk rot,” said Lord Black. “If Harry is up at the castle, my only hope he’s being sensible and keeping his head down. The idea that he’s some kind of criminal master mind is outrageous. I’ve no idea what Dumbledore is thinking. Or why he seems to have it out for Harry.”

“There are circumstances you aren’t privy too,” James replied, darkly.

“What circumstances?” Sirius shot back. “If there’s something going on with my godson, then I demand—“ He stopped mid-sentence and glanced at the two other lords and the minister — listening on with interest. He snapped his mouth shut.

Lord Potter glared at him.

“Gentlemen.” Malfoy stepped smoothly into the conversational open space. “I think we can all agree that Dumbledore, while obviously deserving of the utmost respect for his many lifetime achievements, is not infallible.” He inspected his silver snake’s head cane and made to brush an imaginary spec of dust from the top. “I personally do not find it surprising that Slytherin has enlisted your heir’s aid, Potter.

“Son!”

Malfoy smirked.

#

All was quiet in the Room of Requirement. Or the Room of Lost Things. Or the Come and Go Room. Or whatever name one might give it.

Susan sat with her back to the door to the outside world, hands up around her knees.

Violet Chesterfield stood nearby, looking up at the shuttered windows with her hands behind her back.

The conversation had been awkward and confusing. Susan had never quite known what to make of the pair of Hufflepuff muggleborns one year below her. They were clearly twins, but at the same time, their personalities were very different.

Marrigold was bubbly and energetic.

Violet felt more subdued. More serious.

The first thing Susan had asked when Violet had appeared was if she was the reason the door wouldn’t open.

Violet denied it and then went on to explain how the Hogwarts wards worked during a lockdown.

According to the muggleborn, the unique warding required for the Room of Requirement made it enough of an extension of Hogwarts that the war wards counted it as external to the rest of the Castle. “Hence, the lockout,” Violet said. “Though that doesn’t include the siege wards. If we had enough fire power, I’ve no doubt we could blast our way out.”

“What are you even doing here?” Susan asked. “I would have thought you’d want to watch your sister down in the arena.”

Violet gave her a rare smile. “It was my intension to watch over one our interests in the castle. Everyone being down at the arena, and Marrigold being one of the duelists, makes for such a wonderful opportunity to poke around.”

“What interests?”

“I couldn’t possibly say.”

“Is it something to do with the Gray?” Susan folded her arms. “It’s not a secret, you know. Everyone knows Slytherin has been recruiting all the muggleborns.”

Violet laughed.

#

“Luna! With me!” Lion-Harry roared.

Luna was already sprinting across the chamber. She scrambled onto his back and shimmied up to just behind his head, sinking into the mass of snakes.

“Hold on!” Harry shouted.

“Or, you could hold onto me,” Luna replied.

A dozen snakes coiled tightly around Luna’s ankles. Another group weaved themselves into a set of reins.

“Now, hold on!” Harry shouted again.

In one leap, he bounded into the pipe-way the basilisk had retreated through, and together the two began to give chase.

#

“Snake Crown, this is Eagle Eyes, can you hear me?”

Daphne swung her legs back and forth on the tree branch she was sitting on, trying her best not to worry. Still no reply.

Down in the arena, Alex was panting. The fifth-year Gryffindor opposite her wasn’t as good as the fifth-year from Hufflepuff, but he didn’t need to be. Long continual combat with no breaks was starting to take its toll.

In the Hufflepuff dugout, a certain first-year twin grinned at the display. Behind her, Cedric Diggory watched with a keen eye.

High up in the stands, Lord Jacob Greengrass passed by his wife, one row below, to sit back down next to Xenophilius. “No word from Harry?” Xeno whispered. Jacob shook his head.

On the other side of the arena, Lord Malfoy frowned as Alexandra Black succeeded in dispatching her fifth opponent. Narssissa leaned close. “Maybe we could solve Draco’s problem with a contract between her and Alexandra,” she whispered.

In the quidditch stadium, Virgo watched Dumbledore at work with rapt attention. Every wand move, every incantation — she soaked it in like a sponge.

“Snake Crown? Snake crown, this is Eagle Eyes, can you hear me?”

Daphne pursed her lips.

She heard a faint crackle.

“Hi, Eagle Eyes!” came Luna’s cheerful voice through the ear mirror. “We’re chasing the basilisk! It ate Dumbledore’s phoenix and the tears keep it healing!”

“What?!”

“It left the chamber through an exit Harry doesn’t know about.”

Daphne couldn’t keep the alarm out of her voice. “Where are you?!”

“No idea!” Luna chirped back.

“Shadow!” Daphne shouted down the mirror. “Anything on the map?”

“Not yet,” came Ginny’s voice back.

“Keep watching!”

#

In the Room of Requirement, Susan was starting to get annoyed. The reason for this was simple. Violet Chesterfield, twelve-year-old Hufflepuff muggleborn, was monologuing.

“I can’t help feeling the Wizarding World has lost it’s way,” Violet said. “Back in the old days—back before the statue of secrecy—wizards and muggles lived together. They worked together. They played together. Muggles watched quidditch! Everyone knew magic was real. Can you imagine what our world would be like if they still did?”

“No,” Susan replied. And she couldn’t. She’d lived in the hidden world of magic all her life. The idea of Muggles being let in on the secret was utterly unthinkable. “And I’m not interested in debating it,” she added. “Aren’t you even a little bit worried? We’ve been stuck in here for ages now!”

Violet ignored her. “Haven’t you ever wondered why they did it?”

“Did what?”

“The International Statute of Secrecy.”

A vein throbbed in Susan’s forehead. “Everyone who grew up in our world knows why they did it. Muggles discovered calculus. Once they’d mastered that, it was only a matter of time before they created weapons powerful enough to threaten us.”

Violet smiled. “And so, the Wizarding World set out to erase the knowledge of magic’s existence from the mind of every muggle on planet Earth. Hundreds of millions of them.” She tilted her head. “Instead of erasing the knowledge of calculus from the minds of the dozen or so high-level mathematicians who’d mastered it?”

Susan hesitated.

Violet turned away from her, hands behind her back. “Do you hear that?”

“Hear what?”

Violet chuckled. “I think we’re about to have company.”

#

Lion-Harry bounded up the twisting and spiraling tunnel pipe at full speed, Luna holding herself fast in his snake-mane, relaying coms with the outside world through their ear-mirrors.

Harry’s mind was racing. He’d never been up this pipe before. Keeping track of their direction was pretty much a lost cause. He had only his instincts to guide him. Where were they going to come out?

“Virgo and Dumbledore still haven’t broken into the chamber!” Luna shouted behind him.

Harry didn’t have the breath to spare to growl.

“And Susan still hasn’t left the come and go room!”

Harry banked hard right as the pipe took another twisty turn, throwing all four paws against the wall to arrest his momentum.

That would mean that Ginny was still outside the room as well. It would be a good idea to order her to retreat somewhere safer. The problem was, where would be safer? Without knowing where the exit was, the map wouldn’t provide a useful warning.

A shiver went down Harry’s spine, causing all his snakes to momentarily stand on end.

“Whoa!” Luna called out.

Where else on the map wasn’t shown? The Room of Lost Things.

A certain inevitability sank into Harry’s gut. Where had Virgo been holed up in for many weeks on end?

The Room of Lost Things.

“LUNA!” Harry bellowed as the pipe leveled out. “GET GINNY OUT OF THERE, NOW!”

Luna didn’t hesitate.

#

“GINNY, GET OUT OF THERE, NOW!”

Ginny didn’t hesitate.

She ran.

#

A grinding sound echoed throughout the Room of Lost Things.

Susan’s head whipped around.

The portal to the Chamber of Secrets was opening. With no one to speak parseltongue. All by itself.

“What the he—”

That was as far as she got.

Still only half way open, the portal exploded.

In the next few seconds, several things happened in quick succession.

First, the bricks that made up the wall of the room shot out in all directions.

Susan didn’t even have time to flinch.

Second, a brilliant bubble of golden light snapped into place around her. The bricks smashed against the shield. Some disintegrated on impact. Others spun away deeper into the room. A cloud of dust enveloped the shield.

Now, Susan flinched.

Third, the brick dust billowed apart, like a curtain being flung back, as something huge lunged through it.

Now, Susan screamed.

Fourth, the basilisk. The hells-damned basilisk, crashed into the shield of golden light with a sound like a ten tonne hammer hitting the world’s largest bell.

It bounced off the dome and crashed away.

A moment later, there was another deafeningly loud smashing sound as the thousand year old snake ploughed not only through the room’s door, but also through the castle’s protective wards.

Susan registered a wand at her side, pointing into the shield. Violet.

“W-w-w-w—“

Violet grabbed her firmly, waved her wand again, and the two vanished from sight. She found herself yanked to the side.

Fifthly, and most definitely not finally, Luna freak’n Lovegood arrived in the room, riding a Morgana-be-damned Chimera! The beast roared and took off after the snake, it’s own mane of snakes hissing wildly all the way.

A second later, it was all over.

A book shelf John had set up for storing dueling books from the library finished tipping over and smacked into the floor, sending it’s contents spilling out across the flagstones.

The two of them popped back into sight.

“Well, well, well,” Violet said, looking about as impressed as if someone had just scored an interesting shot in quidditch. “That was something.”

Now, Susan began hyperventilating.

A painful smack across the face snapped her out of it.

“None of that,” Violet said. “Don’t you have something to be doing?”

“Doing?!” Susan screeched. She stared at the girl standing before her. “Doing what?! Do you even know what that was?!”

“Of course. And I know about the promise you made Madam Bones.”

“You were listening?!”

“I was. Well?”

Susan’s mind shifted gears. Yes. Violet was right. The door was open now. She needed to get to the Headmaster’s office. She needed to open the way for the aurors. This had all got way out of hand. She said she’d stop it if it did. And clearly, Virgo had lost control. And there was a Chimera now too!!

She nodded her resolve.

Violet bowed before her. “After you then, Miss Bones.”

#

Ginny ran.

She shifted between cheetah and human form at will, sprinting down long corridors on four legs, while taking stairs three at a time on two.

Behind her, the sounds of a seriously pissed off rampaging killing machine got fainter and fainter, but still she ran.

The snake was still traveling in her general direction, and until she heard other wise, she intended to follow Harry’s order, and stay the hell away.

Not that she wouldn’t like a crack at the beast—in fact, she craved it, it made her heart race and her palms tingle just thinking about it—but she was aware she had a job to do, and do it, she would.

Eventually, the crashing sounds started getting more distant, even when she slowed down. Evidently, the snake had veered off in another direction, giving her some breathing room.

Ginny slowed to a trot, then shifted back into a witch, slowly down from a run to a jog, before finally stopping, breathing heavily, and whipping the map from her pocket to inspect.

A quick scan later told her exactly what she needed to know. “Eagle Eyes, the is Shadow,” she said, after fully getting her breath back. “I have Bones on the map.”

“Where is she?” Daphne’s urgent voice came back.

“Heading towards the professor’s apartments.”

“The Headmaster’s Office,” Luna’s voice cut in, raised to overcome a background cacophony. “The emergency floo. Her Aunt.”

“Shadow, Intercept her,” Daphne said in a firm voice.

“On it.” She moved to head off.

“No hurry,” Luna added. “Snake Crown says he has just locked the passageway leading up to it.” There was the sound of a large magical explosion in the background before her voice returned. “But he also says it’s important to get Bones out of the action.”

“Got it.”

#

The crowd in the dueling arena continued to cheer as Alex put paid to her latest opponent.

“Winner, Alexandra Black!” Bagman’s voice rang out. “Slytherin 6 — Gryffindor 0!”

Sirius clapped loudly. “Well done, Alex! Well done!”

“She is doing well, isn’t she?” said Jacob Greengrass on his right, clapping along side the rest of the crowd.

“Indeed,” agreed Xenophilius Lovegood on his left.

The exclamations of a few wizards further down the line prompted Sirius to turn back to Jacob, just as a magnificent Golden Eagle alighted on Lord Greengrass’s outstretched arm.

“Thank you, daughter,” Jacob said, taking a neatly folded up piece of parchment from a proffered talon.

Daphne Greengrass took flight as Lord Greengrass unfolded and subsequently read the parchment. “Ahhh.” He handed it to Sirius. “Looks like duty calls, my friend.”

Sirius took the parchment and read.

Chief Auror, Sirus Black.

It may interest you to know that one Mister Albus Dumbledore is currently attempting to circumvent the war wards of Hogwarts and break his way into the Chamber of Secrets, taking with him, a Hogwarts student of the first year.

Leaving aside the legality of such behavior, given that Dumbledore currently has no direct authority in Hogwarts, it is imperative that the chamber remains closed until the operations to subdue the monster inside the castle are complete. To do otherwise would needlessly expose the outside citizenry to unnecessary risk of instant death — an outcome that my future lord husband has labored tirelessly to ensure doesn’t happen.

They are in the Ravenclaw girl’s bathroom in the Quidditch Stadium.

Yours with the greatest respect,

Miss Daphne Greengrass

Sirius crumpled the parchment up, tossed it over his shoulder, and glared at Lord Greengrass.

“Well?” Jacob asked.

The two lords stared each other down.

In the arena below, Alex walked back onto the grass to more loud cheering.

Sirius broke first. “Okay, okay. I’ll go. But, I swear, if it turns out that Lord Slytherin is up to anything shady in all this, I will find out.”

“Your duty does you credit, Chief Auror,” Jacob said. “Except you left something out in your deceleration.”

“What?”

“We’ll go,” said Xeno behind him. He was reading the crumpled up note.

“What?”

“We’ll go,” Xeno repeated, putting emphasis on the we’ll. “It will be good for you to have two seated members of the Wizangamot witness whatever it is that’s about to go down. And more to the point—“ He gave Sirius a bright smile. “What else are friends for?”

#

Ginny felt her heart beat in her chest. Invisible, silent, not even a scent to mark her location, she lay in wait for her prey behind a stone statue that hid the secret passage way she’d just sprinted down to get here.

Her ear piece was deactivated.

The invisibility cloak hid her, even from the gaze of Death himself.

Far off, on the other side of the castle, a very faint roar indicated that Harry was finally getting stuck into the fight with the Basilisk. Though the fact that it sounded a long way away, didn’t actually mean much in a castle with magic secret passage ways.

Ginny licked her lips.

Her heart hammered.

On the map she held, Susan Bones was drawing ever closer to her location.

She freak’n loved moments like this.

It wasn’t as good as actually fighting the basilisk, but it would do.

The sound of footsteps on flagstones faded into hearing.

Ginny grinned.

It was time.

She felt a draft on her ankles.

She frowned.

She looked down.

Her shoes, socks, and ankles were visible.

The cloak had risen up and was exposing everything from her shins down.

What the—?

There was a flash of red, and Ginny pitched forward, falling into unconsciousness.

#

"Violet?” Susan called out. “Where did you go?”

“I’m here.”

Susan jumped in surprise as the Hufflepuff slid out of the shadows. “What were you doing there?!”

“Nothing important. Come on.”

“But, what were you—“

“Quickly, now! Hup hup hup!”

Another distant roar made Susan reconsider her need to know just what the girl had been up to and follow her back along the corridor towards the professor’s apartments.

As they jogged along, the faint sounds of titanic battle seemed to get closer and more distant, seemingly at random.

At one point, Susan flinched as a door just ahead of them burst apart in a shower of splinters and the snake barreled through and into another door exactly opposite, followed several seconds later by Luna mounted on the Chimera.

Another second and they were both gone again — the sounds of battle once again distant and faint.

Only then did she realize she was, once more, invisible..

“Not much further,” Violet said in a voice far too calm for the situation.

Susan could only nod and follow.

#

Sweat rolled down Professor Dumbledore’s face.

Virgo watched in begrudging admiration. That kind of power was quite something to behold.

Still, if they couldn’t get through the wards, it wouldn’t make any—

There was the a sound rather like breaking glass — a faint tinkle as something delicate cracked and fell to the ground.

The old coot had actually done it.

Dumbledore straightened up. “Ahh, there we go. After you, my dear.”

Virgo took a deep breath. She’d been considering this moment — considering whether revealing her animagus self was worth it. Ultimately, she’d decided it was. She needed to get into the castle, and this was, annoyingly, the only way.

Virgo transformed. Moments later, where once there had been a young witch, there was now a fully grown lamia.

“Remarkable,” Dumbledore said. “Red and gold are very much your colours, my dear.”

Virgo said nothing, but simply turned to face the wall and hissed out, §Open§.

The secret passage way to the chamber of secrets ground itself open.

“Very interesting that your top half is simply a grown up version of your true self.”

“Yes,” said a deep male voice behind both of them, causing Virgo to almost swallow her tongue. “Very interesting, indeed.”

Virgo turned. Three wizards stood in the doorway to the Ravenclaw girl’s changing room. She instantly recognized Lord Greengrass and Lord Lovegood. They were problematic. The one in the middle though, made her grit her teeth in frustration.

“Ahh,” said Dumbledore in that incredibly annoyingly clam way of his. “Sirius. How good of you to join us. And you too, Jacob, Xenophilus. As you can see, we’ve discovered a way to investigate what might be going on up at the castle and make sure nothing illegal is happening. I was planning to send a message, but you seem to already be on the ball, as the muggles would say.”

Virgo mentally rolled her eyes at that. Grade-A bullshit spoken with a tongue so silver she had no idea how the man hadn’t been put in Slytherin.

“Yes…” Sirius said, slowly. “And you, Miss Malfoy? How long have you been an animagus?”

“Three daysss,” Virgo lied. “I didn’t have time to register, which is why I didn’t ussse it in the tournament.” Damn damn! All that patience and caution wasted!

Lord Black grunted. “Well, we’ve got word from Lord Slytherin that no one is to go up to the castle until he’s done.”

“With respect, chief auror,” Dumbledore started. “Just because Slytherin may control the wards, might I remind you that doesn’t mean he has the legal authority to do so. His position right now is an oddity — one brought about by practical necessity owing to the rogue house elf.”

Virgo’s ears pricked at that.

“The Headmaster administers Hogwarts, under the guidance of the board,” Dumbledore continued. “But the board itself is ultimately responsible to the Wizengamot, as are we all. As the Chief Warlock, it is my responsibility to ensure Hogwarts is not being used as one wizard’s private playground.”

“And this has nothing to do with Harry,” Sirius said.

Virgo bit her rather long tongue.

“Of course not,” Dumbledore rejoined. “Though, if we did find that Harry was involved, obviously I’d expect you to do your duty as Chief Auror.”

Sirius visibly ground his teeth.

“Fine. Xeno, Jacob. Wands out and stick by me. Albus, you too. The girl, however, can not come.”

“What?!” Virgo shouted.

“You are a child,” Sirius rounded on her. “You will stay here and close the door after us. The monster must not be allowed out this way.

Virgo opened her mouth to protest before a thought struck her. A devious thought. Hundreds of tunnels and passageways, spanning many dozens of miles, crisscrossed the space around the chamber and through the school like a web. The chance of anyone finding their way through them without parsel-tongue was next to zero.

“Okay,” she said in the meek voice of a little girl, which instantly earned her a suspicious look thrown at her by Dumbledore. She’d probably over played that one a little.

“Good,” said Lord Black. “Come on.”

The lords and Dumbledore trooped into the passageway.

§Close§ Virgo hissed as they walked deeper into blackness.

The passageway ground shut

But not, if she had any say in the matter, for long.

#

The problem, Harry thought, as he continued to sprint down corridor after corridor on all fours with Luna on his back, was that the basilisk just could. Not. Be. Stopped!

Every trap they’d set up. Every contrivance. Every device. They all barely did anything to so much as slow down the gigantic slithering monstrosity.

And nothing that Luna could fire at the thing from his back was working either.

At that rate they were going, it really would succeed in out-lasting the blinding solution and regaining it’s glare of death.

 Maybe they could coral it into a dead end?

“Bulldozer,” Harry called out. “Is Shadow finished with Bones?”

“Shadow isn’t responding!” Luna shouted back, sounding worried.

Drat. Not good.

The basilisk tripped one of the Weasley Twin’s portable swamps, and, being a giant fuck off snake, swum straight through it.

Also not good.

“If we could get in front of it, I could give it another go with the machine gun!” Luna shouted. “We still have lots of rounds left!”

Harry shook his head. “Useless unless we can stop it healing! We need a way to get the Phoenix out of it’s stomach!”

“What about a puking pastie?!” Luna shouted.

“That… might actually work!”

The basalisk crashed through a guillotined doorway, paying no heed as said guillotine simply bounced off the thick scales.

“We need a place to corner it!” Harry bounded over the fallen blade and continued his headlong dash after the snake.

“What about the Great Hall?!”

“Too many exits!”

“The dungeons?”

“Too confining!”

“The Astronomy tower?”

“Too open!”

“Gryffindor or Ravenclaw Tower?”

The basalisk smashed its way through yet another ‘secret’ passageway, the supply of which, was being sorely tested.

“Those are options!” Harry bellowed back. “Now we need a way to control it’s movement!”

“What about Fiendfyre?”

“I can’t cast it while transformed!”

“I could try!”

“Can you control it?!”

“No! But you can!”

The basalisk didn’t even slow down as it skimmed over a sea of caltraps the size of quaffles.

“Okay!” Harry eventually shouted. “We’ll try it!”

“Kay!”

“Do it!”

Behind him, Luna took in a massively huge breath and shouted, “MALUS IGNIS TOTALUS DIABOLUS!!!”

#

“Another dead end!”

“Let’s try back that other way and then take the second left!”

“Bad news. The second left isn’t there any more.”

“What?!”

“It’s a right now.”

“Damn it all! This is pointless!”

Raised voices echoed up and down the Hogwarts Pipe Network, not even remotely close to the Chamber of Secrets.

Sirius Black stormed up to the Chief Warlock of the Wizengamot, who, against all expectations, had the good grace to at least look sheepish.

“Dumbledore, you can gain at least some access to the wards, can’t you? Can’t you guide us?”

In response, Dumbledore fished a bag of sherbet lemons out of a pocket. He sighed. “If I could, I would, Lord Black. It’s not access to the wards that’s the problem. It’s that we don’t have a parsel mouth with us. All the dead ends we’ve come across are clearly meant only for one of Salazars’ line to cross. I fear I had not anticipated just how extensive the Chamber’s passageways were.”

“Then we need to go back and get the Malfoy girl,” said Jacob, arriving behind them.

Dumbledore popped one of the sweets from his bag into mouth and chewed thoughtfully.

“Yes,” he eventually said. “If we can find our way back.”

#

The inside of the headmaster’s office was absolutely still and quiet. Not even the sounds of battle from elsewhere in the castle filtered in, nor the summoning of literal demons into the mortal realm from where best left unsaid.

That is, until the low sound of stone grinding on stone echoed up the passageway.

Then came the sounds of two sets of footsteps and the panting breath of one set of lungs.

Susan burst into the room, put her hands on her knees, and took in deep labored gulps of air. her whole body ached. Her heart hammered. She looked around and noticed that all the paintings—just like everywhere else in the castle—had been stilled. Even the massive poster of Headmaster Lockhart, hung up behind the desk, was frozen in place, looking down at her with what could only be described as a look of good-natured concussion.

She’d never been in the headmaster’s office before.

She’d never needed to be here.

She looked around all the arcane devices that lined the many shelves — around the many dozens of ancient looking tomes — until her eyes landed on the small bag of floo powder sitting by the fire place.

Susan trotted over to it.

With this, she’d be able to open a path for the aurors. She should have told her aunt about everything that was going on ages ago. She’d let herself be carried along by John and Virgo. That wasn’t how the heiress of a noble house was supposed to act — least of all, one of her linage.

She snatched up the bag of powder.

No. Once this was over, she was going to tell her aunt everything. Everything about the basilisk. Everything about Virgo. And everything about Harry Potter — everything about Lord Slytherin.

Yes, she’d get in massive trouble, but it had to be done.

She should never have let things get this far.

She turned to the empty fire place. “Violet, I need a fire.”

Silence.

“Violet?”

Susan started to turn.

As she did, something powerful shot straight at her! She didn’t have time to counter or even shout.

The magic hit her straight in the chest. Her arms and legs snapped to her side. The bag of floo powder fell to the floor. Her body went as rigid as a wooden board.

Susan started to fall. Before she could hit the ground, powerful levitation magic caught her in its firm grip. Lifting her back up, the magic fully turned her around, bringing her face to face with her assailant.

Violet had her wand casually pointed at her, maintaining the floating spell on her now trapped body.

“All in good time, Miss Bones,” Violet said, with a look on her face that Susan had never before seen, and which sent a chill down her spine. “But before you go calling in your regent, you and I need to sort out some small business.”

#

All across Magical Britain, thousands of wizards were glued to their wirelesses, waiting for news of just what was going on up at Hogwarts.

At the Ministry of Magic, Amelia Bones desperately tried to keep things moving in the right direction while hundreds of ministry wizards fretted at not knowing what was happening with both their executive, over a quarter of their legislative body, as well as a not insubstantial chunk of their total citizenry.

In Hogsmeade, a full half of all the Ministry’s active aurors stood ready by the floo at the Three Broomsticks.

Out in the Duelling Arena, the crowd continued to cheer as Alex battled her last opponent.

Deep below ground, the party of investigating wizards, led by Lord Black, was now trying to find its way back to the surface.

Inside the Ravenclaw girl’s changing room in the quidditch stadium, Virgo Malfoy continued to watch the sealed exit to the Chamber, counting down the minutes.

A small cloaked figure left the dueling arena, unseen, and unnoticed.

Birds chirped and the grass rustled.

Outside the castle — outside the arena — everything was still and calm.

Inside the castle, literal hell reigned.

The destruction wrought throughout the halls was monumental.

Several stairways had been utterly smashed.

A few hallways were now completely unusuable.

Many more had their walls, floors, and ceilings fused from grey stone to black glass.

Countless paintings had vanished.

Debris lay everywhere.

Up in the Headmaster’s Office, Susan, still floating completely immobile, stared at Violet in shock.

“There is no need to look at me like that,” Violet said. “This will not take long. I just need to make sure you won’t be telling anyone about my being here. Or any of that other stuff I just pulled off. Deflecting an ancient basilisk’s strike with a mere magic shield? Breaking into the Headmaster’s office when Lord Slytherin just locked it down? I dare say that our astute Mister Potter would definitely take a little too much notice of something as out of place as that. And we can’t have that.”

What?! Susan thought. What was she talking about?!

“You know, your family has always unironically interested me,” Violet continued. “Well, I mean, of course. Any family that specializes in necromantic forms of divination is on my radar. I have a vested interest in Death, shall we say.”

This isn’t Violet. The thought gripped Susan in a moment of dread. Both for what it meant for her position here, and for what it meant for the real one.

“Now, I know what you’re thinking,” the fake Violet in front of her said. She squinted at Susan and sighed. With a flick of her wand, Susan suddenly found her mouth capable of speech again, even if every other part of her body was still locked in place.

“Who are you?!” Susan demanded. “What have you done with Violet?”

The Violet in front of her smiled. “That’s better. And done? Why, nothing. Violet Chesterfield as you know her, does not exist.”

What?! That couldn’t be! John would have noticed! In the last time line—

“The Chesterfield twins currently believe themselves to be the Martinez twins. They are first years at Beauxbatons Academy of Magic. Do not worry your vicious little head, my dear.”

Susan was still very much worried. The wand pointed at her hadn’t budged an inch. And this person had explicitly said that they meant to silence her. She needed to buy time and learn more. “You still haven’t said who you are.”

The Violet, who apparently had been Violet all along, laughed. “True. And I appologygse. I do have a bad habit of monologuing. My wife always says so.”

Susan’s brain screeched to a halt. “Your wife?!”

#

Virgo silently counted down the final minute she’d given herself. Time to enact part two of her plan. The Chief Auror had given her the perfect excuse to rid herself of Dumbledore. Now she could infiltrate the castle alone.

§Open!§

The entrance to the chamber ground aside, again.

She prepared to slither in. Hahaha.

“Hi, there!” said a cheerful voice.

Virgo nearly bit off her own tongue.

She whirled around.

“Oh my god. Your scales are beautiful!”

Marigold Chesterfield.

#

“My wife,” Violet said, looking utterly unperturbed. “She’s had quite the holiday these recent months — swanning around the Hogwarts halls again. I think the high point for her was beating on your little soul fragment during dueling practice.” Violet smirked. “She does like to take pleasure in the little things. Not one to hold a grudge at all.”

Susan’s heart skipped a beat. “You know about—“ She caught herself just in time — just in case Violet was only fishing. Unfortunately, it was not to be.

Violet laughed. “Know about our dear Virgo Malfoy and the darker side of her past?”

The way she said dear put Susan in mind of a scornful teacher on seeing a failing student.

“Of course I know. And the same goes for our illustrious Lord Harry Potter and his additional serpentine surname. Do you honestly think that one such as I wouldn’t be able to know a soul fragment when I encounter one?”

“I still don’t know who you are!”

Susan continued to bob up and down. She’d slowly rotated and was now bobbing up and down, upside-down. It occurred to her that her communications mirror that let her talk instantly with her aunt was still in her pocket — had been in her pocket the whole time — and if she’d just used it when the basilisk first broke into the Room of Requirement, instead of also wanting to open the way for the aurors, she’d not be in this position now.

Violet chuckled. “True enough, my dear. Not that it really matters anyway. I intend to modify your memories once we’re done here so it’s not as though any of this will matter.”

What?! Not possible.

“It’s not something I like to make a habit of. Reliance on such things can make one sloppy. And if there is one thing among many I cannot stand, it is sloppiness. Another reason why my wife and I took every opportunity to have our fun with your John this year. Though that was more my wife’s thing than mine.” Violet gave Susan another smirk. “Stealing my stone is one thing, but failing to steal it, is quite another.”

Susan’s thoughts—which had been racing through all the horrible possibilities for what this unknown wizard might do once he found out he couldn’t memory charm her, because of the noble house ring she wore—screeched to a halt.

“The stone?” Susan whispered. “The stone from last year? The philosophers’ stone? You are Nicholas Flamel?”

Violet’s smirk grew wider.

#

“Why didn’t you tell anyone you could turn into a snake girl?”

“I have my reasons.”

“But this is so amazing!”

“Be silent. This is not a place for idle chatter.”

 “You could give rides to all the other students!”

“I’m not giving rides to anyone!” Virgo snapped.

Marigold pouted. “Are you always this grumpy?”

Virgo practically snarled. “I didn’t ask you to come with me!” The two witches were half way down one of the many tunnels on the way to the chamber. In truth, Virgo had meant to ditch the Hufflepuff muggle born at the first parsel tongue passageway, but the girl had proved remarkably sticky.

Every bone in her body wanted to just stun the annoying chit and have done with it, but that would damage the reputation she was trying to build.

Virgo took a deep breath to calm herself.

At least this one hadn’t yet once uttered the phrase, ‘fuck toy.’

#

Susan shook her head in denial. “You can’t be Nicholas Flamel,” she stated. “You can’t be. Nicholas Flamel is the Immortal Alchemist. The Watchful Eye. He doesn’t interfere with the affairs of mortal wizards.” Susan felt herself getting angry. “He didn’t intefer when Grindelwald was ravaging Europe. He didn’t intefer when You-Know-Who was taking over Magical Britain. Nicholas Flamel is less active than the Merlin-damned Lupins!”

Violet’s eyes now posessised gleam — as though holding back a joke that no one but she would appreciate. “I’m not interfering now,” she—he? said. I’m just doing what I said I would do when Lord Harry Potter Slytherin extracted my stone from the mirror at the end of the last school year. I am watching. I am, after all, as you said, The Watchful Eye. I will only intefer if I believe it to be truly necessary.”

“And this isn’t interfering now?!” Susan demanded.

“What? Helping you get to the Headmaster’s office? You believe that to be unreasonable? If I hadn’t been where I was, you would have most certainly died.”

Susan hesitated. That was true, wasn’t it?

“Anyway.” Violet shrugged. “Enough monologuing. Time for you to forget this meeting and to forget I was ever here.”

Susan felt the anger flow back. “You can’t memory charm me!” she practically shouted. “If you didn’t remember, I’m an heiress! I am noble! I wear a noble house ring! One that can not be removed by anyone, except me, under any circumstances, and only by me when I’m not being forced, and this would certainly count as forced! Even if you cut off all my fingers, it would still be there in magic!”

She tried to wiggle the finger on which her noble house ring sat to give emphasis to her words, but like the rest of her, the petrification spell still held fast, and she still couldn’t so much as flex a toe.

Violet waited in silence for the rant to end. Then, with very little ceremony, she reached out, placed her fingers around said ring, and, with no effort at all, slid it clean off.

Susan went white.

Her brain simply could not comprehend what had just happened. No. Just, no.

Violet shrugged. “Don’t worry yourself, Susan. The mysteries of the Albion are known only to a few.”

Susan had never felt so exposed, so vulnerable, in her entire life. It was as though she’d had all her clothes violently ripped from her body. Except her ring protected her mind. “Please,” she whispered.

Violet placed her wand on Susan’s forehead. “Obliviate.”

#

Virgo hissed at yet another portal heading towards the chamber. Yet again, doors of ancient magic unlocked in a wriggle of metallic snakes to open the passage beyond.

“Come on,” Virgo hissed. She started to slither forward.

After a few seconds, she realized that there was a distinct lack of something.

That inane babbling chatter had ceased.

“Chesterfield?” Virgo said, coiling around to look back the way she’d come.

Her voice echoed.

The pipe-way was empty.

Virgo snorted. Good riddance.

She was about to turn back again, when she realized that Marigold wasn’t the only thing missing.

Her hands felt strangely empty.

She stared at them in shock.

“No.”

Virgo instantly shifted back into her witch form to start frantically patting her robes — as though that would in any way help. It wouldn’t. She knew.

“No! No! No!”

Her wand had also vanished.

“YOU MUDBLOOD WHORE! I’LL KILL YOU!”

#

“Heiress Alexandra Black wins!”

The crowd went nuts.

“Another clean sweep, my lords and ladies, wizards and witches! I don’t know about you all, but I can’t wait for the internationals when these phenoms grow up! Harry and John Potter, Virgo Malfoy, and now Alexandra Black! Watch out, Wizarding World, because Magical Britain is coming!!!”

Next to Bagman, someone leaned in and spoke excitedly while the crowd continued to stamp and cheer.

“Oh of course!” Bagman shouted after that man finished. “Can’t believe I almost forgot! Do we have Miss Weasley here?! Wouldn’t it be amazing to have our future quidditch star present the dueling tournament cup?! Yes, I think it would! Miss Weasley? Are you here? Come on up!”

Up at the castle, in a passageway on the way to the Headmaster’s Office, hidden under the invisibility cloak, Ginny Weasley stirred.

“Ughhhhh,” she muttered.

Her whole mind felt like someone had stuffed it full of cotton wool.

The young witch got one foot under her, tried to stand, and staggered.

The map was on the floor in front of her

She groped for it.

She stared.

Susan was no longer anywhere to be found.

A cold feeling sank into her heart. That didn’t mean she was dead, did it?

And what had even taken her out? She’d been in maximum stealth mode and everything.

Groaning, Ginny fixed her ear mirror to her ear.

“Shadow?! Shadow?!”

It was Hermione’s voice, spoken in a panicked whisper.

“Shadow here,” Ginny muttered.

“They want you in the dueling arena!” Hermione continued. “They want you to present the cup!”

Ginny groaned again. She was Harry’s secret weapon. The one witch in Harry’s inner circle not everyone was supposed to know was as badass as she actually was. Quidditch star was as far as it was supposed to go. Everyone knowing she’d been in the castle while the basilisk thing was going on would be awkward. “Well, I can’t leave the castle,” Ginny replied. “You know that. Just use my polyjuice and get up there.”

“Oh!” Hermione said, sounding surprised, then flustered. “Oh, right. Yes. Yes, I can do that.”

“Shadow!” came Luna’s squeal. “You’re safe!”

“Yeah,” Ginny replied. “Something took me out. No idea what. But I’m fine now. And Susan’s vanished. Is the basilisk down yet?”

#

Dumbledore frowned as they marched straight into yet another dead end.

“Maybe we could try the old ball of string trick,” suggested Lord Greengrass.

Dumbledore sighed. “If this is indeed an intentional final defense against someone without parseltongue finding their way into the pipe network, I fear that Salazzar would have thought of that trick.”

“Pity,” said Xenophilous. “Then we just have to wait for Lord Slytherin to pull us out. That or your Miss Malfoy. Bet you’re feeling a right old ninny now, aren’t you?”

#

Crouched under the invisibility cloak, Ginny listened with rapped attention while Luna reported the situation.

“Fiend fire is working to corral it, but if it gets too close, the basilisk can still kill it with a bite. Though it does seem to cause a lot of pain. I don’t like that, but it will not let us just kill it. Not a single spell we have tried works — it is just too big — not even the imperious curse. The mouth is clearly its weak spot — we killed it the first time with a baliska bolt, but now its refusing to open its mouth for anything except fiend fire and that won’t work because the demons destroy anything that gets close. That and we are out of bolts. Harry’s pretty sword also works, but we need an already open wound and the phoenix keeps healing it. If we could get it to eat a puking pasty, that’s probably our best bet, but nothing we try is working. Not even transfigured bait. It knows its fake.”

Ginny’s eyes narrowed. An idea lodged in her brain. Her heart sped up at the mere thought of it.

“Well, whatever you’re going to do, you need to do it quickly,” Daphne said. “The tournament’s over now and people are going to start getting angsty if they’re trapped too long.”

Ginny came a decision. Adrenaline pumped through her blood. Her fingers tingled. With a sudden jerk she started running. After all, she thought, the only reason Harry forbade her from joining the fight was because she couldn’t fight blindfolded. And from what she understood, that was no longer a problem.

#

Amelia Bone's head reappeared back in the floo after being away for some minutes. “Done. I’ve sent the word to the strike team in Hogsmeade. Hang tight and stay out of their way.”

“Yes, Aunty,” Susan replied.

There was a flash of green fire and the head of the DMLE vanished from view again.

Susan collapsed down to the floor and breathed in deeply.

She’d been memory wiped.

There was a block in her mind. She could feel it if she concentrated her occlumency in just the right way. She had no idea what had happened that would have convinced her to accept an obliviation, but that was also irrelevant. If there was one thing noble children had hammered into them from the first moment they could summon their rings, it was this… if you had a memory block, you did not tamper with it. You had no idea what you’d done before. You might have signed contracts. Those contracts could have penalty clauses for removing the blocks. More than one noble family had been reduced to destitution by such a mistake.

Ultimately, you just had to trust yourself.

Susan watched the floo from which fully armed aurors would soon be pouring.

After all, she thought, being forced, or even coerced, into removing your noble house ring, was, as everyone knew, impossible.

#

Shackle-bolt marched into the main drinking space in The Three Broomsticks, which, for once, was free of both drinks and the usual local clientele. What it was full of instead was sixteen heavily armoured wizards and witches. Massive iron shields lay against table legs. All manner of magical equipment sat around unpacked on tables and on the bar.

“Aurors!” Shackle-bolt barked. “We have positive confirmation that a mature basilisk and a Chimera with serpentine elements have been spotted fighting within the walls of Hogwarts. Our primary objective is to scout, kill, or trap both. If Fate blesses us, they’ll have worn each other out by the time we get there. If none of that is possible, a contingent of one hundred from Control of Magical Creatures is arriving in thirty minutes. Our priority would then be to ensure that neither leaves the walls until a containment ward can be set up. We’re also to look for opportunities to extract a first-year female student that was spotted in the combat zone. Susan’s in there as well, hopefully keeping her head down by the floo. We’re assuming that at least one of the two monsters may be an agent of Lord Slytherin, but take nothing for granted. Standard 5X engagement rules apply.”

A few nodded. Some exchanged glances. None smiled.

“Gear up!”

As one, every auror whipped out and donned a pair of wrap-around sunglasses before fixing goblin-silver spear tips to spear-like broom shafts with fluid, well-practiced motions. With a deep bellow of “UP!”, every broom leaped from its wielder’s hand like it had gone rogue before settling down, hovering vertical a foot from the ground.

“Move out!”

#

“Hiisss!!!!”

“Roooaarrrr!!!”

“ROAAAARRRRRR!!!!”

In Ravenclaw Tower, three monsters faced off. The basilisk lay coiled tightly right in the very corner of the common room, its massive form backed up as far as it could go.

Before it, stood Chimera!Harry and T-Rex!Luna, the former standing tall and ferious, the later… barely standing at all. Ravenclaw tower, even with all the space expansion charms, was not the best place for such a confrontation. But it was the best they’d managed with the hand they’d been dealt

And now they stood, staring each other down. Neither side willing to engage, but also either incapable or unwilling to retreat.

“We must find a way to end this,” growled Harry in English. “Or we could be in trouble.”

#

The aurors came.

They burst from the floo like an unending stream, wizard after wizard, until all had arrived.

“Kingsley!” exclaimed Susan from under the table.

“Susan,” Shackle-bolt acknowledged. “Good job holding the floo. Now go. Your aunt wants you with her.”

Susan nodded.

The aurors swept out of the headmaster’s office and down the spiral staircase.

They fanned out into the corridor, bayonetted broomsticks whirling around their forms, directed by thought and intent, wands covering every corner, iron shields lined up against any threat.

“Anything?” Shacklebolt asked Madeye.

“Nothing,” the old auror replied, eye whirling around inside his skull.

A distant roar shook the castle.

“Ravenclaw Tower,” snapped one of the aurors.

“Go!” Kingsley ordered.

The aruors stormed up the corridor, turned down a secret passageway, winded their way through several more, and reached the intersection between the Great Hall and the Grand Staircase.

“Stop!”

The aurors all skidded to a halt.

“Traps!” Madeye shouted.

“Magical Merlin,” Shacklebolt whispered. The formerly rough stone walls of the castle had been melted into black glass. A trail of utter destruction fanned out down every corridor.

“Looks like Slytherin really made a go of it,” muttered Savage.

“Any left active?” Shacklebolt asked.

“None so far,” said an auror with short white hair.

“Found one!” said another. There was an intake of breath. “Over-powered runic feezing charm on a trigger. Nasty little thing. Anti-snake, maybe?”

Shacklebolt nodded. “Maybe.”

From far above their heads, another wall-shaking roar vibrated through their bones.

 “Alright! We can’t hang around any more,” Shacklebolt declared. “Traps or no traps. Move with caution! Sweep floors, walls, and ceilings. If we find something we can’t pass, we find another route. Go!”

#

Faster, Ginny thought, sprinting through the castle at max speed. Faster! Faster! Faster!

#

“Another dead end!” Jacob called.

Dumbledore chuckled darkly. This had to be the first time that he’d ever found himself wishing for Tom’s actual presence.

#

Virgo slithered out of one of the many entrances to the chamber. Finally, she was inside the castle! Wandless, yes, but still, success! Now all she had to do was find the basilisk and then—

“CONTACT!”

Virgo’s head snapped around.

The sight of a dozen spells heading her way, all of which felt powerful enough to take out a fully grown bicorn, produced an instinctual reaction. For months, she’d been living on a hair’s trigger, fully expecting another assassination attempt. It was for this reason that she’d never taken off the portkey given to her by John Potter all those months ago.

“LIGHTSAFE!”

#

In the Hogwarts infirmary, a row of petrified wizards and witches lay in neatly-made beds, neither asleep, nor awake.

There was the sound like a hole being wrent in the universe and a red and gold lamia fell onto the flagstones with a loud “Oww!”

Seconds later, a young girl with piercing cold eyes, dressed in full dragon hide dueling robes stood up where the lamia had been.

She sweapt to the doors and tried to physically open them, but they didn’t budge. Like the rest of the castle, the infirmary was in complete lock down.

Virgo screamed.

#

The roars ahead grew ever loader the nearer she got. Ginny sprinted up the stairs of Ravenclaw Tower three at a time, knowing that at the end of this climb lay the beast that had been responsible for her own death in the last timeline. But she was not the same scared little witch that John Potter had condemned to possession. Her heart beat wildly. She was a killer. She had been trained to kill.

Ginny bolted past the destroyed portal into the Ravenclaw common room to find three monsters facing each other down.

“Pastie!” Ginny screamed.

“Ginny!” roared Chimera-Harry.

The Tyranasourus Rex changed.

A puking pastie sailed through the space towards her.

Ginny snatched it out of the air and ran forward. She had only one try to get this right, assuming the basilisk would take the bait at all.

The Basilisk loomed. It stared right down at her.

Ginny could count her own heart beats.

One. Ginny dug into her pocket and produced a silver sickle, indistinguishable from any other, save for a slight alteration of the wording on the face.

Two. She crouched down low to avoid a swipe of the tail and flung both the sickle and the pastie high up into the air above the snake’s head.

Three. Ginny fired three spells in quick succession. With her wand, she fired a sticking spell at the pastie. With her free hand, she fired a finite incantatum at the sickle. As the finite was half way to its target, she followed that up with a self-switching spell.

Four. Five. Six. The sticking spell splatted against the pastie, carrying it further and adhering it clean to the ceiling. The sickle changed and a cloud of dandelion seeds exploded out in all directions. The self switching spell connected with one of the floating seeds and Ginny felt the switch begin.

Seven. Ginny appeared in mid air far above the basilisk.

She just had time to look down at the snake’s head before she began to fall and the basilisk began to tilt its head up.

Eight. She watched the basilisk snap it’s mouth open. Rows of pointed fangs, dripped with the most dangerous venom known to wizard-kind. A coiled tongue as long as she stood tall rested in its jaws. A gullet like a pit into hell promised death and digestion if she messed this up. Ginny fired the most physically powerful spell she knew to her side, flipping her over, back to her fate.

Nine. Ginny fired another switching spell. She curled up into a ball and waited, long red hair streaming before her.

Snap!

Darkness.

Ten.

No teeth pierced her skin.

Her hands landed on moist flesh.

No waiting even a moment, powerful muscles dragged her backwards towards the beast’s gullet, and certain death.

For a moment, Ginny panicked.

Then she felt it.

Eleven.

The pull of the switching spell caught her. She accepted it’s power more gratefully then she’d ever accepted a switching spell before.

The world flipped and she was once again in open air.

…open air, but still right above the basilisk.

She started to fall.

Again.

Ginny’s mind raced.

She immediately flung out her arm and cast another switching spell on one of the dandelions that still floating in the cloud of white seeds.

She fell trough the cloud. Puffs of white went everywhere.

The spell caught.

She switched again, higher this time, but still falling.

And faster.

And faster.

The snake below her snapped open its mouth again.

This time, Ginny did panic.

But before the same pattern of falling and switching could begin again, he was there. Just as he always was.

Harry caught her as she fell, softening the impact, and flashing past the snake’s jaws that tried to snap down on them before they were out of strike range.

He carried her like a bride to the edge of the common room and landed gently back on floor.

Ginny didn’t want to move from where she was now pressed up against his chest, but knew she had to.

“Good work,” Harry said, planting her back on the floor. He tilted her chin up to look at him. “But don’t ever try that again, okay?”

Ginny felt a heat on her cheeks that had nothing to do with physical exertion. She nodded.

Then, from behind her, came a noise like a potions factory going critical through the digestive system of a bicorn.

The basilisk, which hadn’t moved since snapping at her and Harry, was slowly turning a paler shade of sickly green.

#

Harry carefully watched the basilisk go through a series of facial expressions that had no place existing on any snake, let alone one so large and deadly.

They were almost comical.

He stepped around Ginny with purposeful steps, positioning her behind him, and drew his goblin silver sword.

The edge of his mouth curled upwards as a particularly loud gurgle sounded from the belly of the beast.

“That’s right,” he half-whispered. “Give us the Phoenix. Out with it. Like a good little snake.”

“Is basilisk vomit as dangerous as basilisk venom?” Ginny asked from behind him.

Luna answered the question. “Basilisk stomach acid is powerful, but not outrageously so. It can not digest bone, for example. But I do not think wizards have ever tested the acid from a basilisk as old as this.”

The stomach noises slowly started to get louder.

Harry readied himself. “Either way, I think we’re about to find out.” He let his wand slide into his free hand.

The snake bent its neck sharply up and down, as though it’s body was one large cramp.

Then, it made an ear-splitting keening noise, opened its mouth, and something exploded out from it.

But it was not liquid. Not liquid, per say.

It looked like damp blank sand.

Harry frowned.

Another cramp, another ear-splitting keening, and another deposit of the wet blank sand smacked down in front of the beast on top of the first load. Together, the two started to form a pile.

“What is that?” Ginny asked.

“It’s odd,” Luna said.

Harry leaned closer. It was almost like…

His eyes widened.

A frantic look to the side showed that Luna had reached exactly the same conclusion that he had at exactly the same time.

“GET BACK!” Harry shouted.

Not waiting for a reply, he leaped backwards, catching Ginny as he went and pulling her the several meters to the common room door with him.

Luna joined them a second later.

“What IS it?!” Ginny asked again.

Another cramp, another keening, another deposit.

“Pheonix ash!” Luna gasped out. “Cauldrons of it!”

Now Ginny’s eyes widened too.

“And covered in basilisk acid!” Harry added. “We used a lot less than what’s there already for the ritual and that trapped us in an alternate dream space for over a year and a half!”

“And there’s more coming,” Luna added, her voice now taking on a hint of awe as a fifth hacked-up deposit was made. “No wonder the poor thing was in such a bad mood.”

“And I’m guessing we can’t just ignore it, or?” Ginny asked.

Harry shook his head. “That much ash in a situation like this? It’s a quite literal time bomb. We need to wait for it to finish, then hope to Merlin we can move it away before—“

There was a sound like a drain being unclogged, a seventh—or was it eighth—hack, and a medium-sized thing shot from the basilisk’s jaws and right into the damp ash.

Ginny and Luna both gasped.

Harry’s mouth became a thin line.

The thing constantly shifted form. It mutated and shrunk, beaks and feathers growing at weird angles. An extra taloned leg jutted from the small of its back.

Feathers detached and fell away, only to be replaced by new ones. Patches of skin showed through, cyst-covered and raw.

But the most shocking thing, was it’s eyes. Damp ash oozed from twin black orbs in a slow constant stream like flowing magma.

Fawkes let out a pain-filled song note.

Right before Harry’s eyes, in the rich oxygen-filled air of the Ravenclaw Common Room, the pheonix started to burn.“SHIELDS!”

The pile of ash erupted.

There was no plan for this, no pre-arranged training. At no point had Harry ever sat Luna and Ginny down and said, “Alright, girls. If ever we’re caught in the middle of a detonating pile of Phoenix ash triggered by a mutated rebirthing fire chicken, you, Luna, will cast a physical shield, you, Ginny, will cast a shield for magic defense, and I’ll handle the heat.” There was no plan like that.

Nevertheless, three wands instantly raised, and three magic shields instantly snapped into being, one physical, one magical, and one heat. Concentrated and powerful, they overlapped perfectly, giving the three standing behind them, Luna and Ginny pressed up on Harry’s sides, all the protection they needed.

Almost.

Luna apparently decided that what Harry really needed to finish off his perfect defense was a blindfold.

Harry heard the silence as the first blinding flash expanded over them, and tasted the magic smash against the shields. He felt the air rush against his skin and the heat scorch the room to char.

For the briefest moment, he felt nothing else as time seemed to turn to treacle.

Then, all at once, the sound returned — loud and in charge.

Harry wiped the chest wrap off his face to find the common room utterly destroyed, on fire, and both Luna and Ginny kneeling beside him in obvious pain, their hands clasped to their faces as though trying to dig the light out of their eyes.

And before him, in the middle of the room, the mutated Phoenix rose.

Slowly, Fawkes climbed into the air, changing in pulses as he went. More feathers slothed off. Beaks grew, then shrank, then grew again. Wings appeared in places they had no business being, before contracting back in on themselves. But with each pulse, the mutations became less, and the original Pheonix became more.

The clues came together and Harry realized what was he was seeing. The damn thing was actually going backwards in time. That was how the Phenoix rebirth thing worked.

He reached down with his free hand to comfort Luna and got a whimper and a desperate death grip on his forearm in return.

Harry watched with cautious eyes as the Phoenix began a rapid series of transformations, from mutant to chick, from mutant to chick, again and again and again, faster and faster, before a final burst of flames eminated, Harry got the briefest glimps of a restored adult bird, the flames consumed it utterly, and the next moment, it was simply gone.

Harry stared.

The massive pile of phoenix ash on the floor was now gone, vanished as though it had never been.

The basalisk writhed in pain, the front half of it’s head and body almost charred black. But even as he watched, the burn marks were healing, creeping up its neck, leaving pristine scales behind.

The rate of healing was slowing down though.

Harry put his hand on his sword handel and whipped it from its scabbard in one smooth motion.

Determined, he walked forward.

Each step of his feet sounded like canon strikes to his ears.

The sound of the basilisk writhing in pain faded from his consiousness, as did the still burning fires.

The beast’s writhing seemed to slow.

It contorted again.

Clearly it wasn’t quite done throwing up yet.

Fine.

Harry finished the final steps to the snake just as it opened it’s mouth widely again, ready to spew forth whatever might be left in its stomach.

Harry lunged.

His feet left the ground.

His flight sailed true.

His blade found flesh.

The snake juddered as his sword sunk home.

All in an instant, the world sped back up. Harry felt warm liquid splatter on his face as the top half of the head of the basalisk sliced clean in two from snout to neck. A literal spray of basalisk blood shot upwards like a sticky mohawk before it hit the roof of the common room, leaving a wet and dripping red line.

For a moment, the snake didn’t seem sure what had just happened. It just stayed there, still, with Harry’s blade lodged in the mouth of its jaw. Then Harry felt the gravity assert its claim on the massive weight. The ancient monster of Slytherin, possibly the single most dangerous creature in the wizarding world, the the guardian of the school, fell. Harry flew back.

The basalilsk smacked onto the floor at his feet with an almighty thud that shook the stone walls of the room. Dead.

“And we’re done,” Harry announced, wiping the blade on his robes. “If we’re quick, we can get this down into the chamber, and Alex may get her basilisk inferi. Not to mention all the other goodies we can snag from the kill.”

“Finders keepers,” sang Luna wandering over.

Both her and Ginny seemed to have recovered somewhat from the light, though Ginny still wore the expression of a witch emerging from a pitch-dark cave into a mid-day sun. She cautiously inspected the gigantic serpent which had to weight dozens of tonnes. “Big Monster time?” she guessed.

Harry nodded. “Big monster time.”

#

“I really need to start exercising more,” Hermione muttered as both she and Alex descended the stairs from the announcer’s box back towards the Slytherin dug out. “Ginny’s body is so much easier to move in. The girl feels like a rubber ball.”

Alex grinned. She’d been grinning for quite a while now. The dueling trophy still rested in her hands, high above her head. “But if you stopped reading so much and started getting all athletic and stuff, who’d be our team’s designated massive nerd?”

Hermione snorted. “You, probably. Don’t think I don’t know about your Boy-Who-Lived adventure collection.”

Alex spluttered wildly before choosing to ignore the comment in favor of basking in more trophy glory.

As they reached the dugout, the cheering and clapping died down and all around them, spectators started looking around speculatively.

“Now what?” Alex whispered.

Hermione covertly slipped her earpiece back on.

“Bookworm, this is Eagle Eyes,” Daphne’s voice said, almost immediately. She must be watching from a nearby perch. “Snake-Crown has achieved the primary objective. He’s currently securing the kill.”

Hermione let out a deep breath. She turned to Alex. “He did it.”

Alex gave the air a little fist pump. That done, she addressed the next most important matter. “So, now we just wait?”

Hermione nodded. “The most difficult part is over. Once he’s secured the kill and made the school safe again, there will be no reason to stay in lock down.”

On the far side of the arena, Ludo Bagman cleared his throat so everyone could hear him, presumably about to ask everyone to have patience and that they were doing what they could to speed up proceedings.

Hermione smiled. “I’d say that went pretty well.”

#

“That looks heavy.”

Ginny watched the her best friend and Harry slowly drag the massive snake corpse across the Ravenclaw common room, leaving a trail of black blood as they went. The task clearly wasn’t easy, even for a T-Rex and a Chimera.

Ginny bit her lip.

They’d done it.

They’d really taken down the basilisk. And that, even when it turned out to be self-healing.

In another time, this thing was responsible for her death. She couldn’t help wonder how it had happened. It was an image she’d been imagining for years now. Had it been quick? A simple glance into instant death? Had she been poisoned, screaming on the floor in agony as her life spasmed away? Crushed? Squeezed? Swallowed whole?

They’d done it.

Ginny grinned. She’d done it.

And now, Harry would reap the rewards.

A thought hit her, instantly dousing her moment of triumph.

Bones.

Her heart fell.

The Hufflepuff hadn’t been on the map the last time she’d checked.

She stared for a second as Chimera-Harry grunted, shoving his shoulder with maximum effort into the side of the dead snake while Luna pulled on it’s tail.

Maybe she’d just missed her in the excitement? Maybe the witch had just ducked into a secret passageway and appeared on the other side of the castle without Ginny noticing.

Yeah, that had to be it. Or something. The snake hadn’t been anywhere near either of them! There was no way Susan could be dead.

Ginny reached for the Marauder’s map hastily shoved into a pocket.

Her fingers closed around it.

She pulled it out.

And that was as far as she got.

Phoenix fire flared

Ginny’s head jerked around.

Albus Dumbledore appeared between them in a blaze of magical fire, wand out, radiating more power than Ginny had ever felt from anyone, ever.

Luna was nearest.

She roared.

#

Dumbledore had been ready for anything. An ongoing pitched battle with Slytherin’s Monster, perhaps. Maybe Harry Potter in the process of permanently subverting Hogwarts’ defenses. Or possibly, Lord Slytherin facing down his own protege in a climactic battle to the death, as the living horcrux attempted to seize control of the monster that Slytherin wished to destroy.

Dumbledore though he had been ready for anything. He hadn’t been ready for a long extinct land dragon, so large it had to squat and with teeth the size of daggers, roaring right at him.

His magic reacted with barely a prompting thought needed. A powerful magical blast rocked the floor below him, producing a small crater and sending broken flag stones flying into the air around him.

A flick of the elder wand and the flying rubble transformed in three flying halberds.

They shot towards the monster with barely a mental commanded needed.

In the split-second the halberds were in en-route, Dumbledore took stock.

The Ravenclaw Common room was utterly destroyed. A humungous snake almost as large as the Hogwarts Express lay unmoving to one side, confirming Tom’s story about the basilisk.

That was all he saw, until something that made his blood run cold leaped over the land dragon’s head and planted itself right in the path of his attack.

The halberd’s pointy bits all struck the creature, and nothing happened.

Nemean Lion.

Dumbledore’s brain updated with more details a milli second later

Nemean Lion-Hydra hybrid. A chimera.

Not good.

The chimera roared.

Dumbledore shouted. “Fawkes!”

He felt comforting flames surround him and his point of view changed to the other side of the common room, behind the monsters.

He snapped his wrist, producing a flame whip from the elder wand.

The land dragon whipped around, causing the whole room to shake. The chimera jumped on its head and together the two monsters roared again. The chimera’s muscles bunched. No doubt it could easily cover the distance between them in just one leap.

Dumbledores eyes flicked to the gigantic basilisk. It was very much dead. There was no sign of Harry Potter or Lord Slytherin. The castle was still safely in lock down.

…maybe retreating for the moment would be a better idea.

But before he could so much as give a mental command to his newly restored familiar, something sailed into the room from the doorway in a lazy arc, passing right over all their heads. It was small and black, and Dumbledore recognized it immediately. He should, because he supplied the primary raw ingredient to have them made.

Unfortunately, he didn’t have time to put on his sunglasses.

#

Harry’s world exploded. Light brighter than anything he’d ever experienced before seared every one of his many dozens of eyeballs.

Instinctively, he flinched down.

“GOGOGOGO!” Someone shouted.

Footsteps. Dozens of them.

If he changed, he’d be at their mercy.

He didn’t change.

“FREEZE!” Someone else yelled.

He felt the magic of over a dozen spells forming, and recognized many of them as belonging to the aurors.

Crap.

Then he felt the spears. They jabbed into his side, trying and failing to pierce. That he could do something about.

Whirling around, he batted away one spear, grabbed another with his jaws, wrenching it free and snapping it in two, and flicked another two away with his thestral tail.

The attacks stopped.

“Careful!” another of the aurors shouted.

The snakes of Harry’s mane hissed warnings to all not to get close.

Nothing further happened.

Slowly, his vision started to return. Clearly, the phoenix ash flashbangs were not nearly as potent as the mountain they’d just encountered.

Blinking away stars, Harry was greeted by a dozen goblin-silver tipped broom-spears all aimed at him from all sides. Their owners held them with steel-like grips and every auror looked grim.

Without moving his head, several of his snakes surveyed the scene behind and to his sides.

Dumbledore stood before them, next to one of the aurors, his wand out and also pointed at him.

And on Harry’s side, stood Luna. In her human form. Surrounded by three aurors with wands drawn and spears floating, all pointing at directly at her. The skirt of her robes was stained with blood.

Of Ginny, there was no sign.

The room was completely silent.

“I’m sorry,” Luna whispered. “Those spears hurt.”

Harry growled, and this time, there could be no doubt that this was not just a warning. He memorized their faces. He would make those three pay.

Clearly, something in his stance had changed enough to cause alarm. The aurors surrounding him took a step backwards.

“Wait!” shouted one of the aurors.

Harry saw it was Shacklebolt who had called out. Lord Black’s auror partner.

Harry tried to calm. He consciously brought his oclumency in on himself. Taking down the snake. Dumbledore bursting in on them. Then the aurors. He was better than this. He had to control himself. All of himself. He could deal vengeance for Luna later. The fact that the aurors in question couldn’t have known it was his Luna in the form of an ancient predator was, to be fair, a mitigating circumstance. On the other hand, to hells with fair.

Harry took a hundred tiny breaths into his central lungs and one large deep one.

Shacklebolt stepped forward. Like the others, he too held his wand pointing right at him with his spear floating beside.

“Oh, great predator of myth and lore,” he started, sounding like he was reading from a script. “We have seen your magnificence and respect your power. I am High-Warrior Shacklebolt, commander of the elite aurors of the Albion’s Ministry of Magic, led by High-Warlord Fudge the Terrible and the Mighty, by whose word a million warriors of magic and steel take to the sky to crush even the indestructible Nundu underfoot like bugs. Even as we speak, an army of fifty-thousand witches and warlocks approaches the gates of Hogwarts, undefeatable, unstoppable, capable of raising the castle to the bedrock in the blink of an eye. Whatever deal you may have cut with Lord Slytherin is irrelevant. He is not master of these lands! But we would not see such a great predator as yourself humbled by his duplicity. Such a thing would be a crime against nature, for one such as yourself, noble and royal of all the beasts. You will be given an island off the coast to rule over. As king! As is your right. Just speak you will come with us, and we will make it so, oh great predator.”

There was a long moment of silence before Shacklebolt spoke again.

“Unless, of course, you are an animagus as well. In which case, I highly recommend you to declare yourself immediately.”

Harry grunted. He’d been hoping to keep this particular secret under wraps for a little while longer than this. But it was better than the alternative. At least he would get to see Dumbledore’s face as one of the most dangerous magical creatures in the world transformed into Harry Potter.

Heh heh.

Harry locked eyes with the former headmaster.

And changed.

#

Hiding under the invisibility cloak, Ginny couldn’t help but grin. The look on Dumbledore’s face had been utterly delicious. The shock. The horror. The scrabbling to try to take back control of a situation that had clearly spiralled so far out of his control and then utterly failing.

He’d been relegated to taxi duty. Heading back into the pipes to fetch Daphne, Alex, and Luna’s fathers.

That last one in particular wasn’t helping him get much of a grip back on proceedings.

Lord Lovegood had not been amused to find three aurors holding his daughter at wand point and the fact that he was flanked by their boss only made it worse.

Not that team Harry had everything going their way. The matter of the basilisk in particular was proving to be quite difficult.

Words that Ginny more normally heard coming out of Daphne’s mouth, like, “Right of Conquest”, “Eminent Domain,” and “Controlled Substances”, were flying around fast and thick, often with rising voices and flared tempers.

And in the middle of it all, sat Harry, cross-legged on the floor with his hands behind his back, like some kind of criminal. He had two aurors guarding him.

Harry’s fate was the least unambiguous of all the matters being argued.

Despite Lord Black’s desire to take personal responsibility for him, there was only one legal option open to them, as his partner Shacklebolt had pointed out.

Harry was to be handed over to Lord Potter, just as soon as he arrived.

With Dumbledore’s phoenix now back in play, even with the war wards still active, that wouldn’t be all that long.

Well, to hell with that.

Ginny fingered the portkey on the necklace still hidden under her robes.

She’d had to wait until the Aurors had shifted away from Harry enough to have this opportunity.

Slowly, cautiously, taking care to make neither sound nor magic, Ginny crept towards where Harry sat with his guards.

“I’m telling you,” Lord Greengrass said in a raised voice. “Lord Slytherin will be here soon!”

“Well, if he’s not here in the next ten minutes then I don’t care what he has to say!” Shouted back Amelia Bones, who’d arrived not long after the castle had been declared clear. “He should have told us!”

“He did!”

Ginny ghosted past the auror nearest Harry and arrived at his back. She slipped the necklace off herself and reached under the hem of the invisibility cloak.

“And it’s still full of phenoix ash!” Another auror yelled at Lord Lovegood. “We can’t just hand it over!”

Ginny reached out and touched Harry’s hand. Harry’s hand jerked, then relaxed. Ginny squeezed, trying to communicate silently what she was doing, not trusting using even the tiny bit of magic needed to use their com rings around so many magic sensors, then forced the portkey into Harry’s open palm.

She closed his hand around the portkey and carefully backed away.

They needed Lord Slytherin to be here.

And they needed Harry to not.

#

With a stomach churning whoosh, Harry landed lightly in the darkened Hogwarts infirmary.

Thank Merlin for Ginny Weasley! His little ninja was proving herself again and again. He’d have to see if there was anything she wanted that he could reward her with. Although now that he thought about it, every one of his girls had performed above and beyond on this one. Daphne’s scouting and coordination, Alex’s success at the dueling tournament, Luna keeping up with him to lock the castle down, then helping to corral the snake, and shielding his eyes against the phoenix ash. Even Hermione, who hadn’t had that critical a role this time, stepped up when needed to cover for Ginny at the tournament.

Harry glanced around the hospital ward and found it empty, save the petrified students under covers.

A slightly longer glance at the bed where his twin lay helpless had him momentarily considering whether he should take advantage of the situation for some kind of extra petty revenge.

But no. No time. Plus, he was slowly taking everything that John valued in life from him, one chess piece at a time. That was more than good enough. For now, he had to get out of here. And that meant deactivating the war wards around the castle.

Harry closed his eyes. Accessing the wards in this state was no easy feat. It took concentration and skill. Eventually, he found what he was looking for. The switch to deactivate the lock down. He also noted that the magical power in the wards was still quite high, but that the three lock downs over the last two years had definitely taken a toll. The war wards were not infinite and could not be used indefinitely. They took time to recharge.

Harry manipulated his magics into position and, with a mental jab, flicked the switch.

All at once, a feeling like decompressing air could be felt.

Clangs and whirs sounded through the walls of the castle as locks were released, and windows opened.

This included the infirmary’s windows.

Light poured into the room as shutters were drawn back and sunlight poured through the glass.

Harry grinned and turned towards the nearest window.

Freedom.

That was, of course, when the lamia attacked.

#

After getting a hold of herself, the very first thing Virgo had done was crawl under the nearest bed. She liked to think she was no fool. Far from it. She was, in fact, the greatest witch that had ever lived.

She knew full well she wasn’t the only one with a port-key that led right to the Hospital Wing. She knew that with her brand new brother laying petrified right in this very room, that the only other people who’d have portkeys were going to be with the Gray.

Laying there in full Lamia mode, Virgo silently prayed to Death for the opportunity she needed. After all, if Death wanted the horcruxes gone, the least he could do was provide her with a chance to put things right, even if it would also kill his agent. Potter could only be a tool to the powerful being, nothing more. That felt fair to her.

When one of the other portkeys finally did arrive Virgo’s heart started beating wildly in her chest. She tasted the air and the air tasted of victory. And of Harry Potter. The air also tasted of Harry Potter.

… Lord Slytherin.

She peaked out from under her bed and saw The Gray Lord in child form weaving an enchantment in the air. Her own scene of magic told her what it was. He was deactivating lockdown.

Most likely he was going to escape through one of the windows. Her guess was he’d been caught by the same aurors that had ambushed her.

He didn’t look like he had a wand on him, but that was never a certainty. It would have to be a quick strike then.

She waited until the time traveller had finished his spellwork.

Her whole body coiled into a spring.

Potter turned towards the windows.

Now!

Virgo struck. With all the striking force of a giant cobra, she launched herself towards him.

“What?!”

Before the boy knew what was happening, she’d grabbed him in a hug. A second later, several hundred kilos of snake had wrapped around them both, crushing them together.

“Virgo.” His voice was low and dangerous, but Virgo ignored it. She couldn’t help it.

“Sss, Sss, Sss,” she hissed in laughter. “The look on your face, Pottteerrrr,” she drawled the last word.

“You’re a lamia animagus,” Potter stated, his face barley an inch from her own. His feet no longer touched the ground. Despite his position, he seemed remarkably calm. “That’s how you got back in the chamber.”

“Mmm, I don’t know what you mean with that,” she cooed. “You’re the one that released the monster.”

“Still going with that fantasy are we, Tom?” he asked.

Virgo smirked in his face.

Potter looked like he had a sudden realization. “Wait, not Tom… Riddle could never have achieved an animagus form with a split soul. ”

Virgo raised an eyebrow. He was fast on the uptake, but then she’d expect nothing less from a man like him. She felt him strain his muscles, as though trying to get free. It was useless of course.

“You are right,” Virgo said. “I am not the diary. Not any more. The sssoul of Julia Olson ssshines like a beacon.”

“When?” Potter asked.

“Mmm, can you not work that out for yourself?”

There was a pause.

“As you are now, you would make an excellent addition to the Gray,” Potter finally said. “Even your soul speaks to this. Pure darkness and pure light mixing together.”

Virgo hissed in laughter. “You would have me ssserve you, Lord Ssslytherin?”

There was a pause as Potter digested the fact that she knew who he was.

“Why not?” Potter eventually asked, still sounding calm, if incredibly focused. He could keep his head under pressure, she had to give him that. “You are already a daughter of House Malfoy. And your prime soul will never accept you as an independent entity. It is not in Lord Voldemort’s nature.”

“Ahh, yessss,” Virgo hissed. “That is certainly true.”

“He wishes you imprisoned,” Potter continued, gazing deeply into her eyes. “If not within a diary than within something else, maybe even someone else. You cannot stay with the Malfoys. If you join me, I will protect you and grant you the resources needed to flex your talents.”

Virgo still had her arms wrapped around the boy she held in her coils.

“You make good argumentsss,” she hissed. “But there is a problem.”

“What?”

“I love John.”

The look of shock on Potter’s—no, on Lord Slytherin’s face was priceless.

“No you don’t.” The words sounded automatic, spoken without thought.

“I do,” Virgo replied. “He was there for me. When I was trapped in that hell, John was there.”

“Because you are more Julia…” Potter trailed off before speaking again with a little more heat. “The only reason we didn’t eliminate the diary was because we knew Julia was in there.”

Virgo tilted her head. “Mmm, that doesss make me feel bad. I’m not going to deny that joining you isn’t tempting. You are clearly sssuperior to John in many waysss. You are ssstronger. You are sssmarter. You have achieved ssso much in ssso little time. You are more like me than John in many other waysss, too.” Her eyes lingered on the scar on Potter’s forehead. She could feel herself there. This close, she knew what it was.

“And despite all that and more, you’re seriously going to choose my brother over me?” Potter now sounded like he was trying to solve some extraordinarily difficult puzzle.

Virgo chuckled and she let a hint of sadness into her voice. “Yes. It’s a ssshame, in sssome ways.”

There was a moment of silence in the hospital wing before she spoke the next words. Words she knew would be the start of a ritual — a ritual that would solidify her position as the greatest witch the world had ever seen.

“We are sssplit, Potter, and that is something that I truly regret.”

The Hospital Wing vanished.

Darkness filled Virgo’s world.

She suddenly found herself standing on the precipice of her soul chasm.

Virgo very nearly lost her feet as the ground she stood on began to shake violently. Behind her, in her mindscape, the towers of Hogwarts Castle began to crumble. The gate was thrown open. Out in front of her, the void between souls grew, somehow, even darker.

Virgo ran to the edge.

“I regret the forming of this coven!” she shouted into the blackness. “I regret the ritual my prime made to split us apart! By the powers that be may we be returned!”

One of the strands that reached out into the darkness flashed and became illuminated by a blinding white light. The light shot out into the darkness like fire was running up the strand.

The shaking of the soul chasm became more violent.

A second later, a whole cliff face was pulled by a single strand through the darkness. The massive fortress of Azkaban Prison was on a collision course with Hogwarts School.

The blinding bright strand ran straight through the walls of the prison and into something held deep within. Virgo began pooling her magics for what would be the most complicated and difficult spell she’d ever attempted.

“NO!”

The soul chasm vanished.

The Hospital Wing returned.

Virgo suddenly found herself flat on her back, the wind knocked out of her. She gasped. Her whole body felt lit on fire from the accumulated magics all released at once. She couldn’t move. She felt pinned. It took her a few moments to realize why.

There was a giant Chimera standing on her chest! And though her lamia form was large, the Chimera was absolutely massive.

“No.” The lion part said in a firm voice. “I think not.”

#

The look on the lamia animagus’ face was priceless. Virgo squirmed and writhed under his paws, but no matter how much to tried to escape, Harry was simply too heavy and too strong.

“It is a shame,” his lion form said, while his mane of snakes hissed. “I wondered if I might be able to work with you. It seems that is not to be.”

Virgo gasped as he increased the pressure. “You-you’re a Chimera animagus,” she managed to get out. “Lion, snake, and thestral. Gryffindor, Slytherin, and Perverell.”

Harry snorted. “Quick on the uptake as ever, Tom.”

“Not Tom!” Virgo hissed. “I am Virgo!”

“Then you are Virgo. But that doesn’t help you. I presented myself to you as weak and offered partnership. And you chose instead to attempt to kill me. Not even Hermione would fault me for killing you after that.”

“You can’t kill—Hurrhh…“

He pushed the remaining air out of her lungs.

Virgo’s eyes widened in panic.

Harry considered the struggling lamia pinned beneath his weight. If she was a full soul, then delivering a normal fatal wound might be enough to sever her connection to her other soul fragments. Otherwise, he didn’t have many options. He didn’t have a shrunk trunk to abduct the girl with. He didn’t have a wand either, so he couldn’t transfigure her into something easier to carry. That also ruled out using fyiend fire to ensure her destruction.

Trying the same trick that Virgo had to absorb her soul into himself also wasn’t an option. He was a horcrux. A prison for a soul fragment. Unlike Virgo, he wasn’t actually part Dark Lord himself.

That left a wandless killing curse as the only real option. But if he tried that on the highly magically resistant, and quite frankly, large, lamia, and it didn’t work. Harry Potter would become an instant fugitive with a life sentence in Azkaban on capture. And since Virgo somehow had guessed the fact that he was also Lord Slytherin, that could make things difficult. Even if it did work, it might not nessisserily save him. He still didn’t have a wand to dispose of the evidence with.

He growled. “You leave me with very few options, Virgo.”

Virgo’s next words showed two things. The first was that she knew, or at least suspected, that killing her via conventional means might actually work. And second, she believed he was actually about to do it.

“Dead Man’s Ssswitch,” Virgo wheezed out.

The silence of the ward became oppressive.

Harry closed his eyes. Not completely, of course. A hundred snake eyes were still all trained on the lamia beneath him, but the feeling that of course things could still get more complicated was definitely there.

Harry reduced the pressure on Virgo’s chest.

The witch breathed in deeply.

“You, Virgo, have a dead man’s switch set up that will release the infomation that I am Lord Slytherin if you are killed.”

It was a statement.

Virgo’s eyes glittered with triumph. Then she started to laugh. Wild manic laughter whose general tone and cadence Harry definitely recognized, even if it was being modulated through the mouth and throat of a twelve-year-old girl.

“No, Potter. That’s what John and Sssusan think. That’s what I told them. Although my death isn’t the only way the switch can be triggered.” She was still laughing almost hysterically. “I know that you’ll have plans on what to do if that secret got out. I wouldn’t be surprised if you were already planning to drop the facade sssometime anyway!”

It was true of course. The book with Lockhart was nearly completion. He’d already brought many of the lords in the Gray faction in on the secret.

He frowned. “Then, what—?”

“My dead man’sss ssswitch won’t release your sssecret of being Lord Ssslytherin, Potter,” Virgo hissed. “It will show everyone that you’re a time traveller!”

#

Virgo watched the conflicting emotions flash across the lion’s face with utter relish. Shock came and went like a flash in the pan, followed by a bolt of anger. Oh, yes, he really should have seen this one coming. Next came the look of ferocious concentration as many multiple possible ways forward were no doubt called up and just as quickly dismissed. There was no need for Potter to hide how he felt from her. Hundreds of snake eyes studied her as though she were a puzzle.

It was a puzzle they could not solve.

She, Virgo, had left no avenue unguarded.

There was no doubt Potter was powerful. Incredible, even. If she didn’t know he was a time traveller, she’d have considered him an absolute monster. From what she’d learned since breaking free of her soul prison, the dark lord hadn’t started unifying the dark until he was already in his forties.
Potter had done it before the age of ten.

Virgo watched the mighty Gray Lord struggle with himself. There were only a few options for him now. And all resulted either in both of them surviving, or in Virgo surviving and Potter impaling himself on yet another of her prepared traps.

She’d prepared many, many traps.

Virgo felt more than realized the moment when Potter made his decision. All at once, a hundred snakes all locked eyes with her. And for the second time this year, Virgo felt a legilimense attack as strong as the sledgehammer of an angry god smash straight into her brain.

Virgo’s world vanished. Once again she appeared in the blackness of the void, but unlike when she had attacked Potter, this wasn’t the chasm between souls. This was the chasm between minds.

Rapidly, like the painting of a masterpiece sped up a thousand fold, Hogwarts castle appeared below—her mindscape—and down in that castle, Virgo could already hear the roar of an angry chimera tearing shit up.

Virgo smirked. An overwhelming feeling of triumph danced in her heat. Potter had taken the bait!

Landing on the top of the astronomy tower, Virgo sprinted down the stairs towards the sound of a mighty beast really letting itself go. It wasn’t a terrible plan, really. All her secrets were here, after all. If Potter wanted to learn the secrets of her deadman’s switch, ripping them clean out of head was a great way to go about it.

It wasn’t even technically illegal, so long as he didn’t cause any lasting damage. Technically. Though if mental attacks of this scale became common place, Virgo would bet her wand hand it would become illegal very quickly.

The roar was getting closer now. Triangulating the sound, it felt as though the roar was heading to the library, destroying every minor defense she had in place as it went.

Virgo transformed. Legs became tail. Skin became tail. Eyes grew slits. Everything got bigger.

She was not the same teenage dark lord that had sat in stunned helplessness as Luna ‘Fuck Toy’ Lovegood had ripped her mind to shreds looking for her own answers. She’d had plenty of time to prepare for this.

Reaching one of many secret entrances leading down to the chamber, Virgo hissed.

$Open$

The hidden door slid aside.

She’d also not left her mind defenseless since the merging of Tom and Julia had destroyed her last mental guardian.

Not even bothering to travel the long and twisty journey down to the chamber, Virgo simply stuck her head into the tunnel and screamed, $Speak to me, Slytherin! Greatest of the Hogwarts Four! Get up here you giant noddle! I need you!$

For the longest moment, there was silence.

Then it came.

Even larger than basilisk that Tom Riddle had created for his own mindscape, Virgo’s new guardian slithered out of her mental depths and powered into the corridor like an unstoppable tide of death. It hissed.

Virgo had to press herself up against the wall as it passed.

She started to cackle. $Go! Go, my creature! Catch Potter! Catch Potter and trap him in my mind! Make him my guest of honor! Make him my prisoner! And if he flees when he sees you, then see him, and petrify him!$

She really was the greatest witch that had ever lived.

Virgo stood there as the basilisk disappeared around the corner. She smirked.

After a while, the roar of the chimera became quite a bit louder, quite a bit more intense, as though suddenly in combat with something far larger and meaner than it.

Heh.

Virgo casually walked down the corridor towards the library.

The roars stopped when she was halfway there.

Nice.

Virgo rounded the final corner to the library, and froze.

Harry Potter, human Harry Potter, was sitting on the remains of the very large and quite clearly very dead guardian. He had a sword in one hand.
Virgo felt the blood drain from her face. “W-w-what?”

“What, what?” Potter replied, deadpan. “I’ve already killed a real giant basilisk today. What made you think I’d have any problems with your mental version? This thing can’t even kill with its gaze. That should tell you how much weaker it is than the real thing.”

Virgo couldn’t credit what she was hearing. “You, you killed the real basalisk? But then why did you use your portkey? Weren’t you running from it?”
Her heart was starting the thump harder. The full magnitude of the situation was starting to settle in.

“No, that was from the aurors.” Potter shrugged. “You still don’t want to tell me how to deactivate your deadman’s switch?”

Virgo took a step backwards.

“Shame.” Potter turned, hopped off the dead basalisk, and with a flick of his wrist slammed his way clean through the library’s solid oak doors like they were made of marzipan.

Virgo turned and ran.

Damn it all! This wasn’t good. This was NOT good. She went only as far as the next corner before stopping to get her breath back.
That library was where Potter would find the answer he wanted. He probably wouldn't find it straight away, but without anyway to stop him, eventually, he would.

Virgo cursed. She needed a plan. She was the greatest witch in the world. There had to be something else she could use. Some trick she still pull.
Her mind raced. Every possibility was weighed. Every option judged. Outside the castle, the sun began to speed across the sky as though on fast forward. Shadows whipped back and forth. The grass started to visibly grow.

Then it hit her.

It was a long shot. The chance of it working inside of the real Hogwarts wards had to be only one in ten.

It was also stupidly dangerous, even if it did work.

Freedom always was.

But desperate times called for desperate measures, and she was incredibly, bone-chillingly desperate.

Virgo took a deep, deep breath and screamed at the top of her lungs.

“DOBBY!”

#

Virgo’s mind was quite amazingly well organized for a witch born of two souls blending together. Though the fact that one of those souls was a sliver of the dark lord’s made it more understandable.

Unfortunately for Harry, this didn’t make his job any easier.

The shelves of Virgo’s mental Hogwarts Library were filled top to bottom with diaries. They started out pastel colored and covered in stickers, but slowly, more ragged and dirty examples started to dot the chronology.

Julia’s early years and her abduction by the Malfoys.

At around the half way mark, the dirty books suddenly switched to gigantic ornate tomes, inlaid with gold, smelling of old parchment and cloves.

Tom Riddle arriving at Hogwarts as a child.

Those diaries seem to go on forever.

Eventually, though, they were both replaced by much simpler stock. Plane, but well cared for, with little tiny locks on the side that wouldn’t stop a pair of nail clippers — a textbook example of what Harry imagined a teenager’s diary to actually look like.

Investigating those was quite eye opening.

John the hero.
John the handsome.
John my savior.
John.
John.
John.
John.John.
John.
John.
John.John.John.John.
John.John.John.John.John.John.
John.
John.
John.
John.
John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.
Oh, and Susan, too. A bit. I guess…
John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.John.

Harry put that one back like the lady of an ancient house levitating a dead mouse out the door.

And though enlightening, none of that helped him find the information he truly needed. How to deactivate Virgo’s deadman’s switch.

He made his way to the end of the final row, and still it was nowhere to be found.

Unsurprisingly, really.

Even believing her mental basilisk to the ultimate defense of her mind, someone like Virgo could never have too many defenses.

So where would someone like Virgo have hid it?

Harry thought back to what it was that made Voldemort tick.

True, Virgo wasn’t Riddle—that much was now abundantly clear—but asking the question, “Where would a random teenage girl hide her most important secret” probably wasn’t going to yield the results he was after. Though, he made a mental note that if push came to shove, looking under the girl’s bed in Griffindor Tower would be a good last resort.

How Voldemort thought…

Harry tapped his foot while staring up at the giant book shelves surrounding him.

Riddle wanted to be known everywhere as the greatest wizard who ever lived. He also wanted to be immortal. Those were two aspects of the dark lord’s persona that seemed to have mapped quite well onto Virgo.

He’d also dedicated a lot of his time during Hogwarts to fighting his way to the top of the Slytherin hierarchy. He’d studied the noble families, knew their customs and traditions. And though he’d never received formal occlumancy training, he’d nevertheless weaseled out a lot of the details once he’d been the undisputed ruler of the snake-pit.

Harry wandered back over to Virgo’s earlier memories — to the small collection of books that dealt with music. The violin for Tom Riddle, the piano for Julia Olsen.

Harry stared at the books.

Did the one in the middle feel different? Or was he just projecting his own desires onto what he hoped was the answer?

Harry touched the book. It was larger than the two on either side, looked better taken care of. Mastering the Violin — Making Magic out of Music.
Virgo had taken the blood of Malfoy, replacing her Riddle bloodline to become a true pureblood, the blood of Gaunt remaining as her ‘mother’ blood. Ironic as it turned out, since the Riddle bloodline had been Tom’s true connection to the house of Slytherin.

It was something he’d mused on before.

He, Harry, was Lord Slytherin.

Technically, Voldemort, as a son of house Riddle, might possibly be considered a member of his house. He could be said to be Voldemort’s lord. As amusing as that would be.

Harry smirked.

The question was, if Virgo had made a safe spot in her mental library, in the way of many noble families, had she done it before of after she’d taken Malfoy’s blood? Or even more interestingly, was Virgo, as a soul blend that included Voldemort, still connected in even the smallest way to the family of Riddle?

Harry focused his magic in his fingers and a small dagger made of glass materialized out of the aether, floating in the air of his cupped hand.

He pricked his finger and a single drop of blood welled up to the surface. He drew the finger down the middle book.

For a moment, nothing happened.

Then suddenly, a sound like a slow rockfall filled the library and all the books in front of him started to pull away, shaping themselves up and around into an arch way, just like the bricks leading to Diagon Alley. Beyond which, was a tight little nook, containing just three books.

Harry smiled. He loved it when he was right.

He was about to reach in and grab the first, when a squeaky voice behind him stopped him cold.

“You shall not harm Mistress Virgo!”

Harry had scant milliseconds to react before he felt the powerful buildup of demonic magics behind him erupt into a wave of pure force fired straight at him. He wasn’t fast enough. The wave hit like a tsunami, pushing him down through the corridor and out the nearest window. Thousands pieces of glass, iron, and lead lacerated his skin as he fell down towards the grounds below.

No.

Calling on his flight spell, Harry forced his way out of the wave of magic and rocketed up into the air. He slowed to a halt just above Ravenclaw Tower. Blood streamed from dozens of cuts all over his body, but that didn’t stop him from getting to grips with the situation.

That had been a house elf. And there was only one possible candidate for which house elf it could have been. It was the free house elf! The one that had attacked Ginny at the Quidditch match. The one that had given him the excuse to take back control of the Hogwarts wards. And now, Virgo had summoned it straight into her mind, seemingly bypassing the Hogwarts wards in the process. Of all the reckless stunts to pull, that one truly was worthy of the dark lord.

Harry shook himself. He’d think about that later, right now he had an elf to defeat. Free house elves were absolute monsters, but then, so was he.
First, he’d—

A pop from behind him sent every danger cell in his body screaming to attention. It was as though Death himself was shouting at him to move.
Harry ducked. A gigantic sword larger than he was tall whooshed through the air right where his neck had been. The three-foot elf wielding it looked comically out of place attached to it, but there was nothing comical about the power forming around the creature again.

Harry braced himself as another wave of power smashed into him.

Shooting towards the ground, Harry transformed just before he hit, landing in a four-legged crouch that embedded his paws over a foot into the soft grassy earth with a slam loud enough to echo around the grounds.

There was another pop from what had been behind him, but Harry was already turning. A hundred snakes hissed. One giant lion opened it’s jaws wide.

The house elf had just enough time to open its eyes as wide as saucers before Harry’s jaws snapped shut. Around empty air.
The next pop came from quite a bit further away.

Harry launched himself towards it. Free house elves were dangerous. He couldn’t allow it time to get its wits together. Unfortunately, he was nowhere near fast enough. The house elf’s magics were already swirling into a powerful vortex by the time Harry had covered even half the distance.

The house elf didn’t look triumphal though. Instead it looked almost panicked.

“Dobby is not wanting to!” The house elf screamed. “But Dobby must. Potter boy is too strong!”

The vortex snapped into place and A giant tentacle whipped out of it.

Harry screeched to a halt, but wasn’t fast enough.

The tentacle whipped around his right paw and stayed wrapped around his right arm as he transformed back. He severed the tentacle a moment later with a wandless cutting charm, but there was already another in its place. Dozens of tentacles snapped around his arms and legs, around his neck, over his face, and before he could so much as even think a curse, he’d been yanked forward, straight into the vortex. And straight out of Virgo’s mind-scape.

Out in the real Hogwarts hospital wing, Harry flew backwards with a sound like a gigantic burp. He tumbled. He landed. His head snapped up. His eyes snapped open.

Virgo stared back at him, her own eyes wide and unsettled.

There was a moment of silence.

Virgo raised her hand.

Harry instinctively began to form an intent to counter whatever she was about to do, but instead of launching an offensive spell, Virgo raised her hand to her face as though seeing it for the first time. Light began to form around the digits, but the magic that radiated out from her was of no form that any witch or wizard should possess.

“Oh, no.” Virgo whispered. “Virgo not be liking this. Virgo not be liking this at all.”

Suddenly, rapid heavy footsteps could be heard getting louder from outside the hospital wing.

Both Harry and Virgo’s heads whipped to the shut door.

“Potter!” shouted a voice, followed by a rapid banging on the door. “Potter, are you in there?”

Harry didn’t wait. The lock down was already over. He had places, and people, to be. “Consider this a stalemate!” he called behind him as he dashed towards the window.

Virgo just stared in horror at a vision apparently only she could see.

The door slammed open and one of the aurors stepped in. The man just had time to see Harry Potter take a running jump at a full glass window on the top floor of the castle. “Wait! Potter! Your godfather said—!”

Crash.

The sound of shattering glass filled the hospital wing.

The man ran past the thankfully still living lamia animagus and slammed into the window frame, just in time to see the world’s only chimera animagus booking it away on all fours, across the grounds, towards the forbidden forest.

“You’re not in trouble!” he shouted after the boy. “You don’t have to—” But it was useless. Without so much as a backward glance, the majestic beast leapt into the undergrowth surrounding the forest, and vanished clean from sight.

It was the last time anyone not in the Gray would see Harry Potter for several months. And by the time they did see him once more, nothing would be the same again.

#

*Wibble Wobble Wibble Wobble*

All across magical Britain, over five thousand Wizarding Wireless devices halted their performance of the repeated season six finale of Diagon Woes, right before the final kiss, to switch back to the news.

*Wibble Wobble Wibble Wobble*

My Lords and Ladies, wizards and witches, we interrupt the interruption of your usual programing to bring you important news from Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry. The cause of the recent break-off in coverage of the Hogwarts Dueling Tournament has been confirmed as an unscheduled lock-down of the school and its grounds. We’re getting word from a trusted source that the lock-down has now been lifted and no one has been hurt.

While no official statement has yet been made, we understand that the reason for the lock-down was a large-scale magical creature incident from within the school itself. Anonymous sources from within the ministry reported a full-scale mobilization of the Department of Magical Disasters and Catastrophes, along with the Department for the Regulation and Control of Magical Creatures, as well as an advance force of over a dozen aurars. The call up has since been canceled however, and all ministry personal have been put back on standby until further notice. Probably until tea time.

The exact nature of the magical creatures involved are still unknown, though many incredible rumors are flying around and we’ll no doubt know more in the coming days.

The Hogwarts dueling tournament was won by Slytherin House, with MVP going to Heiress Alexandra Patricia Black, only the third student in Hogwarts history to full sweep the opposing team as a first-year student and the first first-year student ever to achieve that feat twice against both opposing teams. Her most spectacular match was against first year Gryffindor, and student minister, Miss Virgo Malfoy, the fourth first year to clean sweep the enemy team. The spectacular fight will no doubt be a memory parlor favorite for years to come and included family magics, elemental summons, spell swatting, creature summoning, and ended in Miss Virgo Malfoy’s unexpected surrender after successfully casting a phoenix patronus strong enough to force back, but not quite defeat, Heiress Black’s Grim animagus form.

The dueling cup was presented to the Black Heiress by her year-mate, and new quidditch phenom, Ginverva ‘Ginny’ Weasley. Coming rulings in the Wizengamot will decide if such a young player can be permitted to compete for the national quidditch team, and after today no doubt our government will be asking themselves the same question about our national dueling team as well.

Due to the interrupted broadcast, we will be repeating the whole tournament two weeks from today, here, on the Wizarding Wireless. Make sure to stay tuned in!

Down at The Burrow, Mrs Weasley turned off the Wireless with a flick of her wand while letting out a deep sigh of relief and pride. On the wall behind her, all 'mortal peril' spoons on the Weasley family clock had once more whirred to the ‘at school’ position. All across the country, parents who couldn’t attend the dueling tournament themselves, did likewise, though mostly just with relief.

Up on the castle grounds, hundreds of wizards and witches made their way out of the arena towards the gates of Hogwarts. Some apparated away towards Hogsmeade, intent on catching the floo back home, or riding the Hogwarts express, for those with time to kill and nostalgia to indulge.
The students, however, were all asked to gather together before going back to the castle.

“Ravenclaw students!” Squeaked Professor Flitwick while still addressing the whole school. “I’m afraid we’re going to have to bunk outside of Ravenclaw Tower for the moment while repairs are underway. No I can’t say why right now. If anyone has friends in other houses, I’d encourage you to join them for the time being. Extra beds will be provided. And no, Mister Baker, you can not join your fiancé. Girls with girls and boys with boys only. In the mean time, we’re all going to have to wait out here until we get the all clear that Hogwarts has been deemed safe once more, so dinner will be provided here.”

“That’s right!” Boomed Headmaster Lockart, swooping in and giving an outraged Flitwick a noogie. “Bring on the benches! Bring on the drink! Let’s feast and be merry! Under the stars of Hogwarts!” He pointed dramatically to the sky, which was still midday, and then up to the castle where the Great Hall’s massive tables floated towards the wide-eyed students.

Soon the tables and benches had been placed in the sands of the arena and food and drink began to fill plates and goblets.

High above the dueling arena, on one of the many flag poles carrying the Hogwarts crest, a golden eagle perched and watched. As students, teachers, and a few remaining parents who’d yet to vacate the grounds, began to dig into the feast, the eagle spread her wings and soared off and up, up into the air, banking around on a stray current and off toward the castle.

Daphne swooped down low, skimming the grass before the Hogwarts giant front doors, before pulling up and transforming mid-air.

“They are still not letting anyone in,” said Hermione, loitering in the doorway with her arms folded.

Standing next to the Slytherin muggleborn, Alexandra Black clenched her fists, a clear sign she was frustrated. “The basilisk corpse is still fresh,” she said. “The inferi ritual is best done when the corpse is still fresh.”

“And it will remain fresh,” Daphne said, shaking out her hair. “The aurors may not be allowing you and I in, but our lord is not so hampered. Soon, he shall grant us passage.”

Alexandra smirked. “I wish I’d seen their faces when they saw his power.”

“Them seeing his power is not a good thing,” Hermione shot back. “It will cause all sorts of problems.”

Daphne nodded her head. “Yes. Yes, it will.” She put a hand to her ear. “Bulldozer? This is Eagle Eyes. Any updates?”

Up in the partially destroyed Ravenclaw Tower, Luna Lovegood, sitting on the floor with several bandages wrapped around her arms and legs, put a hand to her own ear. “Eagle Eyes,” she whispered, although whispering was hardly needed given the shear quantity and volume of argument coming from all around the room. “Our lord arrived not long ago. It’s all getting rather shouty.”

#

“I don’t see what else there needs to be said!” Minister Fudge shouted at the top of his lungs. “You’ve killed the monster. Without telling us about it first, I might add! Why didn’t you tell us first?! Anyway, you’ve killed the monster, so just remove yourself from the wards! The events of today show clearly why one man cannot just have sole power over an institution as old and as… er… venerable as Hogwarts. It simply can not stand!”

“I did inform the ministry,” Slytherin replied calmly, standing in the centre of a ring of hostile glares. “I received no response. And I’m afraid that’s not possible, Minister. Certainly not until the rogue house elf has been found.”

“You’ve used that excuse before!”

“And it remains as true now as it was then.” Slytherin turned to the owner of one of the glares directed at him. “Though it does seem odd, does it not, Lord Malfoy? Free house elves are known to be chaotic in the extreme. But this one seems quite circumspect. Almost as though it is being directed. Don’t you find that odd?”

“Very odd.” Malfoy said back, somehow managing to convey a blank face while still glaring daggers. “But I do not believe the house elf can be our primary concern anymore. This expedition of yours was reckless in the extreme, endangering both my heir and my daughter.”

“The daughter that snuck into Hogwarts through the very chamber the monster itself was released from?”

Lucius sneered. “Virgo did not achieve her animagus form until well after the first attack. Therefore, she cannot be considered a suspect.”

“That’s based on what? Your word?”

“Yes, my word. Just like your assertion that Harry Potter and your bethrothed did not achieve their animagus transformations alongside Greengrass, Weasley, and Black is based on your word.”

“They really didn’t.”

“Oh, like we’ll believe that!” James Potter snarled. “You don’t think I don’t know about how a group of students can become animagi together? You even stole Sirus’ family secret to help!”

“James,” Lord Black said in a warning tone of voice.

“No—” Lord Potter shot back. “It’s clearly obvious what he did. We did the same thing. He’s using your daughter, Sirius. Can’t you see that?”

“He is not using Alex! I’m proud of my daughter’s accomplishments. I don’t know how they managed to become animagi that quickly, but I do know it wasn’t how we did it.”

“But, a chimera!?” James shouted. “A child should not wield such power!”

“I’d have thought you’d be happy,” Lord Slytherin replied. “He is your heir.”

“Harry is NOT my heir. John is my heir. I want you to stay out of my son’s life!”

“It does seem,” Lucious Malfoy jumped in before Harry could respond, “that Lord Slytherin is far too interested in the upbringing of other people’s children. Corrupting minds. Leading them astray… A worrying development, given his insistence on keeping control of the Hogwarts Wards. Perhaps, a gesture of goodwill is appropriate to show Magical Britain your intentions are not malicious.” There was a moment of silence before he continued. “If you, to take a purely hypothetical example, released the children of the Dark faction from their pledge of allegiance to Alexandra Black, I’m sure that would go a long way to assuring society that you don’t—”

“If there’s going to any goodwill gesture,” James interrupted, “It’ll be for him to leave Harry alone!”

“Please, gentlemen. “Harry held up his hands. “I have no malicious designs. I cannot release Draco and his friends from their pledge, because they are not pledged to me. They are pledged to Alex. And from what I hear, she is leading them quite well. Besides, I believe we have already discussed quite a substantial ‘goodwill gesture’ between us already, Lord Malfoy?”

The amnesty deal for former death eaters laid in the upcoming Muggle Protection Act.

Lord Malfoy made an unsatisfied noise in his throat.

“As to Harry, I have absolutely no intention to abandon my care of the boy. Though if it would appease you, I’d be open to having his godfather take some responsibility for his oversight.”

“It doesn’t appease me!” James snapped.

Sirius frowned. “You don't not trust me?”

James looked like someone had punched him in the gut. “No, Padfoot. No, that’s not what I meant. Of course I’d trust you.” He flung out a pointed finger. “It’s him I don’t trust!”

Sirius didn’t look convinced.

Harry in turn nodded. “Well, since it’s me you have a problem with then maybe I have a solution.”

James narrowed his eyes. “What solution?”

Harry withdrew a parchment from his robes. “I have here a betrothal contract, already signed, between Harry Potter and Ginny Weasley.”

Unseen by anyone in a corner of the room, a girl squatting beneath an invisibility cloak breathed in sharply.

“The Weasleys are purebloods of long standing, but their role has always been that of mediators — power brokers for the factious noble houses. Classic civil servants. I’m sure that Arthur would be the top Humblehag by now, if he cared to stretch his ambitions so far. The upcoming Muggle Protection Act in the Wizengamot is proof of his tripartisan nature. Despite that, the Weasleys have always leant more closely to the Light. Your wife and Arthur’s are friends. John is best friends with Ron.”

“In other words, they are the perfect family to hand Harry over to. You’ll know that Harry is in the care of a family close in interests to your own, and I’ll know that Harry will have the support of a large and supportive family. That and I know that Harry and Ginny both really like each other, so the match is a good one.”

Lord Potter said nothing.

“Besides,” Harry continued, “Everyone knows that Ginny is going to join the quidditch league soon. She’s too good for the wizengamot not to make an exception. She’d do well to have a husband who can financially support her sporting ambitions. And a father-in-law who can be proud of her accomplishments.”

For a moment, Lord Potter actually looked tempted. Then he viciously shook his head. “No!” He glared at Slytherin. “I know exactly what you are. And who you are. And I have not forgotten our history. I wouldn’t put it past you to be splitting up my family just out of spite. I will not be betrothing Harry to anyone you approve of…,”—he stepped forward, crossing the distance between them, stood in front of him for a second, before leaning in close to Harry’s ear so that only he would hear and growled out the final word of the incomplete setence, “…Lupin.”

He then stepped away and stared at Lord Slytherin’s impassive visage, as though waiting for a reaction. When he naturally failed to get one from the mask Slytherin always wore, he turned and walked away.

“This isn’t over, Slytherin!” Lord Potter shouted behind him. “I’ll see you in the Wizengamot!”
The remaining lords all stared after him.

“I think I shall take my leave, as well,” said Lord Malfoy. “There’s been more than enough excitement here for one day.” He started to walk away as well, but turning back. “We’ll have to talk again about the Dark’s support for your amendments to the Muggle Protection Act before it goes to the final hearing, Slytherin. Don’t think your actions here today will not have consequences.”

Dumbledore, who’d remained silent up till this point, walked up to Harry and spoke quietly so only he could hear. “I do not believe giving Harry to Miss Weasley will be enough to stem the darkness that lies within. If anything, I fear it is she that would become corrupted by him. And now that we know what kind of dark creature his soul embodies, I fear this is even more so.”

“Then it is fortunate that I’m not asking for your opinion, isn’t it?” Harry bit back.

Dumbledore gave him patented D-stare number 54, disappointed headmaster, before stepping back, raising his arm, giving a command to his now regenerated pheonix, and flaming out without another word.

Harry turned to the minister and his undersecretary, a rotund woman in pink, who, rumors had it, was going to be next in line for the top Humble Hag position.

The witch seemed rather torn by his presence, as though not sure if she should be impressed, scared, or disgusted. Her eyes kept flicking between him and the dead thousand-year old basilisk behind him.

“And you, minister?” Harry asked. “Do you have a suitably dramatic exit to make?”

“What? Oh, err…” The man seemed to get a hold of himself. “Yes! Yes, in fact, I do. You cannot just waltz in here and control Hogwarts like you did. I will have no choice but to talk to people about this! Certainly, defeating this, err… very large snake, is a positive, but it does not outweigh the damage to the ministry’s image and authority. And no, you cannot keep it. I’ll have experts come up form the Department of Magical Creatures to take it away. Until then, it will be under guard. Do you understand, Lord Slytherin?”

“Crystal.”

The minister then turned and did his best impression of a powerful man storming out, though compared to the three men who came before him, it looked rather less than impressive.

Soon, Harry was left alone. Alone, except for a dozen aurors, several other lords of the Wizengamot including Jacob, Sirus, and Xenophilius, paintings waking up from their previously stunned state, the headless haunt arriving back with the Hogwarts ghosts, and lastly, and probably actually the least, Filch the caretaker, staring at the destruction that went far beyond mere mess with more horror than the colossal dead killing machine.
The day passed and night fell.

Standard DMLE guard wizards replaced the elite aurors on watch duty, not light security, but certainly lighter than before.
Light enough for a certain red-haired witch hidden under an invisibility cloak to quietly stun them all.

A figure floated in through one of the destroyed windows. It aligted on the ground, pulled out several miniature ward stones, and quietly got to work.

Some time later, Harry finished up his placement of a fideleus ward around the snake.

A little while after that, a golden eagle swooped into the room.

Daphne received the secret, walked up to the corpse, and concentrated. She whispered an incantation, and the temperature of the room plummeted. Ice began to spread from the tips of her fingers over the corpse. It wasn’t a fast process, but eventually the entire basalisk was one large popsicle.
Possession was two thirds of the law. Keep it fresh, that was the trick. Ministerial overreach could be judged by the wizengamot soon enough. Until then, they’d keep this little treat on ice.

— End of Chapter 59 —